Today
is
the day we
are celebrating Easter. Easter is extremely
symbolic, of - not only of Christ, but also
for all of us. In that the most important
day is that of resurrection. The resurrection
of Christ has
the message of Christianity, not the cross.
Through resurrection Christ had shown that
one can be resurrected with the body that
you have. And without His resurrection, we
could not have managed the crossing of Agnya
chakra, no doubt. His life was very short
of, we can say three and half years only,
He lived there. He came to India and He met
Shalivahana, and Shalivahana asked His name.
He told him His name was Isa Masih.
But He said, "I am coming from the country
where there are malichchas, mala-ichchha.
They have ichchha of mal, desire to get dirty,
and I don't know how to live there. To Me,
this is My country."
But Shalivahana said that, "You should go
back and save Your people and give them Parama
Nirmala Tattwam. So He went back, and as it
is, within three and half years He was crucified.
At the time of His death He said so many beautiful
things for forgiveness, but ultimately He
said "Behold the Mother." That means you should
hope for the Mother. And in His lifetime He
also said that, "I'll send you the Holy Ghost
Who will comfort you, counsel you and also
redeem", means resurrect you. All these things
He had said it because He knew what was the
whole plan.
Also He said that, "You may say anything against
Me or do anything against Me, but anything
against the Holy Ghost I will not tolerate.
I will not tolerate at any cost."
Which is true also, so it is very dangerous
also to go against the Holy Ghost. No doubt
about it. It's not Me that is dangerous, but
these Deities are extremely dangerous.
So, in Sahaja Yoga you are all resurrected
with your body. Before this you were not connected
to the All Pervading Power, and whatever you
did was through your mind or through your
emotions. But you did not come out of that
grave of emotions and your desires, your actions
and your ego. After realization now you know
how free you have become. How you have developed
your own personality.
There are so many instances which we can talk
about Christ, that He said, "Know Thyself"
throughout. He knew without knowing yourself,
you won't be resurrected. But Sahaja Yoga
is the other way round. You get your resurrection
and you know yourself. It's a very Sahaja,
sweet way of getting realization.
But if you see to the life of Christ, He has
talked about murmuring souls. We too have
in Sahaja Yoga, because it's open to everyone,
all kinds of people come. We find very shallow
people coming to Sahaja Yoga who try to express
their shallowness and talk in a very, in a
very loose way, about Sahaja Yoga, about the
work of Sahaja Yoga. So that was inevitable,
but what Christ has said that you have to
be careful about the murmuring souls. And
this is exactly - we have to be very careful.
When you come to Sahaja Yoga, in the beginning,
you may come across such people who are murmuring
souls, you may be enticed by them because
they are a kind of, we should say, messengers
of negative forces. And these messengers of
negative forces, you should try to find out.
They'll complain about this, complain about
that, they talk in a very loose manner, and
when you see that they are not talking in
a positive way, you should run away from them.
Because only by getting your resurrection
you are not all right. After getting your
resurrection, after your Self-realization,
you have to grow. And for that growth we have
to be very careful about how we get impressed
by all these, I should say, very frivolous
people. Those who grow into it become beautiful
angels. No doubt about that. But that is one
thing one has to know is to respect your Self-realization.
You shouldn't worry about what others are
talking, what others are saying, what they
are criticizing, but you should look at yourself
and all the time try to grow into your depth.
It's a very great chance of life that you
are being resurrected, and this is the last
breakthrough, as you know, of our evolution.
But now you should leave your mind on one
side; because this mind, if you go on working
with it, you cannot go beyond mind and Sahaja
Yoga you can achieve by going beyond your
mind. Then you know yourself, because you
get Self-knowledge. You know about your centers.
You know about the centers of others. All
this is available to you, but you have to
become a subtler and subtler person. Not a
gross personality. If you become subtler and
subtler, you will be amazed how you will develop
your inner powers in so many different ways.
But there are people in Sahaja Yoga, I have
seen, who are very ambitious. And they start
saying that, "Mother, we want to be God realized.
I want to be this and do that." There is no
office going on here that you give somebody
a promotion. You have to grow yourself. Then
they start proclaiming, "I am this, I am that."
We call them 'Mahayogis'. Some of them had
started saying that they have reached very
high positions and they ended up in the lunatic
asylum. All such suggestions if people give
you, then you should shun such people. But
there are also other people who join such
a bombastic fellow. So, you must remember
that this last judgment is working and all
the time there is a big sieving out, a very
big arrangement of choices. Those who are
subtle, start getting subtler and subtler
and subtler. But those who are frivolous,
gross, idiotic, stupid, they start frittering
away. So this last sieving starts very fast,
working out where we realize that where are
we.
Now what is the criteria for that? First is
your compassion. Your compassion must be discrete.
Sometimes people only have compassion for
negative people. After Sahaja Yoga you should
know for whom you should have your compassion.
With vibrations you can find out, very easy
to find out with vibrations - what sort of
a person you are facing. But first you must
have vibratory awareness. If you don't have
vibratory awareness, you won't be able to
find out at all what is correct and what is
incorrect. So it is important that you all
must mediate. Without criticizing yourself,
anything, you can just meditate everyday.
Is very important!
I immediately know who is the person who is
meditating and who is not meditating. Immediately!
The person who meditates is very clearly an
angel. The whole reaction, the whole behavior,
the whole attitude of such spiritual maturity
manifests. And you are amazed. As you know
Sahasrare Mahamaya. It's not easy to understand
Me. For the time being you might know what
I am, but suddenly you will forget. That's
the trick. Because if you know Me in full
ways, you won't even sit here. You won't even
come nearer to Me. So that Mahamaya is acting
all the time, but that's the only way you
can judge people.
This last judgment is not a easy thing. Even
if you put thousands of judges, they cannot
do this judgment. All the time you have to
know what is what. And somehow I know everything,
but I will never show that I know. That's
how I work it out, and gradually I know what
I have to do about that person.
This resurrection of yours is much more blessed
than that of Christ. He was alone; people
wouldn't recognize Him. He had to show His
marks where they had put nails on His hands
and feet. But today that is not the situation.
Only thing is, first of all you have to recognize
Me. That's all. Need not know Me. It's not
easy. It's difficult to know Me, but if you
recognize Me, that's all. And it all depends
on your sensitivity. Your resurrection has
to be complete and you have to mature in Sahaja
Yoga. If you cannot mature, I will say you
should leave Sahaja Yoga. Go out for a while,
where you will understand what's going on,
then you'll come back.
In Sahaja Yoga, like Christ sacrificed His
life, is not expected of you to sacrifice
your life. Your Mother doesn't want that.
But you have to do some sacrifices, like you
have to stay in uncomfortable places in Ganapatipule
sometimes, or somewhere. You have to face
many odds while traveling, also coming down
here may not be so comfortable as you are
at your place. But the main sacrifice is of
your ego. You have to crucify your ego. The
ego is the one, which teaches you all these
nonsensical tantrums that people know. If
you can surrender your ego - just surrender
your ego - that surrendering can help you.
But if you surrender your ego by thinking
about it, then you are using your mental capacity.
Everything you do like that is through your
mental capacity, by which you are using your
ego. So the best way is to meditate, to go
into thoughtless awareness and there automatically
you are surrendered.
Now what do I have to have from you? Nothing!
I don't want anything. I don't want to have
anything. You are the ones who try to give
Me this and give Me that. I am trying to run
away from all that. Just for your satisfaction
also, I agree. I don't have to do Sahaja Yoga
Myself, but that's the love of your Mother.
That She wants to save as many as possible
- all that are created on this Earth - to
give them their resurrection. This is a special
time and you are My channels. You can go all
over and spread Sahaja Yoga and try to help
others to come out of it.
Today is a day of promises, where we have
to promise ourselves that we'll grow in a
very deeper understanding, or feeling, or
in sensitiveness of Sahaja Yoga. This growth
has to take place for which I have to meditate.
This is a very important thing.
Secondly, people say that here people are
very miserly. They are not willing to do this.
They don't want to pay any money for this,
pay any money for that. I think generosity
is one expression of your love. You will give
Me, all right. When it comes to expenses,
either I pay or somebody bears the burden.
Now things have improved, but still we should
know that this tremendous work has to be done
and we need money for that. I don't need,
I spend My own money. But generosity is the
best and this generosity is very, very important
for Sahaja Yogis.
I have seen people are very meticulous sometimes,
very calculating. They will tell Me, "Bring
some sarees for them." Take some sarees, all
right, very good idea. And they say, "We don't
like it, we don't want to buy." I am not doing
any business. I buy it because you wanted,
I have selected it. Then to say, "we don't
want to have it." There's no business, there's
no marketing going on. And this is the problem
when I don't understand Sahaja Yogis that
they should know Mother, Herself, has put
in Her money. So what is there also, they
should say, "take little more for Sahaja Yoga."
After all such a big organization going on,
and there are so many countries who cannot
pay a single farthing, for them also one has
to pay.
Now, Christ was sold for thirty rubles. You
can imagine, He was sold for thirty rubles.
So that shows that when you do not try to
understand the financial difficulties of the
organizers and you do not help, you are really
selling the Christ within you. You cannot
sell Christ, you cannot sell Sahaja Yoga.
But that doesn't mean you exploit it. So I
have to tell you that I was Myself surprised
in north India where I least expected people
are extremely generous, extremely generous.
And then generosity helps you, in a way that
our Lakshmi Tatwa is to be awakened.
I had to bring in this point because I have
complaints from people that people are reluctant
to pay for anything like this. It's very remarkable
that some people take over, but everybody
must contribute. It's important, because you
are doing God's work. You have to also come
forward to do other things that are there
without grudging. Enjoying it! I was happy
the posters were put by the Sahaja Yogis,
and you can see the whole place vibrated.
You could see how it has worked out. So everybody
must go all out to do everything that is possible.
Nothing else is needed but your full heart
into Sahaja Yoga. Then you will see how you
will grow. It is only through your heart you
will receive all your nourishment for your
spirituality. So open
your heart, do
not calculate so much.