Today we are here to celebrate Sahastrar Day.
It was not very difficult for Me to open the
Sahastrar because there were so many seekers
in this world: because, of course, I had studied
also, the permutations and combinations from
which you all are, in a way, suffering. Also,
the time had come. I felt [that] horrible
gurus, who are really devils, are trying to
capture all the seekers. I thought it's high
time that Sahastrara should be opened out.
It was not like Christ’s crucifixion by
any chance. In those days one had to do lot
of tapasya and that’s what He went through.
But in these modern times, what you know
is much more important than what you do.
It is such a universal awareness now because
of maybe, medias, because of communications,
because of travelling, that a human mind knows
a lot. It knows so much sometimes that its
brain cannot even bear it. It is so overloaded
with ideas and also the human mind is all
the time anxious to grasp, absorb and retain
whatever he thinks is knowledge. But he lacks
discretion, so all kind of things are accumulated
in his brain in the modern times. Specially
with the advent of all this media like television,
computers. Not a media, but it’s quite a
complicated brain again...the man had to know
the technique of all these things very much.
And this technique, if he understood, he could
do many things, many more things than your
forefathers could do. Thus, materialism started
taking its own development in the minds of
people. So the curse of human beings, at that
time, was materialism: when I felt that Sahastrara
must be opened out.
Before that, people were just simple, innocent:
they all believed in God, they never doubted,
and they didn't even seek the Truth. This
materialism created such a competition among
human beings, such hypocrisy, that people
started finding out that: this is not honest,
materialism is not joy-giving, you can't get
peace out of materialism. Just it started
developing into their awareness that this
is not the end of our achievement, this is
not what we have to know, this is not what
is going to give us joy and peace.
Specially after war, this awareness started
growing very much among young people.
This is also because, now, the human awareness
had reached the state of the brain.
That's how they started knowing better, absorbing
better and retaining better.
You take a little child of today, he knows much better than
you would have known when you were even 25
years of age; because he’s supposed to know
about everything.
And thus, there was no movement
towards knowing what is the Truth.
But, as this awareness grew more and more, lots of
seekers were created on this earth.
So many people, who never knew they were seekers,
suddenly became seekers. It's a atmospheric
effect, I should say.
And thus, a new category
of people were born, became aware, that they
have to find out the Truth.
So, it was all simultaneously, according to
the time,
that Sahastrara was to be opened out.
And thus, this happened.
For us sahaja yogis, of course, Sahastrara
is the biggest event.
Or we should say - whatever work all
the incarnations have done, all the seers
and saints and prophets have done, this is
the culminating point.
They did it for individuals,
but to do for masses, that it should go to
every nook and corner of this world, is the
ultimate end of all spiritual growth all over,
in every religion, through every great incarnations
and prophets.
What They indicated about future, what They
talked about, what you are to know yourself,
that you have to find yourself, that you have
to become a realised-soul, that you should
have atmasakshatkar, that you should be a
wali.
All these indications....Even the Buddhists
know that Matreya has to come. Ma-treya. “Ma”
is Mother. Three times. Trigunatmika.
Even the Greeks had Athena with 3 powers in Her.
So, all of them have been predicting about
this time. And that time came and that’s
how I call it the blossom time and the fruits
that are you people.
So it is all so much, we can say, in the cosmic
cycle of different seasons - [that] this beautiful
time has come and, like the wheel of time,
has to turn and go further - [that] Sahaja
Yoga started. Of course, in a very small way,
but has now grown so big all over the world.
Here now, there’s another thing that has
happened, which is rather remarkable, that
so far, people used to meditate alone and
maybe one of them might get realisation, but
there was no phenomena of en masse realisation,
nor of en masse meditation in those days.
They all used to disappear into some nook
and corner of a quiet place where they would
sit down and meditate. But this en masse realisation,
en masse meditation, en masse understanding
and learning about your being was not even
imagined by Me: that it would go to such a
limit, to such an extent, with leaps and bounds.
This year specially, it has taken a very new
dimension, I think, everywhere and all that
is negative is being exposed
in most of the countries.
So this is how, when the Sahastrara opened,
the Kundalini started moving towards this
Divine Power, getting connected with It and
was all the time flowing within you, when
the nirvikalpa state came. Now when it is
coming through the Sahastrara, one has to
know that the Sahastrara has to be clean,
so that the flow of Divine Power is going,
penetrating, without any obstacle, without
getting impure, without getting into any kind
of problems.
So, to get tot hat level, to that state, all the sahaja
yogi, I am happy to know, are trying to work
it out, their own individual meditations also,
so that this growth should take place.
Thus, you get enlightenment in a full way.
But then one must ask why, for what? What’s
the purpose? What’s the aim? The aim is:
your aim is lost. You don’t seek for aims
at all anymore. This pendal was built with
such great ability for which we didn't pay
anything. Everybody was working here day and
night, in the rainy season, and I was quite
worried about them. I said, “What's the
matter?” they said, “We are enjoying,
Mother. We are enjoying!” “What enjoying?”
“We’re enjoying the rain.” All right.
“We are enjoying the cold.” All right.
“Enjoying everything, lifting all these
heavy things, everything we are enjoying.”
I was quite surprised at them. Nobody had
any complaints, but everybody was just on
the warpath, building this tent for you.
So what happens? Once your Sahastrara is clean,
this flow of joy doesn't allow you even to
think that you are exerting or you are working.
Normally, if you tell somebody that this is
to be erected [they say] “Aaaaaah!” Some
would faint and some would say, “Ah, this
will take at least one year.” Then they'll
start giving excuses. “This pole is no good.
That is no good. It won't stand that. There’s
nothing, there's nothing…” Ultimately,
you'll find nothing is done. It will lie like
this for years together. “You better get
another person. You better buy another one.”
Everything is postponed all the time and nothing
is done.
But here, you don't feel you are doing anything.
When you don't feel you are doing anything,
how can you say then, “Why?” Because I'm
not doing anything, in any way, so I don't
ask question “Why?” Do I? And in any case,
I'm not doing anything. That is the state
where you are working in the Divine Plan.
You are doing lot of work, but nobody feels
they are doing anything. They all think, we
are absolutely just enjoying ourselves, doing
nothing. This kind of a state is the blessing
of Sahastrara because only in your brain you
think all these things; labour-saving devices.
I mean, you tell anybody, “You go and telephone
to this person.” Immediately, if it is a
modern man, he'll say, “He may not be there.
God knows. What’s the use? Telephone may
not be all right.” “Baba, you see! Why
don't you see if the telephone is all right
or not?” Before that only he will give this
hundred and one explanations that it may not
be all right, it maybe something may be wrong
and just labour-saving, first. That is one
of the tricks of the brain.
Then this intelligence cheats you all the
time. It gives you rationality for everything.
Like a person kills his father and you ask
him, “Why did you kill?” “Why not? He
was so old. He was suffering and I wanted
to have all the property,
so I thought better kill him”
Like Queen Victoria became very
old, so her son was to think that “I'll
never become a king if this lady goes on like
this!”
So, the brain starts giving lots of explanation
and cheating – because rationality. It gives
rationality and rationality is nothing but
ego or your conditioning. Your ego tells you,
“No, this is no good,” so you stick on
to that point, “This is not good.” Then
another can ask you why it is not good. “I
think it is not good, so I think.” Or, like
some say, “I believe,” but why? But in
Sahaja Yoga answer is simple, “Why do you
do it?” - “I enjoy it.” What's the next
answer? “Why are you worried?
I am enjoying it.”
Now the people who also say like that, because
of their conditionings, “Oh, I am enjoying
it.” Somebody will say, “I enjoy my drink.”
Somebody can say, “I enjoy my going to the
church.” Sometimes I say going – something
else, you see, like that. They are enjoying
something, which, according to Sahaja Yoga,
we too can never enjoy. But that enjoyment
is not collective. That is not supported by
anyone. For example, somebody says, “I enjoy
drinking.” Nobody has erected any temple
or any statue of a man who drinks. Have you
seen anywhere in the whole world? So, though
he may say that, “I enjoy,” it has no
sanction from the society. People can say,
“I enjoy stealing,” people can say, “I
enjoy killing,” but it is very arbitrary,
it is very individual and never supported
by the society, even by the modern society
and there's always reaction to it.
But Sahaja Yoga is not like them, when you
say, “I enjoy,” you say it because you
have no ego and you have no conditionings.
It's a different situation because now the
Sahastrara is opened out. So, on one side,
your ego has gone down, another side, your
conditioning is finished. You are no more
conditioned. Like you talk to a Catholic...so
I started talking about Christ. Immediately
he said, “Mother, now please.” I said,
“I am talking about Christ, not about Catholicism.
Talking of Christ, why are you frightened
about?” “Mother, we shouldn't become Catholic
again, you know. That's why we are worried
about.”
Babaa! Christ never started Catholicism. So
much so, they have developed a kind of a de-conditioning
of their minds, that they start seeing that
whatever these people have done so far was
wrong and that "Whatever I have done so far
was absolutely wrong and I'm not going do
it." It's a very common thing. I have seen
the people who have worshipped Christ prefer
to worship Ganesha and those who have worshipped
Ganesha prefer to worship Christ. [They are]
just the same, the name is different, but
just the same, but they like it: because [to
them] Christ means the priest, the confessions,
rosaries and also cemeteries. So they don't
want to have. These conditionings, itself,
start showing their own forms, like devils,
and sahaja yogis want to avoid it, or have
nothing to do with them.
I remember in the beginning, we had about
six, seven hippies from England and they had
come to Rahuri. We were having a program and
there were five, six real hippies. These were
hippies [who] became sahaja yogis, real hippies
came to the program. I was just sitting like
this and suddenly they said, “Ooooh nooooo!”
I said, “What has happened?” I started
saying; as if some snake has entered or what
has happened? They were hippies, but with
this de-conditioning of the conditions, they
just couldn't bear those same hippies - that
they [once] were - coming inside. Because
you start seeing clearly, very clearly, that
all these conditionings had blinded us completely
and misled us into a wilderness.
Of course, about ego, in the West people are
extremely conscious. There was a leader’s
wife. I said, “Why don't you help your husband?”
She said, “Mother, I’m worried about my
ego.” I said, “Why?” “If I start doing
some work, this ego might develop again, so
I'm rather worried.” They are so conscious
of it, that this ego should not come back.
One fellow who came to Me and I was talking
to him, then he just ran away. I said, “What
happened?” So he said, “No, those people
who go close to Mother always develop very
bad ego. So I don't want to be there close
with Her.” So, is a such … (laughing)...
such a mind that sees madness, that sees insanity,
that sees immaturity, it sees vulgarity, it
sees deceit, hypocrisy, everything so clearly:
and in that state, he gets confused and quite
upset, wants to run away from everyone.
Then we have some sahaja yogis who have such
problems, who come to Sahaja Yoga with problems.
Then, these people see them with these problems
they are still continuing. Now the Sahastrara
doesn't want to accept it. “It's terrible.
I was like him. No, no, no more. Me, I don't
want to be like that.” So, they abhor the
person who was just like them; they just can't
bear him, they just can't tolerate. Then I
would say still you have to grow. You have
to grow, your Sahastrara has to be cleansed
out at such a speed, at such a level and stage
that, like soap cleanses everything, it should
cleanse everything else, should not be afraid
of anything, should not have any worry about
the conditionings of others or ego of others:
that is the state now we have to reach.
Today is the Sahastrara Day, is the 23rd Sahastrara
Day and I shouldn't expect much, I don't want
to say anything much about it: but I wish
and I hope that all the thousand petals of
your Sahastraras will be so cleansed that
you will never catch from anybody; you will
never be frightened of anybody. You will be
masters of all kinds of curatives and also
you will be the one who can give solace, peace
to others; you will be the one who’ll be
organising programs outside, you will the
one who will be responsible for Sahaja Yoga.
And when that happens, then we can see that
these thousand petals of the Sahastrara have
opened out.
These thousand petals are not yet awakened.
They signify the different thousand powers
of the Goddess, minimum of minimum. These
thousand ones you can open out yourself by
introspection, by looking at yourself, making
fun of yourself.
“Know Thyself” means know yourself with
all the defects you have and also the potential
you have and all the good points you have.
So as far as you are concerned, when you are
looking at yourself you should just see to
the defects that you have. “Why do I behave
like this? Why do I assert so much? What's
the problem? Why can't I see myself clearly?”
With that transparency of your Sahastrara,
you can see your heart, you can see your mind,
you can see yourself fully, clearly, what's
wrong with you. This transparency can come
only if you have really the pure desire,
shuddha iccha, to be of that level.
Now, there is no competition
between A and B. We don't say that, “You
got the first prize for coming out of the
Sahastrara” (laughing) or we don't say,
“You have the second prize.” There's nothing
like first, second in Sahaja Yoga, because
we are not running the race. There’s no
competition between us. Whatever we are doing
is for our own satisfaction. Now think of
something. There are five people who are running.
Now they have to think, out of these five
people, who goes first. Here it is the other
way round: The five people are meditating;
now everyone individually has to see for himself
if he satisfies himself or not, nobody else
is going to give you a certificate. It is
you who has to give certificate to yourself,
honestly. It's a very different position.
It is you, your Sahastrara and your attention
and you have to see, within yourself, “How
far have I realised my own powers, my own
compassion, my own personality?” You’ll
have to test it yourself. It is you are the
one who decides. When you are the one who
is running, it is you are the one who decides
without running, then what is the question
of competition? The whole thing disappears
into nothing.
As I told you the other day, an analogy that,
if you are looking at the mirror, then you
are the one who is observing, your reflection
is the one that is observed and there is the
action of seeing, so you are in 3 dimensions.
But supposing you become the mirror yourself,
the whole process is reversed: You see yourself.
You don't have to see because you are seeing
it all the time, it's just spontaneous. In
the same manner, when it comes to Sahastrara,
it is your Sahastrara itself gives you the
full idea as to how you are. The diagnosis
comes from your own Sahastrara. Your own Sahastrara
tells you what centres are catching because
all the peethas of these seven centres are
in the Sahastrara. As if the Sahastrara is
now watching yourself and reporting to you,
“See, this is wrong with you. This is wrong
with you, this is wrong with you.” So, Sahastrara
being the best well-wisher that you have,
gives you the right information about yourself,
so the best is that you correct yourself.
So then, achieve that perfect state: that
is what you have to do. But once you have
achieved the perfect state, you have achieved
your aim, you have no aim left. Like the lights
now, till you have to make the lights, you
had to work hard, make the lights, put them
right, do everything that is necessary. But
once it is made and the light comes into it,
then the job of the light is to give the light.
So the first function is over.
Now the second function is to give it back.
You reach your aim, your destination. For
example, I had to come here. Alright? So I
come all the way from My house, come in the
car, walking and come and sit down here. Now
it’s finished that part, over. Now I don'
t have to walk, otherwise I’ll be all the
time running. So, all this mad race of this
brain stops. For what should it be used now?
For enjoying the peace, for enjoying the joy,
for enjoying the collectivity. So, the labour
or the hard work or you can also say the planning
of the future finishes off. Only thing now
you have got it, so better enjoy it.
It’s like you are coming from outside, you
are running, you are very hungry, you want
to reach home. Once you reach home, then the
food is served to you. Now what's your aim?
Nothing, but to enjoy the food for which you
were running. But after that also, if you
start running, then one should say it is absolute
stupidity! But the capacity of enjoyment only
comes when your Sahastrara is absolutely open.
Otherwise the capacity to enjoy is much less
and you become like a person who is running
all the time after something which you never
achieve. There are many like that. All their
lives they’re like mad, you know. They are
working morning till evening, everyday, achieving
nothing! Next day again get up, again running!
All their lives running like this till their
foot is in the grave, they are still running.
But after getting to Sahaja Yoga, you stop
all these activities and leave it to your
Sahaja Yoga to work, to your Sahastrara to
work it out. And it works out. You don't have
to rush. You don't have to be so competent.
You don't have to write down everything. You
don't have to think of planning everything.
Just everything works out and it works out
beautifully. The only thing that one has to
do is to accept whatever is happening for
our good. Even in small, small things. For
today's delay in the puja, is the desire of
some people who wanted to give you some sort
of a … I shouldn't say that, but some secret
show was going to be there and they didn't
want any light. So they were thinking, “What
will happen – the puja will be over by about
five, then by six o'clock they’ll eat their
food, but the sun would be there till nine
o'clock, then how can we show this?” All
right, so have it in the night.
In every small thing you will see. Some people
were coming from India and they had to bring
My two boxes from there and they wouldn't
allow these boxes, they said it is overweight,
overweight. So they didn't know what to do.
They thought that they should send them back
and later on it can go till Guru puja or somewhere.
But they thought that there must be some plan,
must be some drama. The plane was late [by]
19 hours, so they thought there must be some
drama; and then they were put into some sort
of a tourist hotel for that night. Next morning
they met two other Indians from, sahaja yogis,
from Poona, two boys. That settled it! My
luggage, they could put it in their name and
that’s how the luggage came in. But they
never felt bored: 19 hours. “We had nice
time, Mother, together. We were enjoying and
talking,” finished! Nobody feels the time
is passing out. Otherwise, anybody else would
have eaten up all the airport personnel and
would have broken all the telephones. Waiting
for 19hours, “My God, what is this!!”
Would have given it in the newspapers. Everybody
… this is the greatest crime! While these
were enjoying life nicely.
So, we have lost now the sense of aim. We
don't have any aims. We just want to enjoy.
It’s a very, very big thing that has happened
because, as you know, the joy in the Sahastrara
is nira-ananda, nira-ananda. Of course, Nira
is My name also, but it means pure absolute
joy. Nira-ananda. And that nirananda, that
joy has no other hues. It’s just pure, pure
joy. Without thinking, it just pours into
it. After all, every activity is for what,
for getting some sort of a pleasure, sensation
and also, some people believe, for joy. It’s
not.
Only after the opening of Sahastrara and the
cleansing of it, then you will know what is
joy.
You can't explain it, how you can spend hours
together like this. People don't understand.
Like even our mayor was telling Me that, “We
can't sit in the church for more than fifteen
minutes. And how people are sitting here for
so many hours. Fifteen minutes we cannot sit,
but how these people are sitting for such
a long time. What are they doing there? What
is their entertainment? How can they sit for
hours together, without saying anything, without
dropping even a pin, they are just all the
time there. So what have you given them? What
is happening to them?” This is very surprising
and remarkable that these people, who are
not even sahaja yogis, can see clearly that
you people are least bothered, you are absolutely
enjoying life. Whatever you may be doing is
not important, what is important is that,
whether you are working in the office or outside,
you are full of joy, enjoying everything.
This is the most important thing in life,
which you can have only through Sahaja Yoga,
because your Sahastraras are open, because
they are opened out.
There is now one more thing I have to tell
you, that is very important for all of you
to remember: that, while living in this Ocean
of Joy, we have to remember that there are
many who have not yet jumped into it, so we
have to bring them in; and it’s such a pleasure,
such a joy to give realisation to someone,
extremely joyful.
So we need people who would come and say that
“We’ll definitely come for this [work].”
I mean, they should really come forward and,
once they come forward, you'll be amazed how
things will work out. There are many, I know,
who are going all over, everywhere and spreading
Sahaja Yoga. So is very important for all
of you to know that you have got the light
to be given to others. Come forward. Don't
have fear of your ego, conditionings, nothing.
Come forward. You have all the strength, you
have everything within yourself and you will
do everything with such happiness and joy.
Everywhere, in every country people are doing
that, but some of them are doing, some of
them are not doing. All of you are quite capable
of doing it, so please come forward and see
for yourself what you are capable of.
First of all you should have faith in yourself.
If you have no faith in yourself, you cannot
do anything. Have faith. You should have no
fears of any kind. And also to introspect,
to see within yourself what's going on. To
be very frank, I find My brain absolutely
empty. What I talk from this emptiness, I
don't know. You will also find your brain
absolutely empty, and still with that empty
brain, you will be achieving a lot.
It’s very remarkable, as you have seen,
that from the candle you get cool breeze.
How you can get it from the candle, cool breeze?
You do get.
So, is important to recognise yourself as
a Sahaja yogi and to recognise - what have
you done for Sahaja Yoga? Without doing for
Sahaja Yoga, you cannot enjoy life. That was
your aim and that aim you have reached. Now,
if you don't...supposing I have to come and
sit on this thing and I don't sit on this
thing, then what's the use of coming here?
I came here to tell you something about Sahastrara
and if I don't tell you, then what's the use
of My coming here and celebrating Sahastrara
Day? In the same way, when you have reached
that state now, what you have to do is not
to use for your own purpose. You have used
it, quite a lot, for your health, wealth,
everything. Now what are we doing about Sahaja
Yoga? What have we done for Sahaja Yoga? After
some time, you will do a lot and you will
never know you have done anything for Sahaja
Yoga. Very surprising, it happens to so many
of you and should happen to all of you. I
hope all of you will realise that your Sahastraras
are cleaned, completely. You are perfectly
alright. You don't have to worry about it
and you can really go ahead with spreading
of Sahaja Yoga.
May God bless you all.