[Music]
I'd belong to a family of very
enlightened people my father was a
linguist and he was mastered of 14
languages he knew about 26 languages and
he translated even karana sharif into
Hindi language my mother was in those
days was honours in mathematics so both
were very well educated and enlightened
people at the time of my birth my mother
dreamt something which she could not
explain but after that she had a great
desire to go and see a tiger in the open
field my father was a great hunter
because Tigers were the meanest in the
area where we were living it was a hill
station called Xinhua
so there was a king who was very much
interested in my father somehow other a
letter came that there's a tiger very
big tiger that has appeared and they're
frightened of him that he might be a
maneater
so my father took my mother and me to
that place and they were sitting what we
call as a mechon where they bid
something for people to sit on top of a
tree from where they can shoot nicely
and then my mother tells me that a big
huge tiger of a very big size very
beautifully appeared on the field and
she felt tremendous love for the tiger
it was a full moon day and she felt
extremely compassionate towards the
tiger and when my father raised his gun
to shoot she stopped and she wouldn't
allow when the Tiger went away and he
never came to that forest again but that
made my father think because he himself
was a realized soul that must be
somebody what we call a goddess durga
who is fond of the tiger must be bought
on to my mother because the symptoms
were rather funny that lady should like
to see a tiger ever so he told my mother
now are you satisfied because they were
struggling with the gun he said he's
there and Durga sitting in your womb
that you are trying to protect the tiger
she said yes yes so stop it now I won't
allow me like that there were many
incidents in my life because I am off a
Christian family brought distance and
when I was born my mother didn't feel
any labor pains or anything and just I
was born she didn't know how and I had
no blood on my body nothing I was clean
washed that's why they called me I knew
as their mana but my grandmother said
that she should be called as Nishka
lanka that means the one which has no
spots on it but that's the name of math
so they said all right we'll call her
Nirmala meaning the same immaculate now
all these incidents and then my father
being a realized soul he felt tremendous
vibrations from me and he felt that this
life is great and she do something
reaching this life I do not know why but
I don't know if he dreamt or he
understood it but all the time if I
remember when he talked to me he used to
say that you have to find out a way of
giving a masse realization all the time
as I told he was a great scholar of so
many things and very
widely that man so he gave me a good
education in religion
in different religions and also good
education about human beings what are
their problems why did he act like this
why don't they take to God why are the
hypocritical all kinds of things he
talked to me he also knew about
Kundalini but not so much of course when
I was born I knew about Kundalini myself
I knew all about it from my very
childhood it was very aware person
extremely aware I didn't know how to
talk to because see people didn't have
that awareness you can't talk to
everyone like that so I was regarded as
a very jolly person at the same time
very serious also very deep and then I
started my studies as a child
[Music]
I was not very much interested in the
study's bias to do very well but I used
to read lives of great men and things
like that at a very young age I were not
shocked when people were reading justly
expectations I was reading but not
shocked but as such I didn't have
interest in particularly reading some
textbooks because I thought they were
childish and when there's nothing to
read about it then I told my father that
I have to do medicine so he said why I
said because I have to talk to doctors
he said you have to talk to doctor us
yes I said but it so happen in my
childhood when I was about 7 years of
age my father was a congressman he had
joined Congress when I was four years
old he is totally with the style with
the westernized his clothes west East
England and sort of a man we had
governesses in order you threw away
everything maybe real Indian and started
leading a life of Amartya then he made a
study our language is Sanskrit he made
me study in an Indian school not in a
missionary school because missionaries
were very unkind they threw us out of
the school when my father was in the
Congress they were against us completely
then at the age of seven years I
happened to go with my father to heart
ma Gandhi he was about 72 mice living
with us but the first time he took me
down and madman and he liked me very
much he said leave this child with me so
I had not been taken clothes or anything
I stayed on when my father sent me
everything with him and it was very fond
of me but I was a little girl but she
understood that there was something
about me he consulted me on very serious
problems sometimes surprisingly like one
day he wanted to make the prayer book
all right so he asked me how should I
put the series and all that so I told me
how to
series and he put the series in that way
I used to go back for my spoon and again
go back to manager every year like that
and he called me Nepali give me a name
Nepali
everybody used to call me Nepali that
time then I grew up with him very
intimately it was a very very kind
person for children otherwise an
extremely strict man with himself and
with others very strict a big
disciplinarian and he would make
everybody get up at 4 o clock have your
baths everything be ready for your
morning prayers at 5 o clock you see and
used to walk very fast I also learnt
walking fast with him in his company had
to walk fast and with extremely loving
and a very nice person and he would
listen to me because I was a child
you see supposing I forced him to eat
more or something than he would in love
he would accept very kindly person but
with others was very strict and I used
to tell him that why you restrict with
him to burn he said but you are a little
girl you get up in the morning time why
can't I get up I said I am literally
that's why I get up that big so they
can't get up like that I see little
chats and then my father went to jail
and my mother also went to jail five
times my father went to jail twice once
for about two and a half years and he
was the only supporting member of the
family by the way we come from a very
old royal family which is called a
shalivahanas they have a calendar also
in India and then when we I mean when
they took my father to jail we had to
leave our house and to live in hearts
and in all problems that was nothing but
also me they've tested a lot because I
helped many people there and I joined
the 42 movement in a very serious way
and I became the leader here for the
young people I thought unless and until
I take a very positive stand it may not
work out with them
it's not vicious to say how are they
tortured me what they did to me but they
really tortured me I was a young girl of
nineteen years that time it's over now
so it's finished and after that we my
father went to really again and then
when he came back he got elected as the
member of the central Assembly later on
as the Constituent Assembly and then at
the Parliament
my brother was also a member of the
Parliament later on now recently he was
the minister in the cabinet another
brother is a High Court judge in Bombay
they are all being well despite the fact
that our parents and neglected us in a
way because they gave their lives of the
country but you see that never debtor as
from studies and we came up very well
then I when I was in 42 whom went to see
my college desta gated me from the
college they threw me out and I had to
go to another college to study far away
from my house
he went out but I studied for two years
science I did then I did my medical I
didn't do fully because just after that
the 47 riots broke out so College was
closed and I didn't want to know more
because what I wanted to know I came to
know about it so I did not need and I
got married you must have heard my
husband was is now the secretary-general
of the International Maritime
Organization he held a very high
positions he was also secretary to Al
Bahadur Shastri who was our prime
minister who was another very great man
but he did not survive long if you had
survived things would have been
different I think for our country
because he was a Gandhian out-and-out
panthéon and he lived like it ideal
mantheon personality
[Music]
so that's how life went on but inner
being was still seeking the way and
methods of giving amass realization
my father said before you do not develop
this technique of giving a mass
sterilization don't talk of religion let
nobody know that you know anything about
it
because they'll crucify you or he was
rather worried that people won't
understand or you may write another
Bible or Gita no use first of all you
must give them realization if they get
their realization then they will realize
that there's something about about this
human awareness for example he always
used to give an analogy supposing you
are born on the 10th story and
everybody's on the ground you must at
least make them climb two stories so
they know there's something about it
otherwise no use talking about it and he
said this is the mistake between the
Saints and the incarnations was that
they never realized that these people
are still on the ground they have to
still enter into the reading so that is
what you have to be very careful that
first of all you must give realization
to me
so I was seeking the ways and methods
working it out inside myself through my
own style of meditation in the sense
that I would work out all the
permutations and combinations supposing
I met one person then I would see what
problems that person had how you can
overcome it like that I would try to
study that person internally and I went
to many people find out but I found
everybody booklets I saw so many of
these gurus most of them I saw them I
was surprised they were all hypocrites
money making and staying and also I went
to Rajneesh also to see him then he said
that I should come to his table I didn't
know what sort of a man because he was
talking about eat and even things I
thought you might be knowing something
about it went that but my husband said
no I won't allow to go to
so he arranged his own mother no and all
that for me so I went down there and
there I couldn't see all the things that
were going on and that is the day
somehow or other I said I must open the
last chakra so the last chakra was open
and I saw the Kundalini which is the
primordial force within us which is the
Holy Ghost within us rising like a
telescope opening out and then I saw the
whole thing open and a big torrential
rain of grease started flowing through
my head all over as if and I felt I'm
lost now I have no more there it's only
that place is that the that is there I
saw it completely happening to me
and but I was amazed that when I went to
the Janine's you see because before
going out to say goodbye he never
realized what had happened or anything
else so I was surprised I said this man
doesn't know anything about God and then
I discovered that they were all
hypocrites and telling lies so in 1973
this happened on 5th of May 17 1970
fifth of May and just after that I we
had a very big lecture in Jahangir all
this already be gone and thousands of
people had to come I told them very
frankly that these are all thugs and
these are like this appropriate some of
them are demonic some are evil people I
took their names everything I told them
don't go near them there were some
foreigners also and there were so many
others whom I told these things very
clearly and they got frightened they
said you shouldn't say like this they
will come and murder you they will do I
said let them come and murder me but
nobody does anything nobody even went to
the courts and that's how you see they
tried to bring bad name to me they paid
money to the newspapers to publish
things against me because I said you
cannot pay money so they thought that I
was just trying to see harm them by
saying such a thing that you can't earn
money in the name of war if it's a job
you can
but God's work is not a job and the
struggle started from the day I started
giving realization and I started with
one lady know what realization first
then we got about 12 people who got
realization in two years I got only
about 14 people realization then
gradually went 14 people got realization
then many others started getting
realization but I started also curing
people because that was helping a lot
then my house my husband got elected to
this post and we had to come to London
so when I came to London we had one
program in party with everyone they
arranged it so the Indians abroad are
not so much interested in God they were
more interested in money so now the
Indian stayed there they all ran away
and only the foreigners who were there
when about seven hippies so I had to
work on them seven hippies for four
years I was working difficult to see the
earlier was back that inhale the head
was all terrible times but in between
eyes to go to India and in India also
the work was done for three months
always I would be in India so we started
working in the villages especially
surprisingly where my forefathers were
ruling in that area the were started
moving in a very big way and there then
we started taking some people from India
then some people came from Australia to
India like that and the work started
moving in those direction now gradually
the work improved and people found that
this is the way we can transform
ourselves many people were taking drugs
or alcohol or mad people answered people
they felt better
then they got cured and it was
established that sahaja yoga is
something really important now when I
travel all over the world you see first
of my husband used to pay for every
thing whenever I went she had to pay any
expenses he is to do for me
gradually then now these people pay for
my travel but otherwise they don't have
to pay for anything else that's how we
started our work there was a lot of
opposition and the media people would
never understand it because it was no
such a sensation as you can say nothing
to people feel excited but in a way it's
very great thing because if this is the
solution for the whole world one should
try to do it then we had very late
people who came to come to sahaja yoga
like we can say the High Court judge who
is now the president who has given
Nicaragua same judgment he and many
lawyers and many barristers we have one
barrister here from Algeria and doctors
and then they took over and they started
helping me out how to propagate sahaja
yoga but it was a difficult task in the
West of course in India it spread very
fast in the villages but City people in
India also are westernized and they
start analyzing they don't know much
about our past they don't know anything
about our heritage that we have over
Kundalini non that but some people do
know but self-realization
but these gurus could not stick on in
India because nobody would accept them
so it all ran away abroad and that was
something of blessing for me also
because I didn't have to fight them and
it started working out and then people
found that it helps in every way and
this found so many miracles about it and
that's how sahaja yoga what settled
quite a lot but still I would say that
we have not been to certain countries so
far and in the West I would say that so
much work has to be done
[Music]
as soon as you start any working
anyplace first of all they want me to
cure people and to help them with
curative now if I pay attention more to
that then the main work is to create
doctors out of everyone that is
neglected then you become unpopular they
think oh she's not sympathetic and this
and that but now as we have everybody
can cure now everyone I don't cure
anyone directly but they don't like it
they want I should be there and there
you go to be pampered and all those
things are there rather difficult it's
not we are not running an election you
see like we should please other sort of
thing is not there but whatever is
reality
if a person has intelligence pure
intelligence we can see that this is
something very different and for that
one has to understand that you cannot
you cannot force on anyone that you get
your realization in the same way you
cannot force me that I give you
realization because if it does not work
it does not work with such a living
forces and that upsets them very soul I
feel that the way this Industrial
Revolution has come in the West people
have lost their moorings perhaps they
are so confused with all these gurus
coming down here confusing them and all
kinds of new things coming they don't
know where to look but unless and until
you get your evolution completed unless
and until you reach that absolute state
of understanding the chaos will remain
so one has to try to get to that but one
must understand you can't pay for it
there's no effort
[Music]
it's another great thing has happened in
Dell University that the Dell university
is accepted that a person can do only a
doctor can do a PhD or we can say the
doctorate in sahaja yoga and he gets the
highest degree called the doctor of
medicine and a perhaps maybe after
sometime they will allow anyone to do
that this is about the medicine part of
it in agriculture we have done lots of
research myself you have somebody here
an expert on agriculture
he is also done lot of research and we
found out that with vibrations we start
after realization if you vibrate the
water and if you water the plants with
that then sometimes you might get even
ten times more breathe that's what they
did in India and one of the agricultural
university but here also he's found out
that this tremendous difference between
the growth of an ordinary thing another
thing we have found out in agriculture
that if you get vibrations then even an
ordinary cow can give lot of milk but if
you have hybrid cows then you see they
it's not good for the brain because a
person who takes hybrid make also gets
hybrid and his brain becomes little
wobbly so better to have a pure milk
from a cow which is not being put to
this kind of him experimentation
moreover food also if it's hybrid food
is not very good for us because that
spoils our nerves I think but ordinary
seats you cannot choose because they
have weakened and they cannot reproduce
so when we vibrate them they produce
very well
just like better than even sometimes
hybrid things and the food is taste very
well and he doesn't give those
complications so this can help in
agriculture in India and the government
has allotted a lot of land where we are
going to now experiment and we are going
to start the experimentation there to
show that how we can use this
but many farmers who are sahaja Yogi's
have done a lot of job and they have
discovered that even animals and this
what you call farming
everything is help very much my
vibration
[Music]
you
what do you think of the important
points in the education of children she
first if they if they get realization to
get trust them to that point of
realization if they're already born
realized no problem but if they have
their given realization then you see
they start seeing from a different level
they become the spirit so their self
respect to see awaken so children behave
in a very dignified elderly man are you
see they talk in a very elderly manner
and this gives solutions of all kinds
you see and there are tremendous people
but we have to guide them properly by
our own behavior how we behave the
greatest thing is how we behave that's
how the children run we put the children
certain to some tests how they are we
find out if they have any physical
problems we cure them with a mental
problem we cure them if they have any
other problem social problem or anything
we try to help them out so that
basically if a human being is all right
in the childhood then fundamentals are
all right for the child the foundation
is laid down then to build that child up
into a good quality is not difficult so
now we find like a great artist on there
there are three positions and at a very
young age they have started being well
why lean I mean suddenly they have
become dynamic also and very humble
they're very humble and self-respecting
and very well-behaved it's surprising
how atmosphere is and how it works out
and the other day the lady asked me
about the women and I told her that a
woman's power as a mother is very great
she felt hurt about it but I didn't mean
that you should be just a mother what
I'm saying she is a mother means she's
compassionate she's kind she's not
aggressive like man that is a very big
quality that's a very big power in a
woman that's what I was suggesting that
that is what we have brought us not to
compete with men it's madness we have to
understand that life has to be
in job nights be a blessing not to be a
misery we create our own miseries by
these false ideas by our own con
confusions we have in our mind mental
projections we have in our mind or our
own obstinacy whatever it is all these
things can be cured if you take to
sahaja yoga because you've become a
balanced person level-headed wise person
and you become a witness the whole thing
becomes like a show like a drama and you
become fearless you start seeing the
whole thing like a drama and this is
what a human being has to achieve we
talk of peace we talk of no war we talk
of many things like this you see atomic
bomb this that all that is not going to
work out only what is going to work out
is the transformation of human beings if
the human beings are transformed things
will work out absolutely first-class not
only that but that they will enjoy the
Bliss of life we are missing the point
altogether this is a very important
thing that human beings must say one
thing what have you achieved out of all
this just for a minute to stop and think
[Music]
or illnesses are caused by the
imbalances in within us by our extreme
behavior and supposing say now the
cancer we can take the cancer is cancer
is caused by the over activity of the
sympathetic nervous system supposing a
person is a very sad person he cries and
we said all the times feels guilty and
thinks that he's the first person ever
born he's committed so many sins and all
sorts of nonsense he then he goes to the
left side according to us and crosses
over to the collective subconscious area
and there according to us what they call
as protein 58 and protein 52 doctors
call it that way but we call it as the
Dead Souls they existed and they catch
hold of you and they trigger the cancer
but supposing by any chance you can
bring the attention fully away from that
in the center you can get your so it is
the centers within us which are subtle
which are basically seven centers there
are many others but basically seven if
you can put them right you cannot have
any sickness or illness of any kind
[Music]
- he was a tremendous man one has to
learn a lot from him he was not taller
he put it that's one thing and he was
not like modern he says the politicians
who say something to something no it's
very outspoken and always he put himself
on the testing point and he used to
confess if you made mistakes immediately
one very great incident I remember when
I was a small child they were having a
meeting together and we got stood there
only sitting giving them water and
things to all the people all the big
people were there like Yamaha Leo was
there and also Maulana Azad all these
people who are sitting there no
discussing something and then suddenly
not when he said that now it's very late
we'll have lunch air so they said yes
this we'll have lunch here they had to
go to the guest house which was far away
so but what he asked for the mice
through his wife shared one out so he
got up he had a key with him he always
of the storeroom you opened the store
and he asked the people who were in
charge of cooking
to measure everything according to the
people there are properly everything you
see and then he when they measured it
out everything was done then he put the
key back and then he went inside then
ask so these people said we did not know
you have to take so much trouble you see
too much time out fifteen minutes but
still so he said what do you think this
is the blood of my country I cannot
allow it to be wasted see that's the
sign of a person who understands the
value of public money that's just
ingrained in him but those who saw him
also felt that look at this man who is
living like a ascetic absolutely in the
sense that he would not touch the public
money and that is one of the key keys
for all the leaders if they are
absolutely about money then only people
with respect otherwise there's no way
out but you find these days in every
country so much of corruption hypocrisy
we were really shocked