so
once you are left shruti is absolutely
jammed
you lose complete discretion
of the chakra here
which we call it hamsa
and then you do not know what is
distracted what is constructive
you start accepting mostly the
destructive thing
if you are left with this man escape
so what what wrong
that is how violence has come
that is how all kind of cheating
corruption
has come what's wrong because if you do
anything wrong we put it there finished
stored up again you do anything you put
it there and
till you become absolutely immune to all
destructive action you go on
so to get out of it what to do
to get out of this horrible state where
you do not feel
any uh
thing wrong
what is the thing is only is to take to
sahaja yoga
in a right fashion first of all
you must face yourself if you start
facing yourself
you will realize that you have committed
a mistake
so this is the mistake i have committed
doesn't matter
i am not going to feel guilty about it
if i ever have to do this
i will not do it and i am not guilty for
whatever has happened is the past
finished
with this faith in yourself
you can definitely get rid of your
leftish
the problem is even if i tell you
something i'm
worried that you start feeling guilty
about it also
i mean i'm telling you for something for
your correction
then you start to guilty ah mother is
saying so she i did this and
but that you did at this moment
what i'm telling you never to do it
again
and face it whatever he did is finished
and gone and is forgiven completely
otherwise vishnu maya will take over
this is very important because
one side is a leela
it's a play and it's
all the world is beautiful the another
side
is the guilt
so we think that by just feeling guilty
we are solving all our problems
and this side we are enjoying ourselves
and this the guilt part is just like a
storehouse of a garbage
big buddha but we never think this
garbage what it is wrong it is doing to
us
and this is what it is that vishnu maya
has to burn this garbage
then she works in her
own ways in her own maya ways and so
many things happen
like there was a lady and she was very
right-sided
she used to dominate everyone but nobody
dared tell her that because if
you tell her she would come back on you
so nobody wanted to tell her what's
wrong with her they said all right let
it be now
but i told her that see you are very
right sided you are dominating everyone
everybody is frightened of it
so she said no mother i am not
i am telling you you better believe me
or
you are in for trouble and that very day
she was getting down from the staircase
and she fell from top to bottom she came
down
and on her right side she came to
madarashi
my right hand is broken my right leg is
broken
this is broken that is broken
i said then you know what happened i now
know
why it has happened then i cured her
she was all right but what i am trying
to tell you that she wouldn't listen to
me
so the right sided people have a special
capacity to put everything here
so i always say that it is the
byproduct of ego
those people who try to dominate who try
to be angry try to control everyone
they put it down there and
then the whole thing works against them
this is to be understood in a very
serious manner
that feeling guilty is not that you are
harming yourself but you are harming all
others
also this vishnu maya gets very upset
with two other things
one of the things is smoking
if you smoke too much then this vishnu
maya
gets very angry she
she is the one who then causes cancer
she can spoil your throat
all kinds of ear nose throat problems
can come in with the smoking
because she doesn't like that smoke
she once twice
tries but once you start smoking then
after some time
what's wrong they will quote such and
such man
who is 83 he still smokes
see coating like this they have ideas
like that then you have also some cinema
of
heroes such and such man see
he murdered his wife he's not you see
he's going along
so we should also murder we should also
smoke
so the all ideals which have destroyed
themselves become our ideas
and we start exactly doing what they are
doing
without knowing that how they are
destroyed
will be also destroyed so
this understanding
about vishnu maya's powers
should be there with us that if we try
to continue with our mistakes
and putting them here
then first thing we become vulnerable
to all kinds of diseases with that if
you have smoke
smoking you can become also
very much vulnerable to cancer of the
throat
another thing which people do not know
is the mantras
if you go on saying any mantra
i mean in india there are people who
will every day morning get up and say
some mantra for about say
hundred times some say it at least 300
times 500 times
they go on measuring mantra mantra
mantra mantra like that
now she's the mantrika
she's the one who gives the power to the
mantra
now if you are not connected
to this divine power then there's a
short-circuiting
take place and if you go on saying this
mantra
you develop all the troubles of the
throat throat cancer
you can develop also stomach in the
stomach problems because
it is krishna and vishnu are the same
you might develop
also the problem of virata
because you are
reciting a mantra like this you see a
telephone if it is not connected
i go on using it the telephone will go
out of order
in the same way if you are doing wrong
mantras
in the sense that the mantras which are
said before your connection with the
divine
then they can spoil your leftish very
much
this is the style they use in india
supposing
you are a businessman in india
now you're a big businessman you have
made a lot of money now i feel guilty
about it
because you are made by bad means also
by all kinds of black market and all
sorts so they'll make a big temple
of vishnu
not vishuddhi but they'll make a very
big temple of sri vishnu
and and they they will create
a kind of image that we they are great
religious people
or they they'll have hierarchies they
will distribute food to people
or distribute some things to people and
feel satisfied
here you go on committing any amount of
sins any amount of nonsense
and then out of that money
you make a little contribution
to sri vishnu thinking that steve vishnu
will be very happy and will not punish
them but he is kubera what can you give
it to him he is the kubera
he gives you all the money he does
everything so how can you
give anything to kubera who is
himself the lord of wealth
it's a very common thing in india like
uh there was a buddha thing i knew of a
man who was very corrupt very bad person
i mean
reidy was really very very bad man
and he had taken away so much land from
the poor farmers and all that
so he gave one land mahatma gandhi
and this land this buddha man was known
it was i think nobody gave this land
was so bad that you could not put
even cactus there
and he was telling everybody i have
given so much land to buddha and i've
given so much land
so trying to sort of justify himself
for taking all the land from the poor
and lynching them and then to
do this kind of a generosity so this is
another escape people have
that do what you like and ultimately
be generous this kind
of gracious covering
of your mistakes can be very misleading
it doesn't work with vishnu she knows
you out and out
and if you try all these tricks with her
she will show her
own powers i would say all our
left side problems come because of
vishnu my power
she punishes you as well as she exposes
as well as she gives you light as well
as she corrects you
with all these powers of shravaya we
should be very thankful
that today we are celebrating
her special puja
because i think it is one of the curses
of the best especially of americans to
feel guilty
so today you all have to promise in your
heart and the mantra
is now they all she also understand
english perhaps
you can say that mother i am not guilty
at all
that's all if that is said she will be
very happy i'm not guilty at all i'm not
going to feel guilty
once you stop feeling guilty you will
not do wrong things
because how will you manage because you
are not doing
you cannot put it as guilt so it was
just doing anything wrong if you do
wrong it comes on your head
you cannot put it in your leftish so
you won't do anything wrong
you will immediately understand that if
i have to do wrong i have to face it
but if there's a space here kept where
you can put your guilt
for your wrongdoings available
then you don't mind so much supposing
somebody has a small house no place to
store
then somebody brings something says no
no space here
i am already very full it's like that
so the best thing is to have
no guilt at any cost i will have no
guilt if i have done mistake all right
i'll admit i've done the mistake
and i'll have no guilt at all about it
i'll face it
you'll be surprised you'll stop doing
wrong things
definitely you stop because there's no
space left
so this is very important today to do
vishnu maya's thing
and i'm sure now very happy
with the tour of america this time i'm
really happy
because i think it has worked in most of
the places
very well and if it has not worked
one should not feel guilty but face the
problem why it has not worked
and the problem lies with sahaja yogis
and nobody else shouldn't blame anybody
else for it just see
yourself what mistakes you must have
committed could be a small or a big
mistake whatever it is
face it that's no harm in saying i am
i've done mistake
but if you say sorry means it goes
that's straightforward
no i have committed a mistake
to admit that is very gracious
very beautiful and very kind to yourself
for your penalties
in sahaja yoga is one of the biggest
mantras for all the western people
they should all the time saying to all
the trees
all the nature around i am not
guilty your ecological problem will
improve
because then you won't do wrong things
to spoil your ecology
you'll be careful because you spoil it
and you feel guilty oh i should not have
done this oh i should not
but why did you do in the first place is
the point
so now next time you are not going to do
it
so many of our problems will be solved
if you face them
and correct them boldly
it's possible for sahaja yogis because
you are separated from your being
you are away from it you can see your
body
you can see your mind you can see your
ego
you can see all of those things and you
know how to put them right
you are not that you know so you are the
spirit
with the light of the spirit you can
correct
all these things but this guilt is
something where it stops you completely
from correcting or doing anything better
about it
or bringing any constructive thing to
your own mind
this will solve many problems for
america
as well as for all the western world
same with the indians that they should
not think that if they
are generous a little bit uh they can
get rid of their mistakes you see they
have to face it
it's a different style indians are very
clever you know they know how to find
excuses and escapes but
after all it is vishnu maya
she will show you that there is no
escape just face it
there is no need to condemn yourself
don't need to
uh in any way degrade yourself or to
feel
inferior but to be superior as the
spiritual i see oh
like i would say all right well i see
you very well you did this
separate yourself from yourself you can
talk on the mirror
you can go to the river and talk there
or you can
go to an ocean and tell them that see i
have done this mistake
and now i am not going to do it you can
make promises to all these elements
once you make these promises this vishnu
maya
will receive the message and she won't
enter
into any one of these elements to
destruction so you have to go and tell
the ocean
that all right america is not guilty for
whatever they have done
say it like that if you say it's all
right
not other people because i told you your
genetics are changed you are different
people
whatever you say vishnu maya will always
believe in
and everything will work out very well
but this is a special time as i told you
before where we call it
is the krita yuga where between the
kali yuga and satyuga this time is so
important
that whatever mistakes we have committed
we have to pay for it
it's a karma palazzo it won't work out
by just putting it here
so one has to get to realization
change the genetics completely and then
you can go and tell the nature that all
right we are not guilty now we've got
our realization
and it will work i'm sure so many of
catastrophes
of this country can be awarded by you
sahaja yogis
may god bless you