The purpose of these marriages is this, that
we should have international understanding
about human beings that after coming to Sahaja
Yoga we transcend all the barriers, all the
barriers of race, religion, ?? and nationality.
We have to create this homogenous world and
make it peaceful by removing this disease
of national identification or racial identification.
We are all created by God Almighty.
Our differences are only skin deep.
Culturally we are different little bit here
and there but basically in ourselves we are
all spiritual.
And the religion that you have is innate built
in within us which is an part and parcel of
us.
By these marriages we want to achieve a very
happy and a very enjoyable married life.
In the marriage one has to know, nobody should
dominate anyone… that’s a wrong idea.
But we have two wheels of the chariot, one
is big and one is small, then the chariot
will never move forward, it will go round
and round.
Both are equally the same, equal sized, but
they are not similar.
The left cannot be the right and the right
cannot be the left.
So men and women have to be men and women
in Sahaja Yoga.
They cannot be unisex people.
They cannot be.
That’s very important.
The man has to protect the wife, love her,
give her all the security that is needed.
And woman has to nourish the husband and give
him all the love and affection she has.
So here we are on the threshold of entering
into a new life where you have a companion
of your own.
She will be your wife.
Not because only she is in Sahaja Yoga that
you have married her but she’s your own.
So try to prove it to her that you love her
very much and that she is your wife and you
have all that is yours is for her.
This is very important in the very beginning
of it.
Now there’s another thing I have found out
in my experience sometimes that they get married,
I don’t know what happens, they are swayed
into it and they get married.
And after they go back to their own country
they start saying “Mother we know we cannot
manage, we have to work it out.
This, that” Marriages are now worked out.
Spontaneously it happens.
But in India you see we are all the time prepared
for a good married life.
The wife is told, the husband is told all
the time.
So normally when they get married they think
this is what it is for us.
They don’t have love affairs before hand;
they don’t have friends and things.
But even if you had your past, now it’s
finished.
You don’t discuss, don’t tell, don’t
talk about it, do your best.
That’s absolutely wrong because the past
doesn’t exist, what exists is the present.
So enjoy the present, forget it, forgive yourself.
Many people also have this big problem that
they cannot forget their past and go on telling
their wives that I was like this.
There is no need to confess anything.
They think it is honest.
There is no question of honesty or dishonesty
at that time is but to enjoy full joyous mood
of marriage.
That’s in the head.
Otherwise what’s the use of marrying and
then telling stories.
Or some people have very bad habit of telling
him how bad the mother was, the father was
or may be that how miserable he is or how
he has gone through struggle… there’s
no need to talk of this.
At this moment you are married, she is your
wife, and you have to express all your love
and all your attention to her so she feels
secure and happy.
This point please try to note.
Nothing has to be talked about your past.
Then we are Sahaja Yogis.
I have seen some Sahaja Yogis, very great
Sahaja Yogis who are married, very very ordinary
men, very ordinary, ordinary looking superficially.
Or can say some of them could be called as
ugly.
Some girls are like that, some men are like
that.
I mean from these norms that you have about
beauty and all this nonsense.
But when you see a person full of vibrations,
she gives you such tranquility, such joy.
Don’t disturb it by having your pre-married
ideas about your wife you see.
The reality is this is your wife and you are
her husband.
Take the reality into consideration.
Not some imaginary image you have about your
wife.
Your wife is before you, she’s your wife.
What’s the use of having imaginary ideas
you will never enjoy your married life, I
mean if you have imagination, then you should
not even marry: marry your imagination is
a better way.
Why to ruin somebody’s life, why to make
somebody miserable?
They are all intelligent and good Sahaja yoginis.
We have seen to it they are all very good
Sahaja Yoginis.
But once you try to misbehave with your wife
or try to create problems for us, naturally
we don’t want you any more in Sahaja Yoga,
because it is getting too much and you know
as it is not easy to marry you, to get your
visas, to take you down there its quite a
lot of work one has to go into it.
So now don’t think that you have been forced
into any marriage, you have been asked into
any marriage, please.
If you give up this kind of an imaginary ideas
about this marriage, again and again I am
telling to you today now and this time also,
this present moment, all those who feel that
way should immediately tell me, I will be
extremely happy.
There is another third thing that I have seen
about the western people is that they are
literally frightened of marriage, literally
frightened.
First is they may live with a woman for 10
days or 20 days or 10 years, but as soon as
they get married they go for a divorce, very
funny(??).
For this I think the law is responsible, because
the women think they will get money out of
their husbands may be or the husbands think
that they will get money out of their wives.
In Sahaja Yoga if you want to take the divorce
later on, which I don’t like at all.
We have only 1 % divorces, then I would not
allow you to extract money from the other,
never, and nor the girl should extract money
from you.
Last but not the least is important that,
once you are married, now the girls may not
be able to go immediately from their various
places because of visa problems, but don’t
give them money to be sent to their families,
that is not allowed in Sahaja Yoga.
The girl should not send their money to their
parents that’s not allowed and trouble the
husband for that.
Sometimes if you want to send is alright,
but there should not be regular remittance
all the time and this is sometimes comes to
my notice which I do not want to encourage.
As far as that part is concerned you should
not give any money for sending it to the relations
of your wife otherwise it will become a money
oriented marriage and people would marry because
they can extract some money from it.
All these things should be kept in to it,
that we are now married, we are stupid if
we want to have a divorce, stupid. and I don’t
like divorce at all.
Though I allow because sometimes I find horrible
things happening.
But rarely I would allow anybody to have a
divorce, rarely, so this idea should be given
up and one should not be selfish…
But from the very beginning if you try to
be very kind and nice, I am sure things will
work out.
We have to prove to the world that marriage
is a divine institution and by this divine
institution if you have been put together
it’s also a divine plan.
And through this divine plan many things are
going to work out.
So those who are getting married today are
helping Sahaja Yoga very much.
I have already told you there are many saints
who want to be married.
And nowadays that you see this world full
of horrible people.
We need so many saints to be born and so the
saints will be born in case you have good
married time, happy married life and enjoyable
life.
I think all this lecturing is of no use unless
and until you start enjoying your married
life.
There are such sweet things I need not tell
you.
I was surprised that there is no book in English
language which describes the romance after
marriage, I was surprised, no book, can you
imagine? and in India you won’t find any
books which describe the romance before the
marriage.
Nowadays they have started doing some sort
of stupid things but normally no question.
So now it is for you, enjoy your married life
much more than you have enjoyed your childhood,
your youth or any other times in college,
schools, anywhere.
So be prepared.
Make yourself friendly, ??open it, open your
heart.
Don’t try to find faults in your wife.
I mean some things she doesn’t know, some
things you don’t know.
Doesn’t matter.
All the time trying to find faults makes you
faulty.
Don’t find faults.
If you see somebody doing something wrong,
suppose if you find that person is trying
to do something.
All right, you just do it your self or don’t
tell.
Gradually she will learn from you what is
the right way is.
And one should make fun of these moments,
for example I don’t know how to do any banking,
write a cheque.
I am very bad at many things you see, can’t
even open a television, I can’t even the
air conditioner.
So many things I just can’t do.
Doesn’t matter.
My husband also equally the same.
So we enjoy each other.
All part and parcel of Sahaja Yoga.
One unit here, one unit there, one unit there.
But they are in the same ocean of spirituality.
So any Sahaja Yogi who comes to your house
or any one, especially Indian women you will
find, they will look after the guests very
well.
And then there is some sort of a thing called
jealousy comes out… it’s very absurd.
Indian women will not have anybody else as
their husbands but their own.
It is then worked out.
So don’t have these funny ideas that she
is very friendly, she is looking after other
people, this and that.
This kind of a nonsense should not be there.
In Sahaja Yoga we don’t have those things,
we have become very pure, their eyes are pure.
So don’t have any doubts about your wives.
Same with the wives I will tell you.
This will make your life very much more happier
and confident.
If you have any problem you can always write
to me directly, need not even.
tell through your leaders you can directly
write to me if you really have problem.
But I think you are all intelligent people,
you should be able to sort out everything.