Today I just thought that there are
quite a lot of people who have come for the first time.
And I should tell them about
the significance of Puja.
Because, as the western style of life is,
that they're meant to be like this.
To seek something outside, to go outside,
find out new ways and methods to grow outside.
Now this is the knowledge of your roots.
Knowledge, through which you receive your nourishment,
this knowledge is not known to you before
and was not deliberately told
because you are supposed to grow outside.
Now when you have to go inside, then you have to understand
the divine laws and divine methods, how it works out.
The Puja has a significance,
from ancient times the saints described them.
Because in India, the whole climate is such
that you can live under a tree,
live in a forest no problem,
you can eat fruits and very happily you could be in a forest.
There is no need to have bed or anything, it is so warm and nice,
and then always enjoy the bliss of a forest.
And thus many people went into the forest
and started thinking, looking at the whole world from that
solitude,
what is the problem with human being?
Why are we here?
What should we do?
What is the purpose of this human life?
Why God has given us this beautiful human life?
They started thinking about it.
And that is how they went into meditative position,
meditative entry within themselves.
And when they started meditating, they found all about Kundalini,
about chakras and the deities that reside on them.
Now, these deities have resided from eternal times.
We can say in the abode of God they have all resided there
and then they were reflected on this Earth
and they incarnated just to give us
a better and better awareness.
We could have avoided all this.
It could have been very easy
if we had listened to God at the time of Adam and Eve.
At the time of Adam and Eve,
it was told that you should not eat the fruit of knowledge.
Now, that was not the fruit of the true knowledge,
but the fruit of knowledge was the knowledge about the matter,
the knowledge about things.
So, as you know, the story is, satanic forces worked,
they lured both of them and they started
developing themselves on the other side.
That is how they made a mistake.
That is why it is called as original sin.
And that original sin has brought us to this brink now,
and we have to go back.
We have to go back within ourselves to find our roots.
And that is why to improve
on their mistakes and to improve on their ignorance
that is how the first ignorance was set in.
The darkness of ignorance was set in because of that mistake.
And then from darkness we had to come to human stage.
And when we have to come to human stage, we have to pass
through all those different various stages of life where
incarnations had to take place.
So, now, as as you know very well,
that we have incarnations placed within our centres
which are not yet awakened.
That means they are not in our attention.
They are not to be felt in our central nervous system.
Or we cannot feel them on our finger tips, to be very very simple.
So they are there, but they are not acting according to our desire.
We do not know them and they do not listen to us.
They do what is right for them or what they think is proper.
You have no connection with them so far.
So, the first thing is to connect yourself
with those different stages through which you have passed.
So, the first as you know is the Ganesha's stage,
it is innocence. Innocence, the
formless of innocence was made into Shri Ganesha,
because some nucleus has to emit that innocence.
Now, in the whole world
there are eight such creations of the Mother Earth,
and luckily they are in Maharastra.
You will find Maharastrian people on the whole are innocent,
compared to others, they are rather innocent by nature.
And the reason is from the Mother Earth only the innocence is emitted.
So the first thing is that within us to establish innocence
we have to worship Shri Ganesha.
So, when you worship Me as Shri Ganesha,
the Shri Ganesha within you is awakened.
You see the result of that.
So, the people who are suffering,
say, from the trouble of all these perversions,
these modern diseases that have come,
must establish their Shri Ganesha.
If they cannot establish their Shri Ganesha, they cannot be cured.
So their innocence has to be first established.
If he cannot establish their innocence,
we cannot cure them.
First and foremost thing is to establish Shri Ganesha.
And Shri Ganesha is made out of the Mother Earth element.
So, by praying to Shri Ganesha we also establish Him,
in a city, in a place like this place now
is San Francisco, where I came here first we had no Puja, nothing.
That is why the whole thing was just touch and go.
I couldn't go deep into people.
I couldn't go deep into the place and so the,
I didn't know how I would be able to manage,
because there is no education on this.
People are not educated about it.
But in India immediately the first thing is Puja.
They will not come to my lecture,
they will not come to anything, first is Puja.
If there is a Puja, everybody is getting up at 4 o'clock,
having a bath, getting ready to come to Puja.
Because they know the importance of it,
that just your essence is awakened by it.
Essence is awakened and to awaken the essence
you have to be
there, at a place where this is done,
so that your essence is awakened.
Now, the trouble is with ego-oriented societies,
is very difficult to tell them about Puja.
It’s find it difficult, that is why we do not allow
everyone to come to Puja for one reason,
because as soon as they see something happening,
their ego starts up, you see.
And instead of doing anything to them,
the barrier is so much, that I can't just do anything about it.
The barrier is too much in their ego, they have their own ideas,
their own conceptions, their own feeling,
and it's impossible to penetrate deep into them, so it is a waste.
And if you cannot receive the vibrations,
I feel the pain in my own centres.
Because the deities, you see, get so annoyed,
and they don't like it and they think that
why Mother should waste Her energy with these people
who do not understand about Puja.
So, I want to prepare you beforehand, that you keep yourself open.
Don't allow your ego to come up.
It's nothing for Me to gain. It is for you to gain.
Keep your minds open.
The trouble is that at the time of this Sahasrara opening,
this brain, everybody's brain is upside down.
It is impossible, you try to turn it and they jump on you.
It is a big problem for me, it is the biggest problem.
Because, all other incarnations came,
they didn't have to do this difficult work of making you something.
Just it was to awaken within you a awareness,
like Christ had to awaken your Agyna Charka.
Alright, he has crucified himself for the same reason,
He resurrected Himself for the same reason.
It was a very hard life for him
and, for the Mother, it was even worse, no doubt.
But still, one should know that this is a very hazardous thing,
to transform people and then to establish them
and create out of these little seeds a huge big tree of a saint.
Now, in the same way, we have got Moses, we have got Abraham,
all these great saints are within our, in our void.
They are the gurus. And on a Guru Puja,
when you worship me on the Guru Puja day,
that time these are awakened within you, and you become a master,
you become yourself a Guru.
You yourself know so much,
even I don't have to tell you, I don't think
I have talked to people very much in private, or explain to things.
But somehow they become so much full of knowledge,
that is rather surprising how they understand. Like,
I was talking to Yogi Mahajan
and he was telling me what's the problem is with human being and,
you see, he was telling me how we cannot relate to them and all.
Which is interesting, because My father did same to Me.
I said that he is my first guru and all of you my second gurus.
Because I don't understand human beings.
You see for example, this homosexual business.
When Gregoire, with very great reluctance, you see,
told me through somebody else,
I  nearly fainted, actually could not understand,
what's happened to them? Now, what am I to do?
And I couldn't eat my food for one week.
I felt so bad about the whole thing.
Like, My own children where are they?.
If you have a heart of an intense Mother,
you can understand what she feels about it.
And I knew they are in for trouble,
I knew everything was going to be very very hazardous.
But doesn't matter, by God's grace
everything will be all right. I am sure it will work out.
So, first we have to establish Shri Ganesha.
First of all, we have to establish Shri Ganesha within ourselves
and Shri Ganesha in this place called San Francisco.
Alright? That is why we have to first do Shri Ganesha's Puja.
Then, secondly I told him
that if possible we should do little bit of Shri Vishnu's,
because he is the one who gives us the evolutionary power
by which we can evolve ourselves and evolve others.
So we have a little time for Shri Vishnu's Puja.
Also, they do Havanas all that for Shri Vishnu's Puja,
which is very good to clear the atmosphere sort of thing.
But we will do next year all these things, perhaps, maybe,
because now we don't have these arrangements.
But that would be a very good idea, too.
And then thirdly they want to do the the Puja of Shakti, the Mother.
Because, unless and until you have power,
even if all the deities are there, you will be exhausted,
you wouldn't be able to work it out.
So the third is of your own power, of your Kundalini,
of the power that is going to work out this Divine work.
That is how we have three Pujas.
But none of you should get into an ego trip.
Please, keep your ego on one side.
Just now, see for yourself how it works within yourself.
You start feeling good, you start feeling better vibrations
and you start feeling much better and healthier within yourself.
So, just keep your self open. It is you
who has to achieve something, not Me.
I don't have to achieve anything. So you better make use of Me.
Because I am here only for today and then I will go away.
So, make best use of Me
and that is why I said as many as possible try to call
the people over here will be a good idea.
May God Bless you.