[Music]
do you have a guru and at what stage did
you receive self-realization and I don't
have a guru lot I want you to have a loo
you better become your own girls
secondly I've been born like that I
never got any realization or anything I
just got realization I should say human
realization when I understood what was
the problem with human beings I worked
on the old permutations and combinations
of human beings because I wanted to have
an our mass media by which I could give
realization to thousands of people
because any discovery which is made and
it's not brought to that level it is
absolutely detrimental to the growth for
example you see Jesus was crucified why
because he was alone only for his mother
nobody knew what he was at that time he
could not achieve this because you all
were not there at that time and also
other people you know how the Saints
have suffered and how every prophet has
suffered because they could not create a
mass understanding of it so at a certain
point it has to become a master in the
Tree of Life there are only three or
four flowers in the beginning but when
it grows when the Blossom time comes
then so many flowers are there and they
become the fruits so I I just saw that
this is the time I have to do this job
so you would call it my human
realization when I understood human
beings of course even now sometimes I
get shocked the way they behave I mean I
just don't understand but I think now I
understand that for those people who
can't quite understand that answer don't
think about it mother has to be somebody
special but find out for yourself that's
the best way you don't worry about me
you are
to yourself I must be someone alright
even if I'm not doesn't matter if you
are going to get it why not have it need
to love you
okay let's first learn about Kundalini
basic many years ago part of what I
understood was that we please don't
leave me you talked about raising it
spontaneously yeah and what I had
understood was that you must always have
a master to help you raise it that
somewhere it isn't safe I mean
psychologically or emotionally to raise
it yourself that you need the master you
should guide you yes so I wanted to ask
about the phrasing of it but she's
asking me if that she's read that you
have to have a master nor do you have to
have a master no doubt meaning the
person who is an enlightened soul a
person was a realized soul can only do I
wish you knew how to do it he would have
done it himself so you have to have a
master who is called as a sudden the one
who has achieved the truth and who is a
fast
now I'm not a master thank God I am NOT
a master at all I am a mother and mother
is always a master in a way so that's
what it is but as far as I am concerned
I am too stopped to be a master writing
because I cannot be hard
that's what so you have to have a master
but to get a master rather or why has
that been over time in history to say
Abraham in nurses see first we have to
build up the Father root you see out of
fear because without fear
human beings won't listen imagine at the
time of Moses the Ten Commandments that
he brought had to be changed the people
were so for it
he had to make them very very strict at
that time you can see from the books
that he seen so you have got the food
you get the fool ideas - how terrible
the people we're now then we had to talk
of Christ because he had to cross the
argument he had to cross it because that
was the problem that time the ego was
too much she imagined at the time of
Romans how they were already - so he had
to do that joke now today we have
reached at a point fact doubt absolutely
fed up offer me who super-heroes
everything now the only the mother can
help
so it has to be at different various
levels of your awareness one had to work
out now is the time of mother to nourish
his mother to give you that love because
you won't be spoiled by anymore that you
understand the authority with which
Moses stopped authority with which
Socrates stopped authority with which
loud say talked all these great are the
gurus from Adi not to Sai not they
didn't say if you do this way will be
good or that way would be good no this
is what it is you better do it this is
what these
but in modern times those gurus may not
work out that's why a mother had to come
first to give you realization because
these gurus did not realize another
point that their disciples not
understand them at all whatever they are
doing they are doing out of all but or
doesn't have understanding in it or even
the earlier ones may have had the
generation that came afterwards did not
have so they turned the gurus into a
facade and the whole building they owned
as their own creating all kinds of
problems filling the universality and
the collectivity because brahma tattwa
is the power of the collectivity is in
everything in the atom in the molecule
in the human heart everywhere it is
reflected depending on the reflector and
it controls
this understanding they had but the
human understanding perhaps they did not
have that if he today tell them
something they might listen to us but
tomorrow they will forget so it was
necessary that you all should be given
realization otherwise also without
realization what's the use was this of
talking to people about the colors those
who don't have eyes so realization has
to be you so the first and foremost
thing we have to know that this Hodja
yoga has worked out because param
Chaitanya is transmitting compassion it
never did before never had that kind of
an attitude which it is there because I
am a mother and this compassion has
worked it this way that you all have got
your realization you have achieved a
state which we can call as a
self-realized Souls but still because
you got it so easily cheaply I think
still we don't realize what we have got
still we do not practice meditation
introspection and dedication some are
very much there many people tell me
mother people had to do so much to go to
Himalayas do these do that and then they
got their realization how is it these
people who are blessed even with some
great Saints asked with that what right
there to get this realization why did
you give this realization what have they
achieved I said only their desire their
desire was very much there that they
should get their realization and that's
how they got it but now to go
into only desire is not sufficient you
have to depend on yourself on the light
of your spirit you should see what's
wrong I am supposed to be your guru but
I feel sometimes that the idea of a guru
is very different from mine
normally a guru is a very very strict
person and has no patience of anything
so there are two three types of tests
are all the time taken after disciple
firstly how much they obey but as you
all have got realization and you are
your own gurus I don't put that
conditionally
I leave it to your freedom I tell you
our Leslie in all the way possible what
I think good for but I don't compel like
these gurus used to do I mean they used
to beat they used to hang them on the
well they were so very strict with their
disciples and I have had an experience
of this they never used to smile no
question of laughing and would never
show any kind of weakness of kindness
for the disciples see a guru has to be a
very angry person wearing only single
dress either upwards or downwards I
don't know however with a big thick rod
in the hand never spoiling laughing no
question smiling and the Guru's have to
be very long fist developing big big
bears and no ladies allowed in such a
situation where the women are not to be
seen at all I mean I shouldn't see will
see my face it's like that
there is a big discussion in all the
scriptures anat scriptures outside the
critics whether a woman should be
allowed to do the spiritual practices or
not imaginable
not only among Christians will be
surprised even in Indian scriptures
whether is women should be allowed or
not to do spiritual practices now when
your mother is a woman and she is yo
guru what will you do this is another
confusion because it is wrong the whole
thing is falsehood based or no basis at
all you may try anything to say that
women are not meant for spiritual life
try any argument it fails the whole
thing has to be brought up this way that
everything faces reality all these false
ideas have to be given up like if you
have a carpet upside down the whole
design is upside down but if you put the
carpet right everything falls in line
and that's why you needed a mother to
give you realization and a guru as a
mother to teach me that for ascent of
God nobody can be provided sahaja yoga
is not a military thing it's just
playing
simple mother slaw and of course every
mother wants her child to be great to
have all her powers she wants her no
doubt how she does it
how she works it out is her own problem
but how you take it and how you use it
is your own problem
I always bow to you people who have got
realization because I think so many
saints we're never there on this earth
but the saintliness has to be complete
without that you cannot help even your
family leave alone your country and no
question of the whole world so what is
needed now is to raise your awakening to
raise your spirituality to go into a
realm of complete support and surrender
to the movement of the spontaneous
movement of Salva may God bless you
[Music]
some child
to the ADI Shakti
[Music]
you