Today, we are going to worship Shri Krishna.
See how cold it was about three o'clock. Now
the reason is this, that Shri Krishna did
little mischief with Indra. Indra, who is
a God, or you can call semi-God, for looking
after the rain. So, Indra got very angry.
You see all such semi-Gods are very sensitive
people, at the smallest thing they get angry
and irritated and they start using their powers
to express their anger. So he started pouring
rain on all the gopas and Shri Krishna, who
were looking after the cows. And the rain
was so heavy that they thought that the whole
land will be completely submerged. So Indra
was very happy to spoil the game of Shri Krishna,
and he thought he was very successful. So,
Shri Krishna lifted a mountain on His finger,
and all these people who were getting drowned,
went under that mountain. This is Shri Krishna's
style. My style is different. I told Indra
that you can't misbehave with me, you can't.
So far I've not harmed you in any way and
I've not irritated you. Of course it's going
to be Shri Krishna's Puja, but that doesn't
mean that you should try to show off your
powers before me. Sometimes I wonder these
Devas - Semi-Gods, they are realized souls
or not, because why do they get angry like
this for small things. Whatever it is, he
could be reconciled and now it's become warm,
I must say.
With Sahaja Yoga you can do many many things,
but you must know what you can do. For that,
Krishna is a very good example. He started
Sahaj culture. Culture, I'm saying - He didn't
give realization to anyone, but He gave the
idea of Sahaj culture. How? - Before him came
Shri Ram, who was Maryada Purushotama, who
was a man very particular about everything.
I mean, like He threw out His wife because
He was a king and a king cannot have a scandal,
especially from His wife. So He threw Her
out - it was not Kali Yuga, that's why. And
His father ordered him to go, not only His
father so much as His stepmother, to go in
an exile into a forest. So He agreed, after
all He was Maryada Purushotama. So whatever
His father said, He agreed, whatever His mother
said, He agreed, and went into the forest,
stayed there fourteen years. This is the obedience
to the father. There was no need, His father
was not God. He was God, but in those days
it was important to make people, not only
respect the parents but also to obey them,
that was the time. In His time there were
many munis, and many saints and many also
hatha yogis. And these, even before him, used
to make people practice very strict type of
discipline and if they did not practice the
discipline, they had to do a lot of penance.
And, so many people who tried also, never
reached the goal, because of the strictness
and complete discipline about following
the path of spirituality.
Recently I was reading a book called "Peaceful
Warrior". There they have described an American
seeking the truth, and the guru of that fellow
really really takes him to such a horrible
severe task - that my granddaughter said,
I am very angry with such a Guru, she couldn't
bear it. So ultimately he finds that he is
the existence.
So that was the practice followed after Shri
Rama. People would leave their wives, children,
go to Himalayas and sit there and practice
meditation. It was a very rigorously followed,
or I should say, a very moral society - so
very moral. But it was out of fear, the whole
morality came through fear, which is also
repeated in other religions. Now I would say
that Islam today, has taken that form, it
is the fear. They are not doing it out of
freedom. Also Christians, same thing, and
Hindus - I don't know - halfway this side,
and half way that side. Even among Sikhs there's
terrible disciplining. So much so that, as
punishment you have to clean the shoes of
all the people. I don't know if it is to beat
yourself with shoes or another. But quite
a lot of punishment is there.
Then came Shri Krishna and He saw the situation
- that the way people are really now fasting.
If you really go through the rituals of Hindu
religion, out of one week, you will be fasting
for six days at least. One day you might eat
some sort of a food, then you'll have to visit
all kinds of places. Now, recently they had
to go, as you know, to Amarnath, and so many
died there. So now they said "we have got
Nirvana, we died while doing this, so we have
got Nirvana". This kind of a very funny idea
was existing. That we have Nirvana now, we
have achieved whatever we wanted and now we
are dead, so many are dead, so those who were
not dead were repenting why they were not
dead - it would have been much better, they
would have got their Nirvana.
So, even in this Kali Yuga these ideas are
prevalent. Even in India, people have very
severe types, especially in south I have seen,
they do all kinds of nonsense for the atonement
or maybe for something they are asking. All
this nonsense was too much for Shri Krishna.
He couldn't understand that they are going
to destroy their lives with this kind of ritualistic
gruelling, then what will remain out of them
for Sahaja Yoga. So He's the one who started
Sahaj culture. He said "let us enjoy, we must
have enjoyment, Nirmala Anand - pure joy".
How do we have pure joy by? - He had this
rakhi bandhan by which, apart from your wife,
everybody is your sister or mother. I must
say it is quite true about Indians. Not in
the north so much because of Islamic influence,
but in the south it is so. In Maharastra it
is so. And then He started also this Holi,
in which you should play with colors, maybe
to get rid of the color barriers we have,
maybe. In America it is a very good idea to
play with colors and put some black on the
whites and some whites on the black and they
can see for themselves how stupid it is to
fight in the name of color.
He used to play with children who were looking
after cows, just like a very ordinary person.
He never tried to show off His powers. He
never tried to stand out, never would dress
up in a very special way, never. Just like
an ordinary cowherd. And His relationship
with His mother, Yeshoda - she was not His
mother - was also extremely beautiful. There
are so many beautiful poems written about
His childhood. That, He's the one who is in
charge of the whole universe. As a little
boy used to put His finger into His mouth
wondering - how can a Divine Virata do that?
What is His thinking like a child? All His
actions of children. Yesterday's song, as
you heard it, is this. All these little, little
actions are described very well. Especially
by another very great poet, Surdas, who was
blind. His childhood is described in a very
beautiful manner and the description of His
relationship with His mother is very natural
and very sweet. It was not like this, as modern
times, a carpet is spoiled, "Oh, the carpet
you have spoiled it, I'll hit you hard, this
carpet you have spoiled". They have more interest
in their things than in their own children.
But according to our culture, if the child
breaks anything, you have to say this "very
good you have broken, some badha has gone
away". Never to scold a child for doing anything
which you think is destructive - because then
he will definitely become destructive. So
to understand a child, I think you must read
those poems, beautiful poems, which are written
about Shri Krishna. I don't know how their
imagination reached that beautiful height
of pure joy.
So towards our children also, we have to be
extremely sweet and nice and forgiving. But
some children, of course, I meet are difficult,
but they also can be corrected if you really
apply Shri Krishna's methods to him. Now when
He went to college, or we can say in to the
school of a Sandipanimuni, the guru. The guru's
wife was very kind. But the guru was strict.
And his wife used to look after him and when
she gave him something for food when they
would go and bring some woods from the forest.
It is very subtle, you know the whole thing
is. He went there and His friend was carrying
the food. His friend was carrying the food
and Shri Krishna was busy cutting the wood,
imagine? Shri Krishna was cutting the wood
for the mother. I mean, for the mother He
could do anything, He was God. So no work
for the mother was menial or lower. But the
other fellow, the friend of His, he was very
hungry, so he ate all the food and nothing
was left. So when he came down, he got very
much worried. He went and told his guru that
"I ate all the food and I didn't share it
with Shri Krishna". The guru got very angry,
very angry and he said "now, you will be cursed
with permanent poverty". But the mother said
"no, not permanent - till you meet Shri Krishna
again". That's how she tried to give, we call
it Upashad, in that you give another curse,
which can neutralize partly. The same friend,
was Sudama, and he was very very poor.
Now see the Sahaj ways of Shri Krishna, He
always used to remember Sudama and He told
His wife that I really I don't know, he's
cursed, I don't know what must be his condition,
where he must be? Now the friendship - He
was a king, such intimacy of feeling with
a friend. He said "I used to go with him,
I used to collect the woods. I mean, imagine
all these little, little things had such a
big importance for him. So, He was not only
worried about the whole world, as He should
have been, but also about Sudama - When will
I meet him? When will I see him again? Where
must be his house? How he must be living?
All these very delicate feelings He had for
His friend. Just like a Sahaja Yogi.
In the Sahaja style, we worry about the whole
world and also individually we are worried.
We come to know about one person who has fallen
sick, who has a problem, something is serious.
All the Sahaja Yogis think of him and are
worried about him, they may have everything,
but still they are worried, what is happening
to such and such person. How many of us know
each other's names - I mean He knows everybody's
name - practically. And how we care for them,
how we respect them, how we love them and
how we have pure relationships. Today is also
the day of Rakshabandhan, which is a very
great thing that we should have pure relationships.
I've seen in, say Maharashtra, men won't go
and talk to women much and women won't go
and talk to men. And once, somebody remarked
- "Then what are you women doing, talking
to women only?". So, I said what are we to
talk to you? You are talking about your office,
we are talking about our houses and homes.
What is there to talk to you? The western
culture is different, they will force you.
They'll make one man sit here and next to
him should be a woman, somebody else's wife,
then another man and then somebody else's
wife. How can you have intimacy? This kind
of idea, which is A-Sahaj, has slipped into
immorality. There's no need for men and women
to sit like that, what is the need, I just
don't understand. Compulsorily you have to
sit. I've had a bad time, I tell you, with
my husband's job, I never liked it. What is
there to talk to these men, after all, I don't
know anything about banking, I don't know
shares, I don't know stock exchange, what
it is. Or I don't know profits, and this and
that - that part is zero. Then, I don't know
about office, I don't know many other things
men talk about, so what is there to talk to
them - it is so very difficult. And whenever
I said something, I really dropped a brick.
Once in a party, they were offering drinks
to everyone and this, so I said "I will have
a soft drink". So the valet came and gave
me a soft drink. The valet was having a bow,
and a white shirt, that's all, absolutely
A-Sahaj methods. Black bow, white shirt, black
coat, black pant, all just the same - whether
it is an ambassador or a valet. You can't
make it out who is who. So I drank, you know,
and when it was finished I gave it to an ambassador,
a very well known ambassador. To me there
was no difference at all, when they are just
say walking the same way, talking the same
way. So A-Sahaj the whole thing is. They say
they have so many Embassies, for what I don't
know and there what they have, always drinks,
parties - shake hands, shake hands. Your hands
will break, I tell you. Most A-Sahaj method
is to shake hands. Why not say Namaste, it
is better, and you know me. Sometimes I used
to get such heat. Like yesterday you have
shown that the ice melted. The same thing
used to happen to me. Mostly they were very
hot people and I didn't know what to do, I
used to stand on one side just feeling shy.
But this method of hand shaking is absolutely
A-Sahaj. And worse than that is French method,
is to kiss, and like it or not - you are kissed.
Or to hug somebody. The first time I gave
realization to one English gentleman, he just
lifted me up like that. I said " all right
- it's just out of joy he has done it, it's
all right". But there is no openness, there's
no openness of heart.
You go to a party, you have to be dressed
up like this only, if you are not dressed
up like that, then you are useless. If you
go for a death also. Somebody died, a great
friend, a nice man. So I was told I had to
wear a black sari. Black blouse, everything
black. I said, "I have no sari, black without
border, you know". So they said "you don't
go". I said "Very good idea". Because I don't
know these A-Sahaj methods. You are not supposed
to cry or weep there, no, you have to keep
quiet. Then when you go there, the body is
lying there, and after a prayer is said, you
are supposed to drink champagne. I mean, imagine
it, how can you, no feelings, for that body
which is lying there dead. And everybody very
happy, and if somebody looked unhappy, they
would ask "what's wrong, are you all right?".
No consciousness that we have lost a friend
here. This is the A-Sahaj style when it comes
to grief. When it comes to joy it is A-Sahaj,
when it comes to grief it is A-Sahaj. We have
to be Sahaj, in the sense that whatever we
do, we do it spontaneously. Not with deliberations.
We have some very anglicized people in India
also. And the lady of the house died
and I went to see - and in India the body
is taken down on the ground. So they were
discussing what to do, what time to start
the funeral and all that. So one lady, who
is a very well known person in India, she
said "you should not do it before twelve o'clock".
I said "why"? She said, "Because I'll have
to wear white". "That's true". "And I'll have
to go to the bank to get my diamonds to match
with the white sari". I said "What is this?"
Such filth of materialism. It is going too
far, we are going away from our feelings,
from our emotions, which are genuine, which
are there all the time, you don't have to
think about them, they exist all the time.
But you think "Now, should I cry or not? Should
I laugh or not? It's so spontaneous. If you
have joy, you are spontaneous. You express
your joy spontaneously. Of course, not in
an uncultured way, but in a very cultured
way.
Now, what 's the meaning of the Sahaj culture
- this culture, is something that is, you
are groomed, you are brought up, in a very
natural manner, that you develop a culture.
A small, like, a child like, simple innocent
behavior. It is Shri Krishna's introduction
of idea of pure joy - Nirmala Anand, which
came as a great relief to Indian people because
they were following Shri Ramachandra. But
then abandonment started. The problem is,
if you make them strict, they become like
starched clothes I think, that you can't wear
them. Or if you allow them - no, no, you must
enjoy, you must enjoy, all right, you allow
them, do what you like. If you allow them
to do what you like, then they start doing
all kinds of things. In India, we had lots
of horrible things, which I dare not even
tell you - in the name of enjoyment. But Shri
Krishna Himself has been very much misrepresented
by stupid people like Vidyapati. He was a
great poet and he used Krishna and Radha as
Romeo and Juliet. That's the greatest insult
to the purity of their relationship. You must
have seen many pictures like that, in Kangra
Shaili, and this shaili, and that shaili.
It's all nonsense. They could not show the
reality of their relationship, but some sort
of a very vulgar expression. Because I think
these poets and these artists at that time
had some hidden suppressed feelings within
themselves and they used Shri Krishna for
that. All kinds of romanticism is attached.
Sometimes I feel that people have not understood
Shri Krishna.
But there's a nice story about Him. That once,
His wives, He had many wives, that is also
another controversial point. He had many wives,
because these were sixteen thousand powers
of Shri Krishna, who had taken birth and were
captured by one king and kept in the prison.
So He had to release them, they were released.
Now how are they to live with Shri Krishna,
He was a young man - so He married all of
them. That is the case of Mohammed Sahib also.
He married all sixteen of them, they were
his powers. For a young man to keep sixteen
thousand women like a harem, what people would
have thought of Him. So He married all of
them. And another point about His life is,
that once these all these ladies, and He had
also five wives. These five wives were the
causal of the five elements. So He had to
go.
Once, these ladies wanted to go to see one
great saint. And the river, which was there,
was all completely flooded. So, they came
to Shri Krishna and told Him that "How are
we to cross? - because this is over flooded.
He said "That's very easy to cross that river.
This river is called as the Virgin River,
Nirmada, now they are having big fights over
it in India nowadays, a big politics. So you
go and tell her that "Oh River, if Shri Krishna
is a complete celibate personality, perfect
brahmachari, if that is the truth, you go
down". And the river went down - and they
crossed over. Then they went and worshipped
the saint and when they came back to the bank
of the river it was again very much flooded.
So they went to that saint and asked him "Now,
how are we to go back?". He said "How did
you come?". They said "this is what Shri Krishna
asked us to tell the river". "Alright, you
go and tell the river that this saint has
not eaten any food whatsoever, nothing", while
they saw him eating plates after plates, if
this is the truth, then you better recede.
So, they went down and told the river, and
the river went down. They were amazed that
this man ate such a lot of things and this
river has gone down thinking this is the truth.
That means - what has been their character?.
They're abhogis. They're abhogis means, they
do not get, indulge into it, they eat, all
right, but they don't care, they don't have
that feeling of eating, and feeling of enjoying
the food, and nothing of the kind, they are
just eating. And this gentleman with seventeen,
I should say sixteen thousand and five wives,
is called as Brahmachari, because they are
not involved. They are in Sar state. With
such a great immaculate personality like Shri
Krishna, the way they have created this nonsense
of romanticism.
For America, I think they have gone too far
with the freedom they have. As people with
Shri Krishna's blessings became free from
all the rules, regulations and got abandoned.
But America has gone much worse and not only
that, but the films they are producing are
very dangerous films and really damaging the
whole world. They don't know what sin they
are committing, for thousands and thousands
of people in the world have taken to all kinds
of very destructive ugly ideas. Freud, all
right, he's ousted - finished, he's done already
a great harm. But what about these films,
they are now very much impressing our Indian
directors. I think all these directors are
guiding Indians to hell. The whole thing is
so absurd and so dirty. For an Indian mind
it is really inconceivable. Even, I have seen
Americans can't bear it, it has gone that
bad. Then other things have started with this
freedom that we have. Imagine if Shri Krishna
was here, He would never have put any oil
in His head, He would have never combed His
hair, as He must have His [indistinct]. And
He might have worn some mod dresses from America.
Otherwise, you cannot exist.
All the junk now has gone all over the world.
Selling in Moscow, selling in all the developing
countries. Only thing, when it was declared
that they have AIDS - people used to buy even
second hand from the tourists - they threw
away all that. They are carrying AIDS all
over and drugs all over. It's a destructive
force. It's a destructive force, which is
very active in this Kali Yuga and so we have
to have many Sahaja Yogis to fight this destructive
force. And when they are destructive they
are not hypocritical, that's they think is
a very great quality. But at least with hypocracy
you can save some people but when it's just
an open thing everybody starts doing that.
So when you think the time Shri Krishna lived
and the beautiful time they had, of such clean
life and how He killed all these demons, is
something so beautiful, so energy giving.
But how many demons there are nowadays in
this world - is it one? is it two?, is it
ten? One is finished, another comes up like
a mushroom that is finished, third one comes
up like a mushroom. And the most fertile land
is America.
So you all have to pay attention to this land
of Shri Krishna. Especially Shri Krishna should
really start using His Sudarshana Chakra,
would be a good idea. The time has come. That's
why I gave you the conch. To declare the time
has come to clean this America. That is the
thing we have to do. Today when we worship
Shri Krishna, you must awaken within you yourself
that consciousness, that now Shri Krishna
is within all of you. And by your communication,
because He's collective, by your speech, by
your songs, by all that you use to communicate
with others, should carry the message of peace,
of love, of compassion, of
truth
and above all
of Sahaja Yoga.
MAY GOD BLESS YOU !!!