see this quadrant is the one that has to
be changed I can see some light now
he has all top Agartha should guess da
da left sided that's why I was trying to
neutralize it the fear comes from left
side
so the most where the dominated people
humor dominate this is the reason most
where the people who are dominated and
fewer dominating and out of fear
advocated fear
to give all of them which means he just
version saying we should give tomorrow
you all by some bit I mean see let's see
see I I personally think that he changes
the climate which made you like that
first of all that one gram so now sahaja
yogi should have no fear nobody is going
to dominate let's come up no fear of any
kind all right
that is first theory you have achieve
discussed today no fear of anyone in
this world even of God because he loves
one should not work anything because you
are afraid of me I hate that idea no
because I love you very much no fear of
anything that's it this will work out
this will work out
this is going to work apart from that
the fear in the mind creates left side
so no fear of anything nobody can touch
you no law can catch you you cannot get
any blots in your life forget it
no fear of anything God is with you I
sing that song by a quiet air you know
that that song is representing that and
I don't know why doubt that song very
much now I know I worked it out
enjoy yourself
enjoy
gently
cut cut cut cut no fear of any kind no
fear at all all right so good night