[Music]
today we are going to worship Raja
Lakshmi the goddess which rules the
Kings it's a very important thing today
to understand that something has
basically gone wrong in the working of
our political systems and why the people
have lost their sense of justice fair
play and the benevolence of the people
well I have you gone wrong that this is
being lost it is not only in India it's
not only in Japan or in England or any
other place where we think there is
democracy there are people in every
country who are really a very very low
level and who are trying to look after
the welfare of them I should say in our
own country
we had great kicks very good and we had
saints who really ruled the kings but
there were real gurus they were the
people who really live their life of
saints they were real Saints inside
outside and the people
also accepted the Kings who had
spiritual background those who respected
spiritually so when the Raja Lakshmi
Lakshmi that is the one responsible for
looking after the benevolence of the
people when she acts people think that
they have not even think they they do it
automatically that they are there for
benevolence they don't have to tell
themselves it just that they feel that
it is their job this is what they have
to do is to look after the people there
to be brought to better levels of life
this is what they think they don't don't
think like a party politics under the
influence of the goddess of Lakshmi
which rules the political side we can
say the kingdoms and order first thing
is generosity when this thing happens
that you get some position if somebody
becomes leader I don't know what happens
to him it is a myth it is ego that gets
bad word but this ego can be easily
managed if you worship the Raja Lakshmi
she is the giver of balance firstly she
writes on the elephant
it is not easy for a lady to climb on an
elephant I have done it and she stood
straight with a complete balanced
attitude I have blessings
are tremendous the first blessing one
gets the environment of dignity dignity
of a king dignity of a cream with her
blessing first of all you get that
dignity that dignity is full of love
love wonders that personality emits
nothing but love and benevolence for us
nothing
wherever she looks in every glance she
blesses people she doesn't expect
anything she's a queen what can you give
to the Queen this is the highest of all
in every way what can you give it to her
so first thing is the sign is that such
a person has a personality that just
blesses me thinks of their benevolence
cares for each and every person or
movers then the second blessing of the
goddess is that to develop a kind of a
temperament which is very dignified but
also very humorous and understanding
what other people are like then Raja
Lakshmi is the one who stands on Dharma
if there is some other me then she will
not bless that person he's a kind of a
divine discretion he should have as to
whom to be kind and whom
punishing that divine discussion should
be there in a person if a king does not
have that divine discretion then he can
punish the good and he may help the bad
people but this divine discretion
disappears when you are self-centered
that's the main point is a complete
detachment about the power should be
their complete detachment
why should Raja Lakshmi care for
anything but now there are some holy
temporary person these days and that and
then they feel haha we are on top of the
earth if you are a king you are a king
so what I mean if you are an impostor
then you might feel your ego but if you
are really the king then you won't feel
if you are under the influence of the
goddess then that is the only thing you
enjoy the rest of it is that whether you
have diamonds or you have silver or you
have anything makes no difference at all
now how people misuse the scriptures
also one should see that Raja Lakshmi is
sitting on the elephant alright so they
should have all very big cars she's
sitting on the elephant because elephant
is the highest animal it's very kind
very forgiving and has such a tremendous
memory she is not sitting there - sure
but she's sitting there to see around
what is happening so the person will
innately a king has the blessings of the
Raja Lakshmi then what does she do what
does she do to such a man
what she does is first his name is
written on the hearts of the people who
me rules she writes it with her own hand
they adore they admire and they try to
imbibe his qualities within himself the
another blessing of Raja Lakshmi is that
she grants a particular type of a body
which has a coefficients which gives
vibrations they may not be very selfish
people to make a big advertisement about
themselves talking about themselves is
that but the way they are wherever they
are be sure so what a politician's has
to understand that he has not to make
money he does not have to have a big
show about himself he has to remember
that I am here for the fame of a good
man he should worry about the fame he
will be living after his death so what
you have to worry is about absolute
correct character so try to make
yourself such beautiful instruments of
Raja Lakshmi that people then they will
see you they will vote for you and
tomorrow you will rule the world I do
not want you to get out of politics or
be attained
but you have to first get the blessings
of the rajalakshmi and then only you
should understand what's wrong with our
country what we have to do what is the
purpose why do we want to become
politicians put your attention from
yourself to outside so now you have to
know that if you have to really take to
politics you have to have the blessings
of Roger and for that you have to build
up yourself with that dignity that says
I bless you from my heart that in every
country such people will come up
[Music]