India, Bordi, 09/02/1985
On this occasion when you are all leaving
me, is rather hard to listen to these qualities
described in your beautiful song.
My words are so loaded with a feeling of extreme
sadness, plus the exuberance of new ventures,
some ideas that I have to do much more to
establish whatever you are describing me.
So many rakshasa are to be killed as you have
described Me.
All the disparities are to be removed from
this world.
All the ignorance, the darkness, the chimera
has to be removed, as you have described me.
It is very easy to destroy this world and
it was easier to destroy the demons and the
devils, but today the time is so precarious
that all these have entered into the brains,
the Sahastrara of many seekers.
So, it’s a very delicate task to remove
those horrible influences to save the seekers
from the clutches of these devils.
You have been very kind to understand that
it is a very delicate thing and we cannot
do it with harshness, with bluntness, with
straightforward statements.
We have to take them round because there are
hard rocks and make them understand through
compassion, love and complete concern.
Discretion is the only way we can manage and
one has to use all kinds of methods of discretion
to save these people.
Once a maximum number is saved, the rakshasas
can be destroyed.
As it is they are so much exposed now, they
are getting destroyed by themselves, by their
own behavior.
That’s the best about the falsehood, that
it shows itself.
The effects are shown.
In the process we also find that the effects
of these devils are still in our behavior
sometimes lingering.
So all the Sahaja Yogis who have been to other
false gurus should be careful so that they
should not be any more dominated when they
are ascending.
Also there are other effects of our past,
our aggressiveness, our incompatibility, our
anti-collective activities.
All this comes from the grossness of personality.
As soon as your grossness becomes subtler
and subtler you’ll merge, dissolve into
the collective understanding, very easily.
Now, the
things that I have to do sometimes looks like
mountainous and I seek your help in every
way.
I cannot do it alone, so I seek your help
and I ask for your guidance in many ways,
because human beings are not easy to understand.
You have to ask human beings what they are
up to.
Now, the first task is ahead of you is to
save yourself from negativity from within,
from within.
You might find one or two murmuring souls
here and there talking nonsense about the
program we had, the tour we had, the way we
went round, about nonsensical thing, which
has no meaning to the spiritual life.
Or maybe some people who would be grudging
about something else, whose attentions have
been on some other things.
So forget about them, because you should worry
about your ascent.
The negativity can also come from your own
understanding of things.
My only effort was to see that you forget
the rest of the world and start ascending
in collectivity, as well as in your own spiritual
growth.
These are so simultaneous that I cannot differentiate
between the two.
Like the sun when it rises the sunshine comes.
It’s like that.
So, one has to be very careful about this
point, that when you go from here, anybody
who starts talking in the anti way, just put
your hands on your ears and say that, “This
is not…
We don’t want to hear.
Please don’t make us pull down”.
Because they’ll pull you down and some who
are half-baked Sahaja Yogis will fall down.
I hope all those who have come will stick
to what they have achieved, what they have
felt, what they have understood and go further
with it.
The wholesomeness, the wholesomeness of the
experience is to be envisaged, to be felt
when you are gone from here.
Just to think of it, the memory of that, the
Mahakali Shakti of that will give you all
the beautiful experiences, the shiver, which
we call the shiver of the experiences and
you will enjoy the thrills that you had in
India, again back when you are in that country.
And those thrills will fill the atmosphere.
The atmosphere changes tremendously.
When the Sahaja Yogis increase in sizes, the
atmosphere changes and the climate changes.
Not only that, but human beings also start
changing.
So it is necessary for us to have more and
more people coming to India.
So now, first your own negativity is to be
seen.
Then, you must see among Sahaja Yogis, we
are one.
Never criticize another Sahaja Yogi.
Never talk to other Sahaja Yogi harshly.
We are very kind to other people, because
we know that if we talk like this to another
person that person will not accept it and
he will react.
But with Sahaja Yoga many people try, I have
seen, to talk to each other in a very rough
manner and sometimes in the organization also
they try to aggress.
Like some arrangement is there so they’ll
say, “Why not this?”
Try to give up most of the things that you
want to say.
Is very simple, like that.
That, now supposing say to have this color.
Just keep quiet, see what happens.
Because you think you can give a suggestion
you just give a suggestion, because you must
say something.
Not necessary.
Because you have seen in Japan, only one person
speaks.
You see, if there is necessary to say something,
then you should say.
Otherwise, unnecessarily, just to create a
new idea, a new theme, a new stuff, is not
proper.
Now, the main thing about Sahaja Yoga is this,
that it does not belong to any country.
It belongs to the country that is God’s
kingdom.
So it’s a very different thing into which
you have landed.
Once you realize this, once you accept this
situation that you have now entered into the
kingdom of God, your sense of security will
be built up, your style will be built up,
your behavior will improve, your attitude
towards yourself will improve and you will
really feel you have jumped into the sea,
the ocean of joy.
Just assume the power.
Assumption is very difficult in Sahaja Yoga.
Reality people assume with difficulties.
If it is unreal, if somebody can mesmerize,
you believe it.
So just believe that you are in the heaven
now.
This is the kingdom of God and this is where
you have to be and enjoy that.
You will be amazed.
Once it happens, all your seeking will end,
all your frustrations will end and now you
will know that you have reached that situation
where now you have to give.
Now you have become the light and light has
to give.
That’s the job of the light and you will
not be any more bothered about how to keep
light going, because once you start giving
it that way it freely moves.
The collectivity cannot come with mediocre
efforts.
Like many people think that if you invite
people for tea or something like that then
the some more people will come.
Such people never stay or those people who
like very sweet words to be said to them and
all that, they just come for a picnic sort
of a thing, have a very sweet sitting down,
some sort of a group, and then they disappear.
So, we have to have people who are of quality.
To begin with we have to have people of quality,
to end with also we have to have people with
quality.
The people who are peripheral are headaches
for Sahaja Yoga.
They come, trouble us from the sides.
Like you see these skirmishes we have from
the outside, that’s how they come and just
hit some people on the outside and [unclear:
sounds like won’t go out].
So the people who are on the periphery are
of no use to us.
So try to have people of quality as far as
possible, as many as can.
The popularity is not the point in Sahaja
Yoga.
Is the quality, what you achieve and where
you reach.
If the quality of the people is poor, just
give them up.
Forget it, don’t argue with them, don’t
try to persuade them, don’t try to bring
them.
This is one of the understandings we should
have.
We should not go on fighting for the whole
world.
Where is the place in God’s heaven to fit
all these nonsensical people?
There’s no room there.
There’s no room.
So better have it, because they don’t deserve
it.
So don’t try to push such people into it.
We are trying some experiments with some people
who are very difficult and useless.
We are trying to push them here and there.
If they do not work out, we’ll have to throw
them out.
And you must accept it.
There should be no compassion for such people,
but compassion for other Sahaja Yogis who
are suffering from them.
That’s the best way to have compassion is
to understand these are saints and they are
suffering because of the negative people,
so why push them into Sahaja Yoga and trouble
everyone.
That’s not the way it should be.
Now, so this is one of the things one should
understand when you are organizing, that have
people of quality.
If you have ten people of quality will create
ten thousand tomorrow.
But, if you have even one hopeless fellow,
it will kill even the rest of the nine.
So be careful that you don’t allow people
who are not of quality to come to puja.
Outsiders should not come to puja.
Only the people who are of quality should
come, and those who have been now traveling,
we have been noting how they have been behaving,
how their behavior has been, how they have
been progressing.
We know all about every one of them.
So, we’ll see them, how they are progressing
further when I visit your countries and I’ll
see for it.
And then, I’ll be able to tell you that
such and such person has not progressed at
all.
So, this should be the attitude that we all
should individually progress and once we progress
individually it shows in collective enjoyment.
A person who cannot enjoy collectivity is
not a Sahaja Yogi.
Now Leader can be only one; there cannot be
three leaders.
Now for all purposes I have appointed Danny
as the Leader of United Nations, United … ah,
that’s the word … that’s the word … that’s
the word…ah, we should say United States,
but then we have to have United Nations later
on.
Because I find in Danny those qualities which
are required for a good Sahaja Yogi.
He’s very congenial.
He knows how to go round people.
He is very steadfast in his own ascent and
he is a person who doesn’t shout at people,
who doesn’t get angry with people too much,
and I haven’t seen him getting angry with
anyone whatsoever, so far.
I have been with him for so many days.
And, he manages people very well and he knows
how to control them.
But, he is extremely strong as far as Sahaja
Yoga is concerned.
Extremely strong and he understands it.
So, all these qualities can help you people
very much to understand how a leader should
be.
Moreover, he is selfless.
He has no selfish aims for anything whatsoever,
for his name, for his position, for anything
I have seen.
He doesn’t mind anybody becoming a leader,
he doesn’t mind anything whatsoever.
That sort of a thing should be that anybody
becomes a leader is just a joke.
Otherwise, I have seen people, you make them
the trustees they just ride on the horse.
You make them something, leader, they ride
on the horse.
All sorts of things happen.
That should not happen any more, and the leaders
must see to the point that they have to become
really great evolved avadhutas.
Otherwise they cannot impress people.
Avadhutas are the people who are extremely
compassionate, extremely kind and for you
I would say you should follow the example,
Tukarama, because he was such a kind and a
sweet person, but he said things which were
very, very deep and very straightforward.
So the forthright behavior need not be so
sharp as to cut everybody through.
Forthright could be such that it guides the
person in the proper way and the plying of
a person in this ocean of maya becomes easier.
That is what is called the leadership.
Now leadership should not be challenged.
Some people have too much ideas from outside,
because they think they are something, you
see, they know.
They are administrators or they are journalists
or they have worked as some sort of a politicians
or this and that, and they try to control
the leaders, is a wrong thing.
So now do not try to control the leaders.
If there’s something wrong I’ll correct
them.
This is very important, because again and
again I tell you that once you start challenging
the leader I get the pangs of it.
So, please do not do it.
If you do not want to hurt me, do not challenge
the leader as he is.
Now, as you are going away, you are taking
all the sweet memories from here of the Indians.
You have to take their last, I should say,
the glimpse and also give them a promise that
you will write to them, thanking them, keep
contact, have friends, write letters to them,
they will write to you.
Let us have contacts and know what’s happening,
where what is happening and thus we can have
a nice circulation and communication with
each other and we can establish a better understanding
of different countries through this method.
Also, those who have come from other countries,
like say Australians have come, should write
to English or they can write to French or
the French could write to Australians.
Like that there should be a big movement.
The circulation has to be good.
If the circulation is not good the body gets
sick, so the circulation has to be good and
all of you have to do that circulation in
a way that is good, compassionate and in a
Sahaj manner.
My own work does not finish.
I am moving on now, as you know, to another
areas.
Then I’ll be going to Calcutta.
For the first time we’ll be having program
in Calcutta in this way.
And then I am going to Australia and again
back, New Zealand and back to India and then
again back to London and I go on moving.
You see mine is such a circuitous, complicated
roundabout ways.
The sun has to do only one way.
I’m going this way, that way.
All sorts of movements are there, nothing
regular.
Absolutely it is regularly irregular.
It is like that, and, it’s, still it’s
working out.
It works out with some sort of a rhythm in
it, I think.
It pulsates and I feel quite happy with that
rhythmic movement.
So, I have to pray that you look after your
health, look after your spiritual wealth and
look after your Sahaja Yoga family in your
own countries.
So may God bless you all.
Section in Marathi language
I’m thanking them for looking after you
very much.
They have, I mean, gone all the way out in
the villages and in very far-fetched places,
and whatever I ask them for they arrange the
programs in the actual jungles and along the
riversides, and all kinds of things they have
done, just to make you feel happy and away
from the madding crowd.
All this has worked out, only because of their
cooperation, without any reward, without anything.
They have to take leave, giving up their jobs
and coming down.
Everything they have done so well that we
can see that how in a place like Brahmapuri
which is such a far-fetched place, or in a
place like Sangli where we had no rooms or
anything, they arranged all these tents, and
all that overnight for you people to stay
and to enjoy your stay there.
So, if there was some sort of a problem you
must understand that we don’t have tents
easily available in India.
We have to make them.
We haven’t got all these facilities as you
have for camping, because you are so fond
of camping there that if you go to a shop
you can get everything for camping.
Here, you have to make everything.
You just cannot get things for camping because
somehow Indians have no time for camping at
all and they have no part time for partaking
a holiday, and neither they go for a holiday,
and I was the other day surprised.
Somebody told me that he took a taxi and went
to south of India for a trip.
I was really surprised.
How could he do it, because normally this
is seldom done, and is a good idea to go down
like that, meet other Sahaja Yogis and have
a little travel.
But they just don’t move.
They’re like Ganeshas.
Once set in one place they have set till they
are put in the sea.
So, it was very remarkable how so many people
have come from Delhi, all the way, and I thank
them for coming down and making this occasion
so auspicious and so good.
[unclear: may be Especially or Specially],
I have to thank Madras Sahaja Yogis who have
come all the way from Madras, it’s so far
away, to come here and to join us.
Of course, the Maharashtra Sahaja Yogis are
to be thanked again and again for looking
after us so well.
I hope one day we’ll be able to invite them
to your different countries and can have some
seminars like this.
One day, might be.
Such a day might come such a time when we
will be able to do it, when we’ll have our
own ship and people can travel on the ship.
And, I have such ideas.
You see, I’m too enthusiastic.
I have tremendous ideas.
If I tell you, you’ll be all jumping in
the air, so I don’t want to tell you about
that.
But it materializes.
Somehow or other, my ideas materialize, and
we should have such a seminar that we can
celebrate it on a ship, where the ship moves
throughout the world, and we meet every corner
and the shores of the world.
That would be a nice idea.
For a month, if you travel, you can do it,
the whole world, I think.
It’s not so difficult if you have a good,
nice ship, given us to us by IMO.
So, this is hoping for the best.
Now as it is, people are very helpful in this
country.
The government is very helpful.
We have seen the central government was very
helpful.
The Customs were very helpful.
All this has happened because one person gets
realization in the Customs, she talks to another
person, he gets all the Custom people to [unclear].
[unclear: may be One other or Another] person,
a policeman, talks to another policeman, all
the policemen are there.
But you see, the rapport in this country is
much more than it is otherwise because the
climate of this country is such that we are
open, our houses are open, we have a open
home.
We live in an open way.
In a village everybody knows everyone.
Say, in a city, now, in [unclear: sounds like
Nepal] if you tell my father’s name everybody
knows him.
I mean, everybody knows me, everybody knows
my father, and I know them, so it’s like
a big rapport, and that’s an advantage we
have which we can create there with the sunshine
of our love.
So, even those who are not Sahaja Yogis, try
to be kind to them, try to be nice to them.
Don’t show that you are fanatics or anything,
but try to be sweet and nice.
Try.
If they can come, well and good, but do not
insist, do not force them.
That’s the worst thing.
Never force such people to come in because
such people, if they come, they are very great
troublesome people.
They are of no gain to us, so just do not
force anybody to come.
There are your relations, brothers, sisters,
husband, wife, just forget them.
If they want to come, let them come.
Otherwise, just forget them.
Don’t bother your heads about them.
Now, regarding next tour, I don’t know how
we could manage it next year but I’ll let
you know about it in time so that we can arrange
it in a better way than this time.
Maybe we might have again two tours, I don’t
know, or maybe fifteen days’ tours, or something
like that, so that we do two sides of tour
in fifteen days, something like that.
So, we’ll try to evolve new ideas as you
have seen that realization giving is becoming
simpler and simpler, and maybe that just attending
the program, people might get realized.
It may happen like that, one day in India.
I would like to have sensible, proper, constructive
ideas from you for your country.
That’s a very good idea, but do not condemn
somebody else and say that that fellow’s
like this and that.
That I don’t like at all because I know
who is who.
So, just tell me if you have any constructive
ideas about this, about propagating, going
to some new countries.
Like, Gregoire wanted to start something in
Greece, and there are some people who want
to do it in Greece also.
So, we have to see how we can work it out
in Greece and we have to find out people who
will work it out in other places, wherever
you think you can do it.
Like Tunisia, some people said it would be
a good idea to enter into.
But you just work it out and let me know whatever
countries you think we can do this.
Maybe Brazil, maybe another place, one could
go.
But now I think, before I go there, some of
you should go, work it out, establish a centre,
have a proper centre running, and then I should
go.
Is better.
Otherwise it is quite wasted.
That’s how we are going to propagate in
the west.
In the same way in India, also we have to
do the same.
I used to propagate it in such a manner that
we ourselves travel a lot.
Say we are living in a place like Delhi, we
can go along, meet people of different organizations,
talk to them and organize that we’ll come
and talk.
It’s not necessary for me to go there.
You can all talk and give lectures, in different
organizations, in different institutions and
in different municipalities and all that.
In India it is much easier to organize these
lectures.
Indians are very fond of listening to lectures.
So that would be a good idea.
But for westerners also, like in universities
you can handle professors and talk to them.
On your own you can think of so many things
that you can do.
And, I’m sure one day will come that all
these efforts will work out.
As I told you about Buddha’s disciples used
to do.
And, I need not go to all these various places.
You can manage it and seeing you only, people
will get to Sahaja Yoga much faster, because
they’ll think, the one who has given them
this, if they are so great, then that the
person who has given must be greater and I
need not see them, because sometimes they
get disappointed to see me also.
They think that a person who was talking to
us was very brilliant and this and that, andin
my own swabhava of Mahamaya I
try to fumble and sometimes make mistakes
and try to become a simple housewife, and
then people don’t understand that this little
housewife, a government servant’s wife,
you see, that’s another gone case, and then
an Indian Christian and all that thing, then
she’s must be hopeless.
So all these things, you see, make up for
the mind and that’s how the, one can go
into the final decision of the last judgment.
You see, Mahamaya is the only way one can
judge people.
There’s no other way out.
Those who can see through the Maya, only such
people will be redeemed.
Those who cannot see through the Maya cannot
be redeemed.
So Maya is important.
Now the last, but not the least, remember
that your Mother loves you very much.
Thank you very much.