It is so Sahaja today that the day of celebration
has fallen onto the birthday of Shri Ganesh.
Every month they celebrate the fourth day
of the moon as the birth date of Shri Ganesh,
and today is that date.
Luckily, we are here for the Puja of Shri
Ganesha on His birthday.
I’ve said a lot about Shri Ganesha and His
importance in our life.
He’s the giver of wisdom, but this wisdom
comes from our innocence.
Innocence that is innate within us.
As children we are innocent, but as we grow
we start exerting ourselves in a manner that
we start losing our innocence.
We lose it in two ways; once we have lost
our innocence, we cannot believe that others
could be innocent.
Another is, that we think innocence is not
important.
Innocence is the sustenance, is the basis
of spirituality.
If a person doesn’t have innocence, he cannot
rise in spirituality.
That’s why the first job of Sahaja Yoga
is to establish Shri Ganesha within you, to
awaken Him.
As soon as the Kundalini awakens, you must
know that, Shri Ganesha comes into being.
Without His awakening within you, the Kundalini
cannot be raised.
But it could be temporary, or it could be
a permanent thing.
It could be very temporary with people who
are not yet adjusted to the new method, or
to the ways of God’s love.
Those who have not understood, or those who
have not gone through those traditions, is
rather difficult for them to establish Shri
Ganesha within them.
At this point I find, there are people who
fight with their problems, and try to overcome
the outward problems, and establish Shri Ganesha.
But there are other people who are still not
there; they start doubting others’ innocence.
In Sahaja Yoga is a very common failing.
I’ve seen people complaining about others,
saying that their innocence is not established.
Is the first sign that your own innocence
is in danger.
Because you doubt yourself, you are doubting
others.
If you are doubting others, then be sure that
you are not going to gain anything.
Your job is to look after yourself, and not
others.
And if you start doing like this, gradually
in your mooladhara, there will be lots of
these bhoots, that will just jump in.
And they’ll give you more ideas, and more
ideas of doubting others.
By doubting others, you can never correct
them, and never yourself.
So those people who indulge into this kind
of practices, go away from their innocence.
They try to find out what others are doing,
what are their ways of using other people
in Sahaja Yoga, for their own purposes.
Or some sort of a funny spy-like attitude,
they develop.
In Sahaja Yoga, you have to only spy yourself,
and not others.
Those who start spying themselves, criticizing
others, will never rise higher, than what
you are.
In the beginning, I have seen many Sahaja
Yogis, who come, also try to do this, to criticize
others; this is the sign of their immaturity,
sign of their, also, poor awakening of their
Shri Ganesha.
So those who come for the first time should
be very careful that, still we have to achieve
a lot.
And we should not start doubting others, making
remarks about others.
Because in innocence, people can be very,
very simple, very friendly, but inside their
hearts there is no malice, there’s no filth.
But those who come for the first time sometimes
have the filth within them.
And they see the reflection of their own filth,
in other people.
I had gone to a program in Kolhapor – and
you know how your Mother is innocent and pure-and
a gentleman came and he told Me that he has
a nabhi problem.
So I said: ‘All right, you put your hand
on My nabhi’ He put his hand there, and
the women there, who were really funny women,
they said: ‘Why should Mother allow another
man to touch Her knee?’
They could not understand that: ‘How could
anybody touch a lady’s knee?’
But once you are at that level, you don’t
really know that there is bad in it.
And you just say: ‘All right, it’s all
right, you can touch my knee.’
And the fellow got all right, with his trouble,
with his nabhi.
So you see, the thing is, if your eyes are
clean, you can understand, what is clean,
and what is unclean.
But if your eyes are not clean, you start
seeing something that you want to see.
Or sometimes you see something that never
exists.
So I would request all the new Sahaja Yogis
who are here, not to criticize the old Sahaja
Yogis, and this is very anti-God activity.
Never say a word about the old Sahaja Yogis.
Because I have heard complaints, people came
and complained to Me.
And I was amazed.
Those who are just now there, how can they
start criticizing, other Sahaja Yogis?
That means you who are trying to hit the roots
of Sahaja Yoga.
And this is not the way you are going to help.
So I have to request you, please, look after
your own vibrations, look after your own ascent,
look after what you have done for Sahaja Yoga,
and then talk.
Suddenly, if you just enter into Sahaja Yoga,
and start criticizing others, about their
innocence, you are hitting the Ganesha at
the root of it.
So be careful; of course, you’ll be hit,
no doubt.
And such people, who have done like this,
I have seen, have ended up with cancer.
Because Ganesha is the one, when He gets angry,
the first thing you get is cancer.
So be careful, I’m warning you, don’t
try these tricks anymore.
Try to improve your spirituality, so that
you can enjoy, the joy of Shri Ganesh.
This is one side; the second side is, that
to keep Shri Ganesha intact we have to have
certain maryadas, everybody must have certain
maryadas.
Like that, I would say that I would ask a
lady to put her hand even up to My heart point
from the front.
But I would not ask a man to do that, because
there is a maryada if you are a man, you are
not supposed to touch My front side, but you
can touch My backside.
There are maryadas for everything, and if
you do not observe these maryadas, or these
boundaries, then you are apt to get out of
it, despite the fact that you are pure.
And you might create a problem unnecessarily.
I will give a very good example of Shri Mahavira,
who was the incarnation of Bhairava.
Himself Bhairava took on this work, and to
Bhairava: ‘What is cloth?’
‘What is dress?’
I mean He’s a person; to Him the whole universe
is His clothes, the whole directions are His
clothes, He is the digambara . To Him, what
does it matter, He’s so innocent.
He’s absolute innocence Himself.
And the innocence that is destructive, that
will destroy, through Him only, you get your
cancer, when you start misbehaving.
So it’s such a simple man like Him, in the
sense that He never knew what was impurity.
He didn’t know what sin was.
Such a personality came on this earth, to
teach people to be innocent, to be dharmic,
to be good.
Now this one once had to go to some forest
where half of His cloth got caught up in the
bushes.
So He had to cut it off, and He was left with
half of the cloth.
And when He came out on the village outskirts,
He met a person, who was actually Shri Krishna,
Who tried to take His pariksha [ED:means’test’],
just came there, and He said that: ‘Why
should you have any cloth?
There is no need, but I am a human being,
I’ve no clothes on My body.
So You are a God, You are Incarnation, so
why don’t You give your cloth to Me?’
He said: ‘All right, take it.’
He gave away the part that was there.
And that’s how, for a very short time, He
was without clothes – very short time.
But that people have exploited, and are making
Him nude, and making all His private parts
insulting.
It’s all nonsense they are doing.
Now many people ask Me: ‘How is it that
Jains indulge into this nudity and all that?’
This is all absurdity; it’s nothing anywhere
near Mahavira.
Nobody’s a Mahavira to become even nude,
even for a short time.
So why should they do it?
Because everybody tries to find out something
that is a loophole, just to cover up their
own weaknesses.
And all such weaknesses tell upon the progenies.
Now that has gone so far, that they cannot
understand that Shri Mahavira – He was a
digambara He was a person who did not need
any clothes.
Still, just to keep the [sounds like: samayachar,
He did wear His cloth throughout, and later
on also; but for a short time, He gave away
His clothes.
That doesn’t mean that in the public He
became nude, and He took out His clothes and
all that, doesn’t mean that.
He respected the public and all that, not
only but He respected His parents to begin
with, before He took to real sannyasa.
He respected His parents, and He said that:
‘Now the time has come for Me to give up
this worldly life.
I’ve been indulging into worldly affairs,
and I have to take to sannyasa’ doesn’t
mean that He was not a sannyasin He was – but
means that the worldly life of His parents,
and other people, He had to leave.
Because if you have to indulge sometimes into
this life – like in the Hindu tradition,
after certain age, seventy-five they say,
you have to take a sannyasa, in the sense
that your family, your children, are settled
down now, there’s no problems, so you have
to take a sannyasa.
But for that, the wisdom has to be gathered
in young age; otherwise, in old age, still
there is no wisdom, and you are behaving like
a young man of sixteen years – is better
you don’t take sannyasa.
So the whole understanding, about life in
India, has to be very subtle.
And to understand these great and great people,
you have to be little bit greater than what
you are.
If you are just mud, how can you see the whole?
You cannot.
So you have to remove this mud from your eyes.
This is a very common feature in the West
that, either they are suspicious, or they
are ‘indulgent’; there’s nothing in
between.
Either the people who are suspicious of others,
or there are people who are indulging into,
so have it [inaudible].
First thing I have to request, because you
are the first Sahaja Yogis now, who have come
for the first time to India, that this soil
of our country is full of rhythm of Shri Ganesh.
You are sitting on it; you have to vow that:
‘I will establish my Ganesha.’
Don’t worry about others, your attention
on others.
‘I’ll establish my Ganesha, and let this
Mother earth; give me the full strength to
establish my Shri Ganesha.’
This is very important because, unless and
until your Shri Ganesh is established, you
cannot be connected to the whole.
Nor can you have the enjoyment, of your spirit.
You’ll be a half-baked personality, which
you should not be.
So far, you can see that the western Sahaja
Yogis are extremely assiduous.
And they take things very seriously, they
get to it.
Because, they know, if they have to have joy,
they have to work it out.
So you have to be a introvert, as far as you
are concerned.
And as far as others are concerned, you have
to be just seeing the good points of others.
Always see the good points, not the bad points.
Otherwise you’ll create problems for yourself,
and the day will come, you’ll have to get
out of Sahaja Yoga.
It has happened with many, who tried these
things.
And they are out, absolutely out of Sahaja
Yoga.
If you have to be in Sahaja Yoga, you have
to understand that, to be one with the whole,
try to look after yourself.
Another thing I have told you that in every
country I have to have somebody on whom I
have to depend.
Just like Shri Ganesha, I depend on Him for
many things; He looks after many things; In
the same way, in every country, I have to
have somebody there.
I do not like that all the time you are complaining
about a person with whom I am in connection.
You need not correct them; I’ve told you
a hundred times, ‘Don’t correct that person.’
I know, because I am in contact, I know about
that person; you don’t know him.
I know everything about that person.
I can correct that person.
But I was surprised, in London also, some
people came and said something funny about
others, and I was surprised that they think
I don’t know.
I know each and everything.
You leave it to Me.
It is not your job to do such things, and
this is very mediocre approach to Sahaja Yoga,
extremely mediocre.
And if you are going to be mediocre, I cannot
help it.
But the day will come; you might have to get
out of Sahaja Yoga.
This is the first warning I want to give you,
because now we are going to the interior of
Maharashtra.
You will see women and men never sit together
in Maharashtra, they sit separately, they
keep a distance from them; we must learn those
things.
In the West we are very open people, it’s
all right, (inaudible) there are methods and
ways, how we are open, how we keep distances.
Like I’ll be much more free with the son
of [inaudible] Dr. (inaudible) but with him
I’ll be a little distance.
It’s a style that, a lady, her elders, she
must keep her distance.
And a man, must keep a distance from a younger
generation to him.
This is a system by which, this country has
worked out its innocence, and we all should
try to follow this point.
That keep a distance with the ladies who are
younger to you.
And keep a distance from the gentlemen who
are older than you.
I mean, there even a eighty-year-old woman
marries an eighteen-year-old girl.
It’s such a confused state of affairs, where
you cannot talk of these things.
But here when we are trying to sort out our
confusions, our mistakes, we should try to
adhere to certain pattern which has helped
our social life – is much better.
And to understand why the social life is better,
is because of Shri Ganesha’s importance.
Where Shri Ganesha is not there, you’ll
find even Sahaja Yoga doesn’t [inaudible,
‘work out’?].
Say in the north of India there is no Shri
Ganesh much worshipped.
So the Muslims came in, and if Shri Ganesha
was there, they would have fought.
They accepted Islamic culture, and when that
culture came in from the Nawabs and all that,
licentious people, it all trickled down.
Not to that extent, still I would say that
there is a sense of chastity in people in
India, and we all should have that sense of
chastity.
But the most thing is, that in your heart,
in your mind; don’t allow funny ideas to
come in.
First of all watch what’s in your mind.
It will give you ideas like, ‘This man is
no good, that man is not good.’
Just don’t listen to these things, just
listen to yourself that ‘Where am I?
‘What am I doing?’
‘What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?’
‘My vibrations – are they all right?’
‘Am I helping others?’
‘Where is my attention?’
The attention has to be: ‘What am I doing
with what Mother has given to me?
So today is a very great day, we must all
pray to Shri Ganesh that He should give His
blessings, because He’s the source of joy,
He’s the source of joy, He is Christ, He’s
in your heart, resides as spirit, so He’s
the one, the innocence you have to achieve.
And that is the beginning of Shri Ganesha’s
being, which evolves at the head here, you
see on this [inaudible] as Aum it becomes.
So the same Shri Ganesha ultimately becomes
[inaudible, ‘Aum’?] within us.
To have the purest form of enjoyment of your
spirit, you must try to see that you establish
our Shri Ganesha.
And let everyone follow a proper pattern;
you don’t try to correct each other.
That’s a very wrong attitude in Sahaja Yoga
and is very detrimental to the growth of Sahaja
Yoga.
Anybody who tries this is thrown out of Sahaja
Yoga in no time, by some way or some other.
And also I’ve seen people getting cancer,
and they ask Me: ‘Mother how is it that
we’ve been doing Sahaja Yoga and now we
get cancer?’
Because of this nonsense.
Don’t try to go against other Sahaja Yogis;
you must respect them, they are all saints.
And respect the older Sahaja Yogis because
they have been there, you have to learn a
lot.
They have worked very hard to establish Sahaja
Yoga.
So I have to make a very simple announcement
today, that on this day of Shri Ganesh, all
My children who are born like Shri Ganesha,
in the same pattern, should become dynamic
like Him, innocent like Him, great like Him,
working twenty-four hours.
This little Child is working throughout the
day and night to give you this source of joy.
May God bless you all.