Sahaja Yoga has emerged,
but
it is not so easy for a human to understand Sahaja Yoga.
If you get a great thing like Sahaja Yoga so easily,
its greatness,
its assessment,
reverence for the shakti,
devotion for the Shakti,
the hard work required to fully integrate it inside with full mind,
all these things will be lacking.
That is why you notice that many are very casual.
But the other swamijis,
you know how they consider the people,
and how they exploit them.
They take money from you,
make you do hard work, make you stand on your head,
make you do bodily work, some or other hard work
so that your ego gets satisfied a little bit
and you stick to it.
You may also have seen such people,
who give away everything they have, like money, etc.
to these swamijis and then they sweep at Swamiji’s place.
One gets Sahaja Yoga
with such ease,
they are casual towards it.
Like they got their eyes so easily,
they are casual, they do not know the value of these eyes.
But the day we have a problem with the eye, we will say ‘Oh, God’.
That is why one must have difficulties.
If there is no difficulty, the Sahaja Yogi will not care for it at all.
How long difficulties will be there will depend on you,
it will be there till you hold on to them, what can be done about it?
There are some people, you know, once they are realised, they are realised; it will not touch them.
They will never have difficulties;
it is due to the Punyas (good deeds) from their previous lives.
They should also be alert.
They should not be unduly happy, ‘We do not have any difficulty, so we are special, no problem’.
Being casual towards
Sahaja Yoga will prove costly.
If you are casual towards yourself, there is no harm,
because there is someone to look after your eyes,
hands, legs, body-there is someone to look after, ready.
You don’t have to look after it.
But your Sahaja Yoga, you have to look after yourselves.
There is a big difference between the two.
All your body will be managed, whatever other things which,
I call your three dimensions, will all be managed.
But your Sahaja Yoga, only you have to practice.
You have to flow in that, but you are so casual,
so casual,
even if someone is sitting next to you,
you don’t tell him, meet him, talk about this and dedicate to Sahaja Yoga.
There are many people and different parts of the body - (alluding to the Sahaja Yogis)- are separated
Yesterday a girl had a problem and her brother came, he got realisation in a split second.
Lots of your limbs have fallen in this world and you have to gather them,
even that is a big Sahaja Yoga.
In your own house, how can one be outside Sahaja Yoga?
If you are in my house, you have to come to Sahaja Yoga,
get realisation and you should not have any problem.
You should insist, you should not get angry with them.
You have to tell them about this, talk about this, but you should not be casual.
Eat, rise, sit and as you take a breath and with every breath,
you have to propose Sahaja Yoga.
Because, if you consider yourself a special form,
and if you think that there is something special about your temple,
there should be ringing of bells all the time,
otherwise it will be a waste.
Sahaja Yoga also can go waste.
You understand this.
Another thing I want to tell you is that without Sahaja Yoga, you do not have a personality now.
Without that there is no glow.
Without that there is no acceptance.
If you come into the kingdom of God, you have to take citizenship!
I heard from many people, my brother came yesterday, he said’ ‘I went to Gajanand Maharaj’.
I do not know who Gajanand Maharaj is.
Phadke talked about Gajanand Maharaj.
Then, I saw that Agnya chakra, Vishuddhi chakra, and another chakra - three chakras were caught up.
He told his experience that he gets a catch from his photograph itself.
Three chakras were caught up.
I said, ‘I am your sister sitting here and why did you go to Gajanand Maharaj?’
He said ‘All told me, he is a saint’. I said check from Vibrations, whether he is a saint or not.
He went casually. He should have checked.
Is this Sahaja Yoga?
After becoming a King, one who becomes a beggar,
he should be removed.
But you are becoming a beggar knowingly.
Went casually, went there also. What to do, my wife is like this,
what to do, my father is like this what to do, my daughter said let us go and I went.
Then what happened, After coming back, Mataji, my Agnya chakra is caught up,
have a catch in the stomach, Nabhi chakra is caught up, three chakras are caught up.
I am your own sister sitting here, who asked you to go to Gajanand Maharaj?
Then we thought our condition was bad, so let us go to Saibaba.
Then I said, first you come here, get the stomach fixed, then go to Saibaba.
If you go there also what wisdom will you get? Thousands go there, what happens there?
What do you want to ask? Want to ask for material things from Saibaba?
When will man’s material desires be fulfilled?
Everything is done, what do you want materially?
You have become a king, what do you still want?
What I have come to give,
what you have to get,
that is very important.
For the human race,
God has made a human after a lot of contemplation.
There is so much dirt in your brains collected from here and there, throw it away.
You have collected a lot of useless things, junk.
Throw away from this temple and make that temple prestigious.
Have to light a lamp in each and every heart.
Purify your house, purify your
family, purify your society.
You care a lot for your relatives!
You have a lot of relatives.
‘I have come for them, my mother-in-law has come, I have to give her, I have to do something for her.
What will your mother-in-law give you,
When you go, she will give you thrashing with footwear.
These are your relatives, Know that.
You do not have any relatives, other than these.
Only a Sahaja Yogi is the relative of a Sahaja Yogi because they speak a distinct language.
Their ways are different, their stride is different.
You have to give your life.
And love.
You have to share your love.
Love will flow on the edge of the mind, Correct your mind, make your mind light.
If you keep so much in your mind,
how will Sahaja Yoga get in there? It is working on the mind, watch.
God is sitting to pour on you.
But where is your attention? It keeps wavering every two minutes.
You have to put your attention at His feet, He does not want your money, etc.
Keep it with you. What is the importance of all the collections made from deaths?
Make your attention important.
God will descend on that mind.
He has made you younger by ten to twenty years.
Your body has become alright.
Thoughts of your mind have been purified.
You have got collective consciousness.
Now what?
Still, you are running after this and that.
Do you attach more importance to that?
In your previous lives, you have earned a lot of dung.
You have left it here and gone. Again gather it!
You will again leave it here and go.
It is very dangerous to be casual for a Sahaja Yogi.
This is called negligence.
A big war has arisen.
You know that
other ways of destruction have been kept ready.
Sahaja Yoga is standing like a lotus in this mud;
delicate,
aromatic,
fragrant,
beautiful
and you are petals of that.
All the mud which is there will fall off once you know that you are the lotus,
you are not the mud.
But by chance if a chakra catches, it is mud, remove it.
You have been made a lotus.
You are the lotus and if the mud falls on the lotus, the lotus should throw it away
and also it is also not going to stick.
Everyone has to be aware of Sahaja Yoga.
If you have to cross with the ferry of Sahaja Yoga, don’t get bogged down
by small problems of family
and small problems in the house.
How long are you going to hold onto this mud with your hand?
There is no one to support you.
The boy is to be married, the girl is to be married,
it may happen, may not happen.
You will spend money on that.
You will earn a name in that.
And for Sahaja Yoga?
For Sahaja Yoga, you have no time.
The most important thing is
that Indians don’t have much money.
If you look at it,
their financial condition is not that good.
But we should know that vibrations are there only in India, which controls everything.
If it were any other country it would have collapsed by now.
You are living only with the help of those Vibrations.
What a big country!
You are born in such a great country.
You know everything.
I don’t know how to tell the English about Devi mahatmyam, they have not read it.
They don’t know what Devi is and what Maa is.
They are such dirty people they don’t know what Maa is;
how can I tell them what Maa is, I feel like crying.
And you have become so casual and you sit in meditation as if for a shave.
How will it happen?!
My brothers asked me ‘why are you struggling day in and day out?
If your health gets affected, what will we tell your husband?
You sleep at night at 4 or 5 and the whole day you are working.
Why are you doing it? What are you going to get,
we don’t understand’. Now they will not understand nor will I!
When we both have an understanding then only something will happen.
I can fight it out alone,
but how will you benefit from that?
Being casual, walking casually are signs of showing apathy towards yourself.
It’s disrespectful to yourself.
The king who got the entire wealth is being so casual.
Rule,
Relax!
Are you going to finish Sahaja Yoga on small issues?
You clean your inner being, you clean your heart. Leave the over smartness.
Cleanse your heart and check
‘Are we sitting in innocence?’
You are not doing a favour to me.
It is for you;
you are getting what you have been asking,
what you have been searching for ages, you are getting.
When you have reached the pinnacle, why are you being mad?
You may not have seen those who turn their face away when they reach the pinnacle, but I have seen.
First, you have to make them stick. Have to keep on saying, ‘stick-on, stick on!’
Sometimes I think of you like this;
‘what can we do? Things are so bad in our country.
We are poor people, we have our problems,
how can we uplift the country, Mataji? You have put us on a higher pedestal’.
It is good that you don’t have money.
I have given realisation to so many rich people here. Where are they?
See only 2 or 4 here. They are even very miserly, we don’t have a rich man among us.
I have given realisation to millionaires.
What are they doing? It is good you don’t have money, it is a hassle.
Very little is sticking to you.
Less money is very good.
I have seen rich people,
people holding positions, Ministers. They don’t have the happiness which you have.
They get realisation and sit back in style, and sit with a lot of money.
Ministers and Secretaries have got their realisation.
What have they done?
God save us from their arrogance.
For God who is Secretary and who is king?
Marathi talk for about 1 minut.
They are better than you because they do not have the dirt of money.
They do not have any position,
to make them stupid.
They just want Mataji.
Yesterday a few children came. Their mother said, ‘let us go’. They were saying ‘let us stay back’.
They were not getting any chocolates, nothing. ‘We don’t want any cinema, we only want Mataji.
Let’s go to Mataji’.
They know more than you.
You also become like them.
Leave everything of the past and become like them. Now you become children.
How beautiful you are.
You are also like this, son!
You were also like this. Now you have all become deformed, disgusting.
Be worried about it.
See the beauty of others.
I will go.
When the mother is away it becomes the responsibility of children to look after the house.
When I come back I should see that My children have spread Sahaja Yoga.
Otherwise, I will see that someone has a catch of Agnya chakra,
someone has a problem with the Nabhi chakra, someone has Vishuddhi problem.
Someone went there... Someone has fallen sick, someone is unwell,
someone’s wife is in hospital and someone is in a Lunatic Asylum.
What has happened?
Don’t think that we are small people.
You are a very great person.
So-called great people are useless, they don’t get their realisation.
You realise your greatness and talk.
You talk openly.
If one speaks one letter of Sahaja Yoga,
Goddess Saraswati will come and sit there, I am telling you.
You speak and see. You will experience it.
Start talking about Sahaja Yoga, Saraswati will be in your voice,
you start writing, Saraswati will be in your writing.
Start any work Hanumana will stand there with folded hands,
Mother tell me, ‘with whom shall I stand?’
Hanuman Ji is doing all your work.
Whatever work you take up in the name of Mataji whatever work you take in this world,
whatever it may be, he will do it.
For Sahaja Yoga work all the five Chiranjeevis- long lived-are standing by.
All of them are putting powers behind you and standing in the background.
And Nat Ji who has come, he is in a bad shape, he is looking here and there.
How will the play be composed?
We don’t want a half-hearted approach.
‘I don’t get time to meditate’. What do you mean I don’t get the time?
For what do you have time?
Who has given you time? If you don’t get time for yourselves, God saves you. How do you not get the time?
Get up at 4 in the morning.
You have woken up your Mother. How many hours does She sleep?
Tell your mind,
I have to meditate from 4 to 5. Throw away the sleep.
Stop staying awake in the nights, stop talking to useless people.
Leave worthless associations, leave aside relatives, they are all useless people.
They are all bhoots.
Have we come to waste our time for them?
I don’t spend even one moment, you will be surprised, on anything other than Sahaja Yoga.
Thousands of people come to my husband’s office,
whenever there is a reception; they all ask for their realisation.
Shake hands and they ask for realisation! Whichever country I go to, I give realisation.
They keep talking to me, I give realisation while talking.
I see that they have got realisation in a split second.
He keeps on talking about so many things.
Wherever I get an opportunity, I keep giving realisation.
At Victoria station, there was a ticket collector. He was a Muslim.
When I was buying the ticket, there was a long queue and I was giving realisation.
Maybe he was from Pakistan-from wherever he maybe.
I think he was from Pakistan.
While standing I was giving realisation and even to others who were standing there, I was giving realisation.
While he was issuing a ticket to me, he looked at me
and he got his realisation. So he gave a ticket to all
and came inside and sat inside my compartment.
I was sitting alone in that compartment.
He asked Me, ‘Who are You?
Why is there so much attraction in you?
I asked him, ‘who are you?’
He said his name was Hussain. I said, ‘Sit down, Hussain mian’.
I said, ‘Put your hand like this’.
He said, ‘What is this cool breeze coming?
Who are you?
I said, ‘See and recognise.’
I went to Rome. It is an incident that happened long back.
Many artists were sitting there. They were painting something.
Gave realisation to one. He got up, told something to someone and fell at my feet,
sat, caught hold of both My feet and started crying, saying loudly, ‘Mother, when did you come?’
I went there as the wife of an officer; three people were standing on this side and four people on that side.
Those people were embarrassed- what is this man doing?
He said, ‘No Mother, I found You. I saw You in my dream last night.
You said you will come wearing a white sari. And you have come wearing that’.
Even for one moment, I can’t think of anything other than Sahaja Yoga.
I have forgotten all my past, there have been great lives, they have all become great.
I have forgotten everything, all the details. I only remember Sahaja Yoga.
I don’t remember anything.
In the same way,
every moment you have to think of Sahaja Yoga,
wherever you are sitting there itself.
Throw away your watches first.
Throw away slavery to watches.
Become a slave of Sahaja Yoga,
Sahaja Yoga is your watch.
It was 12:30, no harm, you were sitting there, it is 3 you were still sitting there.
You were sitting in Sahaja Yoga.
Is Sahaja Yoga slave of the watch or time?
We are not slaves of any regulation or law.
We are only standing in Sahaja Yoga.
Whatever time it may take, we will sit there.
Wherever we are sitting, we will sit there. Are we slaves to the stomach that we have to eat on time?
We are not slaves to anything.
Everything keeps happening, it is going to happen.
First of all, you leave your slavery of everything, whatever old slavery is there leave it.
First of all, throw away watches.
No system has been made for anything.
No system can be made in Sahaja Yoga.
Its own systems are being made, let them be made.
If you make the system, that will be hailed.
Don’t enforce discipline.
Let its discipline be working inside.
Yes, those who have not got their realisation, discipline is required; you enforce it.
But those who are realised, they have to enforce discipline inside them.
The discipline will happen inside by itself.
Sahaja Yogi has an inner discipline.
But if there is indiscipline here, it can’t be forgiven.
But one who is not a Sahaja Yogi, forgive him because he does not know what discipline is.
He knows worldly discipline enforced through ‘the cane’.
Let the Sahaja Yogi get the discipline from within, let him be awakened from within.
Look at its discipline with which you are moving.
You are moving your limbs with its discipline, with its waves.
Who has enforced discipline on the ocean’s waves?
Sitting here you can tell the time of high tide and low tide in London.
Who has enforced its discipline?
You are trying to enforce someone else’s!?
Learn to get into its discipline.
Learn to grow with its signals and its mechanism.
Its machine is working.
Don’t make any of your own.
Just say, ‘let us get into Sahaja Yoga, Let us go, let us invest time in Sahaja Yoga’.
If you wear a watch, it is for Sahaja Yoga.
If you put an alarm, it should be for Sahaja Yoga.
(marathi)
See this,
this age and this is Sahaja Yoga.
(marathi)
Not even a leaf in this world can move without its discipline.
Become one with it; get into its harmony
Get fully harmonised with it;
when it rises you rise when it falls you fall.
If we make something of our own, we will not be in touch with it.
You mold yourself with that.
It can happen only with Sahaja Yoga.
It can not happen with anything else, it can’t happen with any earthly thing of the world.
There is only one way, I have told you thousands of times, I am telling you again and again;
your fortress is ‘Nirvicharita (thoughtlessness).
Find out in Nirvicharita. You will know everything.
Whatever you have to do, go into Nirvicharita.
Do all worldly things in Nirvicharita,
you will see that it becomes dynamic.
Who has seen the blooming of flowers, who has seen fruits growing,
who has seen the execution of all the worldly work? It is happening;
you are moving in the same dynamism, in the same living thing.
It is coming from Nirvicharita, is n’t it?
You sit in that place, from where the whole world blooms.
Make a habit of Nirvicharita, try to be always in thoughtlessness.
All the work of this world happens through that and yours also will happen.
All useless things will happen,
but you have to operate the inner system yourself.
There is no age problem;
no one is old.
You are just born, maybe two or four years.
You are all small babies.
There is no issue of age.
You have to be in Nirvicharita.
This is your place,
this is your wealth,
this is your strength, this is your power,
this is your form,
this is your beauty,
this is your life,
Nirvichar.
As soon as you become thoughtless, the machine outside
starts to fully spin in your hands.
Be in thoughtlessness.
There, there is no time,
no direction,
nor anyone can touch you.
You will get to see the life process, how life blooms.
You will see its beauty, its ability.
Its opulence, its truth;
gaze from the place where the stream of life flows.
But becoming ill-advised,
becoming a fool,
how will it show to you?!
Or heart becoming empty,
loveless,
selfish,
self-centered,
thinking about oneself,
thinking big of oneself,
how can it show you the path?
Being ugly,
torturing.
How much beauty should be there in the movement and speed of Sahaja Yoga?
When you are doing it, there should be reverence.
When you are raising the Kundalini, there should be spirituality in your hands;
you are worshipping someone’s Kundalini, someone’s mother.
How much respect you should have?
How much thought you should give.
In everything, in your behaviour,
in your language,
in your speech,
in your laughter, in your caress,
in your crying, in everything you do, your heart should be seen,
vastness should be seen,
the sky should be seen.
A glimpse of the purity of water should be seen inside you.
The glow of the sun should be seen on your face,
the coolness of the moon should flow from you.
Like the air, you should be outgoing.
Your life is pulsating in the lives of all,
realise this and don’t play with your life.
Be very reverent and devoted and accept it with humility,
the new life which is being poured into us by Paramatma.
Accept its love
and compassion.
Just there is no need for taking a bath, no need for washing hands,
nothing is required. Only the cleanliness of the heart is required. Clean your heart.
Pray, ‘God clean my heart’. Give up your deceit and guile.
Clean your heart. You are to get into the lotus of the heart.
Clean your heart.
Is my heart clean?
Who are you cheating, who are you telling lies to?
You are all one.
I can never say to one person only.
I am speaking to each one of you that you are all in one body;
and that too in my body. You are my projection.
I am telling myself.
o whom else shall I say? Who is the other?
When you are sick, I feel pain within just like I myself have got sick.
And when you are happy then I feel tremendous joy just like I have myself become happy.
When you are unhappy then I too don’t enjoy any joy.
I keep awake night and day for you.
Whatever or whichever way you can do,
one must give time,
give full time.
Now we are going to make an ashram, so the ones who have money can give money.
You will have to give. You spend money here and there.
Of what use has it been your spending money here and there.
I don’t need your money.
I need nothing.
I don’t need to spend anywhere. This ashram is being made for you,
your brothers and sisters, who are going to live there.
Now these realized children are being born,
they need a school and someone who can look after them.
Give money for that.
How will the money come?
Any money that comes from you is very important.
Such people come here who do not want to spend even one rupee.
There are not such poor people here
- if that is the case then it is alright.
But those who cannot give even one rupee can such people be Sahaja Yogis?
I get really amazed that they trouble for giving one rupee or five rupees!
When you have money, you donate, you have to give in thousands,
in tens of thousands.
Who has given you this money?
I don’t want it.
What need do I have?
Please give it to yourself.
Give for your well being.
You will live in those ashrams with your kith and kin, I know.
You do not have to live on freebies, live like a king.
I don’t eat for free, you should also not eat for free.
Whatever you can contribute, contribute.
If you have time, spare your time, if you can put in some hard work, do it.
If you can awaken Kundalini, do it if you can give realisation, give it. If you can remove bhoots, remove bhoots.
Contribute to Sahaja Yoga.
If you don’t do it, your ego is not going to die,
your superego is not going to run away.
Till you do something for Sahaja Yoga, it will again bother you.
Mother my head is caught up, Mother my daughter ran away,
Mataji, this happened to my father’. It will happen.
I don’t do anything.
Ganas also don’t do anything.
The bhoots will catch your weakness. They don’t trouble Me.
Do you know why they don’t catch Me?
‘What has Mataji given me, Mataji has so much to him’.
He had to get so much. He got it.
What you got also is not less. You don’t value what you got.
You should be satisfied within.
Catch hold of satisfaction from inside. Establish yourself on that satisfaction.
How should I tell you this,
there is a computer for this, it has points.
If you press one finger, your satisfaction will be awakened,
if you press one finger your innocence will be awakened,
if you press one finger truth will be awakened.
This is all inside you, by pressing the fingers like this, the entire program can be set.
Shri Mataji keeps doing this.
In the first place, there should be innocence there.
There should be some satisfaction there,
otherwise, you press the finger, what will come out from there-vacuum?!
There is nothing inside.
One who has added satisfaction, he will reach satisfaction.
We are sitting in satisfaction at this time.
We have reached righteousness. We are sitting in righteousness at this time.
All have accumulated wealth
after burning the body for years and now it is present before you.
Like this, you have to keep adding everything,
add satisfaction, a lot of it.
Satisfaction.
Come into innocence,
come into righteousness. Come into the truth,
come into the beauty,
Come into love,
you have a button for everything.
How will it happen, how to do it?
Sahaja Yoga does n’t have to do it. It all happens.
There is no such word like ‘How?’ in Sahaja Yoga.
You can earn whatever you want to be inside you.
If you want satisfaction, you can earn satisfaction.
You can earn everything and keep inside.
Press a button and you will keep getting what you want.
A machine will manifest inside you.
I don’t know how you will earn these.
You add your earning!
Good.
Yes.
Let us now go into Meditation.