At the very outset, we have to know that the truth is what it is.
You cannot change it
You cannot transform it
And at this human awareness you cannot know it
That means in our evolutionary process we have reached this state of a human being
but it is not the end of our evolution
because we don´t know what is Absolute truth.
Whatever I´m going to tell you today
you have to take it
with an open mind like a scientist.
If it is proved
than you have to accept it as
honest people.
Because it is for your benevolence,
it is for the benevolence of your country,
it is for the benevolence of the whole world.
So please listen to me carefully what I have to tell you.
There is within us
a power,
which is placed in the triangular bone,
for our ascend.
It is for our last breakthrough.
And this breakthrough has to happen
as a process of our evolution.
So the truth is that
you are not this body,
this mind, this ego, these conditionings.
But you are the Pure Spirit.
And the second truth is that there is
a very subtle power of Divine Love
that does all the living work.
We see all these beautiful flowers all around us.
But we don´t even think whatever a miracle it is.
That out of one seed such beautiful flowers come out.
Who runs your heart?
The doctors may say it is the autonomous nervous system.
Who is this auto?
We go to science and we find that there
are many questions which cannot be answered.
Science cannot tell us why are we on this Earth.
What is the purpose of life?
What is our identity?
So we take to religions.
But religions have created nothing but fundamentalism.
It is a blind faith.
And all kinds of problems have brought up in the name of God.
They are only money-oriented or power-oriented.
They are not spirit-oriented.
But in these modern times there are a lot of false gurus also
who have come out to make money out of your simplicity.
If it is a living process, how can you pay for it?
Like this Mother Earth.
How are we to pay Her for these flowers?
Also some people say we have to suffer.
There is no need to suffer at all.
Imagine if God Almighty is the father of all the fathers,
how can He want you to suffer or Him?
He is your father,
full of compassion,
full of joy for you.
I have seen there are some false people coming
and teaching some mantras
and things like that
and some boys, I was surprised
poor things were just going on saying some mantras.
If it is coming from India,
You should not believe that all that comems from India is good. Not at all.
Be very careful.
It is people who are trying to mesmerize your younger generation.
As I have told you that
you have to be the Spirit.
That means it is an actualization.
It is a happening
of becoming.
So it is not just a lecture or
or a sermon or a mental process.
But a happening within you.
That you become something different.
We see so many problems in this world these days
You have no idea how much problematic it is
in democratic countries.
But it is happening in America which is supposed to be the greatest democratic country
It is just full of idiotic and stupid people.
It is surprising how they are taking life, for example
they spend all their time in absolute, stupid, nonsencial
idiotic things.
I sometimes don´t understand how come
human beings can become like that.
Also tremendous level of
an enterpreneour starts say a fashion.
Say for example narrow pants.
So they are all dressed up like that.
Nobody has freedom to keep to their own dress.
They all wear it and they get varicose veins.
They wear it even then they get varicose veins.
Then they develop some other nonsense.
Like six-inches of a skirt for ladies.
Even in the cold of England they are wearing that kind of a dress.
They talk of individuality.
Where is the individuality?
They do really very stupid things please thank God you have escaped.
They have got the freedom, alright, but no wisdom.
And now it´s full of AIDS, full of schizofrenia, madness, lunacy, all kinds of funny diseases.
Drugs of all kinds they are taking.
It´s not only the children but even grown-ups in parties.
They talk of drugs.
They have not matured at all.
I don´t say communism was the solution.
But nor is democracy.
Unless and until you have wisdom,
both things can be very dangerous.
Now they are selling all their junk which was not sold in their countries to you people here.
Due to recession now they are going to Russia and all these places, even to India, to sell all their junk.
But there is a solution
to all these problems.
This solution lies within yourself.
You don´t have to go Moon,
You don´t have to go to Jupiter to discover it.
Most of the problems that are visible are due to human beings.
Most of the human problems are beacuse of the subtle centers,
within them are in trouble.
When this Kundalini rises,
She nourishes all these centers,
interates them and connects you to this
All-pervading Power.
Because of these centers we suffer,
physically, mentally, emotionally and spiritually.
No doubt, with the ascend of Kundalini
people have cured of their many incurable diseases.
When the Kundalini comes
out of your fontanel bone area,
you can feel the cool breeze coming out of your head.
This Kundalini is the reflection of the Holy Ghost within us.
...described about God Almighty and His son.
but nothing about the Mother.
The third one is the Holy Ghost which is a dove.
Symbolically it is alright, it is pure and it ascends.
But in all other religions they have described  a Primordial Mother.
This has happened because of Paul.
He was a hater of women.
And he never met Christ, all stories are told.
He had killed so many christians and then he wanted to jump on the platform.
And he chose Peter.
as the person who will be anointed with the highest position
in christian religion.
Peter was the worst disciple of Christ.
So Christ also said to Peter
that a Satan will take you over.
I was myself born in a christian family.
And I asked my father: "Who is this Paul?"
He was a realized soul my father,
and he said: "He is a squatter."
He has done a great harm to the West.
by not respecting women.
He did not respect the Mother of Christ.
He calls her a woman.
In Quran  Mohammed respects her very much.
And said nobody should take any objection about her morality.
This Paul´s turning of Christ´s life has really ruined the message of Christ.
You find all these churches
have become very money-oriented and power-oriented.
So now after giving up communism you might jump onto these, any of them
it´s very dangerous again.
Even the Madonna was never a name given in the Bible to the mother of Christ.
It came from the father religion.
Which was before Christ.
As a result the women in the West are extremely insecure.
I was surprised, how they have to all the time please the men and please the children.
And are really going into the complete waste of immorality.
India politically and economically is a hopeless case. I agree.
But the society is very well named.
And women don´t have to be insecure in that society.
For them their power is their chastity.
Even in modern times.
So to achieve that sense of security also we have to be the Spirit.
First thing that happens to you
you become thoughtlessly aware.
It´s a new dimension in your awareness.
There are thoughts which come to us from the past and the future.
But we cannot be in the present.
When the Kundalini rises she separates the thoughts.
So we become thoughtless but fully aware.
We jump into the present.
Which is the reality.
The past is finished and the future doesn´t exist.
In that state you start growing spiritually.
The Spirit is a universal being within you.
It transcends
all barriers that we have created by our mental activity.
Of ritualism, fundamentalism, all kinds of isms.
You realize that all these religions were born on the same tree of spirituality.
These people have cut them and are fighting with the dead flowers.
In the state of thoughtless awareness
you feel your peace within yourself.
This is the peace we are seeking.
People talk of peace,
have big arguments and conferences but there is no peace within themselves.
They have been given awards and this, that.
But I have seen they are very hot-tempered people.
So by your ascend
you become a peaceful personality,
relaxed personality, satisfied personality.
And you become wise nad discreet.
Because you see the reality.
And you feel the totality.
When this Kundalini pierces thought the fontanel bone area,
you start feeling cool breeze on your fingertips.
This is the All-pervading power.
Which in Quran is called as Ruh.
In sanskrit as Paramachaitanya.
Your attention becomes enlightened and innocent.
You innocence is never lost.
It is always there.
Only thing, because of your so called freedom there are some clouds.
But when Kundalini rises and connects you to the All-pervading power
you become innocent, your eyes ecome innocent.
You know the Absolute truth on your finger tips,
even the realized children can tell you
what´s wrong with your centers.
Not that you can feel your own centers, that´s self-knowledge,
but also the centers of others.
So you develop a new dimension
in your awareness of collective consciousness.
Ultimately you develop the powers to raise the Kundalini of others.
As one enlightened candle can enlighten many candles.
The life becomes absolutely blissful.
And you jump into the ocean of joy.
Joy has no duality.
of happiness and unhappiness.
It is the experience of joy, you feel it.
Sahajayoga is working in 55 nations,
so many have been cured.
so many have now the powers,
but I have never seen them fighting, quarreling,
All full of humour and enjoyment.
What a different type of life.
That´s what is for you.
You have to achieve it without any difficulties.
It is very, very simple.
Sahaja means "born with you,"
is the right to be united, that is yoga, with this All-pervading power.
For which you don´t pay.
But it is a collective happening
it´s a collective organism,
so you have to be collective.
If one nail is cut out, it doesn´t grow.
Now see how Germans and Austrians have come to your town
and arranged this program.
How so many English going to Russia.
Like there is one finger which has some pain, the whole body
goes to it to get it alright.
So it will take hardly about ten minutes from you
to get your realization.
But there are three conditions.
Which are very simple.
The first one is that
you should not feel guilty at all.
It´s a fashion nowadays to feel guilty.
After all, you are human beings and human beings all make mistakes.
You are not God.
If you make mistakes, let´s face it, why feel guilty?
By feeling guilty, this centre here on the left side
goes out of order.
And physically also you may suffer from angina,
or from spondylitis or from lethargic organs all over the body.
Don´t believe people who tell you you are sinners.
They are the greatest sinners who tell you like that.
After all you are human beings, you are at the epitomy of evolution.
The second condition is
that you have to forgive evryone in general.
Logically whether you forgive or you don´t forgive, you don´t do anything.
But if you don´t forgive,
than you play into wrong hands and torture yourself.
So you don´t even have to think about them, you have to just
in general, say " I forgive everyone," it´s nonsense.
Also it is a myth.
Now there is a center within us on the optic chiasm which is like this.
Closed.
And if you don´t forgive,
then it doesn´t open.
But if you forgive, it opens like this.
You feel much lighter and
Kundalini may pass through.
All your life you tortured yourself by not forgiving.
And at this moment you will miss the great point
of achieving your realization.
Now the third condition is
that you have to have full faith in yourself,
full confidence that you will all get your realization tonight.
It sounds fantastic but you are fantastic.
You don´t know yourself. Once you know yourself, you will be amazed,
how many powers you have.
What you can do to yourself and to  the whole world.
Unless and until this microphone is connected to the mains, it has no identity, it has no meaning.
But as soon as you are connected to the mains,
you know what you are.
These are the three conditions
I hope you will fulfill.
As it is I think you are very sensible people,
the way you have elected your president,
the whole  world knows that.
So now those who do not want to have their realization,
should know that I cannot force it on you.
Because I respect your freedom.
It´s a last judgement,
you have to judge yourself.
In Quran it is said that at the time of resurrection
your hands will speak.
They give a witness against you.
And these hands will tell you what´s wrong with you and
what´s wrong with others.
And if you know how to correct your centers,
you can correct yourself
and you can correct others.
Those who do not want to have realization, should leave the hall.
Of course, Sahajayoga is not meant for idiots and stupid people.
And it´s not meant for  arrogant people either.
Also for people who are involved in some sort of an ideology or
some sort of blind faith.
Again I request those who do not want to have their self-realization,
they should leave the hall.
You have to be pleasently placed to yourself,
now please
you have to remove your shoes,
because this Mother Earth also
helps us to suck in our problems.
Now the left and the right are two powers,
one is for your desire
and another for action.
So you have to put both your feet apart from each other
and sit comfortably.
You don´t have to go to the Himalayas and stand on your head.
You will get your realization in your seats tonight.
So now please put your left hand
towards Me on your left hip or left.
Beacuse this is suggestive or symbolic that you
desire to have your self-realization.
You have to have Pure desire.
The right hand we use for nourishing our centers on the lefthand side of ourselves.
This we do it only
for tonight you don´t have to do it later.
So now please put your right hand on your heart.
Somebody will show it.
In the heart resides the Spirit.
If you become the Spirit, in the light of your Spirit,
you become your own master.
So you have to take your right hand
in the upper portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
This is the center of your mastery.
Which is created by all the great Prophets.
It has to be enlightened.
So now you have to take your right hand in the lower portion of your abdomen on the lefthand side.
This is the center of Pure divine knowledge.
We will know about it later on,
how it caters to the Divine knowledge.
Now please raise your hand in the upper portion of your abdomen,
now on your heart.
Now in the corner of your neck and shoulder and turn your head to your right.
I have already told you what happens to you when this center is out of care.
Now take your right hand on your forehead across and put out your head.
This is the center for forgiving everyone in general.
Now please take back your right hand
on the backside of your head and push back.
as far as possible.
This center, without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes, just for your satisfaction.
You have to ask for forgiveness.
From this Divine power.
Now the last center is important.
Please stretch your palm fully.
Put the center of your palm on the fontanel bone area
which was a soft bone in your childhood.
Push back your fingers as far as possible.
Press it hard,
move your scalp and move it seven times slowly, clockwise.
That´s all you have to do.
Now we have to close our eyes,
before that please see that both your feet are apart from each other
Put the left hand toward Me like this.
Right hand on the heart.
Do not concentrate, do not pressurize your mind.
Everything will work out spontaneously.
Now close your eyes.
And please don´t open them till I tell you.
Here you have to ask Me a fundamental question
about yourself three times.
You can call Me Mother or Shri Mataji.
Please ask three times in your heart.
Mother, am I the Spirit?
I have told you, when you become the Spirit,
you become your own master.
So take your right hand in the upper portion of your abdomen on the left hand side
press it hard
and here ask another fundamental question about yourself to Me.
Ask a question: "Mother, am I my own master?"
Three times.
I have already told you that I respect your freedom.
I cannot force pure knowledge on you.
Take out your hand
on the lower portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
Here you have to ask for Pure knowledge.
Here ask 6 times because this center has got 6 petals.
Mother please give me Pure knowledge.
As soon as you ask for Pure knowledge,
the Kundalini starts rising and we have to nourish the upper centers
with our full confidence.
So now raise your right hand to the upper portion of your abdomen
on the left hand side and press it hard
here you ahve to say with full confidence 10 times,
Mother, I am my own master.
I alreday told you that you are not this body, this mind, this ego
these conditionings but
you are the Pure Spirit.
So now raise your right hand on your heart and say
with full confidence 12 times
Mother, I am the Pure Spirit.
This All-pervading power is the
ocean of knowledge.
It is the ocean of joy and blessings.
But above all it is the ocean of forgiveness.
Whatever misteakes you might have committed,
it can be easily dissolved by this power of forgiveness.
So now forgive yourself and raise your hand to the border of your neck and turn your head to the right.
Here you have to say with full confidence 16 times
Mother I am not guilty at all.
I have already told you that logically
whether you forgive or you don´t forgive
you don´t do anything.
But you torture yourself.
At this junction if you don´t forgive, the center won´t open and Kundalini won´t pass.
So please forgive all of them in general, not thinking about them.
Now raise your right hand on the forehead across and put your head down
and here you have to say from your heart, not how many times
Mother, I forgive everyone in general.
Now without feeling guilty
without counting your mistakes
just for your satisfaction,
you have to ask forgiveness from the Divine Power.
Take your hand on the backside of your head
and push back your head
and here with full confidence from your heart, not how many times -
you have to say - Divine Power if I have done wrong,
knowingly or unknowingly, please forogive me.
The last center is important.
Where you have to stretch your palm fully
and put the center of your palm
on top of the fontanel bone area
which is a soft bone in your childhood
Put down your head and push back your fingers so there is sufficient pressure on your scalp.
Here again I cannot force self-realization on you
you have to ask for it.
So move your hand seven times clockwise
say from your heart - Mother please give me my self-realization.
Please bend your head.
Push back your fingers.
Take down your hands please and open your eyes.
Now please put both your hands towards Me.
And don´t think.
Now put the right hand towards Me like this.
Put out your head and see for yourself
if there si cool or hot breeze coming out of your fontanel bone area.
You shouldn´t put your hand on top of your head, but away from it.
Put your left hand towards Me...
not on top, a bit away or you cannot feel it at all.
Please put your left hand towards Me.
Bend your head and see for yourself
if there is a cool or a hot breeze coming out of your fontanel bone area.
If you have not forgiven yourself or others, it will be hot.
Now forgive.
Lastly again, put right hand towards me, put down your head and see for yourself
if there is a cool breeze coming out of your head.
Please bend your heads.
Now please raise your both your hands towards the sky like this.
Push back your head upward.
Ask any out of these three questions three times.
Please ask
Mother, is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?
Mother is this the All-pervading power of God´s Love?
Mother, is this the Paramachaytanya? Or Ruh?
Any of these questions you can ask three times.
Now please take down your hands.
Put your hands like this towards Me.
And don´t think.
All those who have felt cool or hot breeze on their fingertips,
or on their heads, palms,
or out of the fontanel bone area,
please raise your hands.
All of you. All of you.
May God bless you.
Except for one or two people.