[Music]
now first before meditate in your heart
you should see in your heart and they
try to put your guru in the core of it
after establishing in the heart you must
bow to that
with full devotion and dedication now
whatever you do with your mind after
realization is not imagination because
now your mind your imagination is itself
enlightened so project yourself in such
a way that you humble down at the feet
of your guru
and now Oscar
the necessary temperament needed for
meditation or atmosphere needed for
meditation meditation is when you are
one with the divine now if there are
thoughts coming in first you have to say
the first month of course and then watch
inside also you must say mantra of
Ganesha will help some people and then
you should watch inside
and see for yourself which is the
biggest hurdle what's the thought
now for the thought you have to say the
mantra of nearly Chara that Thomas
Akshar near which our sakshat shri
mataji nirmala devi namo namah should
say twice
[Music]
now we come to the hurdle of your ego
because see your thought has talked now
no doubt but there's still the pressure
on the head so if it is ego you have to
say so many Versace ah ma ahankara not
meet the great Ankara means the evil
Sasha shri mataji váradi
in Ivana mommy she's right
[Music]
now even now if you find that ego is
still there then you have to raise your
left side to push it back to the right
hand side with your hand one hand
towards the photograph push the left
side higher and right side door so the
ego and super-ego get the balance
do it seven times try to feel how you
are feeling inside is
now you raise your Kundalini up on the
head and tighten again raise your
Kundalini up on the head and tighten
again they're totally and tighten now at
the sahasrara you should say the mantra
of sastra
[Music]
now you can open again you're so strong
I like this let's take it down okay and
see that you are stationed there once
this has been done then you go into
meditation this is like cleansing as you
call it NASA
[Music]
now if you find any other obstruction
you can also say like if you have got
say mahakal is probably you can say that
mantra clearly clear it and then you sit
down for meditation
any individual thing you can take it out
like if you have the euro problem if you
think then you should start with maja
Tonga this is what you have to find out
what is your problem
when is the Kundalini stop me you can
feel it within yourself
some of you may not feel if you do not
feel it feel it on your fingers if you
are not feeling it in yourself then you
feel it on your fingers you can feel it
how is it now better where is the
problem
gentle heart all right hold your breath
not with great force just ordinary all
right
all right move it
Madonna
once again all right hold your breath
huh
mother
keep your eyes open okay
No
all right your left hand goes but I
can't
you're totally right hand
like this the left leg
okay
you were
what thinking gives you liberals
hmm
that's enough
what is it
they do feel should be
you