We realized is happy and how to hang the situation
We have that's very powerful
Because able to know that negativity
Is it complete force all the time and we have to face the negative?
I
guess-
Legal
negative
Planners and when they apply
It is necessary for physical origin. It is necessary for all the
So do wish
That they should be
Also, you mentioned some funny sort of
People who are in sahaja yoga for some time
And somehow they cannot
Very low grade it because I should say
Disgusted me down. That's the second style
Because God's work today is to say as high as me but there are all kinds of
Mental projections and hands up and honor
And the first thing that you do attack is a question
That there are suggestions
Then there can be actual fight
I have such a
You understand most interesting one, right
That's pregnant
And you don't forget how she's nobody
Kind of a quality she's
We have told her that we don't want her anymore in sahaja yoga. We do not ask people to
Come they talk to us we don't force them
And if they are hopelessly back we'll be serving you have had in your perfect now, please forgive us
and
They get out of sahaja yoga mostly it sounds work up
Because we have to choose that's what we have to do with people because there can be very high quality
There can be very cheap type of
Peggy everybody knows has been
Interest was in
Children and when she came to me, I told her let's see if I do much about you
Then I discovered that she was actually in treating an
Astronaut
Let's just say God next time I hope I don't see your face
The whole adventure goes through something. So nonsensical enemies less person. I mean that time can be realized it's only me and
There she would have shot the sympathy of sound here and there then ultimately
The erase of them to believe me twice and I told her about the realization I do now promise me
That
And she said whether you have promised me that my realization will be established
I said all right props, but you must promise me Scotty that much
imagine to be
Befitting your own Hospital and your own. I mean I have got sufficient time
We leave my children to express by now. Here is a person sitting down quietly with three children
I just taking how to touch a
Very difficult case have trained this woman wavefront of living like a really light personality this time
But
Every time a new friend of which issues to teach you the black and all the time that's not funny stuff
I am she taught that I am drama sure and how is it not astonished?
And then I think we don't know that you but you're not
So she
She suddenly got exposed
Because she just started fighting intoxicated but
Saw hundreds o shameless
She denies
So
There was been happier in a way she said
She was always pestering me and I told her that
If mother doesn't want and if it is not allowed and I'm doing Jarvis is to say to these two
now I'm telling you the story is that
We resisted
Just fight aware of and
Now the baby
We have to understand that how much time do we spend in this tree?
We must learn how much
must change
the depth of a signal
That's very important because we have got time to waste much and
If you don't get anybody in engine anymore, let's all be there. If not in the address for the time
We have together human beings. We are not bothered to work hard enough. You have to wait first of all quality and
In fine, you'll be amazed those people who think to be where you must qualify. We find that uselessly
The divine will not matter the best part of it that you Y do not
it will be angry with you for wasting your time on such a fuss and
As you'll be going you will develop this discrimination within yourself and you understand you are not waste your energy with someone like that
All this idea of being kind to everyone is not for us
We have to be kind
to ourselves and to water
And all such as Leslie
Out of the circulation of evolution. Absolutely. There's no doubt it. This is what I want to tell you that
Today, I want you to ask the questions that's important and when you ask the questions
I'll see how the bear hugs
now to be positive and person has to see
How the question is asked?
It's not a question of your wife it's a question of spirituality
The question is from spirituality to spirituality
It's not from one mind to another mind and I would like to see that
They have come up so much there was so much out and they have done so much but
Some people don't feel vibration doesn't matter
May not see vibrations for structure may be some physical form
Is there some sort of meant I don't understand the main thing is the attitude of the person see
and
negative people
Are
there
Take our time
diverters our attention equal to ten pounds and show
These they do that and they try to divert our attention to that attention
from the spirit
attention from sent
Attention from all that is so important treatments
vision of the whole unit
So we must understand that our lives are valuable that
We are sahaja Yogi's
We are workers of God. We are Kundalini resin itself
We are here license of a very high quality and we have not to waste our energy people
Do not deserve
It's very potent
It's alright what I do
It's different. I'm doing quite a lot of things with that and I see please let me get out
But you please don't waste your energy if you find somebody
difficult funny
Better give no. Thanks now with this idea which have one person
Will sit down here and I would like to see and you should all ask question question
Even because now as you are all going in the fields, you know people ask questions
It was sometimes it can be so aggressive that you can resist amount
But as I said after certain time, you should just give them up as well. So
It's not a responsibility to give realization to anyone
It's only those who deserving it is the deserving quality of people
That's the water if they are not deserving. We are not interested in there
Are sufficient already?
Better yeah, and understand that those people who
Enter into the kingdom of God only enter and not every day
So most people problems just because
You know as it is different from other
organizations
here the Gelinas is judged by vibrations and by
actually
You have to be extremely positive. I've seen even some cancer patients who came to sahaja
Yoga are so very positive
And something good for nothing at all, they're wasting your time and energy so the interest should be
I am NOT for people
Just wasting our time and energy. It's a friend of iñigo Vanilla's that I think that we try to correct
- it's all right their hardness way to be braver
This is what I want to experience
Right my own needs but you can directly understand and robit' know your
But if you try to be extremely now, let's get these all right
So one is to remove a bag or if you are hard to learn they're just the same
Now there are so many interesting pictures and overeducated
See how
Because they still like this stage of understanding, all right
Yes me won't you say to somebody who comes up to
Says very concerning me
what is the difference between sahaja yoga and what is the difference between what you're doing and
They all seem to say the same thing
And the basic difference I feel mother is that in sahaja yoga
It's not the promise of an experience. It's the actualization
something actually happens in the presence of lethargy or other realized Souls and
you get
One thing that you can explain is whether they
Keep the freedom of the individual whether the individual is actually
How does it work do you feel that these people are free in what they're doing
Do you feel that they doing it of their own free will does it look like individuals
Do it if you do that are you taught to think for yourself and
Is it something where your
Freedom isn't affected because
a lot of the other ones you can explain that to people is that
People are second in charge
and
the second in charge morning till evening and even
I've never left alone and they do is do that sink and pray and do whatever and it never stopped
And they're actually made
to fit into a boat
Once a nicely shaped they come get out of it
we they don't understand whatever we
Eventually, we don't
they're
Fitted into something and some witness from the left side
which makes them want to be late and
It's something that you still find inside you use if you look carefully in yourself
You all still got them and we wanted us to be careful with it
Because it's still there its tendency to want to fit into an organization
Be a service attack
And not be who you are and go through with it go look at yourself and get through it
And that's the way it works people are told
That's you
But basically they're taking a charge and then they don't think for themselves
And the languages is correct. You have to see the results if you want facts as plenty of facts
There's people who could fire them in water for the trial on what happened to people
And this is especially
Comes up in America because there are people are used to pay me relatively everything you go to this introduction
So that's something that attracts a lot of people if if they're used to pain
But that's the rules but what happens in the summons suddenly
Great thing about that is that you become collectively conscious which is something that can be
Variations of somebody there won't be the same thing and
Children, don't take and everybody knows that if they try to vibrations
The
Capacity
Nothing does
Actually, I experienced that they can
Use your common sense
I
Experienced a tremendous
Destroying force because when I met mother
Hi
First of all, I got oh my stomach
Something coming up there's in skin that was approved
Negativity came out but something happens, but something really has you mean
Actually, I had no such things I only
Got into their
You're not really not not that anything
Also won another thing the fact that mother is so elusive
The fact that mother is so doesn't possess because I was
Well, I think the point Kevin brought up is relevant
But what you can tell them this if you get a power if it's boobs, all right
it makes you feel powerful but in sahaja, yoga, you can actually raise other people's from the Nene and
You can
empower them with the ability to raise Kundalini
For instance for me. The proof was I stood behind
Some new person. I just told him sit in front of this photograph. I didn't explain anything
I stood behind him and I started moving as mother it showed us it gave his heart and
things started happening to him and began to feel within him things happening and he felt his to be
Linearizing and he began to feel the job
and I think that that is the most important thing you can transmit this awakening to other people and
raise their Kundalini
Rather than just feeling empowering you
Something which could be booze and I don't know
Elvis
Artificial has too often
with always
artificial has to popularly another very handsome of
course outwardly the ghost we can say that artificial danced an
Artificial conceit of a show till here does not
The artificial is both our nest because it has to sell
When the real is least bothered as he said about me
It's correct
But beyond that
How we make out an artificial knee
Is the problem because they have the same kind of thing
Say that we are in the same thing. We are a vibration and energy
And everything
Now the best thing would be extremely practical
First of all, you are seekers over
There do
You see what chakras are can see you move on another life
They move another life because you are important
So you just see what your brother gets on it
If you answer them directly, they reach the mantras an agnostic
So when they say something to you you
Must know that if their groups are there possessed and they know you who's also not only that but they can read your mind
That's one of the powers of because they can't even
See what you know
They cannot work that we can tell about your future they can tell you about fasting until you're gone
Mental problems
Your brother father they will tell you when you're lost your properties are where you have kept your ornaments
Always difficulty
Because their interest is material so they know everything now you're facing a person like that
So he lives so much alright
So when he confronts the person
Deal with the person used to just inquired
Be your fortress in your tortoise events because array
And try to see his
And see when it stops
Now he says by contraction
So I saw the patients
Now
Our real nature as he said to the usual
This emerge from the waters near the mum. She doesn't get in touch today
Only she can manage
The nourishment cannot avoid the person as we need to take energy. What are the giving States? We are not on the thing
If there are the person doesn't want to have it you can't open the mouth
So when such a question comes if you'd just let me through no many to denote
And you'll be amazed the dynamism of the spiritual mountain
Now
Supposing
It stops at tri-county you just have asked him to worship on
Justin.tv season acting
Like I tell you Douglas
Douglas is not such an intention
And
David Prowse, he just saw mindful of inherent oceans and he can put the r7 Douglas Cassini
He said I
one who ice he said I'm Douglas Amazon you
Really want this challenge of I?
Said by the way, are you perspiring - but he said yes and widened
Something you said what have you started and actually you got it
So your powers and divine powers never forget that on arguments
But you can't reach eternity
Give them realization. I didn't down miss candy because then I'm discussing with them actually an amazing them
So first of all to be acceptable because that
Now you know, what if any what is the business
That fun really, is that a bit
That is the strength
But when the light bouncing
The light has come
Even small children listen
You have got your own powers
You can raise your Kundalini
You can raise others cannellini no, no you can show people move up, but that
Coming to the side of it
How do you have achieved you know, you're given of all your habits if you have become a better person?
While people who belong to another country to forgive or image or the contrary will become just famous
The slaves they are not independent as she said that there are religions
They become ourselves together and it be a palace TT to them is just heavenly
Apart from that your knowledge is timeless
You know why I think yeah, nobody make one class
You know what contrastive say when to say how to raise it and the whole sizes
Even the boo, boo boo never give design surgery
Or get feet
So
All the points that you have your own powers
You can ask them that if we need
Yes
very hot
Then your power
Also we - I'm so
You should say now you try to be villainous you say all right in the middle
Supposing the Earth's Epps's finish them is finished
Once his realize that he won't talk so
You have to be made
understanding of the situation
And first of all, you are a realized soul shenyang on the world Devine is behind
It all confidence just face the person
First going to meditative moon down upon your powers
And see that you raised two sons
One by one as
But before raising them
The Kundalini won't rise it's apparently
So first of all, you must a person
Everyone whatever that's it
And first class he has
what it is very good and all these points must be naughty but when
You when you have to
Stop are they just not in the range or they may be done?
But definitely, you know, how much
Around you
Take
We can't promise home his parents came they realize and yet
Absolutely, sweet people absolutely
Balanced in the sense in which society sees it as a whole
And yet they see the depth that Robert can
see and they treat it a little patronizing thing and
They're there. It'll be alright, if you do it your way and we'll do it our way
Meanwhile they have the cigarettes and they entertain their guests and they have their lifestyle
but then but Roberts determination was to to set the example to
Transform to let them see by his transfer
Sahaja yoga is it?
When when we were there?
they behaved like
they they became disturbed by the tranquility that he was they started rushing around and
Shouting and giving orders and the two things and then slowly they could see what there's nothing
there's nothing through 70 and
There was a little microcosm of the transformation actually
over that weekend
you
Cleveland do it by transformation
And people start to watch and then instead of running around in circles getting nowhere they start to say
Beyond
Tell if anybody asks, you can say how much good it's done to you
Crazy
To
Disgusting very
And
Then they started
Is also very subtly go sometimes if we can
Even during the time. No didn't realize guest any half month said
you know son of yours didn't quite
Transformation perhaps I'm not quite as confident as I could be just yet, but I noticed it
My mother for instance would like to come and meet you even
Person I was in therapy with
It's not necessary, I feel like she's been quite interested in a friend of mine I used to be
Away but a friend of mine is interested in seeing you. So I have been having an effect on people but sometimes and a
Very sincere seeker on my mother my my mother's friend. I gave you your pictures. She's very sincere
Sometimes I'm not sure exactly how to
Talk about it how to initiate it
Kind of bring it up and yet I don't know that there are all these people I realized seeking and enough
love quality people
sometimes I feel
instead of offering I'm
Forcing it down our throats. And yeah, and I would like to have him come
The alternative connection my parents for instance, although they profess to be against this they've been very sweet
They've helped me to come here. They they have an attraction to admit them. Despite what they say
They've been helping me I guess because they see that we're the change
Then it should not be more appointees it see whatever these desires
But if you think that it won't be underneath baby water
These are not getting morning people are not themselves
Should she must be someone
You need not send it to them that's one thing about always from the very beginning it is too much to bear
She said there must be something about her we don't
You see if you tell them that I'm such a saint either they'll be finished
Here or maybe on Thomas C so best thing
That's sort of convenient in this life cannot be sanded not talk about it anyone
Till they are realized Souls one second
Even if that book you've written that so strategy
Because
I say white whatever I buy
He would believe the cheese a lot that night you say very scolding later that question
You've got to recognize me and that achieved a tremendous
You said it anyway mother it wasn't a suspect I might have saved in battery but
This is the only condition
That's what they put it up that has to be
Now I tell you
Say this may be
immersed and maybe and
Mine, hope you see just put it like this. It was so painful. I could put it on that wall
but especially this one mask
I mean I sit I do - what's happening to this baby here?
Now this proposal of that it would not all the pages. Believe me
And they were just like nominally emitting such vibrations the remainders I
Didn't ask a beautiful some vibrations from them, so there is room there
See
He told me that but then I just put your photograph in this village
And the whole place was flooded by the river
and thirty one
To
Three inches of it all of us
That
It can only express itself through the own channels
so they want to talk about you and
They won't let us really close to them to come to South Dakota to become
Accept them in their new place in a new style
But they don't have the capacity to achieve this
using the vibrations because that
capacity has
So many always have trouble at first
Integrating your experience into our own life without staying in our own lifestyle ourselves
So I think when people get these urges to Russia
The other question whether is coming from within themselves
And their bodies may not be so much
Anyone always which you may not get in Tibet
What I'm saying whether you have to ask 300 man and she buy it but to do the job because I'm trying to think
How do you manage so well he says she was celebrated by Germany it's just
But it's all managed I mean
but sometimes they also manage so when you can bet that if Pete Weber not managing just
Understand whether convinced them interview or not is not the point how many people be saved?
This is absolutely the sense of how many people on this earth we say
That's the only thing that
Whenever until you satisfy somebody or not whether there's a component see how many do you are going to say?
That's all
See that English was very wish
But they draw each other
Ah students must say of
Range
But it is not what we have to do how many
And don't get after the anyone
Who is still for 30 we have to get more people?
So you should run after one person is referring waste your energy on one person instead of that. Why not?
Earlier wrong mother you were talking about not wasting energy on people. Who were
Or people who've been in sahaja yoga some time but more half-baked and some what
What is the criteria how
Judgements made how that's one or a group of people who decide that an individual should be
Encouraged they
Start talking and they don't you think somebody talked
In the
What should we say people who say that's a video these are self righteous and so much cause we only
Care about very few people. I think we're doing
Well, I just yeah just for now and we are going to say whether
I should be worried you see for the certificate of the Vivianna politician. We are not simply knows
We have to do the desire of God. We have to work for what?
Was
In that is see we have to of course with dignity with compassion with now with affectionate Evita. No doubt
But all these qualities from work or saving
If by all these qualities you cannot save someone better because of
Their certificate is not produced works
There's that you feel kind of a certificate on the phone
Nobody out
There realizes their of those people who are not
A saint has to respect the same as he made something with our men who respect other people ladies
You should respect other people more than the schedules the very family and chalice
Understand if you won seats in another man
if I say he's already hot-tempered fellow you like pieces like that and
Everybody
You
See they told me
-
Well, then he has a
Proper body or not that he has proper tools or not whether he lives in a palace all on the street. It's forgiveness
This is the V which was this identification
Because I have a double life I do how people create an impression. Oh
It is nothing
Those who are deep people must realize the value of other deeply
Because they are the only ones who understand you. Are you understand?
This is one of the reasons why there are dates among sahaja, Yogi's they don't respect it
Once
Every flower
Since after all this matter little bit here and there
Also situation within the avatar, but if we have people living there who frankly just not getting it together
Should be able to do role
What's not immediate why muscles nautical means actually the base for the simply the music
For perfectly yourself, as I said that yourself to be impatient
I shall be the face when you have the perfect just if there are people like that to start instead of me
I see you got a face where?
actually
that place of can be if you have to give them you have to get
the roots and regulations for the ganache on as long as
You know
And those who do not want to vote you get out
Ashram is not a place of any the meanest men. If you put a very cheap you act up come along
So everywhere they want to come down on Saturday night
That's us. I shall please deep but is very easy
Other is
Maybe not an example that could be translated into Britain, but we found that by being stricted first
Then the strictness recedes and they become
Self-discipline. This is a very nice sensual place a certain intensity due to the punch of a channel that beat the show a
Shannon party. So today was a rough day
For five years of age beat the joy daddy
Chiseling
That is actually
The sever shape was ill to fight till then a tweet
One ticket in yourself. Sure. Does he ever shit about it when the child becomes 16 years of age?
tremendous, right
Now only eight years have passed in this country
And there are many who are treating us like say I'm never a problem
And all of you should be like that but in the beginning you do meet
That's the only way you can write out your boots writing
It has to be
With regard to the practices within sahaja yoga
What should we as parents do for our children to a home of sahaja Yogi's in practical ways
But should not spoil it because if there are
In the beginning is sahaja, yoga child and
It's more important for a simile which I and for an RD manager because he has powers
That's how Rama Rama came around he was a real asshole but you are not ready to be a realized soul
But it was really nice on
You must take them out you must discipline them in a way by descent
Did you start with a movie but the department I've seen children in the west of any pollutant
even the airless -
You must I was telling me that you must be demo buyers
Who can have to the light?
this country needs
Or this Western countries become yoga is symmetrical Ito
So best thing is to give them a balance so that they don't ever they reuse
You can work everything on them very important and you are you must use
The little things we do two laps gently look after them
But no dodge follow that they should not become routine aim for that against them again genetic mercy
Discipline is very important. They left
Like that
Think that you start in a new
dynasty now and then
and there to change as
new ballast
It doesn't look nice for here like school behave like
Ordinary mundane time it should be said with dignity - with understanding
Coordinating and all these selfishness
But you're just repetitive every time I can imagine yourself
put their attention move to the
Salvation side
That's
Possibly which I don't you must tell children what you wanted
You must be clean because you see after all
Who is going to buy this ribbon important is our condition
How much is it better than the Alaia I think music
Canadian children have such a natural poise a natural respect
We don't see them in
Tell them to darkness
If you tell them I want this kid won't see now it's now she drives out here then the circulation desk I think enough
Because of
One night but these partners are not seekers
The same relationship with civilians
Whether it is your partner your father mother brothers everything
Your relationship
Because you're connected to water his collective consciousness of these are all very
Nature you might say
I'm sure
He's speaking in
place where
is
disinterested and
Just not a seeker. But when?
the case of one person is very strong you can see
They say the wife may not be interested in sahaja yoga man is
Just
We employed by giving sounded odd Android
It was amazed I told him that once you
After all all signs and we think that done just to give us style types of water
Why this time has come to us
Everybody said to us
Is a fucking believe money does not matter people are not tensions at money with every very
Impressed because them so much time