Final Talk
Sydney, Australia
April 19, 1991
… now because there’ll be so many Sahaja
yogis here and it will work out, not only
for Sydney, but other places, like New Castle
was a surprise. You’ve seen New Castle how
it worked out. You have to go to other, smaller
places which are around.
So, we have to know that Sydney people who
are now coming to Sahaja Yoga and we have
to strengthen ourselves by meditating also
and also by spreading Sahaja Yoga across.
But more if you start paying attention more
to the defects here and the defects there,
then you’ll never grow. What you have to
see is defects within yourself, and it will
definitely grow very well. The best way is
to grow yourself and become something that
we can say is a solid Sahaja yogi. That’s
much more important, I would say, for all
of you.
You can always write to Me. And I always take
heed of that, and I work out many things even
before you have written to Me. So, there’s
no need to be frightened of someone, or to
be afraid of someone. You can always tell
that person what you think. And nobody will
now throw away anyone from Sahaja Yoga without
asking Me. It’s a law.
Nobody is going to be thrown out. But, of
course, always I’ll have your photographs
with Me. And I know you very well. There’s
nothing to be told. But when I am busy with
other people, you should know that Mother
has given such a responsibility on us, we
have to grow and let everyone grow. And gradually,
I’m sure, everything will be all right.
And so far we have had mishaps, not so much
because of leaders but because of you people,
because you should have told Me and you should
have informed Me. Also, I know we are very
capable people here, but still people don’t
meditate. That’s why I find they are catching.
Once you have got your realization, you should
know what should be the attitude towards yourself.
Now we have a Sahaja culture as you know,
and we have to come into that Sahaja culture.
And when we …
Ah! Hey, what are you doing? Bad. No. Ah ah.
At this age they pick up these things here,
so what do you say of children?
Whose child is this? Just take him. You must
correct, yourself. At this age you must correct
. Maybe later on no, but at this age you must
correct. You see if they hit, then you hit
them on their hands. Hit where their legs.
Hit them there so they are all right.
Now come along, now what’s your name? Hallo?
What’s your name? Such a Right Agnya. Very
bright Agnya he has, and also see his eyes
are showing the reason.
Gradually everything will be all right. You
have to be grown in Sahaj culture. And also
the women have to grow in Sahaj culture; men
have to grow in Sahaj culture. And the women
have to grow in a Sahaj culture is this, that
you should not answer back your husbands at
all. That’s not the way you can conquer
him.
They do not understand how they can conquer
their husbands.
That’s the main point. Not by answering
them back. Not by torturing them, but by bearing
up whatever they are saying. And explosiveness
of women is absolutely wrong. That puts them
off. They come from outside; they are very
tired. And they are themselves in explosive
condition. And then you suddenly do something
to them and they start being explosive. You
see?
So women, if they cannot run their husbands
and family, all right. Then I think it is
their responsibility. So the responsibility
is much more on women than on men as far as
the culture is concerned.
Now, what is the matter? Sit down. Sit down
here. Come along. Sit down. Sit down. Be a
nice boy. Otherwise -- Now, sit. Nice boy,
all right?
And when you want to say something, don’t
show anger, but determination. You see. Just
sit down with them. Then they know what
you mean.
So one side of the thing is of establishing
the Sahaj culture among ourselves and being
kind to them. In the family, to create peace.
That’s the job of a woman.
You see how that man was trying to provoke
Me. But I wriggled out of all his provocations,
bBecause I’m a woman. Any other man would
have slapped him twice I tell you.
In My place, any one of them. Krishna must
have used His Sudarshan. And Christ must have
hit him with His cross, you see. They cannot
bear, you see. They don’t have so much bearing
power. And they cannot wriggle out, you see.
But we can. So that is the quality one has
to learn: how to wriggle out of this.
Then the men have the work to go out, earn.
Women also, it doesn’t matter. But you must
share with them, have companionship with them.
Enjoy your companionship. After all, you see,
the romance starts actually after marriage,
not before marriage. I was surprised that
there’s no book which describes the romance
after marriage in English language. I asked
so many people to find out if there’s a
book that describes romance after marriage.
They said, “No book.” But in Indian books,
Indian languages, we don’t have any romance
much described before the marriage but always
after the marriage.
So I didn’t understand what was this thing
was. After marriage, the romance finishes.
Not in Sahaj culture …
Hallo. Now, come along. Ask him to … take
him out … Put him in there in the room.
He’ll be all right. No, you can’t sit
here. Come along. Tell him. Now he’ll be
all right. If you beat, you cannot sit here.
Now you take him. No, you take him out. Take
him out and put him in the room. He will be
all right. Now, why did you beat?
And the men have to know that they have to
respect their women. In the presence of their
children specially, they must really respect.
If you’re angry you can do what you like
in the bedrooms. In the presence of your children
you should behave yourself. And this is one
of the reasons why the children in the West
are not at all obedient. No sense of respect.
So the respect that husband pays to the wife
is absolutely important. For example, now
supposing I’m sitting here and my husband
is sitting here and I want a glass of water.
If I try to get up he’ll ask the children,
“Go and get it for your mother.”
If they say, “All right, daddy, should we
put some oil in your head?”
“First put in your mother’s head.”
“Can we go out?”
“Ask her. What does she say.”
So put all the authority towards her. This
is the job of men. You see, then only the
love grows. Moreover, if wife is sick, she
needs your protection. You must go all out
to be gentle, very gentle with them. If the
husband is gentle with the wife, the children
will be very gentle, too. How you gently hug
your wife. How you talk to her, how you express
yourself to her. It’s all very, very important.
And care for her -- to make her most important.
You see, if she’s sitting uncomfortable,
“Should I make something comfortable for
you?” Then if you are decorating, “Aha,
this year Mommy will like very much, isn’t
she.” All such things suggest how much the
husband cares for the wife.
Or sometimes bring some present for her, in
the presence of children you should give,
so that they also have that respect for the
mother. Gentleness is missing, completely.
We are very harsh sometimes. We are volcanic.
And I don’t know how people can stand volcanic
women and volcanic men. So to be very gentle
is the best way to live together. And to care
for each other is very important. Then you
start missing each other, don’t dominate
each other. On the contrary if the wife is
going towards, then the husband would rush,
say, “No, no, no, no, no, let me go.”
Gradually they develop these qualities in
them. Not by fighting, not by quarreling,
arguing. Gradually they will develop these
habits. And you’ll be very happy to be in
love with each other.
I am only worried about our family system
in Sahaja Yoga. It’s very important, extremely
important. If the family is not all right,
how are we going to keep all of you together?
And I want the whole world to be together.
How can we get the whole world together if
you cannot have one family all together? But
in no way it means that you become a slave
to your husband or a slave to your wife as
far as Sahaja Yoga is concerned. Sahaja Yoga
is above everything. If husband tries to do
something against Sahaja Yog, you should stand
against it. If the wife wants to do something
against Sahaja Yoga, you stand up. Nothing
else. Because this is something precious you
have got and you have to live with it, and
you have to enjoy it.
It is very difficult for people to understand
that Sahaj culture is the only culture in
which people can live happily together. There
is no other way out. We start from the very
primitive to the most modern. We have imbibed
lots of things of the Indian culture as well
as lots of things from the Western culture.
For example, we allow divorce. Not at the
slightest thing. It’s not a very good thing
to divorce also, but in case everything fails
and everything is so horrid and by law you
feel horrible with your standing, then I say,
“All right. You can have this, you can have
the divorce.” So we could have a little
compromise on that point. But we have the
least divorces in Sahaja Yoga. Say in a church
if there are ten marriages per year ---I don’t
know if they even have so many, but even if
they had, nobody goes to the church -- out
of them, nine of them are failures, first
year only. Compared to that, we are much better
off. We have some problems, in the beginning
sometimes it happens, but on the whole we
are much better off than all other people.
Now it’s for you to decide whether you want
to enjoy your wife or your husband or not.
If you have everything and you do not know
how to enjoy, then what to do? So all this
anger, all this temper should go away. You
should introspect also, “ What am I doing?
What am I expecting? What am I doing to the
other party? Why can’t I enjoy?”
Just ask this question: “Why can I not enjoy
my wife or my husband?” Just ask this question
and you’ll realize the problem is more with
you than the other party.
So our family system has to be absolutely
ideal. And we have to prove to the world that
those who are getting married in Sahaja Yoga
are the ideal husband and wife; or those who
are Sahaj yogis, even if they are married
outside but they become Sahaja yogis, they
become ideal husband and wife. The relationship
between them are the best, and for that, whatever
is necessary you should do; whatever has to
be done, you should do. No sacrifice, no adjustment.
It’s just our idea. Just our idea.
So this is My last advice to you, that have
beautiful families, pure families and love
all the children as your own children. It
will work out much better. Nobody should object
if some child is corrected. Never. If somebody
corrects your child, you should be thankful
to that person that they have corrected your
child. And then children are frightened of
the collective because they think all the
collective are together if they are not misbehaving.
You see, if you start supporting on your own
child, then the child becomes, you see, quite
clever. It knows that “Nobody can say anything
to me,” but the whole collective -- if just
now the child has gone there, you see, they
all have felt it. Because all of us have decided.
They’ll all behave. But if somebody had
supported that child, then the children wouldn’t.
So all of us should support all the children,
and if some child is wrong, then we all should
say, “All right, you’re wrong.”
Because all of them are your children. Take
it like that. They are collective children.
You have to look after them; you have to bother
about them; you have to help them. Everything
has to be done on a collective basis. But
supposing one child is bad, then all of us,
all of us, should tell that child that “You’re
bad.” Then he improves. Also we have to
tell them, “You are Sahaja yogis, you can’t
do like that. You are Sahaja yogis; you’re
great. You can’t do like this.” And that
will work also, very well.
Also other relations we have outside who are
not Sahaja yogis, just see if they are nice
people. You need not be rude to them, need
not cut out from them. But if they are rude
and if they are against Sahaja Yoga, then
it’s better not go near them. Better not.
So you should just try to make a point in
your life that you are going to show Mother
that we are very happily married people. And
that’s what it is I want to see among you.
Now we are a very big family all over the
world and as you are Ganesha’s patrons here,
it’s also important that the family should
be the best in Australia. ‘Cause Ganesha
is the product of a very beautiful family.
I hope you’ll all understand this. Seriously
take it up, and work it out and practice it.
I’m told that people get angry if somebody
corrects their children. Is very wrong. Never.
Feel detached about it. You shouldn’t spoil
your children. And we have had a very bad
experience with these children when they came
to India. And we thought from which land they
have arrived.
My tour has been very successful thanks to
you all. You have worked very hard, I must
say, very hard. Next time I’m told I’ll
have no radio, television, nothing of the
kind. Just a waste of time with them. We’ll
just have all posters which are very good
because they emit vibrations by which people
feel much better. We’ll have also beautiful
-- what you call them? Banners. Banners. And
wherever is possible, you can put it. And
it is My name there; when the wind blows also,
the vibrations are emitted. Also you could
go into the newspapers. That’s all right.
But no more of this radio or these things.
The other day I asked some people, “Did
you hear the radio?” Nobody has known if
there was a press card. So we are wasting
our time with this radio and television absolutely,
we are not going to have anything to do with
it.
All those who are coming to India, they should
try to book as early as possible, and let
Me know when they are coming; they are all
welcome. This time we are changing our plans.
We are going via Madras. I want you to see
the south. So we’ll be traveling not by
those horrible buses, but by the train, by
the train this time. Up to Ganapatipule we
cannot go by train as you know, but up to
Kolapur. And from Kolapur to Ganapatipule
is not such a long distance. The road is quite
nice.
This time we are going to very different places
like Madras, Bhairov, Hyderabad, then Puna,
and then to Ganapatipule. I hope you’ll
all enjoy your stay this time again in India.
And lots of people will be coming again. We
are really having a great success everywhere.
I’m sure this time we’ll have many more
people.
If you have money problem, you can write to
Me also. We can make some arrangements for
that. But, you see, we cannot reduce now any
more. We have kept the same price throughout
because we have to pay for the Russians, for
all these Eastern Bloc people, their food,
their living. We have to lend them money.
There are absolutely, say, about a hundred
people coming without a single pai on them.
They’re traveling; so, sorry, but we have
to compensate for it. I know it pressurizes
everyone. But we have to compensate.
And other nations are at least paying for
their travels.
I can’t pay for their travel. That’s a
hundred people traveling. So, as far as Australia
is concerned, you don’t have to share that
part.
So, may God bless you!
Sahaja yogi: Shri Mother. We would like to
give You a little memento of Your tour. It
is something that has been with You for some
time. Each time you had a public program or
even at the puja it was there. It was made
by Sahaj yogis, a whole series of them, even
some children participated in it, into this
screen.
Shri Mataji: Oh, My! Thank you so much. It’s
so beautiful. You know, today only I was just
thinking what a nice thing it is. I shouldn’t
desire anything, I think.
Now, very beautiful. Very, very beautiful.
It gives so many ideas of colors and things.
You have so much of talent here I must say.
But you’ll have to bring it with you.
Sahaja yogi: We could dismantle it, You know
that? and just bring You the silk screen.
Shri Mataji: Thank you, Alex.
Sahaja yogi: Shri Mother, from all your children
in Australia, we thank you in our hearts for
coming and giving us such a wonderful tour.
Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi. Ki Jay!
Shri Mataji: And any disease or anything you
have, any problem, you have to tell Steven,
or you can tell Me, or inform Dr. Spiro, or
someone, whomsoever you want to. Any disease.
Don’t be shy about it. And I’ll tell you
how to treat it. I mean, normally it is only
on the vibrations you have to say left, right,
what is the problem is, but there are certain
things which require more attention …
(part of a bhajan plays)
… only Mrs. Thatcher. Tell Me what is to
be done about the bum. I must say, that’s
the only point where I agreed with her.
Sahaja yogi: Yes, Mother.
Shri Mataji: Otherwise, you know, she is a
very simple woman, otherwise. What happened,
that I was to go to a party to her place for
a luncheon here, and it was a Monday or something
and a holiday. It was a holiday and all My
ornaments were in the bank, you see. But My
daughter had asked Me to buy some artificial
ornaments. So I said, “Now what to do? I
have nothing to wear.” See she doesn’t
like Me to go just like this. So I said, “All
right.”
So I bought one of these artificial diamonds.
Quite big, big ones. Absolutely artificial.
So I went to the lunch. It was in the area.
She saw me. She just started looking at the
diamonds. And she came and talked to Me again
and again. And then ultimately she asked Me,
“Is this from Your family?”
I did not tell her, I said, “Yes.” But
I was wondering, “Look at this woman. She
doesn’t even know this is artificial.”
But apart from that, you see, even if I am
wearing anything, what does it matter, I’m
not going to give it to her in any way.
But the way her eyes, you know, just opened
up. I was amazed at her. And then she became
very friendly with Me and she was following
Me, neglecting everyone. And in the next lunch
party, she made Me sit with her. She asked
lots of things about India and “how You
manage Your family” and this and that.
Very surprising. That artificial diamond stuff.
I told My daughter about it and she just laughed.
But in England people are quite conscious
of ornaments, very conscious. Maybe here also,
I don’t know.
Sahaja yogi: Not so much. In England, they’re
very concerned with status.
Shri Mataji: Status. Like one day, she wore
a, I had an old necklace of Mine with real
pearls, you see. They know what is real pearls
are, I don’t know how. And she went to the
market, she went to the shop and she came
back. She said, “Now take your madam necklace.”
I said, “Now what is this ‘madam?’”
She said, “Mommy, whichever shop I went,
they called me madam.”
At first I didn’t know what was, how I become
madam now, then I realized it was the pearls.
I have lots of such things with Me because
of the family. So I was wearing one ring,
it’s a big emerald. Very big emerald it
is, such a big one, from the family. I don’t
know how many in India would look at this
..
(Break in recording)
Sahaja yogi: There’s a story, Mother, of
King Charles I, when he was riding through
Scotland and he came across a man belonging
to a very small Christian group who didn’t
approve of kings. And his lieutenants -- they
were all on horses and this man was on foot
-- and his lieutenants said, “Will you not
take your hat off before the King, sir?’
And the Scotsman, who was very independent,
said, “No, actually, I won’t.”
So the king said, “Then sir, I will take
my hat off to you.” So he took his hat off.
He was a gracious man, apparently. Actually
it was King Charles II.
Another Sahaja yogi: He must have been the
same man who was going up the stairs, wasn’t
he?
Shri Mataji: You see, it’s all right. I
mean, supposing it’s your country, it’s
all right. But we are from another country.
We are not even in the Commonwealth. So why
make everyone bow to her? Actually, Americans
would have said, “Hi.”
Rosie, are you going to America now?
Sahaja yogini: Yes, Mother.
Shri Mataji: When?
Sahaja yogini: I’m not sure when.
Shri Mataji: I see.
Are you all right? When are you going?
Sahaja yogi: I leave in one week and then
a few weeks after that. Somewhere between
one month and then three months.
Shri Mataji: I see. So where will you be?
Sahaja yogi: Seattle. If that’s okay.
Shri Mataji: Very good.
And when do you love Me?
Sahaja yogini: All the time.
Shri Mataji: Very sweet. She’s a poetess.
Ganesha is standing in attention for you.
Really. It’s beautiful.
Thank you. Ask them to keep it carefully somewhere.
They will do it. There. Give it to King. I’m
very happy now.
So, you are enjoying yourself?
Sahaja yogi: Very much, Shri Mataji. Very,
very much.
Rosie looks so nice.
That Phillip is such a pitiful -- he’s doing
all kinds of things in France. He’s going
on the streets and shouting, “I’m the
incarnation, and this and that.” And big
problems. I said, “Let him shout, he’s
going to lunatic asylum.”
Lots of lunatics are there.
Sahaja yogini: There are.
Shri Mataji: They’re on the streets.
Sahaja yogini: I’ve seen them.
Shri Mataji: They are not in the lunatic asylum
but on the streets and they go within the
buses and things. And talking all kinds of
things, you know. Horrible. And I told Marie,
“What is this nonsense, they put all of
them on the streets and they’re walking
into every bus.” So she told Me that “Mother,
you see, the French are very considerate,
and we try to help them.”
I said, “What? You’re helping them and
ruining everybody else. This is a stupid help
that you are giving them. Better put them
in some lunatic asylum.”
French are coming up now, getting better.
Sahaja yogini: They seem much happier. When
I saw the people that I knew there, they seemed
very joyful.
Shri Mataji: Better now. They must change.
You see, in that country, if you are miserable,
then you are very knowledgeable. You have
to be extremely unhappy, all the time. If
you are not miserable, then you are an ignoramus.
Can you imagine? Les miserable.