Now if you have left Agnya, that means there’s
possession on it.
That means all of you have got something of
that kind, already you’re caught up, you’re
not clean.
What is the mantra for this, Gavin?
For the back Agnya, Mahaganesh.
Mahaganesh, Mahabhairava, correct.
Now see, in the brain you’ve got all these
seeds of the gods and they are the seeds because
they’re the causal of these.
So the first, the causal is created and then
the deities are created.
So, for example, causal of the Mother Earth
is fragrance, all right.
So from fragrance comes the Mother Earth.
In the same way the causal of Brahmadeva is
Hiranyagarbha, all right?
He’s called as Hiranyagarbha.
He’s the causal of Brahmadeva.
Where does he stay in the brain?
In the brain of the Virata whatever deities
leave are the causal and manas also, because
they’re reflected.
So the causal ones are here in our brain,
in our brain, in our brain.
At the back here, around the Agnya, now I
give you the name, no, around the Agnya.
Agnya is Mahaganesha and Mahabhairava, Agnya,
at the back.
And in front…
At the back is actually Mahaganesha, just
in the center.
Just in the central point is Mahaganesha.
This is the minutest point.
Around him moves Mahabhairava, all right?
And around this, the rest of it that moves
is Hiranyagarbha, all right?
Now did you follow that?
So when you think, or whatever thinking you
do, through this superego, through this superego,
you get the development of this Hiranyagarbha.
Did you follow that?
And also otherwise, is also, who acts when
you think?
Is Hiranyagarbha.
This is Swadisthana, we call it, this is Swadisthana
chakra around it, all right?
Now, so Swadisthana is divided into left and
right.
Left Swadisthana is Hiranyagarbha and right
Swadisthana is also Hiranyagarbha, at the
back here.
So now to point out first of all, at the back,
if you move, is Mahaganesha.
Around him moves Bhairava, who protects Mahaganesha.
Around it moves, now moves Hiranyagarbha,
at the back.
But Hiranyagarbha has left and right side
while Bhairava and Ganesha, they move on each
other.
Did you follow that point?
Now in front, in the center here, is who?
Kartikeya, in the center; Christ is in the
center, in the center itself where the optic
chiasma is.
Here outside is Kartikeya.
What is Kartikeya?
Kartikeya is the protector of Christ.
Around Kartikeya, they’re all protectors
of Christ, moves who?
Now who is Mahabhairava’s counterpart?
Mahahanumana, Mahahanumana, all right?
And around that, what does move?
Ekadasha Rudra.
The movement of Ekadasha Rudra is not circular,
doesn’t move like that.
It moves like that.
Or you can say, move like that.
Now what is Ekadasha Rudra?
Let us see.
Can you give the names?
Of Ekadasha.
Take one by one.
Buddha, right?
Mahavira.
Then Christ, then Mahabhairava.
How many of them, four.
Then Mahaganesha, five.
Did I say Bhairava?
Again, again say it one by one, Buddha, Mahavira,
Christ, Mahaganesha, Mahabhairava.
All right, this is very clear cut for you
because just now I’ve told all of them.
Buddha, Mahavira, Christ.
Then, what else, four are left, four are still
left.
Mahahanumana, you didn’t tell?
Mahahanumana, how much it is now?
Three left, no four are left, four, now what
are these four?
Say, it’s very simple.
Just now
I discussed with you Mahahanumana, Mahabhairava,
two, Buddha, Mahavira.
Four, now, Kartikeya.
Kartikeya, Ganesha, sixth.
Christ, seventh.
Now four more are left, now who are the four
more, let’s see, can I have it?
Pat, come along.
You’ve done lot of reading.
They have written it down into something,
eleven of these.
Brahmadeva, Hiranyagarbha, correct.
Vishnu, Narayana, Lakshmi Narayana, how much
it is.
Shiva, Parvati, everyone.
Shiva and Shakti, all right?
Eleven of them.
Lakshmi Narayana is one, Brahmadeva Saraswati
is back, Shiva Parvati has…
All eleven are there.
Why Shiva and Parvati?
Two have to be taken because Shiva is the
Guru, Parvati is the Shakti.
So if you catch on void, the beginning of
the trouble starts because Shiva is the central
path.
There Shiva is to be taken as Guru, Shiva
is Guru, Shiva is the one who is our Guru.
He is our spirit.
But he’s not the spirit that protects because
spirit needs no protection.
Whom do you protect then, also.
So when you protect, you protect the spirit
but what protects it is the Guru personality
which is Shiva, which is Shiva actually.
Did you get that?
Now you might say how is Shiva is “Guru
Brahma, Guru Vishnu, Guru Devom, Maheshwara,
Guru Sakshat, Parabrahma, Tasmai Shri Guruveh
Namah.”
Because Guru means a person who is full of
Gurutwakashan, is weight, is the gravity.
Person who is with gravity, which has some
sense, which is density, which is our spirit.
Otherwise we have no density, we’re useless.
Our spirit goes away, we float in the air.
So the Guru is everything.
Today I’ve called you here to tell you how
to become a Guru.
So that’s why I’ve given you this introduction.
Is it clear to you?
All right let Me know now…
(Apparent break in recording here)
See that? , just laugh at yourself; see that?
, just laugh at yourself.
With all your knowledge of how many years
I’ve been talking to you, look at this,
this is the point.
How Mother raising… just given just like
that, do I tell you something.
You all have gone to the wrong gurus, you
have done, because… , nothing of the kind.
Just because you’re all kept here, it’s
the Ekadasha Rudra on your forehead, it’s
to bow before any wrong guru.
With that your Ekadasha Rudra…
Sahaja Yoga is very simple you know.
If you put your glass upside down , if you
put it like this . Sahaja Yoga is so simple,
do you follow that point?
So we reach one conclusion, by mental understanding
you cannot understand Sahaja Yoga.
So as a guru what could you have?
I’ve made a promise.
That’s different.
You are telling like this, if I say that,
“What is the sense of, say, guru?”
Do you say that it should not become artificial?
Now let’s see again quite straight forward,
what is the question?
No, no, what is the question?
Now try to remember.
What should we have?
What is the question, let’s see exactly.
Exactly.
How do you…
This is another question but the question
I asked is: then what must a guru do?
The thing I said, by discussion Sahaja Yoga
doesn’t work out then what should we do?
I asked the question what should we do?
Make it simple always related to your Mother,
you’ll get the answer.
Hah!
All right?
To neutralize the old guru who has been a
bad guru you have to surrender to the real
guru.
If your guru is the real guru then you surrender
to the Mother of your real guru.
Because your real guru is also surrendered
to Me.
So all gurus are to be surrendered at the
lotus feet of your Mother.
Then if it is Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha, Shiva,
Krishna, Christ, anyone of them also, Ekadasha
still is more than your Mother’s.
It is very difficult because we want to stick
on to something, even the real guru.
Christ is a real guru but the Christ you know
of is to be also surrendered at the lotus
feet of your Mother because we also know that.
Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha, all of them are My
servants.
Adi Shakti is the Mother.
She’s the Mother of all the gurus, of all
the prophets, of all the incarnations, of
all the . After Her, only Parabrahma is created,
after that only Parabrahma.
So when you have got someone like that to
surrender, is a maya.
That is the biggest problem because you’ve
got somebody so easily.
Arjuna was a great warrior till the war started,
and somebody was a great swimmer when he came
to the ocean.
Allow your mind to do the work, allow your
mind.
So to be the highest guru we’ve to be completely
surrendered.
Now when you’re surrendered, you don’t
doubt.
For Me this finger is completely surrendered,
say, to My body, it doesn’t doubt My body.
Supposing I’m pressing and it receives the
information that you’re doing that he informs
the brain and informs the body that I’m
doing that.
It says some thing must be done to remove
it, the whole body acts, all the fingers act
and all the power flows there, the energy
flows there where the finger is hurt.
So when you are surrendered there is no question
of individualism.
Those people who think of any kind of individualism
are going to go out of the circulation of.
From the beginning, I’ve told you many a
time if we take out all those people who want
to assert their individualism of any kind.
You see, this is a branch, all right, you
can see here.
In the last stage, I use the same analogy
better and better.
Outside is the same, all right?
If inside and outside is the same and the
rest is . If this has to become this, what
has to . This myth has to go, all right?
This myth has to vanish.
So this myth is made from what, our ego and
superego only.
These are actually the end result of all the
nonsense we have been.
In a sense, all this has to go, vanish, it
doesn’t exist at all, that is .
In a way you cannot be a guru unless and until
, you are open to it, that’s coming and
going, but supposing you’re like this.
To be like the story I heard in India that
there was a , three of them.
They went inside the to have something.
They sat down on a table and they saw a flask
put like this.
They said, “What sort of a flask is this,
it has no mouth.”
So they called the bearer and said, “See
we can’t have food unless and until it has
a mouth, take it back.”
They said, “What sort of a glass is this,
it has no water?”
Because . But when you’re surrendered the
mouth and bottom is , luckily its…
That surrendering is to be achieved if you’re
going to be .
This is all mental, how do you . Have a bandhan.
How many times you give yourself bandhan?
Before sleeping, after getting up, then namaskar
to your Mother, , touching My feet, very important,
not to come on to the Agnya, supposed to correct.
Even sitting down there I’m catching, . Then
again put on both the feet, again you try.
First right and then left.
Ah!
See now.
It’s not mental, this is the point I’m
bringing you.
It is not mental, now this is.