symmetry what is sahaja yoga sahaja some
is faith Germans born so it is born with
you the right to become United which is
the yoga with the divine and this this
sahaja yoga is something that everybody
can have is it is something everybody
can practice of course and how does the
this connection with the divine take
place we have within ourselves this
power in the triangular bone which is
called a sacred meaning sacred which
when awakened sprouts like a premium in
a seed and Rises through six subtle
centers opens out the last center and
gets connected with the damar which is a
subtle energy all around us which
organizes us which nourishes us does all
the living work above all it loves us
does this mainstream mythology that
people who have not had the ability to
practice sahaja yoga are not connected
with the divine most of them are not I
need some of them are they don't know
all about it so this is what a an extra
force that is available to human beings
to develop themselves in this way of
course this is the last breakthrough of
our evolution where you have to get
connected with the divine you have to
feel it on your central nervous system
and that's how you get your
self-realization do I perceive here that
this is a way of balancing oneself of
keeping in such a way of living one's
life in such a way that one is not
unbalanced in one's view of what is
going on around us yes we have two sites
in our system of autonomous nervous
system
turn right which he called as left and
right sympathetic nervous system the
left side caters for our emotions for
our past our desires the right side
caters for our actual physical and
mental if you indulge into one too much
and go too far with it you develop an
imbalance within yourself in the center
lies the third power which we call as
parasympathetic nervous system this is
the channel which is the central path of
ascent when the kundalini rises through
it it brings you in the balance because
it rises in the center of the system so
this is the minimum that happens that
you developed your balance so how does
one actually achieve this balance it
just happens one tinniest in other words
there's no there's no physical
requirement on an individual not at all
not at all it's a evolutionary step as I
told you in our evolution we have
developed a balance we can stand on our
two legs animals cannot in the same way
you develop this special balance between
your emotions and your actions in a very
proper way you speak as though this is
some sort of evolutionary step yes it is
it is the last breakthrough that you
have to become the spirit now and this
has to be achieved which can be achieved
only through a living process because we
have become human beings through a
living process and that living process
has to act within us the sounds as
though it is rather a significant time
than in the in the history of humanity
very much in the history of humanity in
the history of evolution in the history
of spirituality is the most important
time because here where you get what
heaven has been promised to you so far
so it's no accident
that sahaja yoga has appeared in the
world at this time no not at all not at
all it's all predicted thousands of
years back in India and later on by many
Saints even William Blake has predicted
it shri mataji you went to russia last
year and I believe the reception you got
was most surprising yes I was myself
surprised because thousands of people
came and very sensible well-educated
people came and they all settle down
thousands I didn't know how to cope with
that number because there were so many
and even the members of the Supreme
Council the government they came that I
could only say that in the so-called
free societies we waste too much time
experimenting with our freedom and
indulge too much into the politics which
is a waste thing I think there in
economics all these things while the
people there didn't have any such
chances so they put their energies to
something that was higher than that they
diverted and they were very
knowledgeable they knew a lot about
seeking they knew a lot about Kundalini
and as if they were just waiting for me
it was very de mama
mr. Gorbachev has said the Russians
require a mental revolution do you see
the acceptance of sahaja yoga as part of
this revolution of course he himself is
a saint and what he is meaning by mental
then they should now understand that
they have to develop that balance
between communism and democracy our
democracies are imbalanced they are
one-sided they have no not the other
side of collectivity but communism has
collectivity it is power oriented our
democracies are money-oriented what he
is meaning is the maturity
of all wisdom so yeah referring back to
what we were talking about earlier is it
okay as we were talking about earlier
about bringing the human body into
balance could we say then that mr.
Gorbachev is bringing the whole Eastern
Bloc into balance yes yes they had one
too much on one side and he's trying to
bring them in the center you mentioned
that you went to an Eastern Bloc
conference last year and I believe you
gave many influential people realisation
is it true that you believe that this
was instrumental in helping the
overthrow of oppressive communism it was
a yoga yoga seminar and I expected all
of them to be there and surprisingly I
talked to them hardly for 30 to 35
minutes and then I gave them realization
and all of them got it they were
representative from all these Eastern
Bloc countries when they got it
they're so surprised at it that they
walked out with me out for the hall and
nobody was left in the hall listen to
other people they gave me their
addresses and they said we want this
only in our country and they wanted to
search our centers and I am told they
have already started centers the
all-pervading power requires a medium to
trigger something and when these people
were created as realized Souls as they
got connected with this all-pervading
power
I think they'd record it they had that
confidence that courage in them because
once we realized you become very
courageous and you want to establish
truth at any cost
similarly the the West shall we call it
the Western nations have had sahaja yoga
available to them to to investigate to
to see for themselves how it worked for
20 years and yet it has been very slow
to grow why is it happened this way do
you think here people have so many
diverse ideas about things they are very
self opinionated also about things and
the so-called man-made religions all
over have also conditioned them too much
they have other conditionings of
different norms that they have as far as
the social life is concerned and the
physical appearances rather on a very
superficial level so the people have not
grown I think so much deeper of course I
must say there are so many seekers in
the West so many seekers and they were
lost because as soon as people knew that
there's a market for them the false
gurus jumped out and they started
preaching about false things just to
earn money they were all money oriented
now there's another psychology with the
Western mind that you must buy
everything if something is not for sale
then it is useless and this psychology
has really debted them to come to sahaja
yoga very much because this is a living
process and you cannot pay for it and
they couldn't bear it I mean actually I
must say one of the very important
television gentlemen told me off that
anglo-saxon brain cannot accept anything
which cannot be sold I didn't know what
to tell him I just said who has made
this brain his God has made and why is
it so so you have an expectation really
that the syncro sahaja yoga will change
the world
of course it changes human beings and
they manifest the change outside and we
create a new race that's what they're
talking about if you know they talk of
new age of a new race but I don't know
what is there
Nation about it they talk about all this
thing Aquarius and Aquarius is the
Kundalini she is placed in the Aquarius
and they talk about Aquarius and all
kinds of things they're talking writing
thinking about it but when it comes to
actualization I think they think I am
very too simple for them not complicated
and sahaja Yoga is too simple it should
be very complicated and all their own
ideas about seeking that they must
suffer they must go to Himalayas
they must starve themselves and then
only they can get realization Sri Hari
is the evolution of the planet closely
related to the evolution of humanity and
he was related and the planet our planet
is moving in a spiral way all the
planets are moving in a spiral way and
they are creating all possible things
for the use of human beings so that they
can save time save time for getting
their ascent and for the meditative
growth but people don't understand that
part there are theories around now that
the suggestions so we say that the
planet could be a living organism a
complete entity of course it is one of
the examples of this one I can give you
is that if you sleep under a coconut
tree a coconut never falls on anything
that is living whether it is a human
being or a snake never falls that is so
is it all around the world coconuts
never fallen and living creatures so
they understand we call it as Shri Paulo
because because we think that it is like
a brain which understands well if this
world is a living organism what is the
brain what drives this being this
organism what has made it evolve the way
it
there is the subtle power which is
all-pervading love God's love which
manifests all the things like living
work all nourishment all balancing it's
so balanced
if the Pacific was slightly deeper than
this there would have been problems if
Himalaya was safe one and a half times
then what it is there would have been
problems so everything is so balanced in
nature hmm and the Almighty has created
only one word only we human beings have
divided and moved like criminals with
our passports in our hands Shri Mata
Hari what we have been talking about
many people would regard as a belief or
a theory how does one know that the
difference between truth and a belief
first of all anything for which you have
to pay money is not the truth you can't
pay for it if you cancel out that I
think 99.9% all the falsehood will drop
out but truth to be really actualized
you have to have self realization then
you feel on your fingertips vibratory
awareness a new awareness a new
dimension awareness by which you can
make out what is true and what is false
that's an absolute truth that you
realize at that stage so one must have
one's realization really to be able to
tell the truth you want to follow anyone
one must have realizes shri mataji thank
you very much thank
you know they are doing one thing doing
one another I was reading an article
just now where you were talking about
inner peace and outer peace this seems
to be something that attracts the
attention of people in this present
stressful age my realization what have
you become a person and out with
thoughtless awareness
that means you see everything you
witness everything and whenever you want
to say or to think you can see about it
but you don't react there's no reaction
so you are empowered to see it in such a
manner that there need not be any
thought just the whole creation actually
it's a very subtle thing is to be
experienced and that is the point where
we realize that we are the source of
peace and that's how our inner peace is
established now people have many
foundations of peace I have known all of
them they have no peace within
themselves some people have got peace
Awards there are horribly hot-tempered
people but they have got to be some odds
Nobel Prizes the peace has to be first
of all found inside and then it
manifests outside you know the another
question we wanted to ask you is because
of this rather useful way you use your
hands to describe the movement of the
chakra when they when they they part I
wonder if you could just explain why
when illness occurs it occurs because of
the
the movement away of one center from
another alright what I try to show them
that this is the left side this is the
right side this is the left sympathetic
nervous system say and this is the right
sympathetic nervous system and really
spinal cord looks like this and inside
here is the spinal cord which has the
centers in it the subtle centers now
when you start using the energy of these
centers say too much on the right and it
starts moving more towards the right and
there's a constriction and the power
becomes less because you are exhausting
going more towards the right side
suddenly something happens and from the
left if there's a jerk then the
connection is completely broken this is
on its own it starts working on its own
that's what you say that this has become
malignant I have no relationship with
the whole to have the proportionate
growth so if the nose starts developing
it can cover your eyes and govern your
mouth everything this is how a cancer is
setting or any other disease there's so
many psychosomatic diseases are nothing
but somatic he is from the right side
and when the psyche gives in then it
becomes a psychosomatic disease there
are so many diseases which are more
psychosomatic than physical and these we
call them as incurable can be easily
cured by Kundalini awakening because
when Kundalini passes through this she
just integrates them for example she is
going like this then she goes into this
integrates them just like she strings
them like pearls and so they are brought
down and also she nourishes that Center
that's what people get cured
automatically by themselves by their own
power Shri Mataji you ready
she mythology do you want to speak to
the IBC in Adelaide afternoon or would
you rather that I rang them and said
you're too busy abrupt yes I've been a
lot of problems there abrupt and also
very flippant I don't think they said
they wanted to talk to you about false
gurus and woke a few seconds what just
do what all right they've been having a
little trouble this morning you know we
have banners to put up announcing your
program tonight and they we had them on
various bridges and I kept chasing them
away but we finally found a place where
they've allowed them to stay another
piece that must be busy with big exits
oh yes it's all very reserved places for
addictions yes also if it was for the
election it would be able to go up
anywhere but if it's anything else
they're not so happy
that's was the attention enough