[Music]
you know no no - the child they normally
would be replaced the prophetess turn us
into karate demand rain medicine demo
pseudo poverty spattering they were
simply genetically mediated the ProQuest
was in Jerusalem and she I'm so happy
that in Italy people have so much
respect for my dear mother and also for
Madonna surprising why they did not
describe about Christ's mother in the
Bible the last words spoken of Christ
where he say behold the mother in all
other scriptures of the world this
primordial mother is respect and
everybody has talked about that that
she's the power she's the ship
[Music]
[Applause]
I think it's it's a little fragile it
was it was repaid by misogyny and
repainted it is said that
in the ten commandments whatever is
created by the heavens and by the earth
should not be recreated and reproduced
and worshipped so the incarnations are
created by the heavens only in modern
times it is possible to take a
photograph of the incarnation but in the
former days there was no possibility now
whatever is created by the mother earth
is what has come out of the mother earth
which is the swayambhu is created by the
mother earth now we have everywhere we
find the same blue things
another thing is some realized Souls
also have made beautiful statue
there was one fellow in Russia supposed
to be very intelligent he said that all
right if we keep mother's photograph and
also the icons we can get the same type
of vibration you cannot because icons
are made by some artists imaginary these
are not representing actually even Maria
or Christ or anyone they are all all
imaginary if an Italian once makes
Christ he is Italian stuff he somebody
French one makes is thin like French if
you get somebody say from Holland he'll
have a forehead like that
you see all of them
they depict Christ as they want to then
we have Maria the same way
her expression her photograph everything
is all according to the imagination of
the artists and to whatever country we
belong that way and they are not free
you can see they are not free because
all these artists have a certain style
now if it is a Rembrandt it's a style if
it is a Leonardo it's a style though
they are born realized still they have a
style nobody is like this that he make
today like these tomorrow like this
there's no freedom
they are bound by their own styles
everybody has one style and that is the
style they follow because what is that
his reason is they must have done three
four times style type styles must have
done sure but people must have rejected
this is no good this is no good so it's
all to see opinion of the people so they
must have taken to one style all right
this is the stand so you can see Christ
if he's Japanese
he'll have [ __ ] eyes
if he is Chinese she'll have no nose if
it's Indian he'll be doubt so all kinds
of crisis II and I feel that how can
they emit vibrations tell me while with
my photograph our cunning company now
when we say that we should not worship
in the Bible it is written that we
should not worship anything that is
reproduced and created by the mother
earth and the heavens now what is it
what is it created by the mother earth
and by the heaven which we should not
reproduce this nobody tried to find out
they think that you are not allowed to
worship any form it's all
misinterpretation it's completely
misinterpretation I'll tell you very in
Paris a church called what is it called
them or not reserved and the under
statue of Mary and Christ is celebrating
from outside you can see the vibrations
are coming out now this must have been
made by some very great artist who was a
realized soul
for example the Sistine Chapel ego has
got a very beautiful frescoes of Christ
and all that and if you see that Christ
I mean it's absolutely vibrate but down
below there's a big table on which to
have put Christ just very miserable
creature which is never near Christ I
mean it's impossible that Christ would
be like that so miserable ugly looking
thin burnout hopelessness
how can he be Christ I can't understand
he carried a complete huge big cross
upon himself do you think these bowls
could have can and this was placed just
below where Sistine Chapel you find the
Christ and energy boy how can it be
also the mother of Christ is always
shown as a fat person modern fashion
that should become like a mosquito you
will go is a famous painting Mona Lisa
he was a very fat is all the trace of
the intervenors you are playing into
they are making a fool out of everyone
the divine personality needs water to
protect the center I'll do an example of
Mona Lisa if you see Mona Lisa I mean I
don't know she cannot be an actress she
cannot win any beauty contests I think
she her face is very serene very
motherly very pure her eyes and why is
it that she's eternally so much
appreciated the reason is there is
Ganesh impersonator
she's a mother and the story about that
one is that this lady had lost her child
and she would never spoil she would
never cry and one little child was
brought to her when she saw the child
then the spine that came on her face of
that love for the child is being
depicted by this great artist and that's
why people are appreciating it and you
have seen in the West though the people
don't show much interest in the mother
child relationships anywhere you go is
the mother and child theme is the best
they'd show you photograph this is
mother and child this is Christ mother
and child when the Christ was brought
down the mother is there they have to
have mother and her child
principal acting otherwise that picture
is not regarded as something great or
you have to have actually Christ who is
a Ganesh principal himself to be sure
he wants to know about the appearance of
Holy Mary for example in Fatima on other
addresses mitre is quite possible you
see one of my photographs where people
are taking photographs and she's there
she's appeared before me also it's
possible I went to Portugal and they had
a festival of the Lady of the rocks so I
went to see that place and there was a
very small little statue of this diamond
height of the middle about say five
inches and the face was just like mine
exactly like mine they said that this
was found suddenly by two children who
were following a rabbit which hid inside
a niche so these children saw some light
inside the niche and they started
following under a rock and they reached
the source of the light was the statue
they brought it out and in that light
they walked and when the people outside
where lots of people were gathered they
were amazed to see that they brought out
the statue from somewhere inside so they
worshiped that that statue in that place
now please think these statues give you
vibrations as I give you vibrations but
not so much as I give it and all the
other statues also there may be many who
might be giving you vibrations and also
there was an operation of her first I
never believed that it could be but then
after feeling the vibrations now I know
it was true that she did appear here in
an operation she appeared before me also
you must have seen
in a photograph of course I like
paintings very much up for a file
specially because he has drawn the
mother's face and the child's face so
exactly expressing the feeling of mother
entity and imagine that picture appears
in the sky and I didn't tell them to
show that the father when I was sleeping
I was not even going to look at it but
at this time the hollow that was on the
backside of Bailey comes up on the head
in Suffern himself innate or I don't
know how can I explain this
paramchaitanya is doing all kinds of
things and it does all these just to
convince you about sahaja yoga we have
seen photographs of angels around me so
try to be simple innocent not reacting
and keep quiet and peaceful because here
we are talking about the global
transformation where people will find
their peace in that heart and will
establish a new world of peace joy
spirituality
[Music]
[Applause]