Now I think I have covered most of the points.
But if you have any question, you can ask them today.
Q.; “Shri Mother, we feel the same chakras,
more on legs than on the fingers.”
The integration is not there, that’s why.
You have to attend collectively.
You have to be more collective. The body has to be collective.
The thing is that if you are not a collective person
then sometimes you’ll feel them on the legs,
sometimes on the hand, sometimes in the head.
That’s not a good thing.
You should try to be more collective, you should
meet more people, take more interest.
You see, the body of your’s
want work out efficiently unless and until you use it.
Because individually you see if they individually if you work out,
it will not develop collectively, because where are you using it?
You are correcting your self to give it to others.
And if you don’t give it, if you do not work it out
in a collective way, there is no circulation.
For example, there’s a fruit is there,
and you take it out of the tree, and you mature it.
But if it is connected with the tree,
it will mature by itself giving a proper identity to itself
and to the tree, and taste would be better.
And those who would come under that tree
will receive the fruits of that tree.
But a fruit, which is separated, will be lost after sometime.
That is how one has to be very collective.
Q. How to develop our discrimination, Mother?
Discrimination comes through Hamsa Chakra.
And Hamsa chakra is very simple thing,
is to put some ghee in the nose,
is a physical thing.
On the emotional side, one should not cry too much.
Or women specially have too much crying business.
I also sometimes feel like crying, but seldom.
So sometimes men must cry also.
Now spiritually, to develop discrimination
is by vibratory awareness.
When your vibrations are developed,
then you automatically discriminate.
You are such a big computer.
It has to work in its full way, and
then you’ll be amazed what a computer you are.
I’ll give you an example of Warren now.
Pat’s husband Prole, who was
measuring my house for certain purpose,
while Warren was sleeping. Poor David was working,
Warren was sleeping.
And in his dream, he dreamt that he had finished
with the last measurement.
And in his half-sleep he got up
and he told him that this house measures...how much?
Three thousand nine hundred and sixteen square feet.
And ‘exactly’ that’s what David Prole had written!
Poor David had worked so hard measuring everything!
He actually fell from his chair!
You see.
Like today I told Guido that I think
I spent three hundred and eighty pounds.
And he said, no it was three hundred.
I never calculated, nothing. I just said it.
And by calculation, it was 379, according to him,
but I gave him one pound more!
So it was 380. And that’s how you become a computer.
All mathematics comes through your brain. It’s so dynamic.
But first of all you have to have concentration,
concentration of your devotion.
Such a person achieves that.
There are so many blessing waiting for you, to be manifested.
Just you have to concentrate
your efforts in devotion and dedication.
May God Bless You.