so today that this was eve
Should say tonight is the
Christmas eve and we are all here
we have to
Understand that now we have really
entered into the era of Jerusalem
and where
[you're] [pete] in such a way that
we can understand the
[great] incarnation of Christ
so far
He was never understood
Because it was a very subtle incarnation
and that
Has made people go much away from him
From the principle of which he was made the innocence
So today we have to remember how incarnated on this earth
the innocence the auspiciousness
which was filled by
Adi Shakti to begin with him when she started to create this universe
[that] he was the embodiment of
All that which was so necessary before [the] creation started
It's hard to understand how [people] could not feel it
They all have suffered so much
Whatever it is for the divine. [they] do not suffer
And they come on this earth to show how stupid we are
How we have not being ever see the truth to see the reality?
But we repeat the mistakes again anything
Because we do not know ourselves
Which is the only instrument by which you can know the divine
And when we do not know ourselves
We cannot understand the divine
Still it's such a great thing to see so many of you are
there in that circle area oh
the Spirit
That you have the sensitivity
That you can feel the beauty of their lives
greatness the purity the innocence of the
These great incarnations who came on this earth
but without [that]
We have a very great responsibility awesome
Christ had only [12] disciples
Who didn't even get their realization deep fry sleep?
Afterwards they got realization
[Turner] of them
And he might give somebody like Thomas is [going] to India
So how they took so much responsible. They are just ordinary fishermen
They can care for anything else, but they thought this is the truth and that we have to
Spread this this is their responsibility
We are so many
That is our responsibility. It is not only to enjoy yourself
but to spread sahaja yoga
And practice it
Moreover you have an idea
Life that people could see us. How we behave how we talk?
How we treat each other how we love each other?
How we understand each other how we run to help each other?
like one body
the message of Christ's
Life is love
He openly talked about
Before that, I don't think any incarnation talked like [that] in that Manner
So openly he told his disciples that the greatest joy for me is to see that you love each other
all those things that have really made
Our society made our lives [was] never
after and pettiness
Small-Mindedness has to go otherwise. You are not sahaja Yogi's
Where is the time for Jealousy? There's no mind is?
That gal see those things anymore
All of us have to evolve and the sign of evolution is not how much we can talk about sahaja yoga
How much?
we can
Practice [say] Yoga how much we spread Sahaja yoga?
That's not the side don't be convinced by that
But the sign of Sahaja yoga is that how much we can love each other?
How much we understand each other?
how much we
[can] endure for others with great Joy and
How much we do not bother about ourselves?
[our] families our children
This is mine my me first
He doesn't go by saying go it's a state again, but then only [you] should be convinced now I
said
[I] said love thy neighbor as thyself I would say
that
you have to love every sahaja Yogi as
Yourself because they are part and parcel of this body
You cannot afford to
hate someone of course those who are
Useless I've thrown out of the world
But those who are there living you must love them [I]?
Think this is the message of Christ
And other message is absolute morality
accident morality
As you said that thou shalt not have adulterous. Eyes is such a subtle thing to say that
[you] should not have eyes it have [adultery] [thing]
It doesn't mean only for women, but it also mean for things
It also means for properties it also means for the success of others
Energy means the one where you try to aggress and to be greedy Amar
if there is greed
Or if there is lust in your eyes
Then it is another precise
It is very subtle. I know it is very subtle and attention
Is the best way which communicates to you whether [you're] about?
[lust] and region or not
But the more you try to rise [above] these things
the Heart Opens I
Start in [you're] [virtuous] [Moron] to enjoy
You don't take your money don't think that we?
But you enjoy that state when you are really moral because you are more
Just [enjoy] [yourself]
It's a headache to be interested in some woman Justin in some man. It's a headache the joyless pursuit
And once it does
The Joy is obtained
Because you are one with reality your reality there is no
inhibitions no restrictions no taboos nothing, but just you are that
Nobody has to tell you
If you are gold, you're gold
Nobody has to tell you now you don't behave like non gold you are gold soon your world
That's the power
And the power of a sahaja yogi, is that is the purest form of human being?
Without the power. What are you nothing?
the purest form and the purest form
[of] love
You get the purest form [of] knowledge
This is [cable]. It's the
Absolute
knowledge
and
Absolute now
attached the [oh]
that time when you [are] in that state
You just watch anything see anything
all the
power of giving you joy from everything
just start bubbling into you, and you don't see the bad things [of] [are] you nervous about the
Power of enjoying everything is the power of Sahaja Yogi's enjoying?
Anything can [we] enjoy?
Any small tea can we join?
Any big thing can make life, but impurities what your knowledge?
Immorality you cannot enjoy
It's not enjoyment it just a fascination. Maybe I don't know what it is called as
So I cannot enjoy them so I don't know what it is
but what you are really is the purity of another personality the purity of
this all that is done by someone it's a pure heart and
the Deeper you see
It becomes simpler and simpler then you don't say smart things. No, you don't don't have to
Show nothing
This is Simple street nice things
It's so touching
so beautiful
but
Must allow the deeper
Love within an Astra coma
Many people love also, but they don't know how to express it
Many people who are misunderstood because they don't know how to express that?
Inside yoga you have to learn the you clean
the technique
It [Lt]. Is a it is a very sweet. Word knot technique is not
Technically you see something anybody released
But you can use the click
typically
what to say [when] that really just fierce
Okay, or like [a] dot in the heart of someone a beautiful feel
that one has to understand and practice a
Little Little things here and there
This is turning here and there then the art of giving a sahaja Yoga [lila]
And I see children sense of street sweet things
That's why Christ has said that you have to be like children
To enter into the kingdom [of] God, but I would say to stay in the kingdom of God
You have to be simple actually
D and signal
this
Seminar or whatever you may call it empathy blair to know what [the] call [is] the divine
Congregation of all the gods and goddesses
Is very symbolic to me?
Because this represents
the Whole World
it presents the problems of the old one and
also [captions]
such a
Beautiful idea. [I] don't know how it worked into my head that I started this kind of her beautiful
congregation to which your
It was very nice yesterday. You kept away from the white and came to see me. I could meet all of you and
I could have some [rapport] [who'd] say much
I could was just smiling at you, but just I could express my now and you gave me that [chance]
I was thank you very much for that