[HINDI - Sit down]
[MARATHI - Sit down, sit down]
[HINDI - Sit down, please]
I'll speak, I'll speak later on.
They will sing 'Jogwa'
Just I'll explain. Jogwa you're going to
sing, na - I'll explain to them.
SY: Yes, Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji: [MARATHI - STOP?]
I'm happy you're enjoying this music and
they want to give you, render some more
because I think, Philip has already explained,
Interpreter: [GERMAN]
Shri Mataji: so I don't have to talk too much then.
Shri Mataji: This Jogwa they are singing,
is a song written about 16th century
by a poet called Namadeva
Interpreter: [GERMAN]
Shri Mataji: and he was a tailor and he
went to see another saint, who was a potter
Interpreter: [GERMAN]
Shri Mataji: So when he saw the potter,
he just stood silent and he said,
in Marathi language it is, 'That I came to
see the Formless,' that is the vibrations,
'I came to see the vibrations but here,
I find vibrations in Form."
[INTERPRETER - GERMAN]
Shri Mataji: So, what an appreciation of another
saint; Only a saint can do that, real saint.
[INTERPRETER - GERMAN]
Shri Mataji: So the saintliness is a state
- you cannot certify it. It's a state.
[INTERPRETER - GERMAN]
Shri Mataji: So you have to be, you'll be listening
to this song, which was written by Namadeva
and later on he went to Punjab and also, at that
time, Gurunanaka saw another saint coming in.
[INTERPRETER - GERMAN]
Shri Mataji: So he said that, "Now you're
such a great saint and such a great poet,
so why don't you write in Punjabi
language?" So he studied Punjabi language
and wrote a big book, in Punjabi
language, of lots of poetry in it.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So the scriptures of Gurunanaka,
which He has all the, He's compiled all the
poems of the poets, of who were saints at
that time, is called as 'Guru Granth Sahab'
[INTERPRETER]
What is the name?
Shri Mataji: Guru Granth Sahab. Granth Sahab
is the one, which is, which is the
Holy Scripture for Sikhs.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Hmm, and in that He has put
Namadeva's poems also and that of His maid
servant, who was another saint, Janabai.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: In this song he's saying that,
"O Mother, I'm asking for yoga, for the
union with the Divine." Jogwa means,
"O Mother give me the yoga of the Divine."
with the Divine means, the union
with the Divine.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: I mean, Jogwa means yoga
Shri Mataji: Yoga and then he says that,
"I've given up all that is a temper, which
was my father-in-law," - like a lady he sings so.
"He was my father-in-law who was a temper,
I had uh.. attachments, who were my husband,"
like that, "I've given up all my relations to all
these things."
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Then in the thing he says,
"Now," - Amba is the Kundalini, so he says,
"Now rise the Kundalini - Uday, uday Ambe - Rise,
the Kundalini, rise - Uday, uday Ambe ho," like that.
So it's sung in the villages.
[INTERPRETER]
[INTERPRETER] should take off, take off
Kundalini [INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: And for so many centuries, they have
been singing in Indian villages, this song.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So because of the climate in
India, we were not so much bothered about
the outside projection but inside
projection. Climate is very good.
You can live in a village,
you can live in a forest.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So they were meditative and
were trying to find out what is within us
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So the knowledge of Sahaja yoga was
available long time back, since the time of,
we can say, since the time of Shri Rama, even
earlier than that people knew about Kundalini
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Even recently we had a big
film Ramayana. In that also they told how
Rama was told about Kundalini by his guru
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: But these gurus were realized souls.
They never took money, they didn't enslave people
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So like that, our country was
blessed by many real saints, very great saints.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: And they are not good at
Science, you can say, for the outward
side of it but the inward search
was very deep.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So you can imagine that
background is there already.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So for ages, they know about
Kundalini, they know that Mother has to do that job.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: But as we have learnt so much
about machinery and Science from you,
which is the knowledge of the tree, you have
to also know the knowledge of the roots
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: otherwise this tree will be lost
Shri Mataji: and it is so simple and so
spontaneous, as you saw it yesterday.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: You have worked with your
brains, now you have to work with your heart.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Now your brain has to love
Shri Mataji: That's what Sahaja yoga is.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: So, you can hear this song and with
this song, I'm sure, you all will get realization.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Just take out your shoes,
so that's all.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: And you have to clap with that.
You have to clap.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: And when they say 'Ho', you
too do the same way. That's all.
Shri Mataji: When they say 'Ho', you have
to also do the same. It will all work out.
I won't have to give a lecture.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Annh?(What?)
Baba Mama: The audience can't see us.
We will stand up and sing.
The audience can't see us.
Shri Mataji: No [MARATHI]
Some of you can stand. Some of you at the back.
No, not the musicians who are not singing
- some Sahaja yogis, who are not singing
can stand at the back.
[SAHAJA YOGA MARATHI SONG - Jogwa]
Shri Mataji: Village song of Kohlapur,
Kohlapur style
Kohlapur style, that one you sing
[UNCLEAR] you say 'Ho'
SY, Musician: It is coming
Shri Mataji: Annh?
SY Musician: It comes after, it becomes
Shri Mataji: Later?
SY Musician: [Bhakta Laguni Jogwa Maange
na Aaicha Jogwa, Aai ude de Ambe ude,
Aai ude de Ambe ude]
Shri Mataji: Village style you must sing,
village style
Baba Mama: Little faster
[SAHAJA YOGA MARATHI SONG - Jogwa]
[MUSIC]
Now, you just have to feel the vibrations.
Now let's see, how many of you can feel it.
Just put your hands like this.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: See the power of a saint
Shri Mataji: See.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: You are all very serious,
some of you. It's, it's fun.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Wrong ideas they have given you
about God. God wants you to enjoy everything.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Our religion is to know
ourselves and then to enjoy ourselves.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: You've seen little children
smile. They smile because their Spirit
smiles and laughs - very small children,
in their sleep.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Now just feel, if it is come
up on your head. Just see yourself.
Left hand towards Me and right hand - it's so easy.
Open your hearts, first of all, open your heart.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Now put the right hand
towards Me and see the left hand.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: Now, again with the left
hand and the right hand.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: You must smile otherwise
won't come up.
Shri Mataji: Alright, those who have
felt the cool breeze out of their head or
in their hands, raise both your hands.
Let Me see.
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: See, just imagine, all of you have
felt it. So, I think, now we'll spend the time.
Let them sing. You all can come and meet
Me here, so we'll have a nice family
gathering together.
[APPLAUSE]
[INTERPRETER]
Shri Mataji: [ASIDE - You put the thing
in front, just push the thing]
[MARATHI] you can sing songs.
Mahalaxmi Strotram.
SY: So we put it back anyway.
We put it more there.
Shri Mataji: I showed you
Ai Giri Nandini is good - also
Mahalaxmi Strotram is very good.
[MARATHI] And Ganesha's Stuti
is also very good. Ganesha Stuti.
You have got people from Switzerland
or not? Just bring it
SY: Can we start with Ganesh stuti, Shri Mataji?
Shri Mataji: Haan Ganesh stuti then Mahalaxmi
Little fast, it should be fast. And now, these
children have to get up because they have
to pass through this way.
Seeker: [UNCLEAR]
Shri Mataji: Ah, you come and sit on
top, here.You can sit here.
[INTERPRETER - GERMAN] Okay
[INTERPRETER - GERMAN] Thank you
[SHRI MATAJI WORKING ON SEEKERS]
SYogi: Some Sahaja yogis and some Sahaja
yoginis should come on the stage to
work on the people.
So please come up. Sit down on the stage. Not all
of you but some otherwise getting too crowded.
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
[SAHAJA SONG - Hemaja Sutam(Ganesh Stuti)]
[SAHAJA SONG - AI GIRI NANDINI - MUSIC]
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
[SAHAJA SONG - AI GIRI NANDINI]
[MUSIC]
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
[SAHAJA SONG - AI GIRI NANDINI]
[MAHALAXMI STROTRAM]
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
[MUSIC]
[SAHAJA SONG - MAHALAXMI STROTRAM]
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
Om Twameva Saakshat Shri Jagan Mata,
Mahalaxmi Saakshaat, Shri Nirmala Devi
Namo namah
Shri Nirmala Devi Namo namah,
Shri Nirmala Devi Namo namah
[MUSIC]
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
Musicians: Yes, Shri Mataji
SYogi: This song which we are going to sing
now, is about the seeker who has found the
Truth through Self-realization, so you should
all join in because you are part of them.
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
Better now?
[MUSIC]
SY: She's tired, headache and stomach problems
[SAHAJA YOGA SONG - Saat Janam
Jo Punya Kiye hain]
[Shri Mataji working on seekers]
[SAHAJA YOGA SONG - Saat Janam
Jo Punya Kiye hain]