Who are the new people today, for the first
time?
You?
I am sorry I had to say all these things because
today was the meeting of the Sahaja Yogis
in the beginning.
And we are all going to enter into the same
Realm and it will be handy for you to know
what is expected of Sahaja Yogis, and with
that expectation I request you not to pay
attention to what I have said, much.
You should not be frightened.
It’s not that frightening.
You’ll like it later on very much!
What I have said it, you see.
So come forward.
Those who have come for the first time, please
come forward.
You come for the first time?
All right.
Come forward!
Will be better idea.
No, no, here, on the chair.
On the first row of chairs.
Will be a good idea.
Yes.
Actually, it happens that your religion gets
enlightened.
You become that.
Then you can’t help it.
What to do?
I mean you don’t have to tell, “Don’t
do!
Don’t do!”
It just happens.
You just can’t do it.
It’s so helpful, isn’t it?
You don’t feel like doing it!
Because if you are enjoying your Spirit you
don’t feel like doing nonsensical things.
It is better to get it and see for yourself
what happens.
All right?
That’s the best way to give it a full chance.
Those who have come for the first time do
come forward.
You’ve come for the first time?
Please come forward.
No!
You are not for the first time!
Let her come forward here.
You are all for the first time here?
No.
You can go one step backward, is a good idea.
You see, you can receive my vibrations even
from there where Kingsley is.
Isn’t it Kingsley?
Aren’t you receiving my vibrations?
Much more!
Yes that’s it.
Now this is a system which is built within
us.
That’s why it is called as ‘Sahaja’.
This is what is the system within us that
exists.
‘Sahaja’ means ‘born with you’.
This is all born with you.
You have achieved it.
It’s all within you.
It’s a system that is built into this or
built into that.
In the same way it’s a system built into
you.
You are just ready.
You are to be put to the mains.
That’s all is the job is.
For putting to the mains also there’s something
built into you.
If you see the triangular bone called as ‘sacrum’,
means ‘sacred bone’, this Kundalini is
there.
This is the one that gives you your rebirth.
By rebirth what happens [is] that your awareness,
which is human awareness, becomes enlightened
by your Spirit.
Your Spirit comes into your awareness.
So far your Spirit is not.
Your Spirit knows all about you.
It is in your heart.
But you do not know about It.
So what happens [is] this Spirit, which is
enjoying itself, enlightens your awareness
and you get a new awareness by which you start
feeling a cool breeze in your hand, a cool
breeze in your hand.
And this cool breeze, for the first time,
on your central nervous system starts flowing.
So you feel it, actually you feel it.
Now the enlightenment takes place of all these
centres which are within you, which are there
because of our evolutionary process.
And these enlightened centres are on your
fingers.
They get enlightened too and you start feeling
them within you.
You start feeling your own centres and you
start feeling the centres of others.
Now this happening takes place within you
of the Kundalini awakening just to attract
your attention inside.
Because your attention is outside, you cannot
take it in.
You know many people think, “You put your
attention here, you put your attention there.
” – it’s all wrong.
It has to be spontaneously attracted inside
and it’s done by this Kundalini, and Kundalini
is just like a germinating primule within
us, a seed.
It just rises spontaneously.
And when it rises it breaks through here.
And this is what is the real Baptism.
You really feel it here coming out.
You can feel the cool breeze coming out.
You can feel the cool breeze from your hands.
This is real Baptism that John the Baptist
wanted people to have, and that Christ talked
about.
All the religions have taught us to be in
the centre.
When they said, “Don’t do this, don’t
do that,” they did not want to condition
us but to tell us that how we are going to
be in the centre.
And when we are in the centre then what happens
to us [is] that you get the desire to know
your Spirit.
And this desire is fulfilled through the awakening
of the Kundalini.
Now the Sahaja Yoga at this stage is really
a Maha Yoga in the sense [that] it is the
Great Yoga because many people can get Realisation.
Thousands of people can get it because the
blossom time has come.
But even if they get Realisation, they are
to be looked after, they are to be nourished,
they are to be told about it.
Everything should be decoded.
You will be amazed – everything becomes
so logical.
Gradually you start understanding it.
Your complete freedom is established.
Nobody says that, “Don’t do this!”
Nothing is said.
But you just don’t do it – yourself!
I will not tell you as Moses had to tell,
poor thing.
He had to face all the mad people.
But no, after Realisation it just happens
and you just don’t do it.
You will not do it.
It just happens to you.
It is nothing to be told.
It just happens.
It works out.
This is what is Sahaja Yoga.
In the beginning you have to be really ardent
Sahaja Yogis.
In the beginning you have to be.
It’s the beginning of Sahaja Yoga still
in England, I would say.
Really ardently attached to it by which you
develop yourself very well and develop this
tree of Sahaja Yoga in your own country.
Because you have to save so many.
The Last Judgment has started.
It’s started.
Through Kundalini awakening only you judge
yourself.
You know what are the centres you are catching,
what are your problems.
You know what are the centres others are catching.
You judge yourself.
Supposing a person comes and tell me, “Mother,
my Agnya is very bad.
” Do you know what it means?
That, “My ego has developed.
” But [if] you tell somebody, “You have
got an ego.
” – you will have a punch on your head!
But the person himself comes and says, “Mother,
I see my ego.
” You start seeing yourself.
You start seeing your problems, because you
are out of it.
And then you can cure it also and make it
better.
You improve it and you are better.
You judge yourself and you judge yourself
with love and understanding.
You don’t hate yourself by that.
It’s only you, yourself.
You are going to judge.
Within you is the power of God that judges
you, is the Spirit which tells you.
A rapport is established with the Spirit.
The Spirit itself will tell you, “This is
the mistake, this is the problem.
” We don’t need anybody to tell us.
It’s only you who will know.
It’s only you who will judge yourself.
It’s only you who will grow yourself.
It’s your own freedom.
It’s your own Self.
Your entire personality changes, entire personality
changes.
I have never told anybody not to take drugs
as such, except for one or two people who
were still carrying on.
But also very mildly.
And I told them how to get rid of it.
But you just don’t want to take them, just
don’t like it.
You find it very filthy.
You feel like vomiting.
Just like that, the religion is enlightened
in your stomach.
That the time has come now for you to do it.
That was the time when it was not so [then]
they taught you how to do it.
But today the time has come, it can work out.
You are all just there.
The completion of the whole creation has to
come this way.
It has to work out.
But you cannot reason it out.
But once you get it – because it’s beyond
reason, it happens beyond reason; the Kundalini
awakens not by reason, spontaneously, by master
only – once it happens then the whole thing
becomes logical.
You see, there’s a microscope, then you
can see through it.
But if there is not a microscope, you cannot
understand.
The ‘microscope’ is your Spirit.
It’s very simple.
Now, I do not want to go into details about
it.
I think these people have been given…
Gavin have you given them the papers and things?
Let them see for themselves.
Have you all got the papers?
Have you got?
No?
Let her have.
Let this lady have.
You sit a little erect, all right?
Straight, sit little straight.
All right.
You have to sit a little erect, not much,
but a little erect.
Not slouchy.
Neither like this.
Just sit straight.
Put your hands like this, all of you.
Just put your hands.
Now close your eyes.
Put your feet like this, little straight,
on the ground.
Not pressing much but they should be on the
ground properly.
Come in!
Come!
There are three, four seats.
Here, in front.
Yes.
After Realisation you have to go very fast
and try to understand it, otherwise you may
lose your vibrations.
That happens with some people.
So be careful!
It’s a very, very delicate thing; it’s
very subtle.
And because we are gross – suddenly we become
subtle – if we do not catch up to it, we
lose it also.
So for one month after Realisation you have
to be very, very careful and get hold of another
Sahaja Yogis here and we also have an ashram
here.
We have to work it out.
Close your eyes.
Just close your eyes.
It just works.
Don’t think about it.
Don’t think.
It will work out without thinking.
Put both the hands towards me, please.
Both the hands like this.
One of the centres that is catching in most
of you is that you all feel guilty for nothing
at all, for nothing at all.
It’s a fashion to feel guilty.
So everybody starts feeling guilty for nothing
at all.
Or maybe we confess and this and that.
Now I have to tell you that not to feel guilty
at all.
Say that, “I am not guilty.
”
Thrice you say, “Mother, I am not guilty.
This is also a myth that you feel guilty.
That will help you a lot.
Once you get your Realisation you have to
also have the spiritual education to know
how to handle this, how to handle this power.
You are getting it because this is your own
right, but you must know what
you are getting.
They’ve got it, all of them.
All the Sahaja Yogis should receive vibrations
and expose completely with their heart, absolutely.
Just put it.
Be meditative today.
And you have to promise in your heart.
You have to be much more active and ardent
about Sahaja Yoga if you have to save your
brothers and sisters.
Only your heart can be binding, nothing else.
Nothing else.
It’s only your heart.
As you are attached to someone you love, you
should be attached to your Spirit.
Spirit you should love the most.
Nobody is more important than your Spirit.
Are you feeling any cool breeze in the hands?
Not yet?
Close your eyes.
Have patience with yourself.
One has to have patience.
Close your eyes.
Have patience!
Just don’t think.
It will work out.
Have patience with yourself!
You put both the hands towards me, not meeting
each other but towards me, separate.
Put both the hands separately, not towards
each other but towards me.
Please put them towards me.
Yes.
Close your eyes.
And just leave it.
Don’t think about it.
Don’t worry about it.
It will work.
It’s like just a flower becoming a fruit
– spontaneously.
Just close your eyes and put your hands towards
me.
Put your attention to your heart.
Catch the joy part of it.
Just heart.
Just put your both the hands towards me only
and just pay attention to your heart.
It will work out.
Are you feeling cool breeze?
It’s good, great.
Just enjoy it.
Just enjoy.
Do not pay attention in one particular direction.
Just leave it free.
Do not fix your attention anywhere.
It will work out.
Gavin, organise for these people behind.
Ask people to slowly come along.
Keep your eyes shut.
All new people please keep your eyes shut.
They are going to check you.
One by one, yes move on.
Jill, come forward.
Start moving in the centre.
Yes.
Good.
Those Sahaja Yogis who want to get themselves
also checked up, ask other Sahaja Yogis to
do it.
Magda, I think these three people are for
the first time or what?
Just see them, their vibrations.
They haven’t felt it yet.
Can you move a little coming up here.
Marcus?
Or who is there?
Those who want to be checked.
Also ask others to be checked.
Douglas, go and check Dinesh.
All of you must get checking!
Those of you who want checking should raise
your hands.
Ask people to check you.
Check her.
Vishuddhi, Left Vishuddhis are horrible.
I don’t know what to say.
Hester [Spiro], you ask somebody to check
you also.
Peter [Pearce], you sit down.
David [Spiro] you sit down!
Get yourself checked!
Linda [Pearce], Peter, all of you.
Please.
Because I am going away.
Let everybody be checked – better is.
Marcus?
You be checked also.
Better to get it done once for all.
Get them checked.
Who can check her?
Ray [Harris]?
Where is he?
Go and check Hester.
He’s got it?
Kingsley you check Hester, it’s better.
He (Ray) is a Jew (also) so it would be better!
(laughing) Somebody else should do it it’s
better.
May God bless you!
But everybody gets checked it’s better!
John, you sit down.
You get yourself checked.
Sit down.
Marcus?
Is he checked?
How are they?
Now those who are checking should get themselves
checked also, is a better idea.
There should be nothing.
‘Prana’ – say the mantra for him.
For her, Malcolm [Murdoch], ‘Prana’ is
the mantra for her.
Haa!
Done.
Just broken through.
Haaa!
Now this is to be judged a little by yourself.
You should know.
These are the small things that one should
know.
This gentleman?
Why don’t you see this gentleman?
Can you check John.
John, put your left hand towards me and right
hand outside.
Felicity [Payment].
Somebody should check Felicity also.
Brighton people should again get themselves
rechecked afterwards.
Everybody should get themselves rechecked.
Somehow or other get yourself cleared out.
Every one of you.
Gavin you also get yourself checked.
Everybody should get yourself checked.
That’s the best way.
And we should be thankful to people for checking
us and giving us vibrations.
Instead of getting angry and upset.
How are the children?
Jane [Brown] bring her.
Is she alright?
Bring her here.
How is it?
Let everybody check today
and give bandhans.
What about this gentleman?
He’s got it?
He’s Ray’s father, he should get it.
Tell him not to feel guilty about anything!
You are facing Mother who loves you!
Just say, “Mother I am not guilty.
”
Just say that.
What guilt can you people have?
Jill?
Coming?
Haaa!
Alright Jill?
It’s come up.
How is she?
Don’t talk.
Just raise the Kundalini.
You give him a bandhan.
Chaya, tumse karab dekho.
Regis, you also get yourself checked and others
should check and you check others.
Every one of you.
John, please put yourself into a bandhan.
Now check other people.
Come along.
Those who have been checking sit down and
those who have to be checked.
You’ve done it?
Have you done?
You’ve got it?
Have you felt anything?
Did you feel any cool breeze?
Good, great.
Now close your eyes.
Enjoy your Self.
Now don’t stop at that!
What do you say Malcolm?
Better?
What about this child?