From yesterday's program and all these days
we must have realized that to get your Kundalini
working out, to get Her rush towards the Sahasrara
and to widen your Shushumna Nadi it is not
necessary that you should sit for meditation
for 3 to 5 hours. Of course, you must meditate
for a short time because that is at a point
where you are alone one with your God. But
otherwise in the collective when you emerge
into it then the Kundalini rises the same
way. It's a very discrete way of understanding
what happens. In the collective when you are,
you compensate each other, compliment each
other and the subtler side of the cosmos starts
manifesting in you. Then if you could really
emerge there is a word 'emerge' in Sanskrit
language or in Marati language is very good
is [Ramamana?]. I don't think emerging with
joy but there is no 'with' you see, emerging
into joy. So if you can emerge into the joy
of anything that is Sahaj you can become a
meditative personality. You can achieve that
meditative mood within yourself. With that
mood, with that force, new subtler dimensions
start breaking out within you. Your different
kind of conditionings, which are like, shackles
binding you down, just open out and you become
a free person - 'Bandhamukta'. With that force
everything breaks, your ego breaks, your conditioning
breaks and you become one with the joy of
life, divine life.
This you can experience but to retain it within
yourself is only possible if you do your practices
in Sahaja Yoga. To control your attention,
to keep your attention to higher values, to
the higher things. Let us see what are we,
low value system that we get into
which is regarded as something very important
otherwise. The first in the modern times is
the consciousness of time. What is the time
now? What time we have to reach? Oh God what
is the time we are going to start it? What
time are we going to sleep? Now we have experienced
that yesterday we went home about 6 o'clock
and slept at 6 if we slept at all. You were
quite tired till 2 o'clock I think then that
Mumbai business started and you again relived
the whole sequence with a greater gust I must
say. So at that time those people who try
to keep dignity and try to keep out of it
are still keeping down their conditionings.
Supposing there is a man who is a governor,
for example, quite healthy, young can dance.
I mean old people need not do all that but
at least they can break through very well
into the barriers of conditionings. But such
a person start thinking what's this going
on and oh, nonsense, how can I join this?
It looks very rustic, sometimes looks something
not very decent, decorous, looks like a world's
mud. It's extremely natural and child like,
innocent. You can make out the people who
are still in the barrier. They even find it
difficult to say Jai Mataji! Such people are
still bound down by the shackles of the worldly
life.
Then they are all the time, seeing the time,
what is the time? And again getting a headache
and such time you should never see the time.
Because you will get a headache if you see
it, realizing it’s very late you see, and
oh God, it's 4 o'clock we are still here.
So it is important for all of us not to have
any watches, even if we have, not to see them.
Or even you see them they should be stopped.
So you go beyond time. You go beyond time.
You don't feel the time. You don't feel the
tiredness of time and you just forget yourself,
which is tied down by time all the time.
Now then the second one is we talk so much.
Oh we should have no religions, no jati, no
[party?], like that we say, all of us, you
should have no caste system, the Indians especially.
The caste system is the curse. People will
talk like that and when it comes to their
daughters' wedding they will not go beyond
their caste. Caste system is bad. Your religion
is bad, this is bad, that bad but when it
comes to actual understanding of religion,
you can easily scratch them and find out from
where they come. Once all conditionings of
so called religions
and this has to be broken completely because
they are all false, based on something solid.
Supposing you have a very solid foundation
on that you put up a house of, say pack of
cards, like they say, how long it is going
to last? If you go to the foundations you
find all the foundations are just the same
but these pack of cards are different and
they are the greatest delusions for human
beings which I've seen everyday, in every
religion, in every country, in every caste
but still we are frightened of something nonsensical,
something historical or I don't know what?
We don't want to give up that. That shows
another very big binding force to very low-grade
life. I mean, say two caste people meet, same
people, how will they talk? Oh so you are
of the same caste you see. Then you must be
knowing this man, yes, yes, yes, my father's
brother's, this thing, this thing in Marati
this thing called [Sat ka. Sat lakia Sat ka?]
(Shri Mataji is talking in Marati)
like that. Oh, so you are the cousin sister's,
this thing that thing, real husband?
And such terrible talks. I don't know, they
go on for hours together and then I don't
know what is the satisfaction out of it. Then
ultimately they this this they they find out
sometimes or mostly that both of them are
related to a [decoit? decoy?] or a thug or
some sort of a bankrupt or some sort of a
horrible man and then they recede back. Then
they don't want to show any relationship.
So this kind of a nonsensical talks, for example,
if the ladies meet oh, they will say, where
did you buy this Sari? I bought it there.
Oh, I went there how much you pay it? She
said this, such waste of time, goes on, on,
on, on and on. The whole life is wasted in
such a low-grade understanding of life's swell.
Then they will also talk these and do this
and I mean you can build upon that, all the
filth. It's something like the fungus growing
from the dead with little heat the fungus
starts growing, mutation takes place and the
fungus becomes an aggressive and can become
cancerous, this that and the same way all
these low grade life starts.
Then this low-grade life can extend in every
walk of life, like politics, economics, everywhere,
because it is like plastic. Plastic can get
into cloth, can get into trees, can get into
everything. In the same way this horrible
low-grade business goes into these various
things and a person can not rise above this
built in plastic bondages we have. At this
time when we have such kind of programs everything
breaks off and you really dissolve into the
love of God. There are so many other mundane
things if you see how people talk and how
they joke and all that. You think its all
filth going around you, slowly, you will gradually
recede from it. That is how you prepare yourself
for retaining this joy within yourself.
Now we are coming at the [fag?] end of our
tours and when you will be going to your countries,
you should see for yourself what's happening
around and just laugh and get out of it. You
have to remember those beautiful days in Ganapatipulle
and you have to get into that mood and know
that you belong to the kingdom of God. I know
we had very little time to talk but music
was even better. I could communicate better
through music to you. I am working on you
all the time. But still there are some people
who are caught up. I will request you for
all the leaders who find out there are any
caught up people in their groups. Please don't
call them for the Pujas. They should be kept
back if you think they are not all right.
And they should not also feel bad because
they will be helped, they will be helped much
more if they don't come to the Puja.
So tomorrow is a great day for our Puja. I
hope it will be convenient for all of you
to come and be seated here. I think tomorrow
before coming to the Puja don't talk too much
and don't discuss too much. I think you must
have had enough discussions today and have
reached some conclusions. I would like to
know if some questions were not answered.
If there is any I would like to answer them
now and after that we start our program for
5 minutes is sufficient for answering, all
answered? Is there any questions that was
not answered? Please stand up, I can't see.
Is there anybody? Oh, ho, that's Sahaj. Sahaj
people have no questions. They have to only
answer.