I bow
to all the seekers of Truth
and the Truth
that we are seeking
has to be achieved,
understood and felt
through a very open mind.
You cannot conceive the Truth
with your mental activity,
and you cannot form your own ideas and conventions
about it.
Like a scientist,
you have to keep your mind open
to achieve it.
Moreover
it is an evolutionary process,
the process
by which you have become a human being.
And logically, it should follow,
that you cannot put in any effort
to become the higher personality.
You have put in no effort
for your evolution so far.
Thirdly,
you have paid no money
to become a human being.
God doesn’t understand money.
This is created by human beings.
God has no sense of money
and He doesn’t know also, perhaps, how maddening it is
for human beings.
So you cannot pay for it.
It’s something ridiculous
to think that you can pay for your ascent,
or to say that you can go into a course
of realization,
because it is a living process
of your evolution – a living process.
If we understand the living process,
you will understand Sahaja Yoga much better.
If you have to sprout a seed,
you just put it in the Mother Earth
and She sprouts it.
How much money do you give Her?
She doesn’t understand money.
She only knows
how to sprout the seed.
So when you
put the seed in the Mother Earth,
it sprouts spontaneously, sahaja.
Saha means with,
ja means born.
It is born within you the capacity to sprout;
the capacity to awaken your Kundalini is born with you.
But it has to be
the Mother Earth who has to do the job.
Like every seed has
all the maps
of its past and all its future.
You have those maps within yourself
and once you just
become
capable of getting enlightened,
you get your enlightenment.
But we should not put any diffidence into your mind.
Many people start thinking
that you have to do the cleansing first,
and then you get realization.
When you are
inside the dirt, how can you cleanse?
So this Sahaja Yoga today is of this way
that first you get out of it,
first have a little light in your lamp,
The light is there and the lamp, if it is dirty,
it is easier to clean the lamp which is enlightened
than to clean a lamp which has no enlightenment.
That’s why first
you get your Self realization.
That is very important before
we deal with anything else,
that you must get your Self realization first.
This is what Christ has said that
you are to be born again.
He didn’t mean some sort of an artificial baptism. He never meant that.
How could He mean that?
Logically, you must understand, that if He was Truth
he would not tell that you can have a false
baptism.
But what He has said is that by this Spirit,
your Spirit will be awakened.
It means a person
who has got his Spirit enlightened
can enlighten
a light,
Or a candle which is already enlightened
can enlighten another light.
But what has it done? Nothing.
It had the light, the other one was ready,
so the light passes from one light to another.
There is no obligation,
there is no greatness about it, there’s nothing special done.
So as far as you are concerned, you are all ready
today to have your realization.
Many people I have met so far, in the West ‘specially,
want to escape the Truth
because they say that Mother,
we have to cleanse ourselves.
You go ahead with it.
How many years you have been doing that,
how many lives, how many ages?
Now stop it. It’s finished now.
Better have your enlightenment and then see how you can
very nicely clean yourself and see what’s wrong with you.
Moreover,
it is very difficult to tell anyone,
even if you see
the dirt in a person, that this is dirty.
It is better that, Supposing
there’s something wrong with this shawl.
I’d better take it out, see for myself what’s wrong with it
and I can cleanse it.
In the same way you have to get out of yourself,
to see for yourself what’s wrong with you
and that is how it will be much easier
for you to clean if you know how to clean yourself.
So you become the person
who is the Spirit.
The Spirit sees
the defects in you and the Spirit guides you
and cleanses you completely.
There is no more guide needed
or no gurus needed. You become your own guru.
So many kinds of people have come
to sell their goods in the market.
You cannot sell God
and the one who lives on your earnings is a parasite.
He cannot be a holy person or a saintly person.
Christ did not take any money from people did He?
He was born as a carpenter’s son
and He worked as a carpenter’s son.
But what is the purpose
of His advent?
What is the purpose of my coming to Boston is this:
that we all deserve
this higher state.
It is all your own. It is your right.
I should say I’m like a banker
and I have to cash your checks.
The purpose of this happening is
complete transformation.
The transformation has to take place.
What is the problem
of the world today is a moral crisis.
People are morally,
absolutely fagged out, tired.
They have lost all their discretion.
They don’t know what to do; they are so confused
whether this is true or that is true
because we live in relative world. Everything is relative.
This will do, that will do. Everybody’s compromising.
They don’t know what is absolute
because we have not achieved our absolute within ourselves.
Now the most remarkable thing
about the absolute, that is the Spirit is
that the absolute
is the one that is collectively conscious.
That’s the one that can feel
another person.
That’s the one which knows
about everybody else.
That’s the one which knows also about yourself.
So far as a human being,
the Spirit has not come into your consciousness.
It’s not yet enlightened, means
your consciousness hasn’t got the light of your Spirit.
The Spirit is in your Heart
and this Spirit is just watching you as a witness.
It has not entered
into your consciousness, into your attention,
and because of that,
you do not know what is absolute,
what is collective consciousness.
When it happens to you, it happens in your awareness.
It doesn’t happen in your mental conceptions like,
I can give you a big book to read
and then you become something great?
Your own consciousness,
which is a human consciousness,
becomes a higher consciousness,
which becomes collectively
conscious, means it is an actualization.
Like a person who is a human being
can feel the dirt and filth,
the colors, the beauty,
but an animal cannot.
So something is happening in our consciousness, actually,
that we can feel the filth.
In the same way, when you become absolute,
everything that is not absolute
starts negating itself.
It just disappears,
and you become absolute yourself, which is the Truth.
You become absolute joy
and you become absolute consciousness.
So far, the consciousness has moved to the human stage
in such a way that we have not felt
that we have moved higher
because we were not made like that.
At the human stage only we are made in a special way. If you see,
here as you can see it clearly,
that from the left side
there’s a blue balloon-like stuff rising.
This blue thing is nothing
but all of our conditioning’s
which becomes what we call
in Sanskrit as manasa,
but very closely we can call it as super ego
where we are conditioned: Don’t do this, don’t do that.
We are born, say, as Americans.
I mean it’s not true. You are a human being.
God never created America.
It is we who have created America,
England, these things.
He just created
one beautiful world.
So then you are Americans.
Identification starts like that.
Then you go ahead and you think we are
Christians or Hindus or Muslims.
Then you go ahead with that
and all these misidentifications start accumulating within us
and all of them form an artificial thing
called as superego in your head.
All the conditioning,
all the possessions, all the opposition’s,
all sorts of things that you gathered
in many lives can be there
called as superego.
On the other side we have got the ego,
the one that we
accumulate within ourselves or create within ourselves
by our activity
because we think we have done this,
is the ego.
Actually human beings cannot do anything.
What they do is to explore whatever is dead.
They cannot do living work.
They cannot transfer one flower into fruit,
even one flower into fruit.
All this living work is done by someone.
We do not think how we are created,
how this beautiful human being is created.
We haven’t got humility
to understand that this
something great has happened to us,
that there is some sort of a force,
some living force,
some very kindly,
loving force that has done this.
We never even felt how we were created like that.
Without any pains we are created as human beings.
This great living work
that is happening within us,
who has done this living work?
How has it come?
We have never felt that all-pervading
Power of God
that is doing all these things.
Not only that but
it sorts out things;
it’s such a beautiful mechanism.
Like a mango tree
will give you mangoes.
If it’s an ananas tree it will give you ananas.
Like that you have all kinds of different
sorting out to such an extent
that your child will look like you.
Who does all this sorting out?
All this Power that does
all the living work.
The scientists also have not done their [unclear].
They’re honest but they’re not so educated,
they’re not so well informed
and their seeking is very limited
because their brains are limited,
their mental capacity is limited.
If they have to go further,
they have to become higher personalities to be able to see
how we are created,
how do we exist and how this living force acts.
Now, for us,
as we take everything for granted.
We do not even think about it
is a good thing. Otherwise, we might go mad
thinking that we do not know about the Power
that does the living work.
So we have an idea that we do this work and that work.
What do we do? Supposing a tree is dead
we make this floor,
church, this, that – all stones.
It’s dead from the dead.
We have just changed the forms from dead to the dead.
What special thing have you done?
When we start thinking that we have done something,
that is how we develop an ego.
Like people going in an airplane were told
not to take too much luggage in a village.
They talked it’s better to reduce the weight
of the plane,
so they put the weight on their heads,
sitting in the plane.
In the same way we are putting the weight on our heads,
thinking that we have to do this job, that job.
The one who has created you,
the one who has made you a human being,
is going to make you higher.
Why do you take the load upon yourself?
That’s why Mr. Ego sits on your head
like a heavy weight, “I have to do this. I have to do that,”
without understanding the plan of the Divine.
That’s all we have, ego and superego sitting on our head,
and we start feeling
that we are something great.
Now this happening has taken place within us
because we are human beings.
A dog doesn’t have responsibilities as such.
Whatever he does he does through his responses
through its superego.
But human being has developed the ego
and because of that his brain is closed now.
He is like an egg.
Now this egg
has been ‘specially
made to become the bird
and that transformation has to take place
which is all built in within you.
You have all these powers within you.
It has just to be clicked
and the warmth
of the love
of the Divine has to work it out
so that you become the bird
of complete, absolute freedom.
This is what
Christ wanted to inform us
by His resurrection
and when we have
Easter you know that we have eggs.
The egg is suggesting
that you are the egg today
but on an Easter Christ, as He became the bird,
you also become the birds.
And so we should say the time has come for all of you
to become the birds.
But it is impossible for human beings
because they’re such made,
I don’t know how, especially in the West,
to understand that there could be somebody who is
genuinely interested in the well-being of others.
They cannot understand because of their
relative ideas.
They cannot understand that there should be someone
who should do this job;
who should communicate
with people who are seekers,
to give them their Truth
and to give them their transformation,
to put them up on
their consciousness
as realized souls.
Now, actually, in the movement of consciousness,
when human beings were born, what they started
sorting out everything on mental level,
everything on mental level.
And whatever works on a mental level
works out in a linear manner.
Like there is no sustenance in that.
If something starts moving in a linear way it falls off,
again recoils back.
That’s why today we are shocked.
We have evolved so much,
we have developed so much,
we are supposed to be developed people,
and then how is it we are on the brink of a shock?
Why are you so upset? What has gone wrong with us?
Where did we go wrong?
Because we tried to solve all our problems through mental efforts.
Anything – take your politics, take your economics
– is nothing but a mental effort.
For example, economics says that wants,
in general, are not satiable.
That means there must be some wants that are satiable
and we live in the relative wants which are not satiable.
Now what is that want
which is absolute, which will satisfy us?
And that want is represented here
as this triangular.
In the triangular bone you can see
the Kundalini that is the pure desire within you,
the pure desire to be one with the Divine.
Unless and until that desire manifests,
all your wants will be changing from one to another.
Like today, you would like to have a house,
tomorrow you would like to have a car
and day after tomorrow something else,
then a helicopter, then an
aeroplane – you can go on like that.
But actually to have
all your wants satisfied
there is one want
which is kept sleeping, as they say,
because it has not manifested in the triangular bone
which is to be awakened,
which is to be manifested.
Now, just imagine this bone is called as sacrum.
It means Greeks also knew that it is a sacred bone.
That is why they call it as sacrum.
You can see the rising of the Kundalini,
you can see the pulsation of the Kundalini, you can feel the
percussion of the Kundalini like,
“Lub, dub, lub, dub,” as the Heart is.
In some people it is quite a lot
and then you can feel the
cool breeze coming out of your head.
Now what is this Kundalini within us?
The Spirit is in your Heart
but what about the Kundalini? Who is She?
She is the Holy Ghost.
She is the representation or the reflection of the Holy Ghost.
But if you ask anybody else
they say, “No, we don’t know about Holy Ghost. It’s a mystery.”
In Sahaja Yoga, nothing is a mystery. Everything can be explained.
Now what is the Holy Ghost is?
The Holy Ghost is the primordial Mother.
It's the Mother, primordial Mother.
But people never talked about Mother.
They talked of the Father and the Son.
Now imagine, a father and a son and no mother.
It is absurd.
Have you seen any father and a son without a mother?
Such an absurd situation comes in
that people accepted
because it’s all mental. Somebody tells you, “No, it’s a mystery,
there’s no Mother,” and people accepted it.
But there has to be a Mother
and this is the time of Aquarius
what we call in Sanskrit as Kumbha,
meaning the Aquarius is the Kundalini,
where She nourishes,
where She cures you, She redeems you,
She guides you, counsels you
– and this is the time of the Mother.
We had the time of the Father, then of the Son,
and now this is the time of the Mother
where She has to nourish you,
where She has to take you
to your ultimate goal that is the Spirit.
The consciousness itself,
the way we have been moving in other directions, have been
like people think that if
a woman starts fighting for her life
and then she’s asserting the femininity.
She’s not.
What I’m saying is not
meant for women or men. It is meant for every one of us,
that we have to become like a mother.
Like a Divine Mother,
like a person who can nourish people,
who can give them love, affection,
attention, perseverance, forebearing.
This is only possible for a mother to do it
and that motherhood should be awakened in every human being.
I would say Abraham Lincoln you had
was a great person like that.
After that also we have had so many great people in this world
who have been like that. In our country we had Mahatma Gandhi.
We had many people of that temperament
who were soothing,
nourishing, curing
and helping others
in such a way as a mother
would like to nourish her own children.
So the sense of nourishment has to come within us
but we have no power of nourishment
and that only comes
when your Spirit starts manifesting through you.
When this Power rises, She manifests
Her power of nourishment.
She actually nourishes your chakras,
She’s the one who nourishes those subtle centers
which look after the gross centers,
She’s the one who cures,
She is the one who guides
because She informs you what’s wrong with you
and She’s the one who councils you.
Because once you become collectively conscious
then you start feeling the cool breeze in your hand
and this becomes like a computer.
You become a computer of which you become the master.
You are already a computer, if you understand,
because in a computer if you put something in it,
it cannot just see and say, it has to think.
But we can just see and say things.
As soon as you see, we know what it is.
So we are already a wonderful computer,
which no scientist can produce.
But we become even
conscious of that computer
and become master of that computer
so that we know everything about
whatever is not known to us unknown. All absolute problems
can be asked and we can find out what’s wrong with you.
But it is not that the consciousness moves like a pendulum.
Like a woman fighting a man
and becoming egoistical and fighting and shouting
and then behaving like a man.
Or a man becoming like a woman. It’s a pendulum.
But you move in a spiral way,
in a spiral way to rise higher
and that higher point you start seeing the things.
Like a spring has a spiral you have
seen and it has a sustenance within it.
It’s not linear.
When the spring loses its sustenance it has become linear.
Like in the peptones in the pancreas
are all spiraling…
and human beings, though they have created so many peptones
with all kinds of amino acids and all that put into it,
they are not even five percent
equal to what natural peptones we have.
But we make them linear by our wrong doings
and then the peptones become linear
and they lose their biological effects
because they become lifeless.
In the same way our ascent
takes place in a spiral way
and rises higher than ones where it is.
It doesn’t move like a pendulum: a man
becoming a woman, a woman becoming like a man.
But what happens is you develop a higher consciousness
and in that higher consciousness you start
understanding that now you have become the light.
Now what is the light?
Still you have to make the light, you work hard, you put it right.
But once it has made the light, you put it on top.
So it guides.
Then it becomes the guru,
it becomes the guiding factor.
It becomes everything. That’s how you become.
So we have got the left side of desire
and the right side of action.
These left side and right side of action can be compared
with the brake and
the accelerator in a car, to understand it on a very gross
example.
What happens that when we start
learning how to drive,
we get into the car,
we use both these powers,
trying to balance ourselves, first of all.
Balance the car is very important and
when we have learned how to use these two forces,
then we think we have become drivers.
At that time, we do it automatically.
We don’t think about it.
That’s what happens to you that first, when Kundalini rises
above this center, you become thoughtlessly aware.
That means there is no thought, but you are
completely aware and alert.
And when
this rises from here,
here is the seat of the Spirit though
the seat resides in human beings in the Heart.
When it touches the seat of the Spirit
then the master who’s sitting at the back seat
watching you,
you become the master
and you start watching these two forces within you,
how it is acting and also the driver
within you and you become the master.
This is the second stage into which you arrive.
Now when we
become thoughtlessly aware what happens is
that a thought rises and falls off
and another thought rises and falls off
and in the center of the two thoughts
is a little area.
Now these thoughts may arise
from the future or from the past
and the central part is the present.
So when the Kundalini rises
what happens is that you’ve become
stationed in the present
where there is no thought.
If I say you stand on the present you cannot be
because we are on the future or on the past
because there were thoughts.
But when the thoughts are removed you stand
in the center of those two thoughts
and you’ve become
thoughtlessly aware.
and this state
is such a wonderful state
that at that time whatever you see
becomes a picture memory,
not only as a memory,
but the joy of creation starts pouring into you.
You start understanding the joy of creation
and lots of powers you start manifesting
that at this time you can cure people,
you can heal them
– physically, maybe mentally also.
But that’s not enough.
In that also you should not get lost.
Some people do it by some other forces
which are spirits.
What they do is to put some spirits
into a person, take out some spirits,
transfer some spirits they do.
This is absolutely a different
area into which we don’t have to go.
We have to do everything
which is complete Spirit,
ourselves masters, knowing everything
about what you are doing.
We are never under the blanket, no darkness.
You see everything, what you are doing, what you are getting,
these powers that are flowing through your hand,
you know what exactly they mean.
They are all recorded for you,
you don’t have to research
it and you can only verify it.
Like the gentleman
who got his realization
from me and then he said,
“Mother, I can’t believe I can be collectively conscious
because you see the brains here are working a bit too much,
The Heart is less, the brain is too much.
There’s an imbalance between the Heart and the brain.
So I said, “All right, try with your brain.
By asking you can verify.”
He said. “I want to know -
“Please find out, how is the”
He said. “I want to find out: How is my father?”
I said, “All right, you just put your hands like this
and try to find out how is your father.”
So he says, “Mother, I’m getting a very
great heat here and it's burning, a very funny feeling here.
So I said, “All right, if that
is so, these are all the centers
that are indicating your father
and if it is in this
finger you are feeling,
then you must know that he must be down
with very bad bronchitis
because this finger denotes this center here.”
So he telephoned his father in my place
and his mother came to the phone and she said
he is down with very bad bronchitis
– The same sentence she used.
So that’s how you can feel it.
You must know that in the realm of God
we are really fantastic.
We have to enter into the realm of God,
we have to become the citizen of God’s realm.
Then only be amazed that He has
the greatest capacity,
that you cannot imagine how dynamically it is,
how it works. There have been so many
incidents in Sahaja Yoga
that people can tell you sometimes
how miracles after miracles have taken place
which they cannot explain how it has worked out.
Not miracles like getting a diamond and giving it.
One should understand that those people who go after diamonds
are not the people who are seeking God.
They want diamonds they can get it in the market.
Some people who start jumping, they think they have become godly.
How can it be? Are you going to become frogs now?
We should understand also
logically what is going to happen to us,
that we are going to be empowered by a power
which we should know how to handle.
Otherwise no use
doing all these tricks these days people are doing.
Some peoples are just jumping,
some start shouting, screaming, some becoming dogs,
some becoming like a lion.
You are not to go to your subconscious now
because God has placed so beautifully.
Your subconscious is on
the left hand side and your
right side is your future.
So there is a room kept for you in the center,
like you have made a home here,
like there was a room there.
But the idea of the psychologists here was so confused
that some of the Indians maybe have taken
a little clue from that,
and they have come here to take you down
to subconscious, which is the easiest thing to do
is to take down to your subconscious.
That’s what they have done.
They have mesmerized people,
started these cults and these false gurus have come
and they are just doing nothing
but taking you to your subconscious
where you get caught up and
possessed by the collective subconscious,
and you think you are in the best
position but you don’t know where you are moving.
You have no idea.
So the best thing for us is to see
what we get ourselves,
what we know ourselves.
Some people have given six thousand,
some people have given fifteen thousand.
But for what are you giving money?
It is something I can’t understand.
I came about ten years back
to your great country, America,
and they couldn’t understand me
when I said you cannot pay money for this
and they threw me out, you see.
They wouldn’t take me seriously.
They said, “Oh, what are you talking? It’s nonsense.
How can you do some things without money?”
So this is what it is. But I think after ten years
of good lashing from these people they have learned a lesson now.
They’re coming around and now they have been kind to me.
So you must understand one has to be humble about it.
It’s only the ego that makes you think that you can purchase God,
that you can organize Him,
that you can organize God, organize religion,
organize all that is Divine.
You cannot organize, as I told you,
the changing of one flower into a fruit.
Then it is, too much to think that you can organize thought.
We must humble down within ourselves and that’s how it works out.
It works out, it has worked in thousands
and should work out everywhere.
I’m sure in Boston also it should work out.
But there are categories and categories of people that I must admit.
For example, Steve, I must say, is a special category.
He met me only once in Bristol.
One program he had come, just as all you have come,
then he came to see me next day.
Actually person to person, he met me only once
and then he said he has to go to Boston.
I said, “A very good idea. Go to Boston
and I hope I meet you there.”
When I came to America
two years back he just sent me a telegram.
He said, “Mother, I’m in Boston.
Will you come here we’ll have a program.”
He was occupying a small little room
and sweetly
he invited me there and I said, “All right, I’m going to Boston.”
People said, “Mother, you don’t know
him very well.” I said, “I know him very well.
I’m going.”
I came here and we had a program in Boston and today
because of the quality of people who are running it,
we have a nice proper center
where now many people can get their realization and settle down.
But there are categories of very egoistical people also,
of very funny people.
Like some people in the church came
to hit me with the Bible. You can imagine
in the church they came to hit me with the Bible, no other place
and all such people are there.
But those people who are of that category
are the best who get their realization in no time and settle down.
Some people have physical problems
and that’s why also they cannot get realization.
But the people who have been to false
gurus and have bent their heads before them
also are very difficult.
They have to be a little
bit patient with them,
first of all, to neutralize the effects of this falsehood
and then they get realization.
But some of them – I was amazed the other day in Toronto
– I gave realization to some people
who have been to those gurus
and they just threw away everything
because they had reached the right
conclusion that they had not found the Truth
They had not found the Truth and
they had just thrown away everything apart
and they got their realization, too.
So we have people and people. We have people
who come into Sahaja Yoga all soft
and then they become very violent,
very hot tempered, they are
not so well organized and you find
that their temperament doesn’t look like a realized soul.
But all kinds of people come to Sahaja Yoga
and the negative people will always see
the people who are at the lower end and see them and start
criticizing or, “Look at him. He’s a sahaja yogi.”
A sahaja yogi is a person who has achieved a balance in them,
a person who has achieved a mastery over Kundalini,
the one who has all the knowledge how to raise the Kundalini
and how to give realization.
A sahaja yogi is not every Tom, Dick and Harry.
This one, one should understand,
but everybody comes to Sahaja
Yoga. Everybody is allowed to come.
We have all kinds of people, all types of people.
But the sahaja yogis are a special category
who mature
like a seed which is just sprouted, has to be looked after
very tenderly, carefully, respectfully
and then it grows into a big tree
and when it becomes the tree nobody has to be told,
you don’t have to tell them by oath that this is a tree.
Everyone knows this is a tree.
So this is how it works out:
Those people who are positive about it get it
into their heads, first of all,
and then into their Hearts.
I’m sure it will work out even here
and there are so many people here
it should work out with all of you.
I didn’t know that the program is only for two days. In any case,
two days I’ll be here, that is today and tomorrow.
In the short time whatever is possible I’ve tried to cover.
But it's, The knowledge is like an ocean.
But you become the knowledge itself
which I’ll tell you how you’ll become the knowledge
and you don’t have to listen to
too many lectures to understand me.
But as far as I am concerned
I’ve been lecturing and lecturing for the last ten years
and in London if you see there are thousands of lectures of mine
which you can see for yourself.
This happens much better in a place
where people are not so complicated. Thousands of
them can get realization. People who are here have seen
thousands of Indian villagers get their realization.
But maybe people are much more
oppressed by the
modern society, modern ideas.
Maybe that they take a little time to grow, but doesn’t matter.
You are people of great adventure
and people of great qualities.
You are saintly people,
you are men of God who are born in these countries, all over.
Even in England I saw so many people who are men of God
and as William Blake has said,
that Men of God will become prophets,
and they will have powers
to make others prophets.”
That’s what you have to have.
So many of you are saints, that’s why you are born
in such a nice country like America.
It’s such a highly blessed country.
Is such a great, beautiful country
and then you have to make the best out of it.
May God bless you.
If you have any questions, you can ask me.
Was that audible?
Seeker: I would like to know God
and I do pray to Him
and what you said right there that this is the Christ center here.
How long would it take for me to know?
Shri Mataji: Split of a second.
Split of a second. And
it will happen in a split of a second, no doubt.
But nothing is guaranteed.
You cannot say if all the seeds
will sprout at the same time,
but it is guaranteed that it will
ultimately, alright.
There is no time for God.
God does not know time.
Warren: Any other questions?
Shri Mataji: Please stand up.
Seeker: Say you become enlighten
and you see things
together consciousness and
what happens to you after
you physically die? What after that?
Shri Mataji: Yo see that, you should not be futuristic.
Why do you want to think of death, I'm talking of life?
I’ve given a big lecture on that.
You can take a tape and hear about it,
but just now we’re talking about life, not about death, all right.
You are a realized soul.
If you want, you can take your birth again,
do what you like. You are a free bird after your death.
There’s nothing like death after that,
because you entered into a realm
where there is no death. You know you are dying
and changing this body and you can take the body again.
It’s a very different awareness, all right.
Seeker: Do you need faith in order to know God?
Shri Mataji: No, not at all.
You see faith, if it means blind faith,
on the contrary, it’s very dangerous.
Those people who have blind faith
are very dangerous people because
they are really bound to a certain mental
aspect of it, you see.
And they are bound to some sort of a mental conception,
that this is God, this is God, this is God, is wrong.
But you must have an open mind.
Even if you deny,
then it’s not proper because you keep your mind open.
It is like sunshine.
If you are facing the sunshine
you will be affected by sunshine,
but if you hide yourself from sunshine,
the sunshine is not going to run after.
Seeker: Who taught you your technique,
you said that you need a light to light another light?
Shri Mataji: Nobody.
You better know me when you are enlightened.
You see the thing is, I don’t want to talk about myself.
The trouble is,
Christ just said that He was the Son of God, all right
and they crucified Him.
That’s a fact. He was.
But they crucified him
and I don’t want to talk about
myself till you have your enlightenment.
When you have your enlightenment,
then you will know about me, all right.
You better have your light first, and then you’ll know me.
Otherwise, it’s difficult.
I’m tactful in this lifetime.
I don’t want to get crucified.
Seeker: If you’ve had an operation on your lower back
where the Kundalini is down there
and there is pain all the time can you still have enlightenment?
Shri Mataji: Yes, you can. We can
work it out, first we'll have to adjust the back.
We’ll have to put it right.
So many people have got it even with their
back broken. Realization.
First, their back is put right and they feel all right
and then they get the Kundalini rising. It’s not difficult.
It’s a repairing system, it repairs you.
But if something is dead in you, supposing you put some
steel sticks into your legs, we can’t remove it, you see.
If it is a dead stuff inside, we cannot help you, but if it is a living
machinery, it repairs.
It just gets repaired. It has to be a living thing inside.
Seeker: When the Kundalini rises up,
does it always maintain a position
or does it ever go back down?
Shri Mataji: That’s true, it goes down also, in many people.
It goes down, it comes up and goes down.
You see, in some people it does.
I mean, I would say that it, very much there.
But with many people it goes down.
And the reason why it goes down
is because it comes in a flood, you see.
Because it faces me, knows me. It comes up like a flood
and then it goes down because
you need nourishment in different centers.
Supposing you have a problem somewhere.
It goes and nourishes you.
Then again it nourishes. Very sweetly comes up again.
But if you know,
once you have touched this and it has come out of it
and if you know how to raise it again and again, you can bring it up.
That’s what you have to learn after realization
and that is called as shuddha vidya. Means the true knowledge
of divine activity.
Once you know that how to
it’s very simple. You have to use only your hands.
Like this you have to move it
and bring it up. You have to give yourself a balance a little bit
only because it’s flowing through your hands,
that’s all and you can manage.
It’s not difficult. You can establish it.
A little bit in the beginning, about a month,
you’ll have to work it out,
but not all. I’m saying just
a few people really get it, like you can say,
Steve was like that. He got it, he got it.
Seeker: Is all of this really happening?
Is this real?
Shri Mataji: Yeah.
It is too fantastic to believe.
It is happening. It has to happen sometime.
God who has created this creation,
He is worried
and He has to look after his creation, isn’t it ?
He’s anxious. It has to happen.
After all, we are not responsible for this creation.
He has created it, so He has to jolly well look after it.
It’s happening.
You can’t believe it, isn’t it?
It will work out.
Have faith in yourself, that’s all.
You must have faith in yourself and nothing else.
Seeker: While doing Sahaja Yoga techniques,
which I have been taught.
Is it okay to -
be like a worshipper of Jesus Christ also
will that interfere in anyway. And also wanna
how about like in I'm a musician
and the practice of my music, can that be like Bhakti Yoga,
will that, I mean can I use that as a meditation?
Shri Mataji: Of course, of course
but you become discreet you see after that.
You start understanding the music which is good for your spirit,
which is not good for you, your spirit.
And you become dynamic, dynamic. I mean,
you know about Indian music, something?
Indian music.
So many Indian Musicians have got realization
and after realization they have become absolutely tremendous.
So you become tremendous but you become discreet there.
You start understanding what music will really give joy of the spirit
and you start playing and the joy of the spirit is the main thing
people are seeking that’s eternal music
because all other types of music comes up and goes down
but only the one that gives joy
reminds eternally.
All like those, Mozart.
Mozart was a realised soul and his music
gives joy to the spirit
because you start feeling the vibrations when you hear him.
Like artists also we can say
Michelangelo was a realised soul.
When you see his paintings in the Sistine Chapel, you see.
You have been to Rome.
You start feeling the vibrations from that.
Warren: He asked another half of the question.
Can he remain worshipping the Lord Jesus Christ,
once he gains his realization?
Shri Mataji: Of course Lord Jesus Christ plays a very great importance
but you must understand him in a full way,
you should not just take it from the
Bible because the bible cannot contain Christ,
it's only three and half years of his age is there.
There are so many books which have described Him
and you have to see what he is really,
what importance he has.
I wish people have gone out of
Bible and seen what great person he is.
Today, you'll be surprised people
like Jews, who believe in
Christ very much, Muslims believe in Christ
very much, much more than Christians can believe
because they are realised souls and they know whats his position
in realization.
Seeker: I would like to know more
about the hands, you were speaking of -
I guess senses on the hands?
Shri Mataji: That is all written down in the book,
you will understand
that these are five centers,
six and seven centers in the left hand side
and the same way on the right hand side
but what they do not answer in the book is there
and we give the books after
you have got realization, not before that.
Because before that if I give the book
again you will go into mental projections.
You see, so we are treating you in this way,
that first you get your realization
then only the first book is given
because if you give the last book, it's too much for you to bear.
So first book you have to read and digested it
like that you have to grow really
in Sahaja Yoga you have to become, there is no other interest.
That you have to become so we gradually sort of
make you understand it so that you can digest it.
Seeker: If you're a person who
can't say see things but has visions
when you come under realization,
will that go away or will it be stronger
or will it stay or what?
Shri Mataji: Visions are not all right.
You should not see visions.
That means you’re not normal.
You’re on the right hand side.
If you're on the right hand side you start seeing visions.
The other day we had one boy who used to see auras and visions.
But he told me his head is heavy all the time, he feels very heavy.
And that he doesn’t feel all right
and we had to remove that
because you must see the present,
the reality as it is.
At the time of Christ, people started seeing visions of Moses.
But Christ was there living with them every night
and they were thinking of Moses,
they had been visions of Moses and Abraham.
What about Christ who was living.
Now today I am here and now you will
think you are taking visions of Christ.
What about me? I am here in the present.
So you have to be in the present, not in the future
or in the past. But when you see visions
it could be from the past or from the future.
Like in India people see visions.
And they have their
own visions of the Devis and Goddesses and all that.
And then they deny everything.
They say that no, how are we to believe in
Christ or his Mother or anything?
But when they come to the present
they understand that they were all there. They are there
in the present.
Because you become one side.
Vision is not a normal thing.
It’s not very good and those people who see visions
end up into very bad life
because it’s not normal.
You will know gradually,
how you see visions also,
what happens to you. But after realization, you just come in the center.
Seeker: In Sahaja Yoga,
does the Kundalini go beyond the crown chakra?
Shri Mataji: Of course,
it can go beyond, much beyond.
But it depends on you seeing how you are.
It has to grow. It is for the complete growth of a person.
There are three centers above that which you have to cross.
There are some people who have crossed it, no doubt.
But they are some but you see
they are a very assiduous, I should say.
Also they are a category I should say,
there are so many things about them, the quality itself.
You can ascend much more.
The seventh chakra is just the beginning.
It's is just the beginning.
Seeker: I have a couple of books, one by Yogananda
and one by Sri Ramakrishna.
I would like to know if was they,
is they false prophets?
Shri Mataji: I don’t want to talk about personal things.
see because I don’t want to shock you about things,
but you yourself will find out, all right.
You get your enlightenment, yourself
you can find out what is false, what is real.
If they’re real, then you’ll start
getting the cool breeze in the hands.
If they are false,
then you’ll get even blisters
in the hand.
So one has to understand what is real and unreal
by one’s own understanding.
When you will discover it in no time.
Hatha Yoga is just a wee bit of real Patanjali’s Hatha Yoga,
and it’s absolutely wrong because
it makes you very one sided.
You become physically attentive,
but you are not only a physical
being, you are a mental being, you are
emotional being, you are also a spiritual being.
So this is just such a wee bit.
If you see the book of Patanjali’s it’s so great,
and in that all Sahaja Yoga is written, Sahaja Yoga written.
Why they have taken only the – just like jogging it is.
Just another style of jogging.
So should we have now the realization?
There’s a lady there? Now, that’s the last, eh?
Seeker: I was wondering after death,
whats the quickest that soul turns to return to a body?
How long?
Warren: She answered the question about death by saying,
“Put the attention to the future - to the present
not to the future.”
Shri Mataji: Just now is not important.
I’ll tell you all about it, it's nothing -
What she say?
Seeker: I'm just wondering about that one?
Warren: Whats the question again?
Shri Mataji: Please stand up, please stand up.
Question: After death how quickly does the soul reincarnate?
Shri Mataji: I mean, you know this is a subject
which has to be dealt for one year over at least, you see.
And it's of no use to you,
what is the use of asking a question like this.
Warren: She asking on behalf of somebody else.
Shri Mataji: But where is the friend?
Warren: Is that person dead?
Yes, that person who is dead already.
I think you come and see me and I’ll tell you all about it, all right?
Because just now, we don’t
want to spoil the minds of people,
all right, with the death and all this nonsense.
Just now, let us be in the present.
Seeker: Can I ask one last question?
Shri Mataji: Now, ask.
Seeker: Beyond the crown chakra
is it still the Kundalini that’s at work?
Or is it another power too?
Shri Mataji: Well the Kundalini itself
because she is the primordial mother,
shes the primordial,
shes the primordial.
You see, must understand shes the Adi Shakti,
shes the primordial mother
and she works throughout.
She is the witness to the last (unclear)
So she works throughout, I mean
there’s nobody else who works it out
but because your enlighten you do much faster,
your accelerated.
At that point you are accelerated
because of your enlightenment.
That acceleration takes place much faster.
To look at it, looks like Kundalini
but it is complete Aum.
It is a complete force, the reflection of the
divine love of God which is the Power of God, complete.
Because God Himself separates from His Power.
And becomes the spectator
and the Power of God divides itself into three.
And becomes the creation
and the whole thing is the Kundalini,
is the Kundalini is as they call residual
because she manifests all that but still shes complete.
Shes complete and then she reflects this,
so throughout she works it out.
Of course in you is the reflection
of that primordial Kundalini.
It's a form
of the primordial mother.
she becomes that form.
Say now I'm your teacher
but also I am a wife, I'm grandma.
In the same way she becomes
the Kundalini.
Tomorrow again we will meet here
that's the last day I'll be with you,
please try to telephone to your friends tomorrow
and get their friends, as many as possible
because I don't know when will I'll come back again.
So try to get them, they should all get their realization
and I hope day after tomorrow we might be able
to at least a
workshop and show how
to make you understand
the Sahaja Yoga, how to work it out and everything.
Hope to again on Friday.
So tomorrow please start to call your friends,
it is their right to have to have it, they should be here.
If they had come, they would have got it
and then the growth will start.
Now go home, don't talk to anyone,
do not argue, this cannot be argued
some people haven't got it, supposedly they start arguing.
Do not argue it out, just go home,
have your food and sleep on,
enjoy, you feel very much better tomorrow.
I'm back here and I'll be able to explain to you
some others things about chakras and things.
And if you have any questions, I'd ask you.
May God bless you.