Please sit very comfortably that’s very
important.
There should be no strain on a particular
part of the body.
For example, when you are sitting sometimes
your feet might feel little bit numbed down,
you can change the posture.
You need not carry on with any extreme effort
or any discomfort to yourself, that’s first
thing you must remember.
Moreover some of the people go into tense
postures also by stretching their hands too
straight or sometimes going very straight
or pushing their head behind.
Sometimes they bend their heads also bit too
much also.
Sit very comfortably with both the hands on
your lap in a very comfortable way.
There should be nothing extreme to be done
from outside.
We have to understand the principle of this
living process.
Then you will know that why I say: “No use
doing any such extreme thing to achieve your
goal”.
The principle is like this: that this room
is all dirty supposing or it’s in a chaos,
or maybe it’s in darkness completely, you
can’t see anything.
So you enter inside the room.
Your goal is to achieve the enlightenment.
Some people will say that: “Let us clean
the room in darkness with blindness”.
You start cleaning your body you don’t know
what you are cleaning!
So there is no need to bother about cleaning
when you are blind.
Some people think: “If you clear your mind
before Realization you will be better off."
You have tried all those things, but in doing
so, you have gone to extremes.
It’s all blindness, all your work is done
in darkness, there is no enlightenment.
You have to get your enlightenment first,
this is what I have realized that unless and
until human beings are enlightened they cannot
cleanse themselves properly, they cannot understand
Sahaja Yoga, they cannot understand God, they
cannot understand feel their Spirit, nothing
is possible unless and until they are enlightened.
It is possible then, when you get the enlightenment,
you might find that the light is not coming
through properly, there is some shaking in
the bulb or may be there is some shaking in
the shade or maybe that the room is dirty,
that you cannot see things clearly, that you
cannot see your image in the mirror, your
eyes are weak.
For all this you need a bright light.
But without getting the light itself, without
knowing something about what you have got
within yourself, how are you going to cleanse
yourself?
Of course the light may be dim but still you
can see what is the problem, what is to be
done, what is to be cleared out.
That’s why enlightenment is the first thing.
Now for this, even if you clean the whole
room, even if you do all that, you have not
done the perfect job.
On the contrary you might break some things,
you might spoil some things, you may slip
down, anything can happen in darkness that’s
what happens to people when they do any sadhana
blindly.
After your enlightenment you know your way
through, you know how to go about it and you
understand everything.
Then another myth we have is that if we cleanse
our mind, we can achieve our spirituality,
you can’t.
Even if this room may be clean unless and
until there is light there cannot be enlightenment.
So the main thing is you have to have an enlightenment.
I have known people who lead very clean and
a good life.
When they get enlightenment they get it very
fast and have it nicely established, very
easily and it is there.
But some of the people who lead a very clean
and a good life have overdone it to such an
extent that they have an ego about it, they
think: “I don’t want anything, I am perfect,
I do no wrong, I am committing no problem,
I am a very happy person”.
Such people also get stuck because they do
not want the higher things of life.
They do not want their Spirit to be enlightened
so that also sometimes become a very sticky
point.
Now in Sahaja Yoga, you have to know that
you have the power within yourself.
It is there, it exists there, and it is to
be just awakened.
In some people, it takes time to be awakened.
In thousands I have seen it takes no time.
The only thing that I would suggest is to
keep your mind open, not to become obstinate
about things.
If you are an obstinate person, the Kundalini
is even a greater obstinate thing.
Do not be obstinate, just keep yourself open,
do not argue it out by argument or by thinking
about it, the Kundalini is not going to be
awakened.
On the contrary when the Kundalini is awakened
your thoughts settle down to such an extent
that you feel there is no thought coming to
you from your subconscious or from your supraconscious.
So try to keep yourself absolutely open and
don’t worry even if your vibrations are
not felt.
The principle is that light is light and the
room is room.
The light has nothing to do with the room.
Only thing, when the light is enlightened,
it enlightens the room.
The room has something to do with the light,
but the light has nothing to do: whether the
room is there or not, light exists.
In the same way, we must understand that the
relationship with the atman and our body our
Spirit and our this body, mind, and our ego,
superego.
So many of
you must have done lot of tapasyas and lot
of things which were not really wanted, thinking
that you have done such a lot, you have been
to so many places, you have done so much “tirtha
yatra” [acetic; journey] you have been to
so many pilgrimages and those pilgrimages
and all these places, you think according
to you, it should be blissful to you.
But actually, while going there, you did not
know how to get the bliss from those temple
and those places which are holy actually in
nature but are surrounded by people who are
extremely negative.
Because of that, that mixture was there and
sometimes instead of getting the bliss you
get the headaches.
7:23
Today we are going to discuss the Void what
we call Void in Sahaja Yoga is different from
the way people talk of void.
Void is the complete visceral cavity which
is called in Sahaja Yoga language as Bhavasagara.
Many a times, you must have heard people singing
songs poets singing songs saying “Bhavasagara
se para utaru”
What is this Bhavasagara?
This is the symbol or this is the reflection
of the whole entire universe that is created.
This all universe is created by Brahmadeva.
He is the one who is the creator, who is a
“raksna yeta” [unsure] of this world,
who created this beautiful universe, in that
especially he created the Mother earth.
He has placed the Moon and the Sun on both
the sides of this Mother earth and the representatives
of the Mother earth within us is the Kundalini,
the Mooladhara.
Now this universe exists within us, that
is the Bhavasagara.
This Bhavasagara exists in many stages in
its evolutionary form and today it is Kali
Yuga in this Bhavasagara.
I would say it is the dawn of Satya Yuga and
the end of Kali Yuga.
And this Bhavasagara is placed in the centre-
is the center of Nabhi, Nabhi charka.
And around it, moves the center of Swadhisthana.
Nabhi chakra as you know is governed by Shri
Lakshmi as the power of Shri Vishnu and the
Swadhisthana moves around it, which delimits
our own personality, and which creates all
these different stars within us or the planets
within us.
In these spaces, Void, are born the incarnations
of the Primordial Master who is called as
Dattatreya.
Dattatreya is the innocence of Shiva of – “Vibrations
itni hai ikura” [Vibrations are so cool]-
of Brahmadeva and of Shri Vishnu.
Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesh, the essence of these,
the innocence of these is embodied in the
form of Dattatreya, who is the Primordial
Master.
So these masters who are born on this Earth
are innocence at its best, all integrated
together.
These masters have incarnated on this Earth
mainly ten times, but there have been many
others incarnations also, there have been
repetitions just to correct themselves.
As I told you yesterday that Mohammad Saab
and Nanaka are both the same personalities
of Dattatreya.
The instance is given, in the life of Guru
Nanaka, when he was sleeping people told him
that your feet are towards Mecca, Kaaba towards
Kaaba.
He said: “Alright I’ll remove my feet
and put wherever you say”.
Then they put his feet towards the other side
and again they found that his feet were facing
towards Kaaba.
Then he said: “Tell me the place where there
is no Kaaba I’ll put my feet!”
But they couldn’t arrange it at all, because
wherever he placed his feet, it was such a
Maya, that always they found that the feet
were towards Kaaba.
Now Kaaba is a place where you have a beautiful
Shiva linga, which is called as Mekkaeshwar
Shiva in our Puranas.
From ancient times it is mentioned that, there
is a pinda which is absolutely Vibrating and
which is there.
Now Mohammad Saab religiously avoided talking
about that.
He only said: “If this stone can be so godly,
why not human beings be?”
But he did not explained much as it is whatever
he tried to explain, the people were so insensitive
and so cruel that they tried to kill him many
a times, they to gave him poison, ultimately
he died in a very, very bad state.
They tortured his life, they were lunatic
people, they used to live in tribes and very
tribal by nature.
And they- he tried his level best to propagate
that there is God and God is above all and
I am the messenger of God, but they would
not listen to him.
Then came, you know Nanaka who preached that
there should be no enmity between Hindus and
Muslims, he preached that, because he saw
the Muslims behaving in such a manner, they
were such fanatics and they had become so
funny that he could not understand how is
it?
These are the people whom I have made Muslims
and what are they doing here?
Actually Musalman means the person who is
realized and Peer is a person whose realization
is established so much so that he said that
those who have become Musalman should be buried
and not burnt, because he thought they are
all realized souls, but realization finished
off with his son in law and his daughter,
after that he had two sons who were great
souls who are really the reincarnations of
Lov and Kush.
Now perhaps we do not know what happened to
Luv and Kush when they were born.
Luv and Kush when their mother disappeared
in the Mother Earth and the father, they were
little annoyed with them, went in the North
one went to Caucasus and another went to China.
Luv went to Caucasus and from there he became
a very powerful king in Russia.
Russians always use Sanskrit language; we
do not know how much Sanskrit they use; for
example they will say kharoshou means Harushivaye
the Pravada itself the word Pravada vda is
to say pra means enlightened.
You see their language, it’s full of Sanskrit
words, practically it is absolutely based
on Sanskrit and you’d say slaws people…slaws,
so lov sla…
Luv ruled there for years together and about
four hundred years back, his very descendants
flew away from there, went to Iran, where
there is a Goddess, Goddess Hindolika’s
temple is there which is all described in
the Puranas, where they used to worship Goddess
Hindolika, from there they came down and spread
all over, it’s a big story.
Then Kush went to China, that’s how you
have Kushan in China and Chinese language
is very much near Sanskrit and quite close
to Marathi language, it’s more surprising
if you hear them talking, for example they
say; Ma tza tum , tza is only there in Marathi
language they use this word tza, we never
say in Hindi tza or in any other language
you wont find it tza but only in Chinese and
in Marathi language they have this word, tza.
It’s very interesting to see, how the spirituality
has spread into these countries and then how
it died out.
All these things happened, but then they were
born again and again, they were born as Mahavira
and Buddha, they are the same, they are born
as Markendeya, they are born as Kabira, as
Adishankaracharya, it was Buddha who was born
as Adishankaracharya just to correct himself,
Buddha was shocked the way people were going,
there was Nirakara that he had be born as
Shankaracharaya to tell people, oh God, what
are you doing?
It was only Buddha who came to correct himself
as Shankaracharaya, it is so surprising, that
people are fighting, Buddhist and Hindus are
great enemies of each other, but they do not
know that the person who really re-established
Hinduism was the same who established Buddhism.
So imagine the same personality coming again
and again on this Earth tries to correct his
disciples again finds that there are two groups
he has created, it’s a big problem.
Now Mahavira also was one of them, who was
born again and again and he was Markendeya
and he was Kabira, the way Kabira lashes people
you can see that he is tremendous, he is like
Bhairava and the power of Bhairava, Kabira
has used in his language, but for Hindi poets
it is Sadhukadi and they have made fun of
it.
The best thing of a person who doesn’t want
to face reality, is to make fun of everyone,
that is the best way, they said what is this
talk Ida, Pingla, Sushumna?
Who is he?
What does he think of himself?
But he was appreciated very much, by the saints
and especially by Guru Nanaka, who included
all his poetry in his Grantha sahib; he’s
included so many of these poetry from all
the realized souls from Maharashtra, also.
But I wonder how many Sikhs know that this
was for getting realization, he thought, if
you write an Upanishad, [not clear_] they
try to correct everything just to make people
understand that you have to get to it.
First, they thought that if you write Gita,
they go on remembering Gita by heart.
Then, they thought it is better, that you
write something from the realized souls only
together, so that it is a powerful Grantha
by which people when they read it they get
Vibrations and they’ll stick to it, but
it is not so, even there people are just reading
it.
I don’t know how?
Gradually as we were revolving, we were losing
our sensitivity.
At least in the time of Rama, people knew
he was an incarnation.
At the time of Krishna they knew he was an
incarnation.
Many people know, of course, Raksasha knew
also that they were incarnations; raksasha’s
even today know who the incarnation they are
very sure of it and they are just frightened
of, but in those days, even common people
knew who is an incarnation.
Now the sensitivity among human beings started
getting reduced and reduced as they got involved
into fanaticism, all kinds of tantrism that
developed in this country of ours, in other
countries also, tremendous movement was there
to create fanatics and these fanatics are
diseased people, they are diseased, they are
actually the people who are possessed absolutely
possessed, they are not normal people when
they talk, you are surprised, how can they
talk like that?
When they do not know anything about it, but
thank God today, fanaticism has reached such
a stage that the younger people are understanding
the nonsense of it.
It’s a very good chance for Sahaja Yoga
to come up.
In Sahaja Yoga, the beauty is this, that you
cannot now form a cult as soon as you try
to do such a thing, you loose your vibrations,
you try any such tricks, you try to be fanatic
you will be losing all your vibrations, any
tricks you try with Sahaja Yoga first thing
you will loose your vibrations, you wont like
it, you won’t be happy with it, you would
like to keep your vibrations going, smooth,
smoothly and nicely so that you feel absolutely
happy about it and joyous, but anybody who
tries any tricks with Sahaja Yoga, you get
into problem.
Now these Gurus came on this Earth to remove
fanaticism, the last of them came as Shirdi
Sai Nath, he was the one who had said very
clearly, in Marathi he had said it, that to
speak ill of any other religion is sin, is
sin, nothing can be more powerful than that.
There are many people who worship Sai Nath,
many people, but they drink, he was against
drinking, all of them were against drinking,
why were they against drinking because the
awareness is spread in your void.
The awareness, the Chitta, the attention is
in your void and is nourished by your liver.
The liver takes out all the poison from your
awareness, due to bad health, due to bad mind,
due to anything from bad effects or negativity
and then it clears out as I told you yesterday.
So this awareness within us gets, you know
that our awareness, human awareness goes down
through drinking, these people preach that
you should not drink.
I mean that the one thing that they all preached
together, that you should not drink.
At the time of Mohammad Saab there was no
smoking, so Guru Nanaka also [not clear] this
time you found people smoking with big big
hookah’s, he said that now for heaven sake
do not smoke, because they said that you just
said that don’t drink, so we will smoke
now.
Like in England, people say what’s wrong
in drugs?
Drugs were not approached by saints, so we
can take drugs, so it is in my lot, to tell
them, now drugs are the same; anything that
goes against awareness is not good.
I mean, it is not something that you have
said no because they were mad people, whatever
they said, they said because it was the truth.
If you take drinks of any kind, alcoholics
or any these kinds, anything that takes you
away from your awareness is wrong because
your awareness is to be enlightened as it
is your awareness is like that and on top
of that if this awareness is to be enlightened
and is full of alcoholism, how to raise it?
How to do it?
But these days to talk against alcoholism,
one person asked Me, “Mother are you going
to be minister of permission?”
I mean, it is impossible to talk to people
about anything sensible.
Even in a party you go, they say why don’t
you drink?
You should drink, you are missing such a great
thing, you have missed such a lot in your
life, I said I have drunk from my childhood,
don’t give Me anything I don’t need it,
no, they’ll go on forcing, you must drink.
You see, this is a special thing, that is
thing and all that.
They have no shame about it, no shame.
They think they are trying to be nice and
you tell them even once if you say.
Why do you drink?
Gone, you are the gone case, you have no manners.
You are the most unmannerly person.
How dare you say such a thing to anyone?
Look at these human beings, such [not clear_],
I don’t know how to deal with them?
They think that they should be told, “alright
go ahead drink, kill your self”.
How can you be saints allowed you to drink?
Tell Me, when they know that it goes against
your awareness, of course these thugs will
say “alright drink as much as you like,
do what you please, you have ten wives or
you do what you please, only give me your
purse to me”, because that is their interest
in you.
They are only interested in your purse, how
much money you have got in your purse?
What job you are doing?
Or at times they can be, officers, saying
that, give job to my son or give job to someone.
One has to understand that saint is not afraid
of anyone, he cannot be, it’s a fearless
entity absolutely fearless, it’s not afraid
of anyone because it is standing on truth,
truth itself gives you that strength to say
the truth, but I have learnt certain lessons,
in my past lives that human beings don’t
like truth, don’t tell them, if you tell
them they will crucify you, immediately.
You have to go round and round and put them
into problem so that they come along.
If you tell them straight forward don’t
do something, they will put you, I mean, people
may crucify Me after sometime, if I tell them
don’t drink, it is that bad these days.
The drinking in England is so bad now that
English, who used to drink so little, is now
nothing but a bottle, since morning he starts
it.
In third generation you go down, what about
our Indians who have gone there?
Even the Sikhs, who are told not to drink,
drink more than Scotch people can drink.
It’s a shameful thing and they will fight
that we’ll not put a helmet on our head,
to save our head from going on a motorbike.
Is it written in any Grantha Sahib like this
to be foolish and stupid?
But they will fight for that, but not fight
for this, that no Sikh should drink.
If you are wearing that pagadi, you have no
business to drink.
They don’t think that the essence of religion
is more important, than all these nonsensical
things that you think you are doing.
Such a great religion, Islam, such a great
religion is Sikhism, such a great religion
is Hinduism, such a great religion is Christianity.
Everything gone to dogs because the dogs have
come into it.
They have no sense of proportion; they do
not know how to respect their Guru’s…
in the right way putting their guru’s in
their heart and in their behavior.
That’s all they should have done.
They should have just obeyed their Guru’s.
There was no need to stand on your heads and
take mantras from these thugs paying them.
There was no need at all to do all these things,
but no they thought that here we are doing
black market money, let us make some big temples
so there are great Hindus, big temples are
built, black market money going on.
Here they are killing so many people the Muslims,
so they must say that we are doing it in the
name of God, very nice.
Where Mohammad Saab has talked of nothing
but Rehmat and Rahim, all the time Rehmat
and Rahim he has talked of, see they were
about to kill him every moment wherever he
went, it was such a dangerous situation, so
vicariously he was living and he had to defend
himself.
So now we have to defend ourselves from these
people, instead of these people defending
themselves.
It’s not in defense; it is in aggression,
these people are killing others and they think
they are doing a great very great service
to the people.
Then the Christians, they are one of the worst
fanatics worst fanatics are the Christians
There cannot be worst fanatics than Christianity.
Christianity is one religion which is very
clever and cunning, nobody can beat them all.
For example they will do all missionary work.
You’ll say ha a ha a ha what nice people.
The missionary work, they are looking after
our poor people here, very nice people very
great generous people and they will be converting
people.
What are you converting them for?
Have you got the power of realization?
Have you got the power to call yourself Christian?
Are you baptized in the real sense?
That is how the Christians have been behaving
throughout.
They have put up such a big show, this is
not God’s work, to get some people from
the street who are dying put them in the room
and look after them.
Is this the work of God?
This the work of human beings?
Work of God is just to raise the Kundalini
that is the work of God.
Not the work of God is to have Hospitals and
Schools and things.
This is not the work of God, this is your
job, this is you are doing it, but they are
taking the name of God to earn money.
In the name of God give me money.
Such beggars I tell you of the first waters.
Begging a man, who believes in God, will never
do.
Why to beg?
Why to ask for money?
On the streets they will stand, nowadays our
Hare Rama and Hare Krishna in Oxford Street
and beg money, in the name of God.
Can there be greater sinners than these who
beg in the name of God and get money from
others and live on other people’s money?
All the time like parasites.
This is they have done out of religion, or
ritualism go to the temples, there’s a priest
standing there he gives you ghanta, he makes
something, puts something on your head, God
knows he spoils the Agnya charka or what he
does?
and you think “oh I have been to this temple,
I have been to that temple, I have been to
this Teerath and that teerath and that teerath
and I have been a very religious man”.
I tell you these extreme ideas about God has
really blinded us completely from reality.
If you want the reality, you must know that
God is to be found within your heart and not
in those places.
Once you have found it in your heart then
you will know that where is the real God in
which temple and how to approach.
Now if I ask you, In Delhi how many temples
are really jaagrut, except for Sahaja yogis
nobody can say, you see a stone namaste another
stone might have been brought from some bathroom
namaste.
Is that a real jaagrut one?
It is said in the Bible that whatever is produced,
created by mother Earth and by the Sky should
not be reproduced, now what is that is created?
What is that is created by Mother Earth?
We Indians know these are the jaagrut deities
which are created by Mother Earth, these are
the jaagrut deities and that is to be worshipped
and not to get a Ganapati somewhere for 2
rupees, my forefathers have given me so I
am carrying on.
I must do their Puja, maybe the forefathers
are sitting on that.
You won’t believe, there is a gentleman
in Bombay, who came to Me, to meet Me, his
name is Mr.
Shah, he said “Mother Lot’s of things
are happening, I don’t know how?”
I said what happened?
“In my house I am getting some old deities
from somewhere, just coming into my house
from somewhere, I don’t know where from
where it comes?
Sometimes I keep my windows open in the night
and I find in the morning there is a deity
of silver sometimes diamonds are there in
the nose of the Lakshmi and I am surprised
how am I getting it?”
And the man is not so rich to have all these
things; he showed me and said now what to
do?
I told him; throw them all of them in the
sea, that’s what they deserve.
He said from where have they come?
These are the people who have habit of very
seriously worshipping those deities, without
understanding that these deities have got
vibrations or not, whether they are jaagrut
or not, they are alright or not.
Even a plastic they’ll make, they’ll make
of aluminum.
I don’t know now what they are going to
use next to make a deity and they will be
carrying it on, have no value, have no understanding,
have no respect.
So the people who own those, they must be
bringing it, the old people and putting in
your house, so better put them in the sea,
otherwise they will not have their Mukti and
this fellow is having greediness.
He is always having a chakkar with these things.
He said “what is happening to me?”
His child is getting into problem; his wife
has run away from the house.
All kinds of problems coming up, lost all
his money, every sort of problem coming up
and this deity is coming in he said, should
I sell them and get some money.
I said please don’t do it, to whomsoever
you will sell, you will sell asubah.
These are coming by some dead person using
this bhanawati; they are bringing this down
here.
But there where he told Me thousands of people
wanting just to touch the feet of these bhootas.
They thought such a bhoot cannot bring these
deities and that must be God who is coming
in the form.
If in the thing was written also, made in
near Mumbadevi and this and that.
You mean God is sitting there and making those
statues?
We don’t use our brains also, when it comes
to God.
I mean faith is necessary no doubt, but this
is after realization, before realization it’s
a blind faith, which can be any nonsense.
I have seen such mad people that they just
go on pulling out their hair and they say
that we are doing it in the name of God, really?
Why did God give you these hairs?
If he wanted you to pull it out like that
morning till evening sitting and pulling it
out and they develop such nervousness that
if they are not properly aware they will start
pulling out from your hair also.
It is such a dangerous situation in this blind
faith, that you form some habits.
You know people have an idea of using the
mala, that’s why Kabira has said “kar
kamana ka chade de manna ka manna ka pher”
So they will also say, they will have it “kar
kamana man ka chade de manna ka manna ka pher”
finished.
Even the children have understood the joke,
this is what we are doing, that when it is
told that you have to have God in your heart
and don’t do these rituals, you will find
these people using that rosary to such an
extent, that if they are talking they don’t
have that, they cannot sit tight, it’s like
a nervousness in them, it’s a nervousness
by which they must go on (aur main to hamesha
mala jappti houn 108 and falaana) and you
feel that the person is about to land up in
some lunatic asylum with the number 108.
The way people are mad in religion makes people
really atheist they see these mad people what
are they doing is the religion?
Is this the religion, where people sell it,
you go to any temple?
Once we had bought some Am rood, Guavas and
we went to the temple we were thinking that
we will get out of, then we were very young,
[not clear_], and we were lots of brothers
and sisters we went down to a temple and we
thought that after seeing the temple we will
go outside behind the temple and we will eat
the thing as soon as we reached there, the
Pujari took out the packets from our hands,
you know, all the children poor things were
carrying three, four packets we had and they
took out everything from [not clear_], we
were looking at them why did they took out
everything and gave us one each you see, wah
wah !! and we were about to cry, but my younger
sister couldn’t bare it, she said “why
did you take away my, all my Guavas?
please return it to me”, but this is sort
of a right they have got to live on your money,
these parasites.
In the name of God these parasites, you are
the people who are nurturing them, you just
giving them money, it is better to give to
a beggar, then to give to these horrible sophisticated
beggars sitting on the temples and churches.
You are the people who are responsible for
creating such a mess because half of the people
are indifferent; those who are not indifferent
bhagvaan ke naam pe, half of them are like
that who go to one Sidhhi Vinayak mandir and
Mangalwaar day (Tuesday), you will find that
queue of sometimes two miles in that Bombay,
where people have no time for anything.
People are moving with the pace of an Ant,
one inch in one hour, there are some people
who start in the night and they move on, they
go with their naariyal and the naariyals,
come from the other side and sold again next
month.
They know this; still they say we have done
it with bhakti and Ganesha will give us what
we like.
Ganesha will only give you wisdom, I wish
he could, I wish he could give you wisdom
and understanding about religion.
This is a mess we have done out of our religion,
every religion, every religion is not only
Hinduism, Islam or Christianity or Sikhism.
We have really killed the religion by our
indifference, or by too much of indulgence,
blind fold, faith in all these horrible people,
who claim that they are religious people,
by what means are they?
Go and see their lifestyle.
Go and see what sort of a people they are.
They are raksasha’s some of them I can tell
you, when I went to Vrindavan I felt all the
anucharaas of Kansa are their fundas.
All of them not one I found as a human being,
they are such horrible people and the way
they torture you still you go about religion.
One has to understand that God stands in His
purity He is a pure being and He likes our
wisdom.
He doesn’t like people who are stupid and
foolish.
He likes wise people, wise people… like,
Prahllad, Prahllad was an eight year old boy,
when his father Hiranyakashyup challenged
him, Shri Vishnu appeared in a pillar, you
know in a Narsimha avatar and he killed his
father and then he asked this little boy of
eight years Prahllad, he said, “my child,
my devotee, what do you want?”
He could have asked for anything, Sakshaat
Vishnu was there, but what does he say, “Tav
charna arvinde pritii” Give me love at your
lotus feet, oh my lord that’s all what I
want.
To love you at your lotus feet.
If you have your pure love for God He will
give you wisdom.
If you do not have your purity you go there
to ask for this thing and that thing; Give
me a transfer, specially government servants,
they are never satisfied, they want to have
transfers all the time, Give me a promotion,
Give me a son, when you get a son, give me
a job for my son.
When he gets a job, get him a wife, poor Ganesha
must be tired.
This is what it is, this is not religion,
this is not God, this has nothing to do with
spirituality, you have to ask for one thing,
“Tav charna arvinde pritii."
Oh lord let me be at your lotus feet so that
one day my Kundalini would be awakened and
that my atma would be enlightened within my
awareness.
Let me keep my life so beautiful, “Ye chaadar
rishi muni jann odhi, Odhi ke meli kini chadariya,Daas
Kabir jatan se odhi, Jaisi ki taisi rakh dini
chadariya."
This is what we should have done, instead
of that we go to this Tan trick, that bhajji,
that Pundit ji, that Pandey ji, or some other
Paadri ji or what you call them other sorts
of people those Mullah ji’s and all sorts
of Mau Lana ji’s and Pir’s and all sorts
of things and what do you get?
A bad Agnya.
They have no right to be there, they are there
because they want to make a business out of
God.
Today I spoke about it, because it is important
to understand, what is religion?
In India especially I have seen people go
out of the way to do penances in the name
of God, which is a great thing, but why do
you do penance, what is there to suffer?
Why do you make your body suffer so much?
Keep your body alright, don’t overdo things,
keep a moderate life, lead a normal life,
that’s what Buddha has told you, there is
no need to go to extremes for anything, but
even Buddhist, they have gone to another extreme
so he had to come on this Earth as Shankaracharaya
to tell people what are you doing?
When did I say this?
Then they were born as the son of Fatimabai
[editor’s note to verifier: John Noyce has
verified that this is the correct spelling]
who was herself nothing else but Janaki and
they were her sons Hassan and Hussein, who
had preached non-violence and they saw that
people were trying to save bugs and mosquitoes.
You know there are some funny cults where
we are so particular of bugs mosquitoes and
all the worms, we are not at all particular
about human beings, they, I don’t know what
am I going to do with bugs?
Am I going to give them realization?
Even chicken’s… am I going to give them
realization?
I have to give realization to human beings.
What is the need to pay so much attention
to these nonsensical things?
To save the bugs and save the mosquitoes and
make them bite the Brahmin and pay them money,
because they think they have done a great
kalyana on the bugs.
Perhaps they might have been bugs, in last
lives, the way they are interested in all
these mosquitoes.
Now, these two were born as Hassan and Hussein
and to get rid of these ideas of non-violence
they had this Karbala, in which they fought
and died like great shuras (great warriors).
This is a story of great incarnations on this
Earth.
There are so many of them who were born, I
have no time to tell you, but Socrates was
the same, his disciple was one of these two.
Abraham, Moses, who are propagating Jews their
religion, [not clear] people are another mad,
another mad people I can tell you, these Jews,
God save them from their madness, they will
make a sum that their books are, say called
as, todhat [not clear], they make it microscopic,
the more microscopic it is, the more spiritual
you are and they tie it up here you see, you
can’t even read it, you have to use a nice
magnifying glass to read that, they never
read, its tied up here.
According to them, if it is studded with diamonds,
then you are a greater spiritual person, they
are very rich people you see, so they tie
it up there and before a wailing wall they
go and like mad they are beating their heads
there and weeping for what they have done.
I mean there is no end to the madness of people.
You can understand that this is not religion.
Now the other day there was one Arya samaji
fellow who came to Me, he could not get his
realization; I must tell you these are another
fanatic types we have, Arya samaji, have they
been able to get to their spirit?
They are only bothered about re-converting
the people, marrying the people or building
the buildings and saying that, no we don’t
believe in God, we don’t believe in this
kind of a God.
We don’t believe in.
Who cares whether you believe or not, who
are you?
What right have you got to say anything?
It’s like any monkey standing up and saying,
“I don’t believe in this government, I
don’t believe in that government”.
Who is bothered about these people who talk
like this.
Who are they?
What authority have they got to say what is
good and what is bad.
Do they know what is good and what is bad?
To say like these things about, we don’t
believe in this and we don’t believe in
that.
For us it is essential to know that, first
let us know ourselves, let us get our light
enlightened and in that light let us see the
truth as it is you cannot ask the truth to
be like this.
You cannot organize God.
He is what He is, He remain as He is, you
cannot transform Him.
Only thing you can do is become one with Him.
What you can do is to perceive Him, to feel
Him, to be, that is the thing you can be,
but you cannot make God as you like Him, He
is what He is as I have told you.
and the best thing will be that you be humble
like Prahllad, to say, “Tav charna arvinde
pritii” Who are we to criticize these incarnations
of Primordial master?
What have we done?
Like, once somebody started criticizing Me,
so one of my disciples, Bardarf [not clear]
called him, come here, come here, how many
people have you given realization to?
He said “none”, He said, How many people
have you cured?
What good have you done to people?
He said none, what do you do?
He said I am a barber, he said you better
become a barber.
What are you talking here?
What right have you got?
What is your position to talk?
But in this kalyuga, even a person who does
not even know a word about religion, about
God, who is not awakened, who is not realized,
then talk about God.
This is ghour kalyuga, they are not afraid,
they are not afraid, to make money in the
name of God is the greatest sin, is the greatest
sin, I tell you, to make money like that in
the name of God and to spoil somebody’s
Kundalini, as these, all these fake Guru’s
are doing.
Using there bhoot vidya, they do not know
they will go to hell permanently; absolutely
permanently they will be there and there will
be no return from there.
They have been given many chances before,
but no more chances for them.
We are the people who have to correct them,
we have to stand together and tell them, nothing
doing, we had some people in Bombay who are
Brahmins, who are Brahmins, who are Brahmins
of the high order as we can call, [not clear]
they are called as and they got their realization.
Now they had to be taken up upon yourself
to put down all these horrible fake people
who are making money out of the public.
So one of them is a teacher and he told a
Brahmin in his family, because he was permanently
stuck, you see us Brahmins stuck to the families.
He said that, “my”, “I have to do the
Shard of my father, when can you come, within
the Pitrupaksh?
He said I can only come on Wednesday or something
like that.
He said are you sure that there is a Muhrata
for that?
Yes, he said, yes very I am sure of it.
So he went to another fellow, got the Panchanga,
Maharashtrians, that way know a lot about
these things like Panchanga and all that and
he opened the Panchanga he studied there and
he found out that there was no muhrata, in
any Panchanga whatsoever.
There are three Panchangas which we use, I
don’t know if we know here about it, he
saw all of them, then accordingly the muhrata
was on Tuesday, he celebrated it.
Then the fellow came, “rehne dijiye, rehne
dijiye, baad mein le lenge rehne do”.
Then the fellow came and he said that “I
have come now come along let us have the shard”,
He said that “I will not even give you a
cup of tea to you today” He said how?
You call me for the Shard I am suppose to
eat at your place, he says no, we have not
cooked anything and I am not going to give
you a cup of tea, if there is no muhrata today,
he said according to Tilak Panchanga it is,
he said I have studied also Tilak Panchanga,
I have studied all this, you get out of here.
The mother was poor thing you know, she said
“how you can this, he is our old thing”,
he said “this is the only chance I have
to get rid of this old fool” and he just
told him, get out you will not stay in this
house and I am not going to give a cup of
tea.
Then in Panduranga’s temple, in…, Panduranga’s
temple is there you know about Vitthhalla’s
in Panderpur [not clear] we have people going
down there and when I saw these people I was
surprised, they were all crazy people for
a month poor things are singing songs eat
little take that nasha of tambacco and go
singing songs for months together they go
to see Panduranga there and these people who
live there are called as Badwe, their names
are absolutely suited you see, like in Kolapur
they are called as Bhootis, can you imagine?
The Brahmins are called as Bhootis and these
are called as Badwe’s.
and these people ask them, “How is it, you
have got cracks in your heads?” he said
that this Naral, this naariyal or you can
call the coconut was broken at the lotus feet
of Panduranga, I said, how?
I couldn’t understand, these Badwe’s were
doing this job and when I said that these
Badwe’s should know if they don’t behave,
they are going to have a very bad time, you
see everybody was shocked but you’ll be
amazed within eight days the government took
over that place and its working out, but now
their language has changed, but this is how
these people have been troubling us, but now
we have got four Brahmins, four Brahmins living
in Panderpur who are after their throat and
they go to the temple and tell people that
don’t listen to the [unclear] and they are
propagating and they said that if you want
anything you ask us, but don’t give a single
Pai to these Badwa’s, good for nothing,
useless, whatever you want to do, you do it
to the deity and don’t touch these people,
treat them as untouchables and these are the
people who have started it.
It is we who can change the people.
Once we get realization, the transformation
starts taking place within us.
When the transformation takes place a person
becomes fearless.
He is not tempted easily by things, for example
I have known people, who use to take a lot
of bribes, have given up taking up bribe,
because their financial condition also improves,
their Lakshmi tatwa is awakened and they do
not take any bribes, their Dharma is jaagrut,
they do not drink, many people who were drunkards
have given up drinking, because the Dharma
is awakened within us, you just can’t bare
it.
Just like a human being cannot bear dirt but
an animal can.
In the same way, it happens to you, you just
don’t bear it, you don’t want to have
it anymore.
In the same way, your political situation
will improve, because what is the problem
today, what is the problem?
if you have went down to Maharashtra and there
the people said that we have a problem of
sugar, I said why, you produce a lot of sugar,
he said there is one fellow known as Sugar
king, he has hoarded all the Sugar.
I said really, then why don’t you inform
the police about it?
They said, when Janta government was there
he gave them money, now this government is
here, he gives them money, he gives money
to all police officers, he is driving all
of them and he also bribed us and made us
vote for certain people, who are under his
control.
I said, then you are responsible for this.
You get your realization and next time only
vote for or stand with a realized soul .Do
not vote for anyone who is not a realized
soul and you will see this country will change
just like this, the whole situation will change
.It is you who are misusing your votes, in
the villages even for one time need they give
votes.
How are you going to improve your people?
How this deterioration is going to stop by
only, by your parivartan, by your transformation,
that’s only possible through Kundalini awakening.
When the Kundalini awakening takes place the
man knows his esteem, he stands up like a
human being and he doesn’t behave like a
dog, who runs after every position you get,
every money you get, “give me, give me”.
It’s not like that.
He stands in his dignity and in his [not clear
] and nobody can put him down.
This is what it is; the Sahaja Yoga is such
a blessing, for all of us, in all the world,
wherever there is a chaos, it is everywhere
now and so many angles it is going to it,
for Samaj Karya also, now in Samaj specially
in the north, you see the condition is very
bad, the woman are treated very shabbily,
they say it’s the influence of the Muslim
religion and whatever it is.
But if you go to Turkey, you will be surprised
that the people treat woman with such respect
and such understanding.
In our own scriptures it is written that:
“Yatra naryastu pujyante ramante tatra Devata”[Manu
smriti 3-56] Means, where the woman is respected,
there resides the Gods, but the woman has
to be respectable also, if she is not a respectable,
no use respecting her.
It is both ways, but the way we treat our
woman, in the villages, specially in the North,
like Bihar, U.P, Punjab, Punjab is now better,
woman have taken over quite a lot.
But that should not be the case, woman should
remain woman but men must respect them.
What I mean, that woman must be respected
as they are and men must be respected as they
are.
They don’t have to change their places but
in these places, all Bengal all of them you
now how [unclear].
Women commit suicides in that country because
they cannot get married and they are put down.
If you cannot get married what does it matter?
You have to give dowry, if you don’t give
dowry you cannot get married.
All kinds of problems a husband will come
drunkard, he will beat his wife because he
is fallen in love with another woman, he is
going to some other person .The wife has to
come as out and she becomes a woman who has
no husband, everybody ill treats the woman.
All sorts of things are here, why?
Because we do not understand that woman is
the Shakti.
In her lies the Shakti we have to respect
the women.
When the women are not respected that country
goes to dogs and the women must know that
they are Shakti and they are to be respectable
and not to be frivolous and cheap the way
Indian women are now taking to western life
I am really shocked that means that our tradition
has no depth in it.
That the way we have accepted all these nonsensical
values of the West, where the West has gone
to dogs and we are going to dogs for this
I will hold the woman responsible who behave
so cheaply on the streets and in the offices
and in the houses.
It is the women who have to keep the Dharma
going.
Now with this.
It is very remarkable, what is happening,
if the mother of the house is not respected,
is treated like a servant, she has no place
in the family, husband comes from the office
and shouts at her, children cannot respect
her, they cannot be disciplined, if the mother
is not respected.
Your children can never be disciplined.
You see now, you talk of indiscipline, indiscipline
everywhere.
I remember, when I was young, we could not
do even a thing without asking our mother.
If we had our father we wanted to, he’d
say, “Did you ask your mother?
Go and ask your mother” In the family, in
the house she was the Grahalakshmi, she was
given all the keys all the money, not a single
pie was spent without asking her.
But these days, the woman have become so either
very miserly or so extra wagon that men do
not know what to do with them.
It was both ways, women have to be wise, they
are the axis the Dhuri of the society, that’s
only possible when they are realized, suddenly
I find very rebellious woman become so, so
beautiful, so beautiful and so women like,
so sweet, their, their tongue, their whole
behavior everything changes so beautifully,
it’s surprising, even western women I have
seen, who walk like horses normally.
If you see them they really walk like horses,
but they change their dresses and their whole
thing they become so feminine, so sweet, in
their talks and everything, then what will
happen to Indian women?
But men must know they have to respect women,
if they try to dominate their women, they
will become the same as the western woman
and you will not know what to do with yourself.
If the woman decides to be bad, there’s
no end to miseries that should not be done.
So, please make it a short circuit and let
us understand that for Sahaja yogi it is important
to respect the wife.
So, that there is discipline, still I must
give all my respect to the Indian women, despite
all these things, despite the, all the men
have changed their dresses, all the men have
become English, Indian women have still kept
their dresses and their discipline.
Our men still think, they are great English
people, but our Indian women are not willing
to accept that situation.
I am not saying that there is something wrong
with English, but if we are Indians we should
be Indians, if they are English they should
be English and in the same way with our life,
when there is realization, a woman becomes
a complete woman and a man becomes a complete
man and a complete man we have before us is
Shri Rama, how he loved his wife, in separation
and in meeting, how he loved and how they
despite all their love, how they suffered.
We have before us Shri Rama where he respected
his wife.
It is a Seashell for men to understand that
you are Indians and you have to behave like
them.
You do not know the greatness of our Indian
women.
If you do not treat them well I can assure
you a day will come only very cheap and nasty
and what you call demonic women will be born
here and you will be able to enter even your
homes.
You will be standing outside on your streets.
So be careful about it and also you has brought
us before , the way you treat your wife the
same way your daughters will be treated even
worse, then you will know what you did, so
be kind to her because she has married to
you she is not your slave.
Its is very important.
In northern India more because they think
that southern India, Maharashtra and southern
India women, men are henpecked unless and
until they beat their wives they are henpecked
according to them.
These ideas must be given up but this is only
possible when you get your realization real
joy of leading a very happy married life extremely
beautiful married life of mutual love and
mutual understanding develops I have seen
this happening to so many people the relationship
improving the relationship between parents
and children improving the whole thing becoming
so joyous and so beautiful and the children
becoming so obedient and so sweet, it’s
a beautiful thing so when the atmosphere is
fragrant with your spirituality the whole
aroma , the whole atmosphere we can say completely
charmed ,absolutely charmed by your peaceful
life.
This is the bliss we have to see .
Today I talked about these things because
void is very important thing for us where
all our social, samajic, political, rajkiya
and also our spiritual problems can be solved.
Apart from that I had told you yesterday about
our physical problems tomorrow I will talk
about other charkas to you I hope you have
understood today’s lecture.
I spoke in a very entertaining manner but
you have to know that all this entertainment
has to go within yourself, you have to take
within your self, it’s not meant for others
as soon as you say it is for other, the women
will look at the husbands and the husbands
will look at the wives.
They do not know it is meant for you and not
for others.
All of you should take it up, that am I doing
this, am I doing this, try to correct yourself,
you have to be decent husbands and decent
wives and I would like to see very happy married
couples amongst Sahaja Yogis, when this will
happen then the great souls will take birth
on this earth, you will see great people will
be born.
Already so many Sahaja Yogis have given birth
to very, very great souls.
You will be amazed they know Kundalini from
their very childhood this will happen I am
sure one day it will come and that all the
souls who want to take birth will be born
on this earth, especially in India.
Already lots of great souls I have seen also
in England, let me go I see in Australia I
am sure it’s happening everywhere.
But if you are realized souls you really become
perfect parents and you really invite great
souls on this earth to work it out.