for the Guru puja furnished to laughs
first he'll read it out see how this
guru Gupta business I never gave it to
anyone of you to read the reason is not
that is not true they say it's true but
it was told by Shiva - Parvati what is
the good why I can give you because all
these gurus in the market they say all
right I am your guru and this is guru
Gita in the Guru Gita is written give
all your money all your belongings all
yourself
Hanuman Adana your body your mind
everything to the Guru and become a
stupid food so they give it to that
that's why I didn't give it to you but
today rubbish and told him for the first
time but that doesn't mean that you
should follow the way it has been
described by sheer Oh
today the facts are shri adi guru
sakshat shri adi shakti such a chi
dakshinamurthy Chima that the shinning
l'Damian among Emma who in the Guru Gita
she Shiva who's also known as Shiva
chena murki
the one who faces the South is at the
request of she piratey telling her as to
what is the Guru Danny and all of you
who is the Guru then after over America
and loudly that's no and she shaver
tells she Parvati in the guru gita who
is the Guru and in the first he says
that in the word guru the first letter
the GU
highlights the attributes of Maya
whereas the second letter rule destroys
the illusion caused by the Maya so he is
first and foremost the one who destroys
the illusions that are caused by the
Maya he also creates him he destroys him
he alone has that position and therefore
the position of the Guru is the most
exalted and inaccessible even to all the
gods and she guru is worshipped by them
all salutations to Shi guru who pulls
out those fallen in the ocean of hell
while sitting on the tree of mundane
world
salutations to Shi guru who Sri Rama
Deva see Vishnu and Shiva and who alone
is the superior Brahman salutations to
shri guru who has created all knowledge
for benevolence of the people so that
they had the bridge to cross the ocean
of the mundane world
salutations to Shi guru who opens the
eyes of one who has become blind due to
the darkness of ignorance by anointing
them with the Kajal of knowledge
salutations to Shi guru for achieving
the Enlightenment in the world you are
my father you are my mother
you are my brother and you are my god
salutations to Sri Guru who is the truth
and in the light of this truth the world
becomes manifest and you are the one who
is the joy that in chance that world
salutations to Shi guru who is the Sun
the pure existence the truth having
known which the world a variety of forms
and objects ceases to appear as real
salutations to Sri Guru
whose form is cause in action and who is
present as the cause in all action
salutations to shri guru whose presence
is the cause and actions in everything
bring oneness brings the collectivity
brings the integration in the variety of
forms and objects salutations to Shi
guru whose two lotus feet dispel the
heat of duality and save us from all
calamities
salutations to shri guru with our speech
with our mind with our attention with
our eyes for the Guru is very Shiva and
Shakti together and whose two lotus feet
are red and white and splendorous I
meditate upon the she guru on the letter
GU which shows the state beyond the
three gunas and who which shows the
formless forms and who bestows on us the
form which is beyond the three gunas we
bow again and again - she guru for
destroying through the self-realization
the Karma's that we have accumulated
during the series of all our past lives
we bow again and again and again - she
guru for there is no principle above
that of she guru there is no penance
that you can do for the penance the
highest penances to be done to achieve
she guru and no knowledge can exist
beyond the principle which is she guru
we bow again and again - she guru who
has shown us the form of uninterrupted
canopy it has pervaded all living and
non-living things
salutations again to you - Sri Guru
whose lotus feet are bedecked with
diamonds which are the shooties and the
lustrous lotuses of the Vedas
salutations to she guru who
spontaneously awakens in us
all the pure knowledge salutations again
and again and again toosha guru who is
Chaitanya eternally serene beyond
confusion extremely pure beyond the nod
the Bindu and the caller the origin of
meditation is the form of Shri Guru the
origin of pooja is the lotus feet of sri
guru the first puja is the puja of the
lotus feet of sri guru the first mantra
the origin of the mantra itself is the
speech of shri guru the first liberation
the origin of all liberation is only by
the grace of sri guru sakshat shri
mataji nirmala devi