First of all we should know what powers we
have got, and also we should know how we are
going to preserve those powers and what more
powers we can very easily achieve.
The first power that you get after Realisation
is the greatest power on Earth. This is the
power of Shri Ganesha. It is only He can do
this job that you people are doing today,
and that power is of raising the Kundalini.
No one so far in the history of spirituality
has ever raised the Kundalini in such a short
time as you people are doing. It moves under
your fingers; it is absolutely Shri Ganesha’s
power which is given to you.
At the time when you are giving the Realisation,
even if you are caught up in any one of your
chakras, or you have any problem, even if
you are little bit possessed, even if you
are not such a good Sahaj Yogi, even if you
are not that much surrendered to Mataji, even
if you don’t have much sense of obligation
about Sahaj Yoga, still the Kundalini rises
under your fingers. This Ganesha key is given
to you by Shri Ganesh Himself within you;
to give you the confidence, to give you the
confidence that you can raise the Kundalini,
but not the feeling that you are raising the
Kundalini. If you go on without surrendering
yourself to Sahaj Yoga, after some time you
will lose this power, very fast.
The another power which you have got: At the
raising of the Kundalini of anyone, you can
notice it that, when the Kundalini rises,
that time there will be no obstruction of
any kind. Whatever may be the obstructions
around – say there’s a possessed person
next door, he would not disturb you at that
time. In your family there may be a person
who is a negative person, but if you are raising
the Kundalini, at that moment he will be kept
quiet.
At the time when you are moving your hand
on the Kundalini [it] is the greatest power
you are using. I don’t know how much shraddha
you have about yourself and about the power
that you have. At that time there will be
no obstruction on your hand by anyone whatsoever!
Even by mistake, nobody will hold your hand
or touch your hand.
The second power you have got when you are
raising the Kundalini, [is] that, at that
time when you will be raising your Kundalini,
you will be completely attracting the attention
of the another person within, like a magnet,
by which you should understand that you can
raise your Kundalini wherever you feel like.
When you are raising the Kundalini, supposing
there’s lot of noise going on, there are
all kinds of problems going on – supposing
you are going in the train, there’s a noise
of the train, or any such thing happening
– that time your attention will not be distracted,
but the attention of the person who is taking
the Realisation from you will not be attracted
by outside things at that time when you are
raising the Kundalini. That means that you
can give Realisation at any time because at
that time you reside in the lotus which is
closed.
The other power you have got, at the time
of Kundalini jagruti (awakening), that no
baser feelings will rise within you. Even
if you are a possessed person, at the time
of Kundalini jagruti you will not have baser
feelings, impure feelings about the person
whom you are giving Realisation. Maybe before
and after but not during, when you are giving
Realisation, these dirty feelings will not
come to you – automatically, you don’t
have to stop your mind, automatically it will
work out. You will be absolutely satisfied,
even if you are hungry you will not feel the
hunger or any physical need, at the time when
you are giving Realisation. There will be
no distraction of any kind; you won’t do
anything that is indignified at the time when
you will be raising your hand, because you
are being blessed with dignity. At the time
you are raising the Kundalini, you will never
joke, or you will never make fun, you will
not be frivolous – automatically! You try,
it won’t work out.
But these are your supporting powers. All
these five powers I have described are very
few of the thousands others, but these are
the five powers of Shri Ganesh.
Now these powers can be maintained if you
try to follow Shri Ganesh. His foremost quality
is that He does not know any other god or
anybody else higher than His own Mother. A
complete dedication and complete obedience
to Mother. I mean, sort of He is made out
of that obedience. Complete love and affection
for the Mother. He doesn’t argue, He doesn’t
question, He doesn’t do anything, and that’s
how these powers are, in Him, the maximum.
If you think by arguing with Me you are gaining,
you are sadly mistaken. You have to keep Me
pleased. Even Ganesha tries every minute to
keep Me pleased. Is a fact. So, please don’t
try to displease Me. I may not say anything
because outwardly I don’t say anything,
but your powers will be reduced.
The Ganesha’s fifth power is the power of
wisdom and that whatever He knows He can draw
it and write it down. Even that power you
have got. When you are raising the Kundalini,
you talk to the person in such a manner that
the person becomes wise. And you also talk
to him only that which is wisdom and also
you write or show him figures, automatically
which are right. Even if you don’t remember
your figures, they will come out right.
Now the three powers of Adi Shakti work in
you. One gives you longevity
and a clear-cut idea about your desires. If
your desires are right, all your desires are
fulfilled by this power – all your desires,
all! But the first one, one should know that
your desires should be right. For example,
now Sahaja Yogis want their ashram. Why do
they want ashram for? How many are willing
to stay in the ashram? How many are going
to take their children in the ashram? How
many are going to give their exclusive homes
and take their wives or take their husbands
who are not Sahaja Yogis in the ashram? And
how many of them are wanting only ashram just
because they will have some place to live
in a cheap manner? What is the purpose of
getting an ashram? Are you sure about it?
Have you been able to find out why do you
want an ashram?
If your desires are clear-cut then they will
be fulfilled, absolutely hundred percent.
That power you can achieve only by putting
your bandhan on your heart. Whatever desire
you have, you say it and put it on your heart.
Means you’re asking from your heart. Seven
times, you just give it a bandhan and the
work will be done. But don’t use it for
nonsensical things, because if you use it
for nonsensical things, this power will go
away. Use for something special, of a higher
level.
Now, by your second power you will automatically
meet people who are learned and who are sahaja.
You will also read books which are sahaja.
Even if you have to read some other books,
you will be able to know that this is not
correct and this is correct. And by that you
will be enriching your mind. When you will
start speaking, people will be amazed. Those
who have never spoken would be speaking very
well. Those who have never known poetry will
be writing poetry. Lots of things will happen
on the field of art also. Those who did not
know art will do marvellously in art.
But by the first power, which is the Adi Shakti’s
power or Mahakali’s power, you get the love
of all the people around. Everybody will feel
magnetically attracted towards you. And you
will be always guided by great souls and angels.
If you come across anybody who is meeting
an accident, you will stop that man from going
that way. If you are in an accident everybody
will be saved. You will seldom have an accident
-if you have it, you won’t be hurt much.
Amazing! All these powers come to you because
you are the children of Adi Shakti. The whole
Universe of the subtle, Divine Power is looking
after you individually. You’re all marked,
the mark is on you, you are bearing the mark,
and They are looking after you.
So this power of desiring is the power that
protects you. In all the way that is possible
it guides you, it looks after you, it gives
you peace. And this power gives you tremendous
faith in Sahaja Yoga. Ultimately you become
filled with the joy of Sahaj Yoga, and you
don’t like anything else but Sahaj Yoga.
To you, everything is Sahaja Yoga. But sometimes,
you know, we are identified with our ego and
we think our ego is Sahaj Yog, many a times
I have seen that. People like it because it
is identified with their ego. It should be
separated from that and should be brought
in our lives, in our day-to-day life, when
we are meeting each other, when we are talking
to each other, that joy one should see, one
ripple falling and another rising, another
falling, as you see in the sea. Becoming one
with each other. This power is within you
and it is working all the time that you are
loved and you are looked after.
By the middle power, I have told you, you
will give Realisation to people. You will
be able to tell their chakras. You will be
able to correct your chakras. This is all
by your centre power. And by this power only
you have a very great power over your will.
If you decide that you are going to be like
this you will be. If you want to be a happy
person you will be. The transformation will
be at your hand. You can transform yourself
without any difficulty that will work out,
if you use the central power of Mahalakshmi.
Of course, you will get better jobs, better
money, prospects, but not too much of it.
So much so, that you will feel very much satisfied
about it. So that your attention is more in
the centre. All other powers of Mahalakshmi
you will achieve later on.
There are many other powers of Mahalakshmi
which you have to achieve, but for that your
Sushumna has to be cleaned very much. For
that, you have to develop detachment in life.
Unless and until you develop detachment the
deeper powers of Mahalakshmi do not come up.
For example, even in the smaller things, like
having connection with Me, even that one is
to be a detached way. Even to say Aarti or
to do something, to come forward, that, “I
have to do it.” Even to invite Me for dinner
or this thing, every small thing, that “I
should do it,” is also attachment. If it
works out, well and good; if it does not work
out, well and good. You must say that, “Mother,
You come.” But if I cannot come, there should
not be slightest feeling an unhappiness, but
should be accepted as a part of that. This
detachment has to be developed for your Mahalakshmi
Power.
Then you go beyond. Your timing will be worked
out absolutely correctly – you won’t have
to see the time. There will be time which
will be your own. Whenever you will go, you
will find [that] everything worked out well.
So, to preserve this power of time, you must
not hurry-up too much, you should not be slaves
of watches. Just let it go. Do not have any
obstinacy about anything. Just doesn’t matter:
if it is ten o’clock, alright; if not, if
ten fifteen, doesn’t matter. Just allow
yourself to be drifted with the flow of Sahaja
Yoga. If it works out, well and good, if it
does not work out, well and good. Just keep
it like that. Then only you will be surprised
how this Mahalakshmi Power improves, and the
blessings of this power are tremendous.
Like that you have thousand and one powers
already awakened within you. For example on
Vishuddhi Chakra, you have sixteen thousand
powers, and all these sixteen [thousand] powers
are awakened in you, today as you are. Sixteen
thousand powers are awakened within you as
you are today. But when you speak you don’t
understand that when you are speaking you
are a Sahaja Yogi [and] with all these powers
you are speaking. When you eat you don’t
understand that this tongue belongs to a Sahaja
Yogi; you should not hanker after anything.
Like if somebody likes tea, he will go on
taking fifteen cups. That’s no good. If
he’s fond of one sort of a food, he won’t
take another food. Thinking too much about
food all the time, asking for food and organising
food all the time, that spoils Vishuddhi very
badly. Then talking ill about anyone, complaining
about anyone to Me will spoil your Vishuddhi.
If there’s some sense, if I ask, then is
alright, but all the time talking ill about
each other will spoil your Vishuddhi. If possible,
try to talk good about others -always. By
telling good about another person you will
help yourself and another person. For example
say, one Mr. X comes and tells Me something
against Mr. Y – I’m just stunned, because
Mr. Y has come and already told Me that Mr.
X is a fine man. So I tell Mr. X, “How do
you say that about Mr. Y, because he was praising
you?” So he keeps absolutely in a shocked
condition and he doesn’t know how to answer.
When you judge others, you should know that
you are judged by God. If you are judging
others, God has judged you also. So in His
judgment whatever marks you give to yourself
and to others are not going to be consulted
at all. It is His judgment which is going
to decide how far you are. Those who are in
Sahaj Yoga today, they may be some who think
that they are great Sahaj Yogis, big people.
But may be that they are not. And those who
do not think that they are any[thing] great,
they want to increase and improve their shakti,
they may be the people who are occupying very
high places. So, under these circumstances
one should never boast and should not have
wrong, false estimation about oneself. That
is the way you can preserve your powers much
better of your Vishuddhi, if you [don’t]
start talking ill about others to each other.
Also I’ve seen people start discussing Me,
and in a very funny way they do it. I think
the best way to deal with the problem is not
to speak about Me, and if you have to speak,
then know that it has to be absolutely positive,
otherwise you are harming yourself and you
are harming others. Then you don’t blame
Me for that!
So that’s how your Vishuddhi Chakra’s
problems are increasing, and they go on increasing.
Specially when you try to confuse yourself
and quarrel with yourself and you think that,
you see, Sahaj Yoga has gained by your coming
[then] you catch Vishuddhi. You have gained,
not Sahaj Yoga. Sahaj Yog is ruled by itself,
it doesn’t need your help. If there is Truth,
then by accepting Truth you are enhanced,
your position has gone up, not the position
of the Truth. So this idea from your head
must go right away – that you have any way
obliged the Sahaj Yoga, or that you have obliged
God by coming to Him! This idea must go down.
This will definitely make your head again
upside-down and your Kundalini will be again
back to its own position.
So to keep up even your Vishuddhi alright
is not easy according to many. But is the
easiest when you keep yourself in a state
of witness. And that is possible if you develop
the habit after Realisation, that everything
that you do or want or face is put into nirvicharita,
into thoughtless awareness. If you start that
habit you will be amazed – your witness
state will improve and that you will rise
in your being.
This is very important to understand that
without transformation, you have no meaning.
Whatever you have been, have been useless,
of no good. Whatever you are transformed,
you are of some use. So whatever you have
been, you do not be identified with that.
But whatever you have to be, you will try
to be that. And this power you have got, that
whatever you want, you will be that. But some
people are so funny that if you ask them,
“What do you want to be?” They will say
that, “I want to be a donkey!” All such
silly and foolish people are no good for Sahaj
Yog, once for all you must know. No use running
after such foolish people who have no sense
at all, and who are such gone cases. They
will come back, afterwards. But put your attention
on positivity and not on negativity.
Normally I have seen always negative people
turn towards the negative people. If there’s
one negative person standing, a person who
is negative will immediately go and talk to
that person, find out about that person, he
will have sympathy for that person; he’ll
like that person; all sorts of things will
be there. And first sign is that such a person
is a complete negatively possessed being.
Alright. Now if you have done that kind of
a thing, of being possessed or by getting
impressed by these negative people, you are
out. Either you are in the sea or out of it.
How can you be both? You’d better get out
from there and spare the rest. But if you
want to be in the sea then you must know that
you have to know swimming and you have to
take pride in swimming otherwise it has no
meaning, it is of no help.
Now you have got curative power, you know
that; you can cure people. But do not get
into that mess because there Mahamaya plays
Her part! If I find that you are getting into
your head the idea that you are very much
getting involved into a particular case of
your brother-in-law’s, father-in-law’s,
mother-in-law, then I’ll stop it, or you
get into trouble. If you start making money
out of it I’ll stop it. I do many things
by which I just stop it. And then you cannot
have that power in you. On the contrary, you
will suffer quite a lot, because you do not
know how to protect yourself from all these
bad things.
So, I have to request you that before starting
curing others, you first cure yourself fully
and also you can use My photographs for curing
other people. But you must know that there
is a very subtle thing in human beings that
they want, that everybody should say that,
“Oh, you are great, you have cured so many
people!” in a very subtle way, on a very
subtle base. So, one should not bother about
all these things. One should keep completely
detached about it. Because for one day or
two day, or for say about a year people will
come to you, “Get this man cured, that man
cured.” And then you will find that you
have found nothing, they were all bubbles,
all lost and completely vanished into thin
air!
So, do not cure anyone. If you have to cure
people, then you please give them the photograph
and ask them to work on them. You have got
power to handle My photograph and give it
to others. You have lots of powers which normally
common people don’t have because I do not
tell them many things that I tell you. And
thus you are a person of a very rare quality
and a rare blessing.
Now write it down how many powers you have
got, go home, and you will write one complete
book! Take it from Me.
May God bless you all.
Try to preserve all your powers. Respect yourself.
You are a lamp that is burning a light which
enlightens others in their mind. It’s a
very great thing: even one person like that
who was born among millions and billions of
people, and now here we have so many of you.
But quality-wise if you don’t rise it’s
going to be a hopeless case. So you must improve
your quality. All of you must improve your
quality, individually. Not criticising others,
not looking at others, but individually you
should understand your capacities and how
much you have given to others, and how much
you have really manifested out of what you
have got.
You have control over the sun, over the moon,
over the tides, and over the sea and all those
things – you have. But for that you have
to do a little more, which I’ll tell you
some other time. Now I don’t want you to
control all these things, and sit down on
top of a hillock and start showing off! Better
thing is you work it out first on human beings
and then I’ll give you all these, I’ll
tell you. You already have them awakened,
but I haven’t told you the trick, how to
do it. So best keep it to Myself.
May God bless you all.