An Indian Guru who came to Istanbul to teach Yoga is
in the focus of attention of the high society.
See who kneeled before the Indian Guru wanting
to find solutions for their problems.
Gamze Reisoğlu prepared the news.
It is sufficient to spectacular welcome ceremony in Istanbul
with flowers and songs to understand
how popular the Indian Guru Shri Mataji is.
The 75-year-old Indian guru came on
a wheelchair to avoid getting tired.
Devotees welcomed their Guru kneeling down before Her.
Some had tears in their eyes.
Not only Turks came to Sahaja Yoga conference in Istanbul.
Gurunun müritleri otobüslerle
Rusya’dan Malezya’dan kalkıp geldiler.
Shri Mataji continuous to receive
the high society in Her hotel room in Istanbul.
A concrete example of the interest shown t
o Her are the shoes letf in front of the door.
The devotees, knowing that Shri mataji likes flowers,
they decorated the hotel room with flowers.
There is a strong smell of  flowers
and incence in the room.
One of the Shri Mataji’s visitors today is from
an old Turkish family of Eczacıbaşı.
Nükhet Eczacıbaşı expressed her respect
by offering  flowers to Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji had a conversation with Nükhet Eczacıbaşı
who was sitting on her knees before Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji asked her if she fulfills her family duties.
Shri Mataji:  but you were a daughter,
you looked after the parents,
Nükhet Eczacıbaşı: I tried my best and
Yoga helped me very much
Just by looking into the young ladies face
Shri Mataji said that, she had a kidney problem.
Indian Guru who is said that
She is able to cure AIDS and cancer
took some sugar in Her hand
and put a healing power into the sugar.
Shri Mataji:  But be carefull about your health now.
Nükhet Eczacıbaşı: Yes,
It is important.
Nükhet Eczacıbaşı: Yes, yes, I will.
Take this and this will cooldown you.
Nükhet Eczacıbaşı: OK, I will.
Shri Mataji:  And you will feel better.
Nükhet Eczacıbaşı took the sugar and when she was leaving
the room Shri Mataji again explained to her how to use sugar.
Shri Mataji: Take it with a spoon and put more water.
Like other guests who are impressed
in this way by the Indian Guru,
we kneel down before Her hoping to learn Her secret.
The first assesment is positive
and Guru feels the energy.
Shri Mataji: She has got it already
Then together with Her assistant,
She makes a check up.
Indian Guru does not find a physical ailment
but She draws out attention to a mental problem.
Yogi Mahajan : Do you have feelings in your hands?
Shri Mataji: Now, you have to forgive, allright?
Yogi Mahajan : You don’t forgive.
You have to forgive. It is a mental problem.
Shri Mataji: Now, better?
Negative enegy is taken from the body
and now the mind is brought
to state where it is ready to forgive.