Today we are here to celebrate the resurrection
of Christ.
Resurrection of Christ has the greatest significance
for all the Sahaj Yogis.
And we have to understand that He resurrected
Himself so that we could resurrect ourselves.
The message of His life is His resurrection
and not His cross.
He bore the cross for us and we don’t have
to bear anymore.
I see lots of people having this drama going
on: they are carrying the cross across to
show as if we are going to do the job for
Christ!
As if He has left some work to be done by
these people who play a drama.
But all this drama is to deceive yourself
and to deceive others.
There’s no sense in playing such useless
things to show how Christ suffered.
To make you weep and to make you cry, Christ
did not suffer.
He suffered that you should enjoy, that you
should be happy, that you should lead a life
of complete bliss and gratitude to the Almighty
who has created you.
He would never like you to be unhappy.
Which father would like his son to be unhappy?
So we have to understand that His message
of His life, why He came on this Earth to
do the greatest job is that of resurrection.
If He had not resurrected Himself, I could
not have worked out Sahaj Yoga.
So we have to be eternally thankful to His
life and to Him, the way He did all these
difficult tasks, taking upon Himself.
That, we cannot do, we human beings, cannot
do it.
It’s only He being the Divine, He being
the Om, He being the Logos, He being the Brahma
could do it.
But now you all have ascended.
I can see on your faces: Christ writ large
on your faces.
It’s beautifully shining in your eyes and
twinkling.
He’s there within us, in our hearts, in
our eyes, and He has resurrected Himself and
He has resurrected you, too.
But now it is for you to resurrect other people.
You can resurrect other people, this is the
power you have got through Him, maybe, or
through your Kundalini.
But you have this power to resurrect other
people, but first and foremost thing [is]
you have to be strong like Christ: how He
obeyed His Mother and how He obeyed all the
demands of His life.
How He was committed and how He dedicated
Himself to this single task.
He didn’t bother as to develop His monetary
side or to become some sort of a big officer
or to become another great rider, or a swimmer,
or climb on the Alps, some sort of a thing
like that.
(laughter) He didn’t try all these tricks,
and didn’t try to hanker after all these
things that sometimes make us quite mad.
What He did was to establish His identity
as the Brahma itself, as the Divine vibrations
itself, which He established.
And what you have to do is to establish yourself
as the resurrected people, as the realised-souls,
as the Sahaj Yogis.
And this is going to be very easy.
Now everything is made easy for you: your
realisation, then your powers, everything
has beautifully settled within you.
It has worked out so beautifully, slowly and
steadily.
I don’t think I have ever tried to force
you to do something or have compelled you
to do something.
But through your own ascent you can see what’s
wrong with you or with the people about whom
we are talking.
And then you can also know through all these
powers whatever is to be known.
All that is unknown can be your own, everything.
But the attention should be towards your ascent,
towards the state.
Now ascent is not some sort of a physical
process.
It is not that you ascend some staircases.
It is a state.
It’s a state of your personality.
And there where I always say…
Excuse me, I think I’ll [remove my sweater].
The sun is showing its results.
See how the sun listens to me!
Can you help me, a little bit, to take out
things, thanks.
It’s very hot for me, I don’t know what
about you people.
He’s just telling me off (the Sun).
I forgot to tell you about the Sun so he’s
just troubling me, so I better tell! (laughter
and clapping).
They have been telling for the last one year,
you see, we’ve been thinking of coming here
for this puja.
And I was very anxious that we should have
the Easter Puja here, but the dates were not
very suitable, because those days the moon
would be waning.
So I thought, “How will I do it without
the moon?
We have to have the moon there.
It’s important."
So I thought, “We’ll have it sometime
later."
And suddenly it happened that I have to come
here: luckily I was here.
And then on the television for the last one
week, they have been telling it’s going
to rain heavily, it’s going to be very clouded
(laughter) and the temperature is going to
be very bad and it’s going to be very, very
heavy rains.
(laughter and clapping).
And again and again, every night, every time
they announced about the weather it was looking
even worse, every time.
So I thought, “Now what to do?”
(laughter) If you ask the clouds to move out
you have to have a tremendous breeze and that
may spoil your tent.
So somehow or other I just told the clouds
that, “You’d better move on to Newfoundland,
slowly, steadily, not with great speed."
And they did it.
And then the Sun which was very bright came
out.
Early in the morning I saw Him, red like my
sari.
So beautiful it was.
And you were all asleep but I was awake, very
early (laughter).
And I was watching the way it came up: just
like my bindi it came up.
I saw it, and I said, “Look at the sun!
How obedient, how dedicated, how beautiful!”
Whatever it is: today is Mother’s Puja,
you have to have proper light, you have to
have proper temperature.
So look at the sky!
Look at everything!
And then gradually it became pink like your
faces.
It’s beautiful!
It became pink, beautifully pink, and then
now it’s shining.
I’m sorry I should have given full tribute
to the Sun, the way He has acted.
So that’s why He is troubling me a little
bit, you see, to remind me!
So, as you know the Sun is the Agnya chakra.
Christ resides in the Sun.
And in the body, in the being, He is the Spirit.
When He’s the Spirit, He’s the moon.
And when He acts on the Agnya He’s the Sun.
Now we have seen in His life that He was absolutely
spotlessly immaculate.
He had no defects in Him.
He was a perfect personality.
“Then why did He want to resurrect?” one
can ask.
What is in His time, is the resurrection.
His resurrection is like making the way through
the Agnya chakra for all of you to pass through
it.
He was like the gate, or we should say He
was the One who opened the gate for all of
you.
Because He was so perfect, He had no problems
as we have of our chakras, our Kundalini.
He had no problems.
But He was the complete compassion in the
nature of vibrations: the vibrations became
complete compassion.
So much so that even when He was resurrected
and even before that when He was crucified
He said, “Oh, God, the Father, please forgive
those people because they do not know what
they are doing."
Such forgiveness, such compassion!
And the Mother had to watch all that, keeping
quiet, because that was the game, that was
the thing one had to do.
He had to play His game and He played it so
well.
So now when we talk about Christ, we have
to remember one thing: that He has done all
this for us, now what are we going to do for
Him?
He is the pattern we have to follow.
Supposing if that is the pattern we have to
follow, then it’s not that we carry the
cross on our shoulder.
That’s not the pattern you have to follow.
Many people think [that] because He carried
the cross, we can carry the cross.
Anybody can carry the cross!
In India, if you give about five rupees to
a loader, he can carry a cross across!
What is so great about it?
What is so great in carrying a cross on your
shoulder?
It’s nothing great.
Any wrestler can do it, anybody can do it.
That’s not the point!
The point is we have to carry the work of
Christ, of resurrection.
That is what we have to realise.
We have to understand the importance of our
being, of our lives, like Christ understood
that He has come for this great job here.
And though He came as a human being, though
He came as an ordinary son of an ordinary
carpenter.
Though on this Earth He had a body and He
lived like other human beings, still He knew
what He had to do, He knew what He had to
achieve and He achieved it.
I think His was the most difficult task, which
He achieved and which He furnished it, so
well, that today we are having all the benefits
of that.
Now let us see if we have done something for
Sahaj Yoga or not.
We all should examine ourselves: what have
we done for Sahaj Yoga?
Not carrying the cross, I mean to say.
Some people think when they travel in India
and if they carry the luggage of people downward
they are carrying the cross of Christ.
That’s not the way!
It’s something very, very serious one has
to think about.
And that seriousness is: how far we have achieved
that state, for that what have we done?
And a simple thing I have been asking all
of you: you have to meditate every day!
All of you have to meditate everyday.
But somehow nobody has time to meditate.
We are having these watches just to know that
we have to meditate, not for anything else.
Our lives are for meditation.
You need not spend all your twenty-four hours,
but you have to meditate!
Everyday you must meditate.
If you meditate your children will meditate.
And meditation is such a simple thing for
you, made so easy that all the elements you
can see work it out.
All your chakras are made of different elements
and when you clear out with the different
styles — I mean, you know all the methods
and the techniques of Sahaj Yoga — with
that when you clear out the chakras, when
you clear them out you are absolutely free,
absolutely at that stage where you have to
be.
But if you do not do this much even — is
to meditate — it’s going to be very, very
difficult for me and for you to achieve, for
which you have come on this Earth.
It’s a tremendous task that I have taken
over, I know that, but I know how to do it,
and you also know how to do it.
But the trouble is you get entangled into
your different conditionings.
Now, by now you must have realised, all these
so-called religions in anybody’s name: whether
it is in the name of Islam, in the name of
Christianity, in the name of Hinduism, in
the name of Sikhism — all this is falsehood.
It has no truth in it.
They have all tried to use it for their own
purposes.
There’s only one truth and that is: all
these great prophets and all these great incarnations
came on this Earth for your ascent and not
for establishing those religions who are just
interested in money.
In these religions also you will find there
are people who are either left-sided or right-sided.
There are some religions which preach you
should be very, very strict: you should not
do this, you should not do that, you should
not drink, you should not smoke.
There are some who say you should not marry,
you should not look at women, you should not
look at men — all kinds of restrictions.
Even in Hinduism you will be surprised, there
are so many restrictions.
If you see the amount of superstitions that
exist and that are created by brahmins in
India you will be shocked.
For everything there’s a superstition: if
you walk with the left hand ahead, that means
this, if you walk with the right hand, then
that means this; if you sit like this, that
means that.
Everything!
They have made a human being into a machine
and there’s no spontaneity about it.
All kinds of absurdities there are in Islam,
too.
But when we find them in a free place like
England, where there’s complete left-sidedness,
where you can do what you like but still you
are a Christian: if you drink, it’s all
right; if you have ten wives, it’s all right;
if you have fifteen keeps, it’s all right.
Anything you do is all right as long as you
go to church and pay money!
So there’s nothing [forbidden], especially
for the Protestants – that’s the religion
I was born in, where everything is allowed.
Now when we come to this kind of a thing,
what is the Christian religion is, then, comes
to, that, if you ask them the road, they’ll
tell you which way to go — that’s Christianity.
It’s coming to that end.
Now, all these religions either are indulging
into the Right Side or onto the Left Side.
Some people like the Left Side and some people
like the Right Side.
I will tell you the story of a priest, I went
to see him in Russia.
I think I have told it to some people before.
I went to Russia and the Russian people asked
me, “What would you like to see?”
So I told them I would like to go and see
some churches.
So they said, “All right, very good, we’ll
take you to a church."
So they took me to church and it was that
Greek Orthodox Church, and a Black Order,
which is supposed to be the highest.
I don’t know how they call it.
So we went inside and the priest said, “All
right, today I’m sorry, we cannot offer
you meat because our fasting is there.
But we’ll have lunch."
So we had a very sumptuous lunch and all that.
But the priest was only busy drinking, because
it was a fasting, so drinking is allowed,
according to them!
So he was drinking and drinking and drinking.
He drank so much that he forgot we were there!
We were supposed to be VIPs: just lost himself
into drinking!
So we thought better now have an honourable
retreat.
So we got up and walked out of that place
and this fellow didn’t even come to wish
us.
And these officers, the Russian officers,
didn’t drink, and didn’t do anything,
and they were laughing and laughing.
He said, “See now, this is Christianity!
That’s why we didn’t want to take to Christianity."
So I said, “But see, that’s not Christ."
They said, “That’s true, but what these
people are saying, is it Christianity?”
I said, “It’s not."
Now this gentleman, was supposed to be the
highest person in spirituality living in Russia!
So they have told me a story about the tzars.
You see, tzars wanted to have some religion
because they thought, “Everybody’s having
a religion, we have no religion.
Must have some religion."
So they sent for some people and the people
who came forward were Catholics to begin with.
So the Catholics said, “All right, you can
drink in Catholic religion."
I don’t know how they got this idea, but
it’s all right.
“Catholic religion you can drink but you
cannot have more than one wife."
The tzar said, “No, that’s not possible!
We have to have many tsarinas, you see, for
different purposes.
So we can’t have that religion!”
So they cancelled it.
So then the Islam: you see that time I think
they were no hindus available, thank God!
They had the Islam, Islam people went, and
the Islamic people said, “No, all right,
you can have five wives, it’s all right,
but you cannot drink."
They said, “That’s impossible!
How can we follow Islam?
That’s not possible!”
So, cancel it!
So these orthodox people — orthodox, you
see, the word orthodox remember that — they
came.
They said, “No, we are just in the centre,
you see.
We don’t mind if you drink, we don’t mind
if you have many wives, we don’t mind.
Only thing is, you have to pay us well!”
Tzars said, “All right, that’s good, let’s
have this religion!”
And that’s how they had this religion there.
So this is the situation of the religion today.
All these religions have become sort of deformed
statues, good for nothing.
So now the inner religion within us is the
Sahaja dharma, which has to be fully followed.
Now, I told, in India, that now you are all
become Sahajas.
The story is like this, that there was a villager
who became a Christian.
So he came down to Allahabad to become Christian.
So he told them that, “You have to give
me a big name because now I am Saheb, I have
become an English man.
So you better give me a big name."
They said, “What name you want?”
He said “Give me the name of Alexander the
Great!”
So they called him Alexander.
But his name was Blondie, you see.
His real Indian name was Bhoora, so they called
him Alexander Bhoora.
So Mr.
Alexander Bhoora came to Allahabad and went
to the River Ganges for having his bath.
So the priest said, the pastor, he said, “You
can’t do that!”
He said, “Why?
Why can’t I do that?”
He said, “No, you can’t go and have bath
in the River Ganges because the Christianity
will drop out, you see!”
If he goes and has a bath in the River Ganges.
He said, “This you can’t do!”
So Alexander Bhoora said, “If I have become
saheb, I have become Englishman, that doesn’t
mean I have given up my religion!”
You see!
This is exactly what is happening to us when
we try to follow any religion whatsoever.
Now we are all identified with our so-called
religions in which we were born.
For example, if I told Indians, “Now, you
don’t go to temples!
You are not to go to any temple, even if it
is a swayambhu temple, unless and until you
have told me, don’t go to a swayambhu temple
at any cost."
There are many churches also where there are
very good statues, we can say, or have got
something which are really swayambhus, but
they are very few.
So you tell me and then go.
But they wouldn’t listen to me, they won’t
listen, and when they go there they catch
on their Agnyas.
Once I went to see one temple which was of
course a swayambhu temple, no doubt, so some
Sahaj Yogis decided to go there.
But I didn’t ask them, they didn’t tell
me.
When they came back, as soon as they saw me,
they all fainted.
I said, “What happened?
Where did you go?”
“Oh, we went to this temple."
I said, “Why?
You never told me.
And what do you have here [on your forehead]?”
You see, the Brahmin put the teeka (bindi)
and it’s finished!
Then it took them one month to clear out!
Now they don’t go, they’ve had enough
of it.
Same with the Christians: now the other day
I heard about the Paris episode where people
wanted to have weddings in the church, in
Paris.
So they must have special dresses!
So somebody came here to buy some special
dresses from…what shop is that?
I forgot the name, some big name.
So the special dresses must be worn because
they have to go to the church!
And when they came out of the church with
those dresses, they had become bhoots.
I was surprised, what has happened to these
twenty-five of them?
What has happened is that in the church there
are many dead bodies buried, and they are
all caught up.
So when you go also to see the beautiful architecture,
go with a detached mind.
Don’t think that you belong to that church.
You don’t belong to any church.
You don’t belong to any temple.
Don’t belong to any one of these forms,
then only you will ascend.
And I have to tell you today that Christ did
not belong to any religion.
He didn’t follow any religion.
He followed His own spiritual religion.
When He went to one church where there were
people who were discussing, I mean they were
Jews, He went there and He was talking to
them.
The other day I saw a beautiful painting they
had given on the newspaper, a very beautiful
famous painting where Christ is talking to
the doctors and He is holding His, rubbing
His Left Swadhishthana, very nicely, and all
the doctors, one of them is listening to Him,
one of them is looking at Him, sneering at
Him, another one is little bit paying attention
to Him.
He’s just rubbing His Left Swadhishthan.
It’s clearly [shown].
You can see it so clearly!
And so now, with these new achievements, you
must rise above all these things and you must
understand that we have to be very independently
looking at ourselves.
We are no more belonging to any religion.
We belong to the religion of God which is
Sahaj.
And Sahaj is the religion, it will spread
only when you really become nothing but Sahaj.
But that’s something I don’t understand
— it doesn’t work out.
I met somebody from, I forget that, there
was, say, called ‘Hamaty’ or something
who was supposed to be an incarnation or something.
His disciples absolutely, I should say that
they behave in such a manner that you can’t
believe it: how ardently they believe in this
man.
Whatever he says, whatever he does, how they
believe in him.
It’s very surprising.
You meet anyone who is following any guru,
anyone, you’ll be surprised the way they
are fanatic about this fellow and they will
not hear anything against.
Leave alone that, but if he says, “You stand
on your head for the whole night,” they
will do it!
I don’t know what happens: when it comes
to falsehood, we try to follow it, and when
we know the truth, this is the truth, then
we take advantage and we try to compromise.
We think the truth will not do anything about
it.
Not that truth will punish you, it will not,
because you are realised-souls.
It will not.
It will not punish you up to a point.
But remember that Ekadasha is absolutely working
at the same time.
If we do anything wrong, like these people
went to the church, they were all caught up.
Now they may say that, “Mother, why should
we be caught up?
We are Sahaj Yogis."
Because you are vulnerable, you are vulnerable.
Yet you have not reached that stage.
If you reach that stage, then when you go
there, all the church people will come out
of the church and run away.
They’ll start shaking before you.
They will not know what has happened.
I have seen when I enter into any church all
the candles start going chuk, chuk, chuk,
chuk, chuk, chuk, and people start wondering
what has happened.
Even when they are having a dinner or something
and there is a candlelight dinner I am surprised
the way every candle starts flickering and
people start looking.
Because the bhoots are sitting before them,
you see, so the candles immediately show that
these are the bhoots sitting here.
With all this knowledge that you have, the
light you have within yourself, by which you
are enlightened, still if you are going to
these left and right-sided things, it’s
very, very dangerous.
We see that also, today, I must tell you about
the part that is politics.
In politics also these people have developed
two types of theories: one is left-sided,
one right-sided.
The left-sided theories are democratic, where
you can indulge into anything you like.
It’s the individual that is important.
The individual indulges into everything and
you should not stop him from doing whatever
he likes, he’s an individual: so he has
a right to cut his nose, he has a right to
cut his eyes, to do what he likes.
An individual is allowed to do what he likes
to do, and then what happens [is] that we
find this democracy becomes a demonocracy:
everybody is a demon.
Everybody is busy cutting throats, cutting
all the basis and the roots of life because
everybody is Brahma, becomes a great personality,
because the individual is so great and the
collective is lost, completely lost.
But on the other side, where it is more discipline,
more aggressiveness, more controls and everything
[with] the Right Side, which we can call as
communism, where people are controlled all
the time.
Now why?
Because for the collective the individual
must sacrifice.
In that case, the individuals become weak
and if the individuals are weak, then the
collective cannot be strong: it cannot be
strong.
The individuals have to be strong.
For example, you will see that the people
who come from communist countries, they drink
more than people who can drink here.
Or those who come, say from Islamic countries,
where they don’t touch anything, can drink
more than even sardarjees.
So you can imagine what is the situation of
human beings is that, out of fear if you try
to control him, he goes to the Right Side.
But he is in no way perfected, he’s not
transformed, he doesn’t accept the situation,
he doesn’t become that, he doesn’t have
that power to control himself.
He doesn’t get over his sinning aptitudes.
He’s still there.
As soon as he gets a chance he falls into
it.
So that fails.
So the individuals are weak in that case.
And where there is complete abandonment, do
what you like, live the way you like, indulgences,
all kinds of things, so you find [decadence].
I mean, everyday you see and you say, “Oh
God, this is a decadent society, this is happening!”
Decadence is because an individual [to] whom
you have given all these powers, has no power
to bear them.
An individual cannot bear money.
He cannot bear power of any kind.
He cannot bear love.
He cannot bear kindness.
He cannot understand peace because he’s
still an individual.
But when an individual becomes the collective
— this is the ascent through the central
path — when he becomes the collective, in
his strength he strengthens the collective.
And also the collective looks after, protects,
and guides the individual.
This is what Sahaj Yoga is.
So the politics of Sahaj Yoga is that you
have to become the collective personality.
And there where we feel that still we are
something great, we are different, we are
Indians or we are from England or from France,
still if you are identified then you are not
collective.
In collective sense we are all one, part and
parcel of one being.
Then you are really acting as collective being
and you are one with the Divine.
Where the Sun is looking after you, the Moon
is looking after you, the winds are looking
after you; all the Mother Earth and all these
elements are working.
Ether, everything is working for you and you
are so well-protected and blessed by the special
quality to enjoy the joy.
Then you really become sensitive to that joy,
when you are one with the whole.
Like if supposing this finger or this finger
is not one with the whole, is numbed out…as
it happens in leprosy, what happens that this
finger becomes numbed out.
Even if a rat eats it off we don’t know
because there is no connection, no nerves
acting, it’s insensitive.
In the same way if you are not collective
and not bothered about collective you are
going to be dropped out.
You are not going to be there to enjoy the
beauties of your own glory and that of the
collective.
So one has to understand that we have to be
strong ourselves, we have to ascend and we
have to be collective.
It’s very easy to find out faults with others.
Very easy to find faults with the leaders.
Very easy also to find faults also with Sahaj
Yoga, sometimes with me.
Better find faults with yourself.
The rest I’ll look after.
First you just find faults with yourself and
try to understand others and love others and
enjoy the company of others.
This, once you decide that we have to enjoy,
I tell you, it’s so spontaneous.
Just this decision, this faith, within you
that, “I’m going to enjoy now my Spirit.
I’m going to enjoy the collective within
me,” that’s the Spirit.
Just this decision itself will give you the
power to enjoy.
But the decision should be firm, no hypocrisy,
no playing games, no ego, no conditioning,
nothing, just pure desire within us that we
have to be the Spirit.
And the Spirit which is the collective being
within us.
I hope today on this day of resurrection,
we have to be thankful to Christ very much
for showing us the way and also we have to
be very much concerned and alerted about ourselves:
Where are we?
Where do we stand?
What are we up to?
What are we doing?
What is our responsibility?
What is expected of us?
Why all these blessings are given to us?
There’s no sacrifice in Sahaj Yoga, no sacrifice.
Nobody wants you anything to commit or to
do or membership or anything like that.
I think it’s my commitment.
As I said, that God has the commitment but
you also have one commitment that your desire
should be pure.
That’s the only thing, that, “Let my desire
be pure!
No impurities of any kind, should work it
out."
As Christ had His desire, so pure, and that’s
what He achieved.
I am sure you can all achieve a lot in your
life.
Today is my sixty-fifth birthday.
Now imagine, I’m sixty-five years of age
and at this age most of the ladies, you see,
just, I don’t know what they do.
(laughter)
So now you must come up and work out everything
as far as possible, thinking that we all have
to stand up.
Now the children are coming up.
They are also going to stand up.
You are all looking younger to me and younger
to me.
Every day I see you, you look younger.
Sometimes I don’t even recognise you, the
way you look younger and I think, is he the
son or is he the father?
The situation is such that you are all blessed:
you’ve got jobs, you’ve got everything.
And everybody tells me, “Mother, this is
what has happened, that has happened!” everything.
Now, so what?
These are temptations, be careful.
This is not what you wanted.
What you wanted is the state of that complete
faith within yourself where you don’t have
to ask, nothing — everything will work out.
It works!
That’s [what] the point is.
So, I hope next time when we meet I’ll see
even younger people than what I see today
and I’ll be able to recognise you.
Christ died at a very, very young age, very
young age.
He was very young, I must say.
But how much He has done for humanity.
Nobody could have achieved that much in that
small age as He has done it.
It’s remarkable!
It’s really remarkable!
That’s what I expect you to follow, His
footsteps in doing remarkable things.
And let me see all of you, every one of you
have to do something great.
And today is the day of certain promises.
May God bless you for that.
And I thank you very much for this birthday
of mine.