Today's Puja we have arranged of Durga or
the Kali. That is the destroying form of the
Goddess of all the evil and negativity. This
we had to do it in France, because I feel
very strongly that day by day, in general,
France is going down and down and down. While
you people are coming up, the rest of the
France is in the most pitiable condition.
Firstly, as you understand, is the Catholic
church, which - perhaps you are not aware
of, perhaps maybe - because you don't read
any other languages, you just read French
compulsorily by this country. So you have
no international views or international news
that this Catholic church has done so many
horrible things in the past, that is unbelievable
that they have anything to do with God. They
burnt many cardinals in the heart - roasted
them.
Not only that, they killed so many people
who ever tried to utter a word about them.
They were much worse than Muslim people. They
went to other countries like South America,
America - all these places they're all Catholics
- even our country. And they killed millions
and millions of people.
Now as this is Kruta Yuga that has started,
one of the things as I said yesterday is that:
you will have to pay for whatever you have
done, on mass scale or individual scale. If
that is the case, then one must know that
France has to pay a lot and this Catholic
church has to pay more. Catholic church has
just taken out yarns out of their heads and
started a theory of original sin. That's how
to condemn every other Incarnation, every
other Prophet - that they were all with original
sin. And even they said Mary was born with
original sin, for many popes they were discussing
it.
This shows that this whole hocus-pocus religion
of Catholic church had to establish itself
by forcing people, by torturing them, by taking
all their ideas into their own control, give
them funny ideas like original sin. Another
is that you must confess, giving them the
left Vishuddhis. They treated women as nothing
and to Mother of Mary they called Her a woman.
And this Paul, as I told you yesterday, is
a fact.
Now it's necessary for Sahaja Yogis to understand
how this Catholic church is so dangerous and
has been doing such harm. As there has been
so many books about it - that you people don't
read, because it's not in French. There are
English books from America - you must learn
English. It's very important now I feel, that
all the French must know English, they must
read English. French will not give you the
international personality that you are supposed
to acquire. You had some scholarship, not
much. The real scholarship comes from England
and also from America in English language,
and also from India. One gentleman who tried
to translate all these things in UNESCO, he
was thrown out by your media. Your media is
taking full advantage that you don't read
any other newspapers; they are doing whatever
they feel like. All kinds of scandals, all
kinds of sensationalization - whatever they
want to write, they write in free press. On
one side there's suppression of natural life
of human beings, let them to go to Freud.
Freud is the dirtiest man you can think of,
who has put his ideas into your head. But
as if you are already brainwashed people that
you accepted all that. How could you accept
Freud? If Freud had come to India, they would
have killed him in no time! What happens is
that, somehow or other - I don't know what
is the reason, I don't know where to place
it, but the wisdom is not there. There is
no maturity, there is no wisdom. America I
can understand because it is only two-three
hundred years old. But what about the French?
They have not been able to mature but they
have become extremely frivolous. Maturity
is finished.
One of the reasons could be that they want
that you should be always young. In India,
young people are called as stupid: you call
it gadha pachisi, means in 25 years they are
donkeys. They are never regarded as sensible
people to be followed. And gradually by this
movement from Catholic church to Freud, what
has happened that you haven't got your own
personality to understand what is right and
what is wrong. Of course I must say Sahaja
Yogis must have done lots of punyas and must
be very courageous people to be born in this
country. Otherwise I don't know how you could
have taken your birth here. The law is so
funny that they said it depends on the mood
of the magistrate. (Shri Mataji laughing)
You see the magistrate doesn't know the law.
Such a stupid country in modern times I've
never known. Nowhere in the world there's
such a stupid law as it is here. Of course
in America, there is no justice, they do what
they like. But here is so-called modern people.
What is their condition is that they have
no sense of law. If you ask them, "What is
the law?" They don't care. It's the mood of
the magistrate. Now supposing he has had a
big drink in the last night, second day he
comes with a hangover, so finished. And then
he will be very much biased towards the drunkards
only.
So here it is becoming such a horrible society
that Indians would be shocked, beyond doubt,
but nothing but prostitution. To see and to
be seen. Why? Every woman has to dress up
in such a way that she should be attractive,
for what? Is she a prostitute? All kinds of
bathroom cultures developed. For example French
bath, you know what it means, all over the
world. It's a very dirty habit of laziness,
it comes because of drinking. If you drink
too much, next morning you are so lethargic
that you take just a French bath and go.
So, please try to remember as French Sahaja
Yogis, that your task is much more difficult
than the task of other countries, because
it lacks complete wisdom. Neither you'll find
in your institutions, nor in your government,
nor in any education. It's lacking wisdom
completely. And to have wisdom, according
to these Freudian people, is that you are
egoistical! They have such funny ideas from
the yarn of Mr. Freud that no sensible man
would accept. But people have lost their senses,
and like blotting paper, whatever is filthy,
destructive, horrible, subhuman they try to
absorb. Supposed to be Christian nation.
Please, all Sahaja Yogis must understand:
You must get hold of books and find out, where
are we? I worked very hard in France, you
know that very well. I used to think, this
is the gate of hell. But it is much worse
than that, it's a mire of filth and you are
born here and you have become like lotuses,
so fragrant and beautiful. You'll have to
fight it out: I am always with you, all My
powers with you. But remember that you have
to fight the society, you have to save so
many people, you have to rescue them.
Children are given liberty, "Do what you like."
They have no sense of liberty! Supposing there's
an aeroplane, which was not fixed properly
and made to fly. What will happen to the aeroplane?
If the children are given liberty without
the right sense of their duty and the right
sense about themselves, what will happen to
them? Why children are born to parents? It
is - to get spoiled, to have liberty or to
get some guidance? You cannot guide your children.
They are so rude, they are so arrogant. They
have gone off, completely. You know for one
month we had to struggle with these western
children and we had come to the point of urge
of closing down that school because they were
really violent children, as if coming from
some jungle. Even the jungle animals have
some sense. So you've to think about your
children. What's going to happen to your children?
What is going to be their situation? If they
are going to live in the same manner in this
dirt, these children will turn out to be waste,
just a waste! They will have no education,
no character, no personality, they'll end
up with AIDS or with drugs or something like
that. I do not see any future for the children
of France, no future.
And you have to fight that, "We want to have
future for our children, we don't want them
to be ruined." And you must have courage,
to fight it. It's very important to have courage.
If you do not have the courage, you cannot
fight it. And today's Puja is to give that
courage in your hearts. See it all around
you, what's happening? You are all nicely
enjoying yourself in the realm of God, (Shri
Mataji smiling) you have entered into the
Kingdom of God. But what about the rest of
the people? The majority of the people, where
are they going? What is going to be the future
of this horrible Mooladhara place?
Now Freud has been discovered as a fraudulent
man, and now there are books after so many
years, when he has already ruined the people
all over the world. But the worst of all they
have ruined here.
It's a responsibility specially of the women
I think, because they are responsible for
the society. The society of France has gone
to dogs and for you to now take up upon yourself
to talk against this kind of anarchy that
is working out the destruction of your families.
If the women decide, I am sure, they can very,
very easily work it out. Instead of asking
for liberation nonsensical, you better ask
for the ascent of this country.
I know I've worked very hard and you are all
there. I am very happy to see that you all
are there to fulfill the desires of the Divine.
Because now you should know in a very big
way, masses of masses of people will be destroyed.
Not from without but from within. Suddenly
you'll hear so many millions disappear with
this disease.
Also you must protect yourself, all of you:
always give yourself a bandhan; always lead
a clean life. There are certain hygienic rules
of Sahaja Yoga, please try to follow them.
Do not neglect it. If somebody gets AIDS,
you'll not have him in Sahaja Yoga, whatever
may be the conditions, whatever may be the
reason. You have to be very careful, also
I would say never treat a AIDS patient. Like
the one yesterday who was arguing with Me,
actually because they have only two types
of people: one who are arrogant and another
one which always think that it's better they
should die. They have no will to live. So
there are only two types of people, either
right-sided or left-sided. And they can never
ascend. We have tried, we have tried, of course
one first one is living for the last seven
years, but still. He has no faith in himself.
Maybe next generation might be better on,
if they come back. But as far as this generation
is concerned, you should know your responsibility
is very great. All the Sahaja Yogis must take
a vow that they'll fight this society and
try to save their country and their countrymen
from a complete disaster. There is going to
be no war, only they will fight themselves
and die. It's a very serious matter.
For that, we decided to have this Puja of
Durga today that all negativity should be
destroyed. So many Deities build up the body
of Kali. Every part of Her body was created
by a Deity, looked after by a Deity, and is
also, later on, is reflected in you all. So
they say that God has made human beings in
His own image, I would say, I've made you
in My own image, all the Deities at your disposal.
They're all with you, and they have created
you - if you see it minutely - it is the Deities
who have brought forth all the beauty that
you had. They have made all this beautiful
congregation, beautiful transformation, and
they have created such angelic people out
of you. They are always working it out, but
one thing you have to do is to have the drive.
You had pure desire to ascend, but for what?
You want to have the light, but for what?
You want to become gurus, for what? To save
people, for their salvation. Only through
your channels I can work out Sahaja Yoga.
If I could work out Myself, I would have.
It's not question of killing one rakshasa.
God knows how many there are, rakshasas and
rakshasas. And they are everywhere, even within
you they were. Now they've gone out.
So you have to do full justice to Sahaja Yoga,
that's very important. I knew the puja would
be very late, because Kali's puja is always
done in the night, after twelve. So it had
to be this way. Though last night I slept
at four o'clock and I, tonight, I don't know
what am I to do, - it all works out. It's
all worked out. But you have to have deliberations
and you have to think, "What can we do to
change this?" Why not write some books, why
not write some experiences? Get them published
in French only. Let the French know what's
happening outside. Get some of the books translated
- some American books, some English books.
At least give quotations from there. How they
are unaware. First this Catholic church has
to go away. It will, no doubt, I am sure about
it. They are literally frightened of us.
And we have to now really show them what we
are capable of. And the funniest thing is
that a president has chosen his lady-friend
as the prime minister. I mean, it's not possible
in any sensible country. It's never heard
of. I must say, English are thousand times
better. They are really very good. At least,
as far as administration is concerned, as
far as their parliament is concerned, the
justice is not stupid like this, it's based
on law, not based on the mood of a magistrate.
How you are still continuing with such stupidity
which are really even before medieval age:
primitive, people are absolutely primitive
to accept such laws. At least you can write
a book about the strange laws of French, one
title. How it has harmed. There is a very
nice book "Fraudulent Freud". Please read
that, and see how Freud has ruined the French,
how their brains are twisted, how they have
twisted ideas. You are also intelligent, clever
people. So if not with the sword, Kali has
to work through the pen.
I never knew it was in that bad shape, though
I knew it was. So this is a challenge for
all of us, and let Me see what you can write,
all of you - put together your experience:
how the French parents behave, how the grandparents
behave, what's happening in this country and
all that.
They are living in fool's paradise. They don't
know how destruction is just hanging over
their heads.
Though you are all saved, but you have to
think of others, that is what Sahaja Yoga
is, that is not only that we care for the
bhaktas - like Kali just wanted to protect
the bhaktas, the sadhakas. But you have to
protect many, many more people. You have all
the powers, just assume them and use them.
You can do it. Your media is the worst of
all and we can start the newspaper also calling
it anti-media. What can they do to us? Or
some sort of an independent name, we can give
it. And it should be open for people who are
suffering from media sensationalization. They
can write: how the media is harming them,
how they are giving false reports and things.
We can! Why not? I am sure it will work out.
Think it over what you can do with your pen.
Whatever you have gained, whatever you are
enjoying: beautiful music, all the Pujas,
everything. But think of others. They are
already drunk and tossing their heads on their
pillows. Think of them. They, when will they
feel this joy? I simply feel pity for them
that they should have taken to all these bad
things, because of the suppression of the
Catholic church. It's the Catholic church
which has suppressed them, that's why they
have come to this. No other way - reason why
they should accept this kind of thing.
In Sahaja Yoga, we do not do all these things,
we're in the centre. We do not have this kind
of problems, because we don't suppress anyone,
nor do we go to the other extreme of indulgences.
I think the whole Europe can be divided into
two types of people: one are Anglo-Saxons,
and others are Latins. Anglo-Saxons are right-sided
and the Latins are left-sided: they cry, weep,
miserable, they indulge into dirt and filth.
Just these two types they are. Now unluckily
you are in the Latin side. So here, Catholic
church is prospering. Now, if you see to the
Latin side and understand to what extent they
have gone to the left side, and getting to
the left side what diseases you get, very
nicely, make a list of them. So what I said
will work out in France: the left-sided incurable
diseases. As it is, you walk on the street,
you find at least three, four mad people,
lunatic people walking, you'll find. Very
simple it is. Don't have to go to the lunatic
asylum, on the street! They'll be all talking
and saying things, but it's all there. That's
why they drink, that's why they are miserable.
I do not know what are the statistics of the
diseases.
So the problem is extremely grave, very grave.
And you have to work it out, with the gravity
of your gurupada which you have asked Me the
other day - you asked for the status of a
guru, for ladies as well as for men. And I
said, "All right, start!"
I hope you all have heard the song I've made,
for asking.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside in Marathi]
All right once they will sing that song.
They will sing that song to you. There are
different request from the Mother, and in
this the last one is that: "Mother, now you
give us the gurupada, the status of a guru."
But every guru has a duty: to cleanse the
society in which he lives. It's his duty,
he has to fight it. Christ fought it alone,
so many saints fought it alone, they were
treated very badly, put in jail, given poisons,
things, but they fought it. In the same way
you stand on Truth, and you have to fight
it. Because you are saints.
May God bless you!
[Yogis sing: "Vinati Suniye Adishakti Meri".
Shri Mataji speaks aside in Marathi]
They'll repeat it twice, so you can also.
I don't think all of you have heard it, because
those who came to Guru Puja must have.