Actually Christians do not know anything about
His becoming.
How He became Christ or what was the need
to have Christ or a son to come down.
Why not God Himself could do the job.
And this is the reason why I would request
you to read for yourself the incarnation of
Maha Vishnu by which you realize why Christ
was born.
And it is the most important incarnation because
He is the principle.
He is the principle of creation.
The Tattwa as they call it in Sanskrit language.
He is the tattwa.
Ganesha, who resides in the Mooladhara gradually
evolves to be Christ at this stage.
From that red Chakra up to this Chakra He
became the Christ.
He is the principle.
Now what is the principle?
Within us what is our principle?
Is say the Kundalini you can say?
In this the electricity is the principle of
this one is.
In the same way the creation, the whole creation
if you take it as such, it is the principle
and the support of this creation.
He represents the essence, the essence of
creation.
Like we can say we have a family, husband
and wife and the child.
Now the child is the essence of husband and
wife.
He is the essence of the family, of the house.
The whole thing is sustained for him, is created
for him.
Till they did not have the child there was
no meaning to that house, no meaning to their
life.
But when they had a child then they had a
meaning.
In the same way Christ is the essence, is
the tattwa itself.
He’s the Omkara as they call it.
He is the first sound, first sound that was
created AUM when the Primordial Father and
Primordial Mother separated, They created
this sound.
And He is that sound which is filled into
All-Pervading Power and looks after and support,
actually it is more the support because looking
after is done by the father you can say or
by the mother.
But is the support of all the universe.
And because He is just the essence, the essence
never dies.
Say My essence is My Spirit, it will never
die.
The body dies or the creation will die but
the essence has to be there.
If the essence is lost then nothing could
be there that’s why He is the most important
incarnation.
Because He is the support.
Now this incarnation is placed in this Agnya
Chakra of ours.
Here in the center where the optic nerve or
optic thalamus cross each other like this.
In the center is a very subtle point which
moves both the sides like this and like that
and it creates two sounds Ham Ksham, Ham Ksham,
Ham Ksham.
Ham is on the right hand side where you have
seen the superego is there and Ksham is on
the left hand side where the ego is.
Now these two sounds create two kinds of vibrations.
The Ham sound creates the vibrations, which
make you think, “I am, I am.
Ham, I am.”
This comes from our existence power that we
know we have to live in this world, we’re
not going to die.
Any human being who tries to kill himself
is abnormal.
Normally every human being, why every animal
or any living thing tries to retain its life.
That is through this power of Ham that I am.
Now the superego on the left hand side and
ego on the right hand side is Ksham.
But now I’ll tell you about the right hand
side superego.
In this superego when you are conditioned
by so many things, then you are frightened
and you are worried because these experiences
make you that type of a person which has fear
in the mind.
And this fear is all settled in your superego.
This starts from your amoeba stage you can
say and is still today is being stored there.
You are afraid of police, you are afraid of
that, you are afraid of this.
Some people are not afraid of these things
but are afraid of something else.
Because whatever have been your conditions,
whatever have been your experiences are all
put down here.
Moreover when somebody reads the book of “Dracula”
now he’s afraid of the word Dracula but
the children who do not read they do not know
what is a Dracula is.
If you say Dracula has come they say all right
lets have a look at him.
But those children have read about Dracula,
they are literally frightened and they say,
“Oh God, Dracula is coming, something terrible
is going to happen.”
So you see whatever you have read, whatever
you have gone through whatever experiences
you have had all is in the superego.
So this superego in that this center sends
message, I am, you are, you are Ham, Ham don’t
be afraid, don’t be afraid, you are.
So the people who come to Me, you have seen
some people who come to Me are victims of
superego conditioning And these are the people,
actually at this stage only you can really
discriminate between the two types.
One who are very aggressive, the other who
are absolutely we should say subordinated,
frightened.
These people when they come to Me I have seen,
they go on crying and weeping, “Mother you
know this has happened that has happened,”
and I really get tired talking to them.
And there are so many of this kind that really
you have to pay attention to them as Sahaja
Yogis because you’ll have to deal with them,
how to manage them and how to work it out.
Now at that time if a Sahaja Yogi says, now
you go on saying Ham, Ham, Ham, Ham, a Sahaja
Yogi if he says then the vibrations will drive
out his fear.
Even if you are under any fear and you are
walking around and you feel that there’s
frightened, you just say Ham, Ham, Ham.
Now with this saying the vibrations will clear
out this side very nicely.
Apart from that, that is the way you can get
help from the Divine by saying Ham.
Now there are many things about Ham and Ksham
but as the time is you know, so I do not want
to go into great details about it.
But I would say the mantra for the right hand
side is Ham and for the left hand side is
Ksham.
The right hand side is the ego, which is real
problem, you understand that, is a real colossal
one you have to face them, I mean.
I say anything small here and there I find
the whole thing coming up onto my head like
that.
So what is the solution for a colossal ego?
Colossal ego can only be conquered by forgiving
others.
Those who have ego must learn if they feel
hurt they must say, “forgive.”
Then another person hurts them, say, “forgive.”
And not only forgive but ask for forgiveness.
Both things should be done, more asking for
forgiveness.
You have to ask for forgiveness if you have
too much of ego.
It is very important.
Because if you have too much of ego means
what?
That you have pampered it too much.
That means you have used it too much.
You have dominated people and that’s why
you have such a lot of ego.
If you have such a lot of ego you must all
the time try to humble down in your heart.
Now in the heart resides the spirit.
The ego, too much of ego in a person always
takes you away from that spirit.
That’s why it is said, “Humble down in
your heart.”
The reason is, in the heart resides that part
of yours which gets completely obliterated
or forgotten once you start pumping up your
ego.
But ego has its limits, it ends up into stupidity
and foolishness.
You take any person who is egoistical and
who’s blowing his own trumpet.
You will immediately know because he’ll
be stupid.
Without understanding what he’s doing he’ll
be doing such stupid things that you will
start wondering, especially children, “What’s
the matter with this fellow, he is quite funny?”
And then the stupidity you see faces the person
then he sees for himself, “Oh God!
how did I become so stupid?”
The stupidity comes to you because you forget
the existence of God and your relationship
with the whole.
You think, “I am on my own.
Why should I not do this?
What is wrong in this, what is wrong in that?
I should do these things.”
I mean in this country the way people are
fighting for things.
I mean you must, anybody I mean, those so-called
developing countries can’t understand what
kind of a thing happening to these people.
Because the other day My son-in-law Lav was
reading an article that people are demanding
now that the son-in-law should be allowed
to marry the mother-in-law.
And he just couldn’t understand how can
people gather together and ask for such an
absurd thing like that.
She is your mother.
How can you say that way?
I mean it is something an impossibility for
people, normal people to think like that.
That a son-in-law can marry the mother-in-law.
And what is there to make a law about it and
to talk about it.
It’s a very difficult thing.
All kinds of stupid things we are doing in
this country, which really makes everybody
roar with laughter.
Is because of our Mr. Ego companionship.
It is not easy to understand how he befools
us.
It goes on befooling us all the time and then
we think what’s wrong?
An eighty-year-old man running after a twenty-year-old
girl.
And the twenty-year-old girl befooling this
eighty-year-old man, supposed to be a statesman
this, that and his statue is erected somewhere
there.
How is it possible?
It is only the ego makes you do all these
nonsensical and stupid things.
Once you are in Sahaja Yoga you don’t know
how to control your laughter sometimes the
way people are foolish.
Extremely foolish.
And this is what it is; it ends up in stupidity
absolute stupidity.
I mean even if you want to write a novel you
won’t get such beautiful characters as you
could around you, when you listen to them.
And you’re shocked, Oh God what’s this
going on and very embarrassing too.
Extremely embarrassing and they become so
foolish with their ego that one cannot understand
how thinking man, because by thinking you
get your ego, becomes foolish.
There is no wisdom in a person whose ego is
completely developed like that.
If somebody has an ego like that there is
no wisdom in him.
You can see that he does not know what is
wisdom.
He behaves in such an immature way.
He may be an elderly man, great grandfather
of somebody but as soon as he opens his mouth
you are shocked at him.
You think from where this joker has come?
The maturity is completely lacking.
The other day somebody told Me that, “Mother
how is it our parents are so stupid and we
are searching God?
And the elderly people are so foolish and
we are searching God?”
And then I said, “No, maybe because of war
the parents are disturbed, you see”.
Most of the parents were disturbed during
war and they said, “Majority of them are
like this.
And the younger people are searching God and
much wiser and we don’t know how to compromise
with them because they are not searching God.
Why is it they are not searching God and we
are searching God?
And if there are some searching, they are
very few.”
Now I said this may be due to war but somebody
said, “Then what about America?
You see, in America the people didn’t face
war so much, the stupidity that they have
is sometimes surprising.”
That is the same thing as I said, is the development
of ego in a human being.
Now ego is the thing that makes you think
about everything.
For example, now we have to, say go from here
to Birmingham, all right.
So we think now how will I go?
Simple way is that I’ll take a train or
I’ll take a car and go away.
If there’s no reservation needed I will
just jump into the train or going by the car.
If the car is available I’ll go by car or
by train finished.
What is there to think about?
But no, then we must plan it out, “I’m
programmed now I have to go”.
You go to the station and find the train is
not there because there was some accident
so the train is not moving.
So you are absolutely upset because you think
that the train has gone now what to do.
In that upsetting you do not even remember
that you have a car and you have to go by
the car.
Now that whole things upsets you because you
had plans to go by train and you had planned
everything, now you cannot reach there and
what will happen?
Now you are sitting here and worrying about
it.
As a person who is spontaneous what will you
do?
All right depends on, I may go by train or
by car whatever I feel like at that time.
He is sitting tight.
So he goes to the train, sees if the train
is there.
If it is, nicely there’s a space available
he gets into it.
If the train is not available, all right,
he comes home takes his car and goes away.
So now you have informed the people that you
must meet at such and such a place.
That’s also is there you see.
So those people are running up down there
and they will be there at the station.
Now what’s the matter?
Even if they’re at the station you can meet
them at the station.
You go by train and you can meet them.
What is there to be that much upset about
it?
You see you can always contact them.
But the way we get upset we have spoiled the
complete program of going to Birmingham, which
is a very beautiful program that we have got.
We have to meet new people, we have to meet
many people, we have to enjoy ourselves.
That’s all finished because we had planned
something and it did not work out, we are
finished.
All these things make us a miserable person.
And we are so miserable and so grudging and
so boring that those who are next to you just
get fed up with it and they say, “Now shut
up.
If you are not going to Birmingham, if you
are not going don’t go.
But don’t eat my head now”, is a common
experience of many.
If this Mr. Ego he’s so, he doesn’t want
you to be happy.
He doesn’t want you to be relaxed.
He all the time gives you ideas and tells
you, “Do this and do that and you must get
it done and this is to be done.
You had better inform that person, be meticulous
about it,” and it will go to such details
that anything fails you are finished because
your nerves are already finished and shattered.
Anything, even a drop of inconvenience comes
into you or even a feather of disturbance
is there, you are finished.
And so everybody is rattling, ”We have tensions.
We have problems.”
Why?
What is the advantage of doing all these things?
No advantage you know that.
But then why do you do it?
Because you have a big ego.
It won’t allow you to rest.
Whatever you may try it won’t.
So what is the solution of that?
Morning till evening ask for forgiveness from
God.
Pull your ears from both the sides and say,
“Oh God, forgive me.
Oh God, forgive me.
And, oh God forgive me,” so this balloon
of ego goes down a little.
Remember Him morning, evening, every time.
Remembering Christ brings down your ego very
much.
He did everything that was possible that you
should not develop your ego.
Everything that was possible.
He was born as an ordinary carpenter’s son.
Lived in the most ordinary conditions.
Kept Himself behind the whole scene.
He could have been born as Roman Emperor.
He could have been anybody there.
But no He was born Himself.
You know that He took his birth in a place
where even ordinary people do not take their
births.
But, there also the light was there.
Wherever He was born there was light and joy.
And this is the thing we have to know, that
we have lost the joy because we have forgotten
God Almighty.
When we forget Him, that He is love and He
is joy, naturally joy is also forgotten.
And then we see people are not at all happy.
They have affluence, they have money, they
have everything, but still they are not happy.
All the time they are in such a mess that
you don’t know how to talk to them.
If you say this word they’ll be angry.
If you say that word they’ll be angry.
They are not at all normal human beings.
They are sick people.
Sick with their ego.
It’s a very simple thing is to ask for forgiveness.
How many times do we do that?
Not even once a day, not even once a month,
not even once a year.
Even on a Christmas day if we could say, “Forgive
us Oh Lord for whatever we have done so far.”
It will work out.
But that day we must champagne to forgive
Him more.
So we must have gossips and we must have all
the arrogant things by the time it is the
end of Christmas.
This ego, yellow side one, is the one that
presses your superego too much.
It does.
It presses it so much sometimes that a person
forgets that others are hurt by what they
talk.
On the contrary they devise methods how to
say things which are cutting, which are hurting,
which are painful to others.
They say such things, I mean all the time
if you see.
A person say from a village if he comes and
sees he’ll think, are they quarreling, what
are they doing?
I mean the whole discussion, even in the parliament
I was surprised the way they talked to each
other, no bull will treat another bull that
way, see.
Even a dog normally does not bark at another
dog.
No animal in the world all the time is barking
at its fellow man.
No animal in the whole world I can tell you
this much.
Only the human beings if two people are there
all the time they are going, ha ha ha ha all
the time that way.
How is it possible?
His ego and her ego or maybe both his ego
are dashing at each other.
There is a kind of a funny type of feeling
that oh I have mastered the thing, I have
got the thing, I have got the point.
I have proved the point.
But in that I have lost everything that was
so beautiful and so much joy giving within
me.
Actually a sensible person would recede from
the place where two people are having an argument.
Argument is a sign of tomfoolery.
I haven’t seen any argument coming to any
end whatsoever.
If it is then it is all right.
But it never does come.
Because, if say, you ask Me questions I answer
you, all right.
If you do not like the answer give it up.
But if you argue with Me still and I argue
with you where will you end?
Argument is not going to lead you to any knowledge
but a very terrible ego developing into you.
The whole modern concept is ego oriented.
All western countries are ego orientated.
They want to develop your ego and pamper it.
There are so many other ways by which they
do.
Why I’m talking more about it because we
are all supposed to be western people and
affluent people you see.
Supposed to be very wise and leading or misleading,
I don’t know, the developing countries.
So we have to understand ourselves where are
we as far as our understanding of things are
concerned.
How ego is pampered within us is by a large-scale
method.
They work on your ego throughout to have all
these so-called enterprises.
For example to a woman they’ll say, “Oh
you must have a waist like this and you must
have a face like this and you must have –“ For
a man, “You must this kind of a body.
You should be Mr. Universe or you should be
something,” so the man starts working on
it immediately.
You must, there so many people I have seen
running on the roads in this cold, I don’t
understand.
Like mad you know and some of them are Member
of Parliament.
The whole night they keep awake and the whole
day they are running about.
I say what are you doing?
What is the need to do this?
To keep good health you must do it.
To keep good health don’t work like mad,
be a sensible and a wise person.
Wisdom is to be sought to keep good health,
to be all right and not this kind of mad ego
orientated things.
So then the one way is to excite your ego
about your physique.
Then there is ego about, you must have a big
car.
You see people try to show off their possessions.
You have a big car, then they’re going about.
I mean they really look to me like jokers,
that’s all they are.
I mean car I can understand is a convenience
and a good quality car if somebody can afford
it should have it because it is a headache
to have a bad car.
So it’s all right.
But by having a car you become something great.
You may not have food in the house but you
must have a very good car to go about.
And all these ideas come.
Then they will advertise, you see, this will
be a very good car for you.
What is it for you?
It is nothing but to pamper your ego.
All these advertisements are nothing but by
which your ego is pampered.
All these things they’re treated.
Now in America if you go every handle has
to be different.
Everything has to be different.
Why so much difference in everything?
Why do you want to have everything so different?
Is it some aesthetics, you think in that?
It is none of the aesthetics but is just to
pamper your ego.
Even the so-called art connoisseurs are nothing
but ego pamperers.
Your stamp collections this, that, all this
is nothing but ego pampering.
And what a waste of time, you just think about
it.
This ego thing comes into us because we are
first of all, as I said, that in the west
the living was very difficult.
They had to fight the nature.
And when you have to fight the nature you
have to develop your ego to fight it.
Or actually when you are fighting the nature
the ego develops within you.
And then once that momentum has started in
you it is very difficult to bring it down.
It is such a terrible disease that people
have taken it for granted that that’s a
part of their lives.
You are not your ego.
You are not.
When I say that you must surrender yourself
to God they think Mother why should we surrender?
Yourself means that ego with which you are
identified.
I don’t say that you surrender your wisdom.
Or I can say surrender your ego to your wisdom.
But it is so difficult to give it up because
we have learned to live with it, identified
with it.
We just cannot think of life without our ego,
we just cannot.
And it has gone to such an extent that we
don’t even realize how far we have gone
in cruelty.
Like, “I like this kind, I like that kind.”
You go to somebody’s house and you say like
this.
Is indecent to talk like that.
It is vulgar to express, “I like.”
Who are you?
Are you God?
I want this.
I want that.
I am very particular about this.
I’m very, who are you?
Just ask yourself a question, “Who am I?
I’m the Spirit.
I’m that eternal being.
Have I become that?”
On the contrary we are hurting everybody’s
Spirit by our ego.
Every moment when we talk to others we are
hurting them.
Actually people have lost faith in God, because
those who are in charge of God are so arrogant
and so egoistical that it has become impossible
for anybody to think of God, which is beyond
your ego.
You’ll be surprised, ego is absolutely superficial
like a bubble.
It is just like a balloon, which can burst
just like that.
And it should go.
It should go so that you should rise.
It should disappear so that your attention
rises in your Spirit.
And that you see the whole world as a part
of that Spirit that you are.
This is the boundary, which you have to cross
and for that we have to take help from Christ.
Christ crucified himself.
Why?
Because what did He do?
Did He loot people?
Today you have thousands of these thugs coming
here and looting you.
Nobody crucifies them.
What did He do?
He just challenged the ego of these Romans
and of these Jews, those who were angry with
Him, and that’s why He was crucified.
And we have to crucify our ego now through
His cross.
Otherwise we are going to do the same again
to ourselves that in our own being we crucify
our Christ by our ego.
It is a very symbolic gesture of Christ, His
birth in the most humble place, in a very
humble place.
He is born in the optic thalamus, you can
say, is the place where there brain, all activities
coming and all the, all sorts of problems
there chasing you, and there He lives and
you have to just awaken Him there so that
your ego is crucified once for all.
But I don’t think you fight your ego because
it is not that important to fight.
You are fighting with your shadow.
You have shadow which is called as ego which
is not to be fought and wasted, waste your
energy on him.
Just no need to fight, only thing if you stand
in the center of the light you don’t see
any shadow.
It is so simple as that.
If you stand in the center of light that is
Christ you don’t see any shadow anywhere.
But when I say this I may sound like other
people who give sermons, “Stand in the shadow
of Christ or stand in the light of Christ.”
Now what does that mean?
Where is that light or where is that place
where you should stand?
That place is here – the center of your
optic thalamus where there is no thought.
You have to stand in thoughtless awareness.
Many people who have had a problem with Agnya,
many people who have come
[Talk is interrupted here and a few words
are missing]
…thoughts will stop and they will be beyond
thought.
And this a very, very important Chakra for
Sahaja Yogis because when the Kundalini rises
above, above the Agnya Chakra immediately
there is no thought.
You do not get any thoughts from ego or superego.
But there is wobbling in the Agnya because
of your imbalanced ways.
And the imbalanced ways are, that sometimes
you are with ego or with superego.
This has happened to our people in the West
because we have had so much of ego we got
really tired of it.
We got frightened with it.
Then we started taking to drugs and things
to increase our superego.
But by doing that what we are doing is pushing
by one end and bringing back another end and
that’s how we are wobbling our ego and superego
by which we are not helping ourselves at all.
So what one has to do is to rise within oneself
up to the point of Agnya and try to steady
your Agnya.
There are many people have asked Me one question.
How to steady the Agnya?
Agnya is placed at the crossing point of our
nerves and also optic thalamus.
Now, so it is said that if you have wobbling
eyes you’ll have a wobbling Agnya.
You have to steady your eyes.
You have to soothe them.
Now it is very, very out of date, ancient,
old and all sorts of names that you call it
to a thing like that.
But you must steady your eyes and steady them
in such a way that it is very soothing for
the eyes.
Which is the most soothing thing for the eyes
is the green grass.
If you could see the green grass with your
eyes means you walk with your eyes on the
ground.
Your eyes will be soothed, your Agnya will
be all right.
That’s why Christ said that, “I tell you
about the adulterous eyes”.
He talked about adulterous eyes.
The eyes with which you do adultery.
Is a very common thing these days.
Every woman a man must see.
Every man a woman must see.
As if it is the most important job.
If you have not seen one woman you’re finished.
I mean this is being modern.
But I am an old fashioned lady.
And at the time of Christ he said, “You
should not have adulterous eyes.”
And the ones who have adulterous eyes are,
no more than any other, but our Western Christians.
Who all the time even in the church, even
when they’re giving sermons, their eyes
are moving with adultery.
These eyes have to be very, very pure, very,
very deep and very loving when you want to
have your Agnya all right.
Because you receive through you eyes.
Say if you have closed your eyes you do not
put your attention to anything because your
eyes are closed.
You are not adding more thoughts to yourself.
But if your eyes are open you are adding much
more thoughts because everywhere the eyes
go the attention goes and you see things and
create thoughts and put in them.
So your attention which has to go to the Spirit,
which has to go to God, which has to shine
through the window of Divine.
This beautiful thing is ruined by the way
we use our eyes and we do not respect it.
There’s nothing so pure and beautiful as
the grass on the ground or the ground itself,
which takes our feet, which supports us, which
looks after us, enriches us.
We should put our eyes on the Mother Earth
instead of looking at every person.
But from Sahaja Yoga point of view now many
of you know what happens to your eyes when
you look at somebody.
Maybe a entity might enter your eyes.
And it is, you’ll be amazed that it is the
play of the entity what we call this so-called
flirting is.
I’ve talked about it before also and people
didn’t like it when I told them about it.
But I have seen actual entities entering from
eyes to eyes.
I have seen very simple people who come down
to such places, say in a party.
In a party people are just exchanging entities
from one eye to another.
Once it goes to another person he puts his
entity into another person.
And that third goes into another person.
All the time your attention is diverted.
And you feel it is attracted towards something,
you do not know why it is attracted.
Now the certain symbols are also made like
that.
To add up to the problems, you see all the
society is working at it.
That you should appear in such a way that
every man should look at you.
Every woman should look at you.
Why?
What is the use?
Supposing I look at you what do I get?
What do I get by looking at a person?
What is the advantage just looking at a person?
We are wasting such a lot of energy for what?
In the same way if you are walking on the
roads, we are seeing some beautiful things
all right.
If you have to buy something, all right go
ahead, see those things, whatever you have
to select is all right.
But all the time just because your eyes are
such, you are just doing it and you do not
know the reason why you are doing like this,
all the time why your eyes are wobbling.
And that is a sure and certain sign for a
person to become mad.
Absolutely, that’s a sure and certain sign
is, when a person is mad how do you make it
out that a person is lunatic.
If you see his eyes the iris in the eyes are
all the time wobbling.
They cannot keep it steady.
Or they are sick they’re also, you can see,
that these eyes are all the time wobbling.
There is no steadiness.
Not only this but you have seen those people
who have come in the Sahaja Yoga when they
close their eyes they find their eyes are
flickering.
Their eyelids are flickering.
That means there is some sort of a disturbance
in the Kundalini rising.
Whole tension if you call it as hundred then
at least eighty percent of it comes through
our eyes.
Then how important it is to protect our eyes
from all kind of useless activities we are
doing.
Christ - Christ’s life shows so many aspects
of how to respect others.
But one of them which has been very much misused
throughout is that of the prostitute.
He saved the prostitute, He saved her no doubt.
But you spoil these prostitutes.
A good woman you make her into prostitutes.
You give her ideas by which she becomes a
prostitute.
A good Huswife (old English word like housewife)
is turned into a prostitute by an egotistical
man.
Young small girls who are virgins are being
destroyed by your dirty glances.
Do you realize this?
That you are doing just the opposite what
Christ had done?
And you say that He saved, Christ, so even
if we are prostitutes He’ll save us.
But why be prostitutes?
This is such a stupid style of thinking.
That we should become prostitutes so that
Christ will save us.
One has to think about all these things in
the proper light of Sahaja Yoga.
Unless and until you are realized My talk
is just useless for you.
But once you are realized you will know that
if you glance at someone you might suddenly
get a headache at the back.
You might feel a dart has gone into your head
or something has happened.
You might feel that you’re blinding with
somebody’s face and you will get all kinds
of experiences by which you will know how
important are your eyes.
All your nervousness and everything can be
cured if you have pure eyes.
But it is such a vicious circle that through
your eyes you gather all the bad and is accumulated
in the Agnya and you have to clear the Agnya
to make the eyes clear.
It’s a vicious circle.
But it can start at a point as I said, we
have to ask for forgiveness.
Secondly we have to bring Christ in our Agnya
Chakra.
Thirdly we have to give up all drugs and all
intoxicants and all smoking.
That happens automatically when you are a
Sahaja Yogi, it will work out.
But eyes express the whole of your being,
your brain, your body, your limbs everything.
And if your Agnya is all right then you eyes
are perfectly all right.
They emit nothing but love wherever they glance.
Only with a glance of your eyes you can raise
the Kundalini.
Only with the glance of your eyes you can
cure people.
Only with your glance you can bring joy into
the destroyed and the ruined people.
So these eyes which you see are the windows
of your being, of your heart.
When the Spirit is expressed through your
eyes, you must have noticed yourself, that
when the Kundalini rises then the eyes become
dilated.
And a realized soul has got black eyes because
they have these eyes are dilated.
At least when I see them they are all dilated
black eyes.
Apart from that a realized soul can be made
out by his eyes which are sparkling.
There’s a sparkle like diamonds.
They sparkle all the time and you can make
out from the eyes that this person is a realized
soul.
There’s a tremendous difference between
a non-realized soul’s eyes and a realized
soul’s eyes.
So you can imagine how your Spirit sees through
your eyes.
But if the eyes are not pure it doesn’t
stay there long.
So if we have to understand Christ physically
we have to respect our eyes.
Mentally we have to give up all that is impure
in our mind.
Now, so we come to the impurities of the mind.
And the impurities of mind are, there are
so many poisons, you know, about.
I mean there are books and books written about
the poison.
And the psychologists are supposed to take
out all your poisons.
I don’t know if they can do it at all.
But they have the worst Agnya.
All these psychologists have the worst Agnya
and I don’t think they are capable of really
giving any relief to people who suffering
mentally.
Mental sufferings are of two types.
Say the same thing is that one is…
MOTHER SAYS ASIDE: Vibrations are so much,
I can’t stand it.
One type of mental troubles are where people
oppress you very much.
You see you go on bearing the cross.
Now this is a very wrong idea people have
about Christ.
Bearing the cross doesn’t mean that anybody
who tries to oppress you should go on taking
the enslavement upon yourself.
You’re not to enslave to anyone whatsoever.
Anybody who tries to make a slave out of you,
you should deny it absolutely.
You should say Hum, I am.
Who are you to dominate me?
Anyone whether you are of a black skin, or
a red skin or a yellow skin, nobody has right
to dominate anyone in this whole world.
And if anybody is doing it, “Oh what to
do now, after all you see we are poor people,
or we are like this or he’s supporting,”
and all that.
Then they are running away from their duty
towards themselves.
Such people cannot get Realization.
Slaves are not going to become kings.
So the slavery that is supposed to be confused
with bearing the cross is another confusion
of modern times.
We have to rise in our self-respect.
And we have to understand that no one in this
world has a right to dominate us.
But then what is bearing of the cross is?
First of all the people of His level never
suffer.
It’s just a joke going on.
It’s a Leela, it’s a play going on for
them.
They never suffer, and even if they so called
act as suffering they just do it because they
want to do it.
They are not helpless people.
They are not slaves.
And those who think that by bearing it up
and by suffering it we are becoming Christians
they should know they are psychological cases.
And if they are crying and weeping and all
the time saying, “What to do, you see I
am in love and my lover tortures me.”
You are neither in love neither you have a
lover.
It is a kind of a psychological clubbing.
That he is a dominating man and you like his
domination, that’s why you are together.
Is a simple fact.
So every human being has his own self-respect.
And he must respect his self that is the Spirit
within him.
And nothing should dominate it.
Whether you belong to this country or that
country, or this ism or that ism.
All this will break down.
[The red part is not present in the tape with
FV.
Also in the FV’s tape the following sentence
is a single sentence, spoken unbroken by Shri
Mataji]
Under the rule of God nobody has the right
to dominate anybody’s Spirit.
But when you are given freedom you go to the
other side that is Mr. Ego.
You do not know how to use your freedom.
So you try to dominate others.
Your freedom is, everybody’s freedom is
in danger.
You’re on top of everyone, and torturing
everybody’s souls.
And you are dominating by land and by properties
or by possessions.
So either this way or that way, mentally if
you are of this category or that category,
you are against yourself.
Just be in the center and see for yourself.
Just be looking at it.
Are you emitting love towards another person?
If you are a slave how can you love?
You cannot.
If you are free and abandoned how can you
love?
Love has its own bondages very sweet and beautiful.
You have to live with them.
You enjoy those bondages.
For a little child will come to your house
and he will spoil your house no doubt, and
that he should do.
And you should enjoy that spoiling.
Then your freedom if it is challenged by a
little child’s crying, then you are not
wise people.
This is abandonment.
Or I would say it is loneliness.
It is cutting off from the primordial, from
the big one, from the large one that you are.
Is not to be able to tolerate the freedom
of others.
A child has no freedom to cry in the house.
What sort of freedom you conceive of.
A mother has no right to say something she
wants to say about her child, which is her
duty to tell him what is right and wrong.
If the son does not have right to eat whatever
he likes in his own mother’s family then
what sort of freedom do you have?
It’s such a confusion of things.
So this kind of freedom is just the opposite
and extreme of enslavement.
But in the center is love where you are bound
by everyone.
I am bound by My children.
Yes, I am.
I am proud of them.
They bound Me and I bound them too.
It’s a mutual bounding which we enjoy among
ourselves.
There is such a give and take when there is
such a bondage of love.
But do we understand the importance of bondage
of love?
At the slightest pretext we break it.
Say wife says, “I would like to go out today”.
The husband says “Why?
I am very tired don’t you understand?“
Or if the husband says, “I feel like eating
something,” or some particular thing he
says pancake or something, a small thing.
“Oh I am very tired every time you are demanding.”
If she could just think by making that little
thing he would be so very happy.
She should be dying to know what he wants.
And he should be dying to do what she wants.
And then enjoy each other’s company or you
are wasting all your properties that you have
as human beings.
You don’t know how much you are wasting
from each other.
Every moment is filled with such beautiful
bondages, where exchanges are there.
What have you gained?
The way you are fighting.
The way you are going about.
What have you gained let me see?
When you die you have to announce in the paper
that XYZ is dead and you find there is nobody.
And you have even to pay for people to visit
you when you die.
This is the case today.
Such dryness, such emptiness, such loneliness
exists.
What have you achieved through this.
So this bondage we have to.
And there is no question of sacrifice you
see, the way.
We must sacrifice for the family.
What are you sacrificing?
I mean if you pay for your family you get
the joy out of it.
That’s why you do it.
If you have to lead a nice good life you are
not sacrificing anything but you are gaining
by that, leading a good life.
If your wife says, “Don’t go to the pub,”
and if you do not go there, then you should
not say she is an orthodox, old fashioned
this that, that and that and that.
But instead you should thank you stars that
in this modern times also that there is somebody
who’s telling you the truth.
Because the whole edifice has come up, do
you mean to say that truth should not be told?
All this is falsehood in which you are living.
And if you have to be happy come down to reality.
Friends, also same thing.
With the friends what sort of relations do
we have with our friends?
What do we expect from them?
Sending them a Christmas card and then if
they don’t send, feeling bad about it.
There are no deeper bondages we have not lived
with them.
If you allow our self to be bound by them,
they will be bound by us.
You better try this.
Try to be bound by them.
Don’t be afraid of anybody else.
Just try to be bound by others and you’ll
be amazed how much they will be giving you.
I am a living example of this.
I can tell you I am a living example of this.
I am bound by all of you.
If somebody says, “Mother when are you going
to leave us?”
No I cannot.
I cannot.
I am just bound by you.
I just do not want to leave because I love
you very much.
How can I leave you?
It’s impossible for Me.
So then, what do I gain out of this life?
Everything that is in this world.
What do you want Me to get?
I cannot even count what I can get out of
it.
Immeasurable, ocean.
I become an ocean Myself.
Break your ideas about your own personal freedom
and liberation, is liberating your intelligence.
You‘re liberating your own wisdom.
And the sweetness and the beauty which is
never perishable whether you are old or young.
That is going to be your own.
But these poisons that are being built outside
and inside you, please throw them away.
These are mental poisons.
Through Agnya you can take them out.
You see, this is an opening also through which
many things go out.
Try to work it out.
Look at the tree with love and you’ll find
that the tree itself is giving you the joy
of its creation.
Because you’ll become thoughtless.
And the creator who has made that beautiful
tree will be pouring all that joy which is
stored into it into you.
Every human being is a store of joy.
Unlimited, I assure you, believe Me.
And don’t waste them because somebody is
not properly dressed, or he’s not according
to the way you want him to be which you learnt
in your public school.
Every doorstep, everywhere there is beauty
lying, do not miss it.
But if you have possessiveness about it, an
adultery about it, then you can never enjoy
them.
You can never enjoy all that beauty, all that
store, all that wealth that is in every human
being every moment it is bubbling.
For Agnya it’s a good thing, Christmas is
coming.
And at the time that when I have to wish you
Happy Christmas, that at this occasion I am
speaking about Agnya Chakra in which, what
I said is, Agnya is one must know what to
order and how to obey.
Obey the Divine.
Obey your elders.
Obey your self and not your ego.
And then you can order also others.
Not only human beings, but you can even order
the sun and the moon and all the winds and
everything in the world.
Everything you can control, everything with
this Agnya.
You try one thing.
If you know somebody is going to do something
wrong, just take his name and put it to Agnya.
He’ll not do it, try it.
This is a trick I’m telling about for those
who are realized souls not for those who are
not yet realized but those who are realized
can try.
If the other person is doing something wrong
you can try your Agnya.
Anything you order on your Agnya will be respected
but your Agnya must have Christ there.
Because you have the great support awakened
within you, which does not exist here but
into every man’s head.
It is all pervading into all small atoms and
molecules, it is everywhere into the sun and
any place you go.
It is there.
So try to develop your Agnya that is the mastery
of your self.
Those who have a good Agnya can master anything
and understand that the idea about mastering
worldly things and mastering human beings
and mastering this and some of them are mastering
in, say, other crafts and things, best thing
is to master your Agnya.
And you really become the master of yourself
by which you can master many things.
And today on this great day when I’m wishing
you a Happy Christmas, I wish you to have
the most powerful Agnya, that people when
they see your forehead should know that Christ
is reborn again with in you.