…and how it resides within us and how we
are lost in the curtains of Maya.
Today I am going to tell you how we get to
that Spirit.
There are two types of methods people employ
in finding out that Spirit.
One is called as anuvopai, and another one
is called as shaktopai.
‘Anu’ means a molecule.
When we are lost in the Maya, as I had told
you last time, actually the Spirit is eternal,
It is all-powerful.
It never loses Its power whether we are old,
young, whatever condition we may be, the Spirit
has Its own power, all the time.
But, the reflection of the Spirit in us, the
light of the Spirit in us, depends on the
quality of our reflector, how we are.
And because of the quality being so poor sometimes,
darkness is created within us and in that
darkness, we do not know sometimes, even to
that extent, that there is something beyond.
So the first style of seeking is anuvopai
as you call it, which is depending on separating
molecules after molecules.
Because under these circumstances, when you
are surrounded by darkness, you see Spirit
just as a molecule or you can say a spark
or a flicker.
Sometimes you just get a flicker of it.
As you know the thoughts arise within us and
fade away.
We see the thoughts rising and fading away.
And there are many thoughts all around us.
Our attention is on those thoughts, moving
all the time.
It is very hard to find that space in between
two thoughts, that’s why what we see is
just a flicker, you can call it, or a little
atom of that Spirit, sometimes sparkling.
And then the search starts among human beings.
From that darkness, from Tamoguna they start
searching and the kriya (action) starts within
us.
So we can see in the left hand side as you
see the Ida Nadi, by which we live in Tamoguna,
in desiring for it, and then we move to the
right hand side, on the Pingala Nadi, in which
we act.
In that action we try to find the Spirit.
Of course, first we think it is in getting
material advancement that you will find that
Spirit, that flicker, and so we go in for
material advancement.
Now, material advancement is very different
from the spiritual advancement.
Or we can say the material happening, what
we see, like a plane landing or a plane taking
off or a collision of two trains or any such
happenings are outside and spiritual happening
is within.
Our attention is always attracted towards
outside happenings and it is an impossibility
to take this attention inside.
That is why something has to happen within
us to attract that attention inside.
We cannot force our attention inside, so people
try, normally, the anuvopai is that what you
call Ashtanga Yoga and other Yogas, by which
they try separating themselves from myth,
from darkness; for which you need very astute,
honest, sincere people, very young celibate,
innocent people, those who have to live in
the forest with their Gurus.
So they keep out their attention, which is
called as nirodha (restraint).
They stop their attention spreading itself.
They concentrate their attention with the
help of a Realised soul.
If you come to India you’ll meet some real
sages like that who live on top of hills and
mountains, who are not easily available to
people.
They do not sell their religion or they do
not sell their Realisation to people.
Hidden away from the madding crowd, they exist
there.
One of them has told someone, some Sahaja
Yogis that he has practiced anuvopai for twenty-one
thousand years from when he was just a frog!
It’s fantastic that he carried on for twenty-one
thousand years, every year, life, he was born
and still he cannot raise the Kundalini of
others very easily!
Still he does not have the power to raise
the Kundalini the way you Sahaja Yogis can
raise!
It’s most surprising!
He has given Realisation to only one person,
only one.
In twenty five years he worked on him; the
same way, anuvopai.
These are the people who are detached, veetragas.
Not that you have to run way from anywhere,
but living in the society only you can achieve
it through our Sahaja Yoga or Mahayoga.
This is shaktopai.
But these people still are afraid to come
in the cities because they could not make
people understand.
They do not trust human beings and they want
to keep away from them.
They are not married.
They lead a celibate life.
They live up to two hundred years sometimes,
sometimes a thousand years also.
But it is a very individualistic movement,
works on one or two people.
Births after births they cleansed themselves.
This is anuvopai.
So the search for the Divine or for the Spirit
has been on for ages now, it’s not a new
thing that we are doing here.
And you also have been seeking that Divine
in your previous lives and many lives before.
But you must know that for seeking you have
to go inside.
It’s not outside.
And how do you go inside?
Is the problem.
Some people say that if you go on suggesting,
“I’m going inside,” you go inside.
It’s all imagination, because when the attention
is out, the knower and the knowledge, both
are different.
Like if I see this thing now, for example,
if I am not a Realised soul, I’ll see this
one and I will just think, “How much they
must have paid for it?
What is it made of?
From where did they get it?”
All sorts of these superficial things as you
can call it.
At the most somebody might say, “It’s
very aesthetically placed and it has very
great balance,” and all that.
At the most!
But it is all outside, because the knower
who knows about it is outside the knowledge.
So there’s a tremendous difference between
the happening outside and happening inside.
When you see a train colliding you will say,
“Oh, look at this!
What is this they have done?
This driver is wrong!” and that, “These
people have suffered so much,” and all sorts
of things.
You’ll start collecting money.
Whatever we do normally, you see.
But the knowledge about it is outside the
knower that is your Self.
But when the spiritual happening takes place
the knowledge and the knower become one.
For example now this machine that is here,
to a normal person as I told you will be,
“It is so much, it costs so much,” or
whatever it is, you see.
But to a Realised soul it would be, “Is
it vibrating?
Is it emitting vibrations?
What sort of vibrations is it emitting?
It is good or bad?”
Because then you start understanding it according
to spiritual value and not according to material
value.
I hope you understand this point.
Spiritual value is an absolute value.
And what is the measure of that is the spiritual
joy.
The vibrations give you spiritual joy – the
good vibrations, I mean.
What are good vibrations?
Are nothing but the coefficience (sic) of
this whole thing is emitting through it, the
All Pervading Power, which is giving you joy.
It is an absolute value.
You take ten children who are Realised souls:
you tie their eyes and ask them to put their
hands towards one person.
All of them will show you the same finger,
which is burning; whichever is the chakra
they are catching.
There will be no confusion, no second opinion
about it, no quarrelling, because that’s
what it is, because the knower and the knowledge
is the same.
That is why when our attention is outside
and we are seeking something or knowing something,
then we start seeing it according to our thinking
and who does the thinking is Mr. Ego or maybe
Superego.
We are not there to think about it, so anything
you give them, say for example you marry two
persons in modern times.
So they’ll sit down and work it out.
How can you work out a marriage with your
brains?
It’s a question of your heart.
Just enjoy it.
You give them food, they’ll sit down and
work it out, start analysing it.
They cannot synthesise it.
The food will get cold, it will lose all its
taste and the whole thing will be wasted.
They make the same thing out of their lives.
For nothing at all they create problems by
thinking.
Analysis starts outside, synthesis starts
inside.
Now this nirodha is the withdrawing of your
attention inside as I told you is only possible
through a happening within.
Now how do you get the happening within yourself?
For example, I am talking to you, you are
paying attention to Me: supposing something
falls down, immediately your attention goes
to that happening.
So there has to be some happening within.
Now, what is that happening, is Kundalini
Yoga, and this Kundalini Yoga is the shaktopai,
is the, is known as shaktipath, is the giving
of the Shakti.
Very few are entitled with this, I mean today
these are all selling ‘shaktis’ there.
There have their ashramas, and this that,
they are talking of shakti, when that people
start dancing, jumping, screaming like possessed
people.
That is not Shakti at all.
Only a person of a very high quality can raise
the Kundalini because he is to be authorised
by God.
It’s a very rare thing to give Realisation
to people.
Only such people who have been authorised
by God can just move the Kundalini straight
forward.
So the anuvopai is a very slow action, is
for few individuals who get out of this maya,
this illusion and tell people that, “This
is all illusion, is a mirage, you are running
after a mirage.
Don’t run after this mirage.”
But still, people can’t believe them.
They crucify them, they poison them, they
beat them, they do all kinds of things to
them.
I mean, they did not do any harm to anyone
whatsoever that they should be treated so
badly by human beings.
So, it is to be understood that your attention
has to be sucked in.
The nirodha has to work out.
Not by denying things, “Don’t look at
the women.”
“Don’t look at the gold.”
“Don’t look at things, your attention
will be spoiled.”
Not by those methods.
Or by taking you to the jungles, leading you
a celibate life, making a very holy atmosphere
around and just forcing you that you do not
see that [which] is evil.
But when you see it again you go back to the
same!
There’s no immunity developed.
So the attention when it’s sucked in by
Kundalini rising, the first thing you notice
is that there is dilatation of the pupil.
Now, dilatation of the pupil will cause a
kind of a blindness, normally.
There was a lady doctor who had come for her
Realisation to me once and I tried to raise
her Kundalini, it wouldn’t go beyond Agya.
While she was driving suddenly she felt that
her eyes were dilating and she couldn’t
see, so she took her car on one side and she
said , “For about a minute I just could
not see anything, I was quite worried.
I felt my dilatation of the pupil is taking
place and I was worried about it that how
I’ve become blind.”
And then again she got back but when she went
back, she was seeing much better and there
was a sparkle in her eyes, eyes were sparkling.
She telephoned to me, she said , “Does it
happen?”
I said , “Yes.”
To attract your attention from outside inward,
Kundalini does that to you, that She dilates
your pupil.
Now the doctors may come on my head and say
that it is a parasympathetic or a sympathetic
action.
They do not know, they have not yet decided.
It’s the action of Kundalini.
They don’t know about Kundalini.
Even if you show them pulsating they will
not believe it.
They don’t want to believe it.
They want to remain outside, in ignorance.
All of them are like that.
Now, everybody is saying that now outside
battles are over, we have to have battle inside,
we have to fight ourselves.
Anywhere you go they will say that, “We
must find our wholesomeness.”
Oh, big lectures you know!
Conferences after conferences people are talking
so big!
Talk, talk, talk, talk, talk, talk, talk.
But when it comes to reality that you can
have it, it’s a very slow movement [but]
still better than anuvopai!
By anuvopai [those] who are living in the
city they will not reach anywhere, they cannot.
If you try to do all those things, if you
do not have a Realised soul as your guru and
also the atmosphere, either you’ll get into
ego or into superego; you’ll have a problem
there, either onto to the left or onto the
right.
Supposing you tell them , “Now, don’t
drink, don’t smoke!”
Immediately you will get conditioned and Mr.
Freud will stand up and say, “See, you are
conditioned, you should have all the freedom!”
Alright.
So you go ahead [and] do whatever you please.
So your Mr. Ego will become like a big balloon
on your head if you do whatever you please.
And then you have a big forehead coming out,
eating everyone out like that.
(laughing) And I have given a nice speech
on Mr. Ego, how it tries to strangle everyone
and how we are raising against everyone.
This Mr. Ego gives us the feeling that we
are something and that is the one which keeps
us in bondage of ignorance.
And it’s like, I sometimes feel, like the
fist of a boxer!
Anybody tries to go near it, it gives you
a bang back!
Anybody tries to say anything about it, it
will come out with a big bang on your head.
So if you do not pay attention to your ego
and say, “No, no, no, no, I must not eat
this, I must not do this, I must not do that,”
finished!
You go onto the left hand side and then you
get the conditioning and then you may fall
into the traps of Mr. Rajneesh or someone
like that, who is conditioning you.
And you cannot get out of it.
You try your level best, you cannot get out
of it, because they entrap you with their
hypnosis, you go into your superego, you are
hypnotised, you are possessed and whatever
you may try, all such people are very difficult
for Sahaja Yoga.
They think I don’t know what they are doing,
but it is not my knowing, it is your knowing
is the point.
The loser is within you, and the winner is
also within you.
It is you [who] have to gain, not me.
Sahaja Yoga is not for me at all.
I don’t have to do it.
It is for you to do it to gain that knowledge
which is your Self.
Only thing I can do is the Shakti path but
actually I don’t do it either, I can tell
you.
I don’t do anything.
I’m just sitting quiet.
It just emits, what can I do?
That’s my nature, it just flows.
It works out that way.
But, because of our ego, we want all challenges.
Supposing I tell you tomorrow that, “You
can only get it by jumping hundred times,”
you will immediately start doing that!
If I tell you, say, on another sort of a efficiency
trip, that, “Supposing you do a hundred
jumps in five minutes, you will get it faster,”
you will do that.
Or else I give you another kind of a pralobhan
(प्रलोभन) as they call it, a
temptation.
Like you put five rupees today then I say,
“No, no, you better put ten rupees,” and
you put that.
It’s like a running a horse, race.
See how superficially we look at this.
In this superficiality we are going to get
lost completely.
If you are really seeking then you find it
and be there and get it!
This is your own!
We talk big; I find very – I mean I meet
the people who are the cream of every nation,
I should say, and they are creaming each other,
that’s all!
Nothing more than that.
They do not want to go deeper into it and
talking about, “Oh, we understand.
There has to be a Messiah.
There has to be [that] something must happen
to us.”
“We should all become wholesome.”
Now they are finding fanaticism is troubling
them so they are saying, “No, these fanatics
are there.”
And we are all fanatics when we are outside.
I mean, if you ask me, they look like mad
people to me.
Such extremists!
All [their] attention outside.
And an arrangement has been made within you,
as I told you, of Kundalini being placed at
the triangular bone there.
It’s so beautiful it is constructed, just
see the beauty of the Kundalini.
Even in seeking we have gone all out to torture
our Kundalini.
We are not honest to ourselves and to our
Mother, the Kundalini, the One who is sitting
there for us to give us our Realisation, our
re-birth.
She is there, you can see for yourself with
your naked eyes.
For example, one of the Sahaja Yogis who is
a doctor went and talked to the doctors.
I said, “Now, what are they doing?”
They said, “Yes, we know, we got the cool
breeze in the hand, alright.”
“Then?”
“And yes we see, we know there is something
pulsating in the triangular bone.”
“Then?
Does not intrigue you?”
“But still, how can that be Self Realisation?”
I mean, it is beyond any one to drink water
for others and digest it and enjoy it.
You can take somebody to the water, make them
drink, push them down into it, but if they
just refuse then what can you do about it?
And then they will come out of it and have
a big conference: “It’s a big conference.
Having, a big, big conferences!”
Halls they’ll fill up!
And what are they discussing?
How to know that you are a part of the one
living organism!
Again you take out some books, read here,
have a big discussion, have a big party out
of that and finished.
This ‘Sunday School’ seeking, is not going
to help us.
First thing we have to be genuine about it
that we want to seek it.
As you know in Sahaja Yoga, those who have
advanced, those who have really worked genuinely,
without paying attention outside, have been
able to know the Divine, to enjoy It and to
give It to others.
But anywhere in life you see, without genuineness,
what are you going to achieve?
It’s like some mad man who’s a Liaison
Officer, you see.
Imagine what a job and a half!
He’s a Liaison Officer, so he is running
with the flowers for one person, another for
another person, he doesn’t know who is coming.
He may give flowers to somebody else, all
sorts of madness.
In the same way, we are like Liaison Officers,
without any feelings within our heart.
But with this happening you start feeling
the other within you.
You start feeling.
It’s an actualisation, as I told you last
time.
And when that actualisation takes place the
only thing you have to do, is to allow it
to grow, because it has happened spontaneously
without your effort being put into it and
it is going to work out spontaneously.
Only don’t stop its progress by your own
ego and your own style of looking at things.
You cannot make a career out of it or a business.
It is to be enjoyed!
Now I am surprised how human beings are not
selling their children.
I mean they are selling everything.
They are selling their hair, nose, eyes, everything
that is possible under the sun, blood.
But the source of all the joy that is within
you is in the heart pulsating.
That is called as the pranashakti, is the
pulsating power of the Spirit within you,
which is just to be enlightened so [that]
the whole attention gets enlightened.
And the difference between an ordinary awareness,
where the knower and the knowledge are two
different things and an enlightened awareness,
where both become one, it is tremendous!
But nobody wants to practice it and see for
yourself how dynamic it is!
This is what the whole world is seeking today,
this is what we are talking about and that
is how the supply department from India for
all the kinds of thugs are coming here!
So it’s a big circus going on everywhere!
Do you want to also run in the same circus?
I mean, it is not to please me, sir, but is
to please your Self.
Because it is only the spiritual value of
everything whatsoever is going to give you
joy, nothing else.
Let the awakening take place.
Give some time to it.
You have problems, the Kundalini rises, alright.
It touches the Sahastrara, that’s also correct.
But many people they say, “Mother, when
it has touched, why should it fall?”
Now, it’s not my fault.
Mine does not fall.
It falls because of your faults, whatever
you have done to yourself.
The Kundalini has to supply, she has to look
after you.
You have been so cruel to yourself or to others,
whatever you have done.
You have done all wrong things so far, so
Kundalini falls.
Let Her look after all these things.
She knows you have a problem.
But if you are not genuine, she knows also
that you are not genuine.
She’ll just disappear into your Mooladhara
there in the triangular bone and will never
rise.
She’ll be very badly frozen.
When you start thinking about the Kundalini,
you just close her completely there and she
just goes down.
She sees, “This man doesn’t know anything.
He’ll have to take another ten births perhaps
to get his Kundalini again back in place.”
But with some people it comes up and stays
there.
You must respect it.
You must value it.
If you value that, you have valued yourself
and nobody else.
By crucifying Christ, you cannot reduce his
value by any chance.
You have crucified yourself by that, when
you crucified you.
So the good time is coming, Christmas ahead.
Let Christ be born within us on our Agya here
in the crossing point.
Let us remember all these great incarnations
and prophets who came on this earth, who lived
like us, like ordinary human beings, in the
most ordinary way.
They led a very ordinary simple life.
Some of them married also, had children.
Why?
They could have lived on the hills and mountains
very easily avoiding all the nonsense.
No, they did come to give you a milestone
in your achievement of your evolution, and
this is what is the evolution, the Maha Yoga,
where you become one with the Spirit.
All the rest is useless, of no value.
Spirit is your Self, is you.
You are identified with your ego, so you want
to always satisfy your ego, “I like it.”
“I like it,” means Mr. Ego likes it, really,
most of the time.
And the Self doesn’t say , “I like it.”
It feels it.
It feels within Itself.
It’s absolute.
This is the shaktopai, which many people are
practicing.
I haven’t come across even one genuine person
who does this, so far.
I mean we had: Nanaka was there, Kabira was
there, we had in India – great people.
And they have talked about these fake people.
Even in the anuvopai, also Kundalini has to
rise in any case!
It has happened in the case of Buddha and
Mahavira.
But I told you that they were the children
of Rama and thousands of years later, they
got their Realisation, and they are like incarnations
only, you can say, but they are different
styles.
We have no time to waste now.
This is the Last Judgment where we have to
give up all our nonsensical ideas.
You see, it’s difficult to talk to people
who have made business out of God, or some
sort of a political issue out of a God.
But sensible people should know that they
have to know themselves first of all, they
have to become themselves and then they will
know that they are really a part and parcel
of the whole, of the Viraat, the Akbar.
You cannot know religion from outside like
these people are saying, “Allah ho Akbar,
Allah ho Akbar,” and killing you!
Or sitting in the Church and, “Let’s us
sing hymn number such and such.”
Or in our temples selling all kinds of drugs.
That’s why this contrast one doesn’t understand
how religious people could be like that.
And then you get some nice people, ‘gentlemen’,
you know, ‘very good people’.
Useless!
“Oh, they are very good,” alright, what
will they do?
They’ll make some bridges or may have some
tunnels or may do some creative work of writing
some novels or something.
But still the knower and the knowledge is
separated in them.
They are useless to themselves, I am saying,
not to others.
And the confusion has to go by achieving your
absolute.
But all the time our attention is outside
criticising others or finding faults with
others or some sort of a trivial thing.
All this sounds so trivial in this world,
the way we are wasting our energy.
Here is the store within us of our own earnings,
of our own punyas by which you have to get
that [which] is promised to you and to enjoy
that and here is the key for you!
Keep your minds open and take in, have it,
it’s a gift.
As you yourself know that – you have got
so many gifts from God.
How is it you have become a human being?
What have you done to become a human being?
This is a gift of God, this beautiful human
body, mind, everything you have got it.
And now that gift itself is going to transform
you into the greatest of greatest gift – is
to know your Father.
The One who has created you is anxious to
bestow all His powers to you, like a father
wants to bestow all his property.
So take it with both the hands and have it,
and enjoy it.
Before Realisation, I do not tell you that
you give up drinking, smoking or any kind
of nirodh.
No, I cannot ask you to do that.
But after Realisation, jolly well you give
it up, you just do it, because you now taste
the ambrosia, the amruta.
Then you don’t want to have anything else.
But, till you have tasted it, give some time,
have some patience.
You need not be very well educated for this.
You need not have a very good practice of
say, standing on your heads!
You need not be going to churches or anything.
If you are a normal human being, it is going
to work out.
But mostly, when we do all these things, we
are abnormal.
Even in saying that we are seeking God, we
are doing lots of abnormal things.
We have to be absolutely normal.
It is like this room being dark, you are sitting
down here, now sit down!
It’s going to work out.
But we start jumping here and there and we
get hurt.
It’s like going in a boat: just keep quiet,
just be in the centre, with the centre of
gravity of the boat.
Just be there!
That is dharma.
In your sustenance, stay there.
I mean to remain good, you don’t have to
do anything.
I mean to become bad, you have to do something,
isn’t it?
All these things will come to you automatically
when there is light.
Just be quiet.
All of you are going to get it.
That is being ordained, that’s being arranged,
organised, very well within you, beautifully.
As in a seed everything is arranged, to create
a tree, it’s arranged within you.
But you have to be together, work it out,
understand each other and this group grows
in that understanding, in collectivity, and
creates a nucleus for others to follow it.
So, there should be no problem for you to
understand that it is a special grace.
Because you are special, maybe I am also special,
and special people needed somebody special,
so I had to come down here!
Let’s have it in a mutual admiration way,
will be a good idea.
There is no need to feel obliged because I
have to do it.
I feel loaded with it and I feel lighter when
you get it.
Like a mother I tell you.
Sometimes I have to be stern.
I know the job of a mother.
You need not be afraid of me at all.
I know everything about you, somehow.
Like we had one Douglas (Fry) with us and
I suddenly asked him, “What about your birthday?”
He was taken aback!
He didn’t know – he’s sitting here – how
I knew that his birthday was there.
And he really had a rebirth from the life
he had.
And when I said, he said , “How do You know,
Mother?”
I said , “I know what about your birthday.”
And I went to his house and saw him.
[I was] so overjoyed to see him settled down.
It is amazing how your seed grows and how
fragrant you become.
May God bless you all.
If you have any questions, please ask me.
We have little time.
There are eighty-four tapes already with these
people and, if you want to have tapes for
yourself, you can give them the tapes and
they can tape for you or perhaps…
Those who do not feel vibration should not
get upset.
There’s something wrong somewhere.
I may not tell you on your face, because I
don’t want to hurt you in any way.
But doesn’t matter, I am going to work it
out, you see, doctor doesn’t come and tell
you that, “You have got all these diseases
and you may die next moment.”
If doctor can do that, I am after all your
Mother, so I am not going to tell you.
You yourself will know, later on, what was
wrong with you.
Because by knowing that, you are not going
to help yourself.
On the contrary, you are going to feel dejected.
Now please put your hands just like this,
just like this.
And both the feet on the ground, straight.
On the ground.
I think perhaps next Monday is the last meeting,
is it?
Two more?
You are going to have me till the the end
is it?
Alright!
So I was thinking of, next Monday, I’ll
be telling about elements and all those things
how we are made.
That would be better.
Now close your eyes please.
If you watch your thoughts you’ll find there
are no thoughts.
Keep your eyes shut.
Just see.
There are no thoughts in your mind.
Now, in your finger tips you’ll feel a cool
breeze coming in.
That means the Realisation has taken place
because the cool breeze is the sign of the
Holy Ghost, in Sanskrit it is, “salilam,
salilam,” described that the Spirit emits
or radiates, you can say, Itself as cool breeze.
The light of the Spirit is the cool breeze.
Power of God.
It’s a breeze like thing which starts floating
or going inside your…If any one of you are
feeling sleepy, keep your eyes open please.
Be alert.
You have to be alert because this is the happening
for which you have been desiring.
See for yourself.
The more desirous you are the better it is.
Are you getting cool breeze in the hand?
Good.
Close your eyes and enjoy yourself.
All those who are getting cool breeze, please
raise your hands, all of you.
All those who are getting cool breeze in the
hand, please raise your hands.
All those who are feeling cool breeze in the
Now those who have come today and not yet
Realised and are not getting cool breeze,
please raise your hands.
Can you come forward?
Keep your eyes shut, please.
That lady?
You’re getting the cool breeze in the hands?
Are you feeling any cool breeze?
Lady: Not so much.
Shri Mataji: Not so much?
So you started thinking about it, that’s
all.
Alright.
So for that you ask for forgiveness, that,
“I should not think about it,” and it
will start flowing.
Alright?
By thinking you did not get it.
So, it’s alright now.
Good!
See how clever it is!
Still wearing that?
What is that?
Now see him what’s the matter.
On the heart he is catching.
Now, better now ? It plays tricks.
John, see here, this side.
Don’t watch others at this time.
You watch yourself, alright?
Very important.
You catch people.
Just don’t watch.
Watch yourself.
This is the time to watch yourself, alright?
David, come forward, here.
John, you also come here, I would like to
see you.
John, you come here.
David, you come here.
Lindsey, you also come here.
Let’s see.
You sit down here first.
Lindsey just come here I would like to see
you also.
Just there.
Just somewhere here.
Just sit.
Is that Alan?
How are you?
Better now?
Better?
Can you come forward.
You also.
Just let me see.
I wanted to see your vibrations also.
Yes, please.
Come forward.
Can you take two chairs?
You must see your vibrations.
We must get ourselves corrected.
There may be some sort of a thing because
the vibrations if they are not sucking in
alright, then there is some problem.
Let’s get it alright.
What is there to feel bad about anything whatsoever?
Well, Alan, just come here, if possible.
Alright.
You can take a chair here next to John.
Alan, please open your eyes, please.