[Music]
today we are here
to know about guru principle what does a
guru to whatever you have all the
precious things within you he discovers
them for your knowledge
actually it is all there everything all
the knowledge all the spirituality all
the joy is there like time
is all contained within you
only thing the guru does
makes you knowledgeable about your
knowledge about your own spirit everyone
has the spirit within himself everyone
has the spirituality within yourself
there is nothing that you get from
outside but before getting this
knowledge you are dealing or you are
living in ignorance in that ignorance
you do not know what clay here you have
got within ear so the Guru's job is to
make you know what you are that
sensation that you should know your
but means you know yourself you know
party the experience is not so she the
knowledge has to come and the Guru gives
the knowledge about yourself now you
have to tell it you should find out
whatever your guru has to it is it true
or not
is it correct or not when we talk about
realization one has to do first of all
that we have to have patience with
ourselves I know some people don't feel
so good
some people still have sicknesses some
people don't even feel vibration
sometimes have patience with you when
you become your own guru first thing as
the Guru has patience with his or her
disciple you must have patience
in that patience you will learn that you
can tolerate so many things without any
club
they say one person who goes on grudging
oh this is not good that is not good
because they have no patience with
themselves if you have patience with
yourself everything you'll accept
wherever you are you are with yourself
cause you're realized Souls so you want
the state to not get angry
and also you not go on crumbling than
clutching because you are enjoying
yourself so for such people who have
imaginary miseries of the past which do
not exist in reality
they cannot have the joy of reality they
can so for a sahaja yogi is important
that he should have joy
within his heart it's like an ocean it's
like an ocean which is there all the
time to give you such trees
even little drops of this ocean when
they trickle down in your being it is so
soothing the experience can be only
experienced it's all waiting within
yourself so I sahaja Yogi's and as gurus
we have to love ourselves and understand
our own wagon
I think sahaja Yogi's have not yet
understood their worth how many people
in this world can give realization how
many know about Kundalini so this is
what is to remember that you are a
sahaja yogi take abandon owning and
ending it's so simple even to say on the
mind it seems stupid to me but I have to
say because people forget you forget
that you are realizes use your vibratory
awareness for at least protecting
yourself
because there is negativity sitting next
to her so they're very careful about
this to remember that I am a sahaja yoga
once you say that you will know how you
have to behave what is the protocol you
will know what is the discipline you
have to follow you will know how to love
others everything this is the essence
that will give you complete confidence
in yourself and will be absolutely
secure try to establish the state that
you are sahaja yoga thus you become
gurus of yourself and of others I hope
we will understand as a guru what you
have to do as a guru there's so many
change and as your character yesterday
as they showed how love se has written
about the Masters how they were about
about turmoil about jealousy about
talking loose they are so great they are
the Masters and they will be the Masters
and you will be the Guru's if you try to
do this what you hope to achieve I know
somehow achieve it but most of you have
to achieve with compassion and may about
this
[Music]
you