Today you all have decided to have the puja
of Adi Shakti.
There’s a difference between doing the puja
of Kundalini Shakti or Adi Kundalini and Adi
Shakti.
The difference is like this, on one side the
Kundalini is reflected in you by Adi Kundalini.
The second side is the power of Adi Shakti
which is Paramchaitanya.
So in totality if you see, it has two sides:
one is Her power as Paramchaitanya and also
reflection in human beings as Kundalini.
The third work that Adi Shakti had to do was
to create this whole universe.
To begin with, as you have seen yesterday
also, how the cosmos was created and then
how this special planet of Mother Earth was
created.
Now what I have told you about Adam and Eve
we have found out said by also John in his
Gnostics book.
It is very surprising.
They’ve always told you that Christ must
have told you many things but they are not
in the Bible.
So if you understand that this Adi Shakti
came as a serpent, the Adi Kundalini part
of Her, and told the Adam and Eve, especially
Eve, that she should ask for the fruit of
knowledge to be eaten.
And the reason I gave you is exactly the thing
there; that the Mother power, the feminine
power didn’t want Her children to live like
animals without understanding what is the
knowledge of the higher realms, not giving
them chance to rise higher through their freedom
and then to higher and higher awareness.
It was the concern of the Mother.
So there were two types of worlds were created:
one was the Divine and another one started
evolving.
To look at it looks very tremendous task thousands
of thousands, billions and billions of years,
have passed for this kind of a work to be
done.
But if you see in modern age we are going
to the moon, at such a small, with such a
small effort and also with, with such a little
time you reach there.
Nobody could think that we ever be there.
All this is happened through the human brain.
Now what is the human brain after all?
Human brain is not at all anywhere near the
brain of the [Bharat?] nor is this used fully,
it’s not used fully.
It’s very little bit is used by human beings,
by which they have achieved this kind of a
flight to moon.
Of course there was no purpose in it, I don’t
know why they are doing it.
But they did it.
So the whole nature was created by Her.
Whatever you see today around yourself is
all created by Her, is all Her work that is
there.
You’ll be amazed, just now I said I was
going to wear a very heavy sari and I said
it’s very hot so better change to a simple
sari so I changed and when I came out I found
it has become cooler.
So the nature knows everything and who informs
the nature is this Paramchaitanya.
Paramchaitanya was never that active which
has started since My birth, I should say,
when Krita Yuga started.
At this time you had to have your realisation.
That was decided by the Divine collectivity
you can call it.
All the Gods, Goddesses, all of them decided
to put this work on somebody who thought,
whom they thought to be very capable.
So They said We all will be with You, entirely
with You, all Our powers will be with You
but You take up this job now in this Kali
Yuga to transform human beings.
In a way human beings are more difficult than
animals because they have their own freedom
and they have been given this freedom to achieve
their final freedom.
In their freedom, the way they behave, is
something very surprising how they go completely
out of control and try to do things which
are so destructive.
Of course in Kali Yuga it was predicted in
India but I think they could not predict what
would happen in America or what would happen
in the Western countries where people have
freedom just to destroy themselves and they’re
finding new methods of destroying themselves.
This tendency cannot be curbed, cannot be
stopped by Adi Shakti or by God Almighty because
you have been given the freedom to ruin yourselves,
spoil yourselves and to go to hell.
That cannot be controlled by any Divine power.
Divine power also respects your freedom.
So the Divine collectivity thought, are We
going to completely ruin the creation of Adi
Shakti.
Are We going to completely destroy whatever
She has created and then re-create something
better, this was the discussion going on.
And most of Them were so fed up with the human
beings, especially with the Western freedom
that They said these people want help.
And why should We give them the Heavens, it’s
not proper.
So first thing Adi Shakti did was to create
a seeking in them.
She created it, this desire to seek.
And so these people belonging to this culture
which was so destructive started seeking.
And when the seeking started, also, as usual
in the market there were many others who came
forward to demand [answers/substance?] to
their seeking.
They had to go to various cults and things
and false people and all that because they
had no way to know.
But if they had read some books of enlightened
people like Kabir, like Nanak, even Gnostics,
their scriptures, anything like that, they
would have understood what is the truth and
where to find it and how to find it.
It is a big struggle I find between the people
who are seekers and those who are not at all
seekers.
They don’t want to know and they can never
be seekers.
I can assure you that some of them will never
think of seeking.
They’ll get possessed, they’ll have diseases,
they’ll have earthquakes, they’ll have
anything, they will never seek.
Even if they get diseases, they’ll say “Oh,
we are martyrs, we’re doing great work”.
Such stupidity has come into their heads that
they think that by doing these wrong things,
we are going to be saved.
And this stupidity comes through perverted
brains.
And this perverted brain acts when people
are free to use.
I just don’t know why don’t they see around
and see for themselves what is happening.
So to expect that the whole world will go
to Heaven is absolutely not possible, it’s
not possible, it cannot.
They have tried all kinds of things.
I’ve seen people ah drugs, alcohol, this,
that.
There is one fellow who got his PhD on writing
how he reached spirituality through drinking
and they gave him PhD for that.
So even at the helm of affairs in the universities,
I don’t know how such stupid people came
up, from where, out of which creation.
It’s impossible to understand how could
they think that this kind of destruction will
lead them to their salvation.
They see it everyday.
They watch it everyday.
They know it, it’s happening but still they
cannot listen.
But those who are seekers are so ardently
seeking that they will all have to be given
their self-realisation.
Now this is of course My job I agree.
I have come on this earth for that job.
I am suppose to do it.
I am trying my level best and no incarnation
has lived like I have lived for so many years
and such compassion of Mine which really makes
Me think that I feel we have to have many
more sahaja yogis, we have to have big salvation.
With that compassion and with that love, one
can take to any measures, anything.
I do not think those who are not seekers will
achieve it.
Now why is it some are seekers and some are
not?
One may say that Adi Shakti if She has created
all the human beings, all of them should have
seeking.
Because in freedom, they have lost their way.
They are seeking something else.
And they think they’re right.
They have a right to think that they are right.
Even a stupid fellow, even a mad person thinks
he's right.
If you tell him that you are mad, he’ll
say, you are mad.
And this seeking though put into them, they
are not yet capable, so many of them, of achieving
it in the proper way.
Because for that one has to surrender, not
one’s freedom, not one’s intelligence
but the ego that has developed in human beings.
With this ego even I’ve seen people who
are possessed, they want to keep their ego
intact and through the ego they want to use,
to use the possessions.
Can you imagine?
There are possessions of negative forces.
Such people want to keep that intact so that
they can use it for their own purpose.
They don’t hate it, they don’t want to
get rid of it.
But they want to keep it just because they
can use this possessions for their use.
So the category of seeking is much less there.
But there are many who are no where near seeking
who are really what we call them the evil
people and they never want, never never would
want that this world should change.
Our media is dominated by these evil people.
They don’t want world to change.
They don’t want to show anything that is
good.
They don’t want to see the point what is
going to help, what is benevolent for human
beings.
So on one side, we see
such collective search, collective negativity.
Another side we find seekers who are real
seekers.
There are some we can call as half-baked and
some are pseudo seekers.
If there, and in the name of seeking, if they
have done we can say some sort of a sacrifice
for them, they are very great.
Also they get involved with people who are
claiming.
Because I have never claimed anything, they
are not impressed by me.
I’ve not changed my dress.
I live like a housewife.
So they are not impressed by me.
I have not developed two [horns??] to show
something great about myself so they won’t
be impressed.
But on the other side if you see, this is
maya, this is Mahamaya where Adi Shakti you
see does everything like human beings do,
everything.
You won’t be able to find out that She is
Divine.
My family people could not find out till I
started this work, none of them, except for
my father and mother.
Nobody could find out that I had any powers.
Such insensitivity to Divine can be created
by Mahamaya power of Adi Shakti, which is
very important, otherwise you cannot judge,
you cannot understand.
Despite that, I’ve many times misjudged
people because they know how to camouflage
for a little while.
But then I discover.
If the seeking is ardent and they are seeking
really the truth, they will find it, they
will find it, no doubt because the whole creation
is for them.
The whole universe is for them.
All Dieties are for them.
All angels are for them.
They are all looking out for them.
This is important that we have so many sahaja
yogis.
Nobody had so many sahaja yogis in their lifetime.
Because we have to have channels.
I have to have channels and these channels
have to be very clean, have to be beautiful,
innocent and benevolent.
If only they surrender to this fact that we
are here for as the instrument of God Almighty
and that we have to give benevolence to others,
I tell you at least 70% of work is done.
But even if they have got realisation, like
an egg comes out of the shell, some of the
birds still carry the part of the egg and
some of them are not even grown up to be birds.
Now we have to judge ourselves.
We have to understand ourselves.
Another thing you know that, I’m a very
mild person, very mild.
People think I’m very forgiving.
I know everyone, not that I don’t.
But I allow alright, go ahead, as far as you
can go.
Experience is the only way a human being can
understand, no doubt.
If you tell him something, he will never understand.
Experience of self-realisation has made you
understand but again, I would say, that we
cannot give realisation to the whole world,
we cannot.
They’re like stones, absolutely horrible
people.
Whatever is happening is that those who are
false are getting exposed.
And everybody is noticing that that they are
getting exposed.
This exposure of course will save them from
these horrible people.
But I don’t know if they will come to Sahaja
Yoga or if they would take their realisation.
This I’m telling you because now I to have
experience of human beings and all these years
I have been working, I have seen that there
are people and people and people.
Out of them the seekers are extremely proud
of their seeking.
So some of them don’t want to give up their
seeking, it's, it’s kind of a job.
You can call it a hobby, they are seekers.
Now they have a certificate of being a seeker,
they wear funny dresses, have funny houses,
funny hair, everything, recluses they could
be, aggressive, anything, we are seekers.
They take a certificate upon themselves, we
are seekers.
This is another quality of seekers also.
They, for them it’s a kind of lifestyle,
they're seekers and wherever they have to
go, they will go for seeking, they’ll go
to 10 places, or 20 places.
Every time they have argued with me, Mother
there must be some more ways of, yes maybe,
I don’t know of any, you can know.
Now the main job of Adi Shakti today is to
give realisation.
That’s My main job.
All the rest is looked after, is already managed
I should say is like a computer.
I don’t have to work it, it’s a reflex
action.
Whatever is happening is in a reflex action.
I don’t have to worry about these things,
whether ah like people might say that, “Mother
I prayed to you and how is it you helped me
so much?”
It’s all reflex action.
That time maybe that thought may come to me,
thought, but it’s reflex action.
I really don’t do anything.
Actually, I’m a [Shria??].
Not doing anything whatsoever.
The laziest person you could think of is Me.
Really because if there's a complete organisation
working for Me why should I, why [there is
nothing necessary].
But one thing is there, I’m witnessing and
when I’m witnessing that acts on the reflex,
that works out, the Paramchaitanya.
Because if that is the power of the Adi Shakti
then whatever I witness gets reported to that
power.
It’s the other way round, like see we have
electricity power somewhere so something goes
wrong here, it is not reflected to that power.
It is not.
Something goes wrong, it finishes off here
and here.
But the other way round that if I witness
something wrong, I don’t have to do anything,
I just witness, I’m just watching, the whole
thing acts through this tremendous power of
Paramchaitanya.
Now this power you do not know.
You know Kundalini, you know all about charkas
there, this, that, but this power of Paramchaitanya
is in every particle in you, every atom.
And it acts in such a manner that it directs,
it pushes you, it takes you to the path of
benevolence.
Sometimes people say, “Mother I wanted to
see to buy this shop, I couldn’t get it"
and all that.
It is for your benevolence you didn’t get,
thank God.
After 10 days they’ll come and say, thank
God I didn’t get it.
So gradually through experience, you start
understanding that you don’t have to worry.
If you are lost on the way, normally people
get very upset but sahaja yogis don’t, oh
very nice, must be something here that God
has brought us.
This action is like then changes.
I would say the person who is overactive,
starts thinking now, surrender, Islam, surrender.
Give this problem to this Paramchaitanya and
it works.
Such tremendous things have happened in this
world just by bandhans that it is unbelievable
how these things are happening.
Even supposing you find there are so many
murders, this thing has happened, that has
happened.
This is also just to express presence of Paramchaitanya,
it’s prutha, it’s working out.
The way it works.
Prutha means the one which is done.
Then you start realising that this power you
can achieve through your Kundalini.
So when your Kundalini rises, that is also
a reflection of Adi Shakti.
Like we can say, we see one part of moon,
the another part we don’t see.
In the same way this power when rises within
you and touches this Paramchaitanya, then
you become empowered by that.
That’s how you are sahaja yogis.
But you are not God.
The incarnations can say, “Í am God”.
You are not incarnations.
But none of the incarnations have ever said
that they are Adi Shakti, cannot.
This power of Adi Shakti which we call Paramchaitanya
is the power that loves you, has complete
control of the nature.
It understands, it thinks, it knows everything,
everything about you, it knows.
It works in every angle in every walk of your
life.
It is with you entirely as if supposing you
fall into a river which is flowing fast and
you cannot swim anymore, you cannot use your
hands anymore, you start flowing with it and
then you realise that flowing with it is a
better thing than to try to get out of it.
But just flowing with it, just enjoy all the
nature around you.
You don’t get drowned.
On the contrary, you feel you are elevated.
And you’re flowing with it, then you understand,
what am I to do about something, whether it’s
done by Paramchaitanya for me.
But that it should be given to your Kundalini
which has worked it out, has put you onto
that shore, has put you onto that beautiful
Heavenly Kingdom of God.
Thus, you understand there are two things
that have happened: that first, your Mother,
your Kundalini which is within you, which
is your own Mother, which has been with you
throughout, has given you this birth.
And then it has taken to that power, which
power you can use yourself.
You are empowered by that.
You’ll be amazed how this power helps.
I mean, you see, I shouldn’t say that you
can have all the powers, I shouldn’t say
that.
But today you see they were complaining about
somebody, immediately I told the name of the
person.
Now you’ll say, how I knew.
I just know.
That’s all I can say.
Supposing you are dealing with carpets, alright,
so you know what pattern is this, what pattern
is that, from where it has come, everything,
you know, isn’t it.
If you are there, you know everything.
If this power is everywhere, one has to know
everything, the connection is such.
If you want to know, you can know anything.
So they have called also Buddha as Avalokiteshvara
that He sees all the lotus How does He see,
Avalokiteshvara, because His ego what we call
is the paramaego, Mahatahamkara, knows everything,
while your ego doesn’t know anything.
Because it doesn’t know anything, you are
enveloped by it.
If he had known, if the ego had known what
is the truth, you’ll be free person absolutely
free.
But you don’t want to surrender your ego.
You don’t want to allow yourself to flow
into the river as Tao, [??] we say.
No you don’t want to enjoy, you want to
have your own speciality.
Individuality is very different from having
a kind of a ego within yourself that I am
this, I am that.
So this differentiation must start, after
realisation, in the light of realisation,
you should start seeing.
Now the first and foremost thing is to tell
your ego to sit down, keep quiet, you don’t
want.
And also in the modern times it’s a big
fashion you ask somebody, “I don’t know”.
You ask somebody, what’s your name, “I
don’t know”.
He doesn’t even know his name.
And to be stupid is a fashion.
To show that you are very stupid they think
they are showing they’re very innocent.
It’s not, it’s a stupidity.
This stupidity, I don’t know which animal
has.
Still I don’t know what is the source of
it.
Still I’ll have to find out.
Who is the animal that has generated this
stupidity in them.
But I know one thing, it is our ego.
Ego makes a person absolutely stupid.
In Marathi, you see, thank God, language is
so rich, that anybody who starts showing off
his ego, they say his climbing on a bush,
there is a little bush and he is climbing
on that.
All this ego comes through your own so called
ideas, achievements.
But what are these achievements.
You don’t know anything.
And this is what today I have to tell you
that if anything is working out today, is
your surrender of your ego.
If you know how to surrender your ego, you’ll
work it out.
Another thing which surprises me sometimes,
in the West specially, that I think that the
women are the power are the Shakti.
But in the West I find women are not using
Adi Shakti, no.
Firstly, they are still very much possessed
by their emotions and by their ideas and things
like that.
One side is man, who is doing everything.
But even women are very egoistical, very much.
It’s very difficult.
For example, you marry some girl, Western
girl, to somebody, she’ll be very happy,
jumping, taking all the presents, congratulations,
wearing all dress, everything.
After 10 days, she’ll come and say, “Mother
I’m confused”.
Confused, how?
“I’m now confused”.
You’re confused now or before.
Alright.
You return all your ornaments and everything.
“No, no then let me think”.
This is not the level of a sahaja yogini.
Sahaja yogini is the Shakti and she has to
take up challenges, I’ll show you, I’ll
do it better.
On the contrary I find them extremely dominating,
I’m amazed, why should Shakti dominate.
If she’s Shakti, she’ll not dominate.
Those who are not will dominate.
Like you see you go in India to any collector’s
house, the collector will be humble but the
constable would be dominating.
In the same way, I find, this domination business
is very common.
And also a kind of a temperament of like a
nun.
They’ll dress up like a nun, behave like
a nun.
They won’t smile.
What is?
Are you sahaja yoginis?
Or what are you, are you nuns?
Then better join nunnery.
Why I’m telling you while talking about
Adi Shakti so I’m talking about Shakti,
how the Shakti has to come up.
I was surprised that women were not spreading
Sahaja Yoga.
Somebody told me that the leaders do not want
women to spread Sahaja Yoga.
This is wrong.
If the leaders say that, it’s not proper.
But first of all the sahaja yoginis have to
be real sahaja yoginis because so far I’ve
seen anybody is, you try to give any lady,
try to give her the position of a leader,
she just finishes off the thing.
Not all, but some.
Now the duty of a sahaja yogini is to develop
herself through meditation, through understanding
oneself and through self-esteem that I’m
a sahaja yogini, I’m the one who is Shakti,
I’m the potential of that.
I’m the potential myself.
What do I do, nothing?
I didn’t do like this, I didn’t put this
on, nothing of the kind.
I’m nice visiting and talking.
But potential, am I the potential?
This is what the sahaja yoginis have to decide.
Otherwise, they’re possessed, they're day
dreaming, thinking no end of themselves.
It’s very difficult.
I want some nice sahaja yoginis to be the
leaders, I really want.
But as soon as they become leader, they are
on a horse, running so fast.
So humble downwards.
Unless and until there’s a big space in
the pitcher what water can flow into it.
Have a very large heart.
Anybody comes to your house, you don’t like
it, don’t want to do anything for other
sahaja yogis, looking after them.
It is really again and again I say in the
West, that women have to take up Shakti unto
themselves.
And Shakti doesn’t mean dominate your husband
and make a fool out of him.
No, it means give him powers.
You are the supply of power of the whole family.
And this is our family.
All this is my family.
I’m so concerned about everyone.
Even the little thing I’m bothered about.
I’m never satisfied that I’ve done my
job now and I can now tonight I’ll go off
to sleep and not think of anyone.
Never.
I’m concerned about this, I’m concerned
about that.
All the time it’s flowing, this power, and
My concern this power that works because My
concern is genuine.
I’m not concerned about Myself, never.
You’ll be amazed when I see all these women
doing all kinds of things to themselves, I’m
surprised.
What is needed is the concern.
And once you develop that concern, a genuine,
loving, compassionate concern about others.
Even about children, I’ve seen that, they
never look after each other’s children.
They never help others.
Somebody had to go for taking out the tooth,
she had to carry the child with her.
This is true.
If you do not have concern, then you’ll
not have collective mind, you’ll not have
the collective power.
And it’s important that you all should try
to be very collective, look after each other’s.
Now I shouldn’t say this, I was going to
tell it to Cabella ladies, that this house
in Cabella is an ashram and those people who
come from other ashrams, even from Australia,
are surprised, that they are all living here
just like a hotel.
They’re paying for it, we all pay but we
have gardens, we look after the gardens, we
look after the outside.
Here nobody’s bothered.
They’re using everything, not bothered.
Surprisingly why when I’m living here, they
are like this.
You go to any place in Australia, you go to
America, anywhere, wherever there’s an ashram,
they all work on Sundays.
Here I’ve not seen.
They all disappear.
This is your ashram.
You are staying here.
And is now today I have to tell this because
I feel that Sahaja Yoga is missing out itself
on their Shaktis.
Some of them do not know how to smiling, And
some of them are extremely dominating.
I have to tell you this because you are so
important.
But for Me, no man would have done this job.
No man incarnation would have done this job.
Christ, he get crucified at a young age, very
nice.
Get crucified at such a young age, then another
one takes to poison, another one is killed
by somebody.
It’s like that, they all died very young.
Nobody wanted to do this work, nobody was,
I mean, they got fed up.
Got fed up.
We had Ganeshwara who went into Samadhi at
the age of 23 years, can you imagine.
He must have been fed up with the people.
Now it is for you people, the ladies, have
to develop that patience of your Mother, that
affection, that love and then you will see
how your Shakti will work out.
I again and again always have talked about
this.
And at Adi Shakti point, I have to say you
are in your family like a Shakti.
And you have to be wise, you have to be sensible.
You have to understand your husband.
You have to understand your children.
You have to have patience.
On the contrary, they spoil their children.
That is to be understood, that you must know
first what is good for their benevolence.
Today for example, if I say the children if
they go to a school, they should not be removed.
It is for their benevolence.
What are the people going to gain out of it.
So somebody says no.
Alright, get out.
What can you do?
Such attachment to your own children shows
you are a powerless person.
You must love all the children, you must look
after all the children, you must enjoy all
the children, take interest.
But what I find that they are only interested
in their own children.
We are a joint family.
We live together.
We have to share everything.
It is something I can’t understand.
Say, our, in India, say, if you see 5, 6 children,
all the girls will run after them.
All the women will look after them.
I mean, it’s such a pleasure to them, to
any children, just to look after them.
But this kind of insensitivity to your collective
behaviour is going to also spoil your children.
So what you are going to transmit to the whole
world is this Sahaja living and the women
make the society.
If Indian society is good, the credit goes
to the Indian women and their wisdom.
Men are stupid in India.
They spoil politics, economics, everything.
But society is still maintained and they are
very very still say on the right path.
This only comes because of the wisdom of the
women.
If the women are busy dressing up for hours
together, thinking about their clothes, what
they’re going to wear, finished.
This is a day of worshipping the Kundalini
who is the Mother.
She is the Mother.
And you are the mother.
You must know each and everything about your
child.
Somebody comes and tells me, “My child is
now a drug addict”.
How can that be possible?
In India children, don’t get drug addicts
because all the time the mother is on their
head like a hawk.
She knows where he goes, what he does, she
loves.
But she knows, very well.
Even when we are in college, even when I'm
married, we went home, my mother would ask,
“Where did you go?
Did I not say, come back by 6”.
Even when we are married.
And we are suppose to tell her.
That was the mother’s work.
The child where he goes, what does he do,
and then to say children don’t listen to
me.
Because why the children do not listen, because
you do not discipline them.
Here the atmosphere is very bad agreed, and
the children are very bad, agreed.
Everything is there, agreed.
But if you are a strong mother in your love,
your children will not wander.
See, even now as you know that, all the time
there are all these leaders are hovering around
Me, what is there.
I have no honey with me or anything but they
are just sitting there, just sitting next
to Me, all the leaders.
But this is after realisation but My even
all My nephews you see, they would all come
and sit next to Me, all My in, daughter-in-laws
they would sit next to Me, they would not
leave Me.
And people will start saying, what’s wrong
with you, you're all the time sticking on
to your aunt, what is it?
The concern and they understand that it is
for their benevolence you are telling them.
But yourself should be alright.
As a mother one has to be tolerant, one has
to understand but when you have to tell them
you have to tell them.
If you think you can tell them sharply or
maybe in a proper way but the child should
know that you love the child and that you
love all the children.
It is very subtle.
Like I've seen, once I took a child of one
sahaja yogi with Me to the market, he was
asking "I'll buy this, I'll buy that,[I]’ll
buy that", everything he wanted to buy.
I was wondering What's wrong with this boy.
But say if I take my own grandchildren, they
won't buy, nothing.
Even if you want to buy two pairs of shoes,
"No, no, no, one is sufficient".
If this will be then only.
They'll never ask for anything.
It's a kind of a self-esteem.
They don't want anything.
Same with the wives.
Wives never ask for anything from their husband,
nothing.
Nothing.
The husband will go on asking, please ask
for something, ask for something.
No, they don't want anything.
That is going to be a sahaja yogini mother
and a wife and a shakti.
She has no demands.
Nothing she's asking for.
The one who's a giver, what is she going to
ask.
The one who is a supplier, what is she going
to ask.
So I feel sometimes that the left side, the
women side in Sahaja Yoga is a little bit
going down.
And they have to come up.
First, meditation, the respect of Mother,
teaching the children how to work out Sahaja
Yoga, talking to them about Sahaja Yoga and
not only about food, of cleanliness, of being
nice to others, how to share things.
And telling children about good stories that
you have heard about.
Telling them what is dharma is, talking to
them.
Having a rapport.
This is what you have to understand to make
Sahaja Yoga very strong.
You are the Shakti of Sahaja Yoga take it
from Me.
And you have to work it out that way.
Instead of worrying about small, small things.
Some times I receive letters from the ladies,
sometimes, it really pains me.
I can't understand how they are sahaja yogis.
Our whole system of Sahaja has to be a moral
system that others should see and understand
that what we have achieved in our day to day
life.
Adi Shakti works in day to day life, the smallest
things to the highest.
And all the time you have to learn, all the
time you have to learn.
Whether you are a leader or not a leader,
all the time you must know what it is you
have to know.
I have not known this, I have not known that.
Unless and until you develop that kind of
an attitude that I have to learn that you
humble attitude, that humility, I have to
learn, I have to learn, still I have to learn,
this ego will never come.
Because of this ego you are satisfied with
yourself, that's the sign of an ego.
You don't know how much you are torturing
others, what you are destroying, nothing.
But you feel extremely happy with yourself.
Such a happy go lucky personality sometimes
is living on air.
What I have done today for somebody else,
how have I talked to somebody else, what have
I given to somebody else.
I need not give you presents, there's nothing,
why should I give you presents.
But I give you presents because of My own
satisfaction.
And if I take presents from you, it is for
your own satisfaction.
So what we have to do, in what we find satisfaction,
what do we find satisfaction, just think about
it, what do we find satisfaction in.
My house should be alright, my husband should
be alright, my children should be alright,
my, my, my.
Unless and until this my shifts to another
person, you are still in the realm of maya.
You have to learn this is to think everyday
or write, all of you should write diaries,
what have I done for others, what have I said
to others, what will make or please another
person.
Small, small things can make the life so beautiful.
And also very big things there are for you.
If you do not think, if you do not think you
are very big, all these big things are also
for you.
It's like this, this whole sky can be covered
by one leaf if you see the leaf against the
sky, the leaf shows it’s existence.
In the same way, this whole vision of Sahaja
Yoga can be completely covered by one person
who stands with this great expanse, one person
here and one person there.
It's so remarkable.
It's such a lot of Sahaja Yoga.
There are people who are here and there and
there, so remarkable that if you take their
names also, I just feel I'm drenched into
the ocean of joy.
Only one person, then what about you?
Why can't we do that.
When Adi Shakti is with you reflected when
all Her powers are with you, how much we can
do in this expanse of My vision.
I want to have more and more people who will
be of some visions themselves.
But not small people who just think of their
children, think of food.
No, no, they are not wanted, useless.
They will all drop out.
I hope you have understood where you are,
what do you have, what is created within you
is this Kundalini which has given you all
the knowledge and everything.
But there are so many I know who don't even
know what is this chakra, they don't know,
I mean going to that limit of ignorance.
You have to know all these things.
You have to understand what it is because
this is for you, all for you, all this knowledge.
And the greatest of all is the faith.
Not a faith which is blind but enlightened
faith that you are now one with that Divine
power.
This should really settle you completely.
This is I think that this is one of the most
important pujas because so far guru pujas
have been there, so many people have worshipped
those gurus.
Or maybe My birthday as you think it be, it's
alright.
But I think to understand your own powers
of Kundalini and your powers that are available
to you to the working of Paramchaitanya is
very important.
That will give you confidence, that'll give
you compassion, that'll give you a vision
and that will make you a very great personality,
a very great personality.
What was George Washington?
They said he was great.
What was Abraham Lincoln.
He was great.
But you are all having your self-realisation.
You have to think of the whole universe, the
whole expanse unless and until that brain
develops in you, I'm sure very sure that the
progress of Sahaja Yoga within and without
will be less.
So understand these powers are with you.
You have to utilise them, with humility.
May God bless you.
0195AdiShakti94Hanumana