1
00:10:18,990 --> 00:10:27,123
Today we have assembled here

2
00:10:27,123 --> 00:10:34,356
to celebrate the Diwali, the Deepavali.

3
00:10:42,423 --> 00:10:56,556
Actually, only after Sahaja Yoga started,

4
00:10:56,556 --> 00:11:02,523
the real Diwali is taking shape.

5
00:11:13,656 --> 00:11:20,423
We had many beautiful lamps,

6
00:11:20,423 --> 00:11:29,756
and we had lot of oil to burn,

7
00:11:36,323 --> 00:11:48,890
but there was no spark, to enlighten the deepas.

8
00:12:01,423 --> 00:12:11,390
And the wick, as you call it is called
as bati in Hindi language

9
00:12:11,390 --> 00:12:14,489
is like your Kundalini,

10
00:12:25,756 --> 00:12:31,756
so the Kundalini had to meet the spark.

11
00:12:42,090 --> 00:12:49,690
The beautiful lamps were all a waste,
purposeless, pointless.

12
00:12:59,656 --> 00:13:08,890
And this is the great blessings in modern times,

13
00:13:08,890 --> 00:13:11,990
that so many lights are enlightened

14
00:13:11,990 --> 00:13:18,489
and we are having a Deepavali of human hearts.

15
00:13:35,656 --> 00:13:42,590
When you become the light,
you don’t worry about the lamp,

16
00:13:42,590 --> 00:13:45,590
how it looks, how it is to be made,

17
00:13:45,590 --> 00:13:48,023
it’s all done.

18
00:13:58,489 --> 00:14:06,790
You just have to worry about the flame, about the oil,

19
00:14:12,323 --> 00:14:16,656
because it’s the oil that burns and gives light.

20
00:14:22,190 --> 00:14:27,890
In Sanskrit language,
which is the language of the Gods,

21
00:14:31,790 --> 00:14:34,623
the oil is called as ‘snigdha’, ‘snigdha’;

22
00:14:34,623 --> 00:14:40,223
is something that is soft but is snigdha.

23
00:14:48,056 --> 00:14:55,190
And ‘sneha’ means ‘friendship of love.

24
00:15:02,290 --> 00:15:07,923
 And the poets in other languages have used this word,

25
00:15:07,923 --> 00:15:10,690
in different way calling it ‘neha’.

26
00:15:10,690 --> 00:15:15,456
They have sung the praise of this love.

27
00:15:24,290 --> 00:15:29,356
Every poet, every Saint

28
00:15:29,356 --> 00:15:37,023
has used this word in their beautiful poetry,

29
00:15:44,423 --> 00:15:52,790
whether they were in separation or they were
in the meeting, in the yoga, in the union.

30
00:16:01,890 --> 00:16:08,723
This love is the thing that gives the light.

31
00:16:13,290 --> 00:16:19,356
If this oil is not clean, contaminated,

32
00:16:19,356 --> 00:16:21,890
you get the smoke.

33
00:16:27,990 --> 00:16:30,256
but is pure,

34
00:16:30,256 --> 00:16:34,923
then it gives a brilliant light without any smoke.

35
00:16:41,823 --> 00:16:45,023
But when this oil is fragrant

36
00:16:45,023 --> 00:16:49,290
then the light gives the fragrance as well.

37
00:16:58,556 --> 00:17:03,423
The oil is made from various things.

38
00:17:08,423 --> 00:17:13,890
The one that comes from the Mother Earth cannot be used

39
00:17:13,890 --> 00:17:18,290
because it’s very materialistic, it gives carbon.

40
00:17:24,190 --> 00:17:29,190
Like petrol, kerosene,
it pollutes the atmosphere.

41
00:17:36,023 --> 00:17:39,223
Then the one that comes from animals,

42
00:17:39,223 --> 00:17:45,790
who are – some of them,
are very much worshipped in India,

43
00:17:45,790 --> 00:17:52,356
they have a very particular type of snigdha

44
00:17:52,356 --> 00:17:55,056
or we can call it ghee or oil

45
00:17:55,056 --> 00:18:04,123
which is giving a light which is
very soothing and peaceful.

46
00:18:19,489 --> 00:18:23,190
So when matter evolves into animal state

47
00:18:23,190 --> 00:18:26,990
also the oil evolves.

48
00:18:34,456 --> 00:18:41,390
But when this oil is rubbed
onto the feet of a Saint,

49
00:18:41,390 --> 00:18:44,323
it gets the fragrance.

50
00:18:52,756 --> 00:18:57,256
In the same way if this oil is
brought in contact with flowers

51
00:18:57,256 --> 00:18:59,356
it gives fragrance.

52
00:19:04,456 --> 00:19:12,023
So the feet of a Saint are
like the flowers on the tree.

53
00:19:17,523 --> 00:19:24,890
And when the flower falls on the ground,
the Mother Earth,

54
00:19:24,890 --> 00:19:35,556
it’s so delicate, it’s so sensible,
it doesn’t hurt Her.

55
00:19:35,556 --> 00:19:38,556
It falls with great reverence

56
00:19:38,556 --> 00:19:43,423
as a great homage to the Mother Earth.

57
00:19:54,290 --> 00:19:59,990
In the same way a Saint has to be gentle,

58
00:19:59,990 --> 00:20:07,590
gentle in the way the moonlight
falls upon this Earth.

59
00:20:18,790 --> 00:20:25,290
It is light without any burning in it,
no scorching.

60
00:20:29,223 --> 00:20:35,090
That gentleness one has to develop,

61
00:20:41,356 --> 00:20:46,890
out of the oil that is the love in your heart,

62
00:20:52,556 --> 00:20:54,856
which lubricates everything,

63
00:20:54,856 --> 00:20:57,323
which removes the frictions

64
00:21:04,123 --> 00:21:08,090
and soothes.

65
00:21:14,923 --> 00:21:20,123
You have seen the way nature works.

66
00:21:20,123 --> 00:21:24,623
We never see a flower opening out,

67
00:21:24,623 --> 00:21:31,190
we never see the fruit coming out of the flower.

68
00:21:41,323 --> 00:21:45,090
It is so gentle and so slow

69
00:21:49,090 --> 00:21:53,156
that the movement is not seen by these human eyes.

70
00:21:57,856 --> 00:22:03,890
Because the Nature wants you
should not be disturbed by the movements.

71
00:22:09,956 --> 00:22:17,990
The Nature cares, so you people
do not feel the growth,

72
00:22:17,990 --> 00:22:24,656
the movement and the explosions of the evolution

73
00:22:24,656 --> 00:22:32,790
or we can say the movement of Nature’s own behavior.

74
00:22:45,790 --> 00:22:50,056
In the same way a Saint, a Sahaja Yogi,

75
00:22:50,056 --> 00:22:56,323
has to move very smoothly
in the society of Sahaja Yogis.

76
00:23:07,756 --> 00:23:16,390
It is with the Sahaja Yogis, I said;
not with the non-Sahajas.

77
00:23:23,590 --> 00:23:31,856
Nature reacts to anything that is foreign.

78
00:23:36,856 --> 00:23:41,923
It throws out anything that is not Sahaj.

79
00:23:47,590 --> 00:23:53,990
In the same way, a Saint should not accept

80
00:23:53,990 --> 00:24:00,356
anything, anybody who is foreign to Sahaj behavior.

81
00:24:09,056 --> 00:24:17,723
When it deals with the matter,
with the materialistic people,

82
00:24:17,723 --> 00:24:26,990
then it acts with the greatest wisdom,
as the tip of a root.

83
00:24:36,790 --> 00:24:39,590
It moves with majesty,

84
00:24:39,590 --> 00:24:42,923
embeds itself into the Mother Earth

85
00:24:42,923 --> 00:24:47,356
going round all hard rocks

86
00:24:47,356 --> 00:24:49,590
and holding them together;

87
00:24:49,590 --> 00:24:52,890
it makes the tree to stand up erect.

88
00:25:03,190 --> 00:25:06,090
The sign of life is that

89
00:25:06,090 --> 00:25:16,156
it goes against the matter,
the one that is "jara".

90
00:25:23,890 --> 00:25:29,223
Like the tree goes against the gravity;

91
00:25:33,556 --> 00:25:37,990
like the great human beings
have lifted their body

92
00:25:37,990 --> 00:25:42,190
against the gravity in a straight posture.

93
00:25:48,556 --> 00:25:52,690
In the same way, if you see, the flame

94
00:25:52,690 --> 00:25:55,690
goes against the gravity.

95
00:26:00,190 --> 00:26:06,923
Nobody has heard of fire going from
the top floor to the ground floor.

96
00:26:12,123 --> 00:26:16,356
It starts from the ground floor
and it goes upward.

97
00:26:19,690 --> 00:26:27,423
But the fire also comes from
the matter which is burning.

98
00:26:32,656 --> 00:26:39,023
So the matter has to be burnt,
if you want to rise.

99
00:26:43,489 --> 00:26:48,123
If your attention is all the time
towards baser things,

100
00:26:48,123 --> 00:26:53,856
materialistic things,
towards physical pleasures,

101
00:26:53,856 --> 00:26:56,523
you cannot rise.

102
00:27:05,256 --> 00:27:10,290
You may do any amount of meditations,
use My Photographs, come to My Pujas,

103
00:27:10,290 --> 00:27:12,790
but if your attention is imbedded

104
00:27:12,790 --> 00:27:19,256
it’s like you are standing on a crocodile
trying to get into a boat.

105
00:27:35,023 --> 00:27:38,690
Now, that doesn’t mean when a flame burns,

106
00:27:38,690 --> 00:27:41,489
it gives up matter,

107
00:27:46,290 --> 00:27:50,756
but it gets detached and it burns it.

108
00:27:55,123 --> 00:27:56,856
So this body,

109
00:27:56,856 --> 00:27:58,656
this mind,

110
00:27:58,656 --> 00:27:59,656
this ego,

111
00:27:59,656 --> 00:28:01,590
this superego,

112
00:28:01,590 --> 00:28:09,190
is all to be burned to keep this flame
burning all the time.

113
00:28:19,190 --> 00:28:21,990
You don’t have to give up anything,

114
00:28:21,990 --> 00:28:27,190
but to use the same thing for a higher life,

115
00:28:35,256 --> 00:28:41,489
and that is what should be
the aim of every Sahaja Yogi.

116
00:28:47,690 --> 00:28:51,890
Actually after getting Realization,

117
00:28:51,890 --> 00:28:54,723
you just start spontaneously giving

118
00:28:54,723 --> 00:28:58,156
because you are the light.

119
00:29:06,923 --> 00:29:14,556
But respect your light and the light of others.

120
00:29:21,256 --> 00:29:24,056
The darkness is too much

121
00:29:28,456 --> 00:29:31,223
and we need so many lights

122
00:29:31,223 --> 00:29:33,690
to remove this darkness.

123
00:29:39,190 --> 00:29:44,190
These lights are to be maintained,
to be looked after,

124
00:29:44,190 --> 00:29:45,956
to be loved.

125
00:29:54,156 --> 00:29:56,523
As you know very well,

126
00:29:56,523 --> 00:29:59,223
I cannot do it alone.

127
00:30:03,256 --> 00:30:10,056
For example the source of electricity,
if you use to burn,

128
00:30:10,056 --> 00:30:13,223
you may have a big explosion.

129
00:30:13,223 --> 00:30:16,356
It has to go to various bulbs

130
00:30:16,356 --> 00:30:20,923
to give a nice, spread-out light.

131
00:30:34,056 --> 00:30:37,323
And you are the channels,

132
00:30:37,323 --> 00:30:45,090
you are the ones who are going
to express Me.

133
00:30:53,456 --> 00:30:57,323
I am just the potential energy,

134
00:31:00,523 --> 00:31:05,456
as the energy is coming from
somewhere which is stored

135
00:31:05,456 --> 00:31:06,890
and if I asked you,

136
00:31:06,890 --> 00:31:10,990
you would not even know where it is stored.

137
00:31:31,156 --> 00:31:34,623
It is through your behaviour,

138
00:31:34,623 --> 00:31:37,690
through your pure lights,

139
00:31:37,690 --> 00:31:40,290
through your fragrance,

140
00:31:40,290 --> 00:31:44,390
people are going to know God Almighty.

141
00:31:56,623 --> 00:32:02,256
There are some, which can blacken the Face;

142
00:32:02,256 --> 00:32:04,690
they are lights no doubt,

143
00:32:04,690 --> 00:32:07,256
but can blacken the Face

144
00:32:07,256 --> 00:32:10,356
if there are impurities,

145
00:32:18,456 --> 00:32:21,090
blacken the Face of the Divine,

146
00:32:21,090 --> 00:32:28,590
blacken the Face of your Creator.

147
00:32:41,323 --> 00:32:46,190
And that is what, one has to be careful,

148
00:32:46,190 --> 00:32:53,156
that we are not blackening the Name
of God by our misbehaviour.

149
00:33:05,323 --> 00:33:08,156
Now listen to Me very carefully,

150
00:33:11,790 --> 00:33:16,690
If there is no light out of the lamp,

151
00:33:16,690 --> 00:33:21,190
it does not blacken nor enlighten.

152
00:33:28,390 --> 00:33:33,823
But if there is a light,

153
00:33:33,823 --> 00:33:39,656
it can blacken as well as enlighten.

154
00:33:46,156 --> 00:33:49,156
It’s only the Sahaja Yogis who

155
00:33:49,156 --> 00:33:54,590
can blacken or enlighten
the Name of God Almighty.

156
00:34:05,489 --> 00:34:09,523
Say, for example, if you have a fake man,

157
00:34:09,523 --> 00:34:12,690
he doesn’t blacken the Name of God

158
00:34:12,690 --> 00:34:15,090
because he is himself black,

159
00:34:15,090 --> 00:34:18,256
so nobody’s bothered about that.

160
00:34:28,256 --> 00:34:33,990
If there is a person
who is teaching about God

161
00:34:33,990 --> 00:34:37,156
or talking about God, about religion

162
00:34:37,156 --> 00:34:39,790
and making money out of it,

163
00:34:52,190 --> 00:34:54,890
he blackens his own name.

164
00:34:57,656 --> 00:35:01,489
He does not blacken the Name of God Almighty.

165
00:35:05,656 --> 00:35:10,890
The Name of God, cannot be blackened,

166
00:35:10,890 --> 00:35:14,056
It’s ever shining.

167
00:35:18,856 --> 00:35:21,223
But it’s only a Sahaja Yogi

168
00:35:21,223 --> 00:35:27,356
which can form that cloud to cover It.

169
00:35:33,590 --> 00:35:38,990
They can only finish the hope of this world.

170
00:35:44,090 --> 00:35:49,923
They can only bring the real
destruction of this world.

171
00:35:55,090 --> 00:35:58,823
They will be held responsible.

172
00:36:02,223 --> 00:36:05,723
And they should be punished in time,

173
00:36:05,723 --> 00:36:12,190
so that the Name of God should not be ruined.

174
00:36:17,756 --> 00:36:23,356
For they have been given the right
to enter into the Kingdom of God,

175
00:36:23,356 --> 00:36:25,489
others are outside.

176
00:36:32,456 --> 00:36:36,556
They are the only ones who can abuse the right.

177
00:36:40,290 --> 00:36:44,489
Those who are outside this building,
cannot spoil it.

178
00:36:49,390 --> 00:36:51,823
You have the special privilege

179
00:36:51,823 --> 00:36:55,023
to enter into this beautiful building.

180
00:37:02,990 --> 00:37:11,790
You have got this right because of the
great things you have done in previous lives.

181
00:37:20,256 --> 00:37:24,990
And if you now want to spoil it,

182
00:37:24,990 --> 00:37:32,290
you’d better understand that
you will be very severely punished.

183
00:37:40,290 --> 00:37:46,489
The light which can enlighten can also burn.

184
00:37:51,623 --> 00:37:59,790
But this light will burn all those
who try to burn the Kingdom of God.

185
00:38:05,356 --> 00:38:08,090
So on a Diwali day let us know that

186
00:38:08,090 --> 00:38:13,990
we should have the lamps, burnt in such a way that

187
00:38:13,990 --> 00:38:19,556
it has purest of pure love in it.

188
00:38:34,790 --> 00:38:41,489
Not a lip service, lip service of love,

189
00:38:46,190 --> 00:38:49,390
but from your heart.

190
00:38:51,290 --> 00:38:55,590
It should pour,

191
00:38:55,590 --> 00:38:59,990
like the Nature pours
all its blessings upon you.

192
00:39:08,590 --> 00:39:15,523
Then, wherever the flowers
of your feet will touch,

193
00:39:15,523 --> 00:39:19,590
the Nature will blossom with joy.

194
00:39:28,323 --> 00:39:31,056
There will be a Deepavali.

195
00:39:33,156 --> 00:39:42,190
Like I was told when, before coming to Rome,
Italy had no rain.

196
00:39:48,390 --> 00:39:51,323
The Mother Earth was parched.

197
00:39:55,056 --> 00:39:59,690
And as soon as you all Sahaja Yogis
came on this Mother Earth,

198
00:39:59,690 --> 00:40:02,790
it started pouring.

199
00:40:13,290 --> 00:40:20,256
So the purity of love is to be understood
with complete discretion,

200
00:40:28,790 --> 00:40:32,023
because this purity acts;

201
00:40:34,323 --> 00:40:42,956
it acts in the nature, it acts in the
human beings, it acts into everything.

202
00:40:51,056 --> 00:40:59,090
The action is the same as the action,
the gentle action of the Mother Earth.

203
00:41:07,090 --> 00:41:11,723
Those who come in contact with such a personality

204
00:41:11,723 --> 00:41:24,290
start suddenly feeling the soothing, the settling,
of the whole being, into a blissful state.

205
00:41:35,590 --> 00:41:37,156
into a blissful state.

206
00:41:49,890 --> 00:41:52,823
State of benediction.

207
00:41:52,823 --> 00:41:59,390
But I don’t know, after this word,
how much has gone wrong,

208
00:41:59,390 --> 00:42:02,323
because our words are corrupt.

209
00:42:02,323 --> 00:42:04,790
Our words are corrupt,

210
00:42:04,790 --> 00:42:10,090
they do not express what they mean.

211
00:42:10,090 --> 00:42:13,323
They are not also pure.

212
00:42:26,823 --> 00:42:32,356
They do not reflect what is to be reflected.

213
00:42:38,190 --> 00:42:46,890
So, it is for us to create
new meanings of the words,

214
00:42:51,656 --> 00:42:53,890
give a clear vision.

215
00:42:53,890 --> 00:42:55,356
When you want to see a clear vision,

216
00:42:55,356 --> 00:43:00,723
you put a powerful light before the mirror.

217
00:43:10,823 --> 00:43:19,856
Clear vision of the expression in language,
in gestures, in behaviours;

218
00:43:26,590 --> 00:43:31,656
and a clear vision of the Divine.

219
00:43:34,823 --> 00:43:39,590
Let people see in your light,

220
00:43:39,590 --> 00:43:44,256
the beautiful dream coming true.

221
00:43:52,956 --> 00:43:58,990
In My childhood I used to think
My dreams are too fantastic.

222
00:44:05,956 --> 00:44:08,390
Will they ever materialize?

223
00:44:12,690 --> 00:44:19,890
I used to collect small, little stones.

224
00:44:26,023 --> 00:44:29,990
And I would say:

225
00:44:29,990 --> 00:44:41,556
“Will there be people, who are
not the stones but who are the hearts?”

226
00:44:51,423 --> 00:44:55,556
By God’s grace, I have met you.

227
00:44:59,623 --> 00:45:01,956
I thank you very much

228
00:45:03,823 --> 00:45:06,656
for accepting Sahaja Yoga.

229
00:45:08,990 --> 00:45:16,890
But this invitation that is extended to you

230
00:45:16,890 --> 00:45:22,523
should not be such that,
I will be blamed

231
00:45:22,523 --> 00:45:26,690
for giving it to people who never deserved it.

232
00:45:35,190 --> 00:45:37,890
Please do not let Me down.

233
00:45:42,056 --> 00:45:44,690
There’s one small thing,

234
00:45:44,690 --> 00:45:46,623
I come from a country

235
00:45:46,623 --> 00:45:51,423
which is not so sophisticated
in the modern world,

236
00:45:57,756 --> 00:46:02,090
but is very much embedded in Truth,

237
00:46:07,556 --> 00:46:13,523
and I’m happy you respect that country despite

238
00:46:13,523 --> 00:46:22,823
it’s unmodernised, natural existence,

239
00:46:31,823 --> 00:46:37,023
and you are proud of a Mother
who comes of such a country.

240
00:46:42,656 --> 00:46:47,990
This is the Deepavali
which is celebrated in that country

241
00:46:47,990 --> 00:46:51,523
for thousands and thousands of years.

242
00:46:58,023 --> 00:47:01,423
And this is the first time in Rome,

243
00:47:04,456 --> 00:47:08,556
which is the center of Europe.

244
00:47:11,290 --> 00:47:18,290
Because here is the seven hills,

245
00:47:21,456 --> 00:47:28,290
expressing the whole of seven chakras.

246
00:47:32,156 --> 00:47:44,489
That is why a big torch had to be brought
from England in an aeroplane

247
00:47:44,489 --> 00:47:50,990
to enlighten these seven chakras of Europe.

248
00:48:03,356 --> 00:48:12,790
The Kundalini rises from mooladhara
and goes up to the seventh chakra

249
00:48:12,790 --> 00:48:15,623
and touches the Sadashiva’s place

250
00:48:15,623 --> 00:48:24,523
but in this case from Sadashiva’s place,
the light has come down,

251
00:48:24,523 --> 00:48:31,056
to enlighten and respect
all the chakras from their heart.

252
00:48:52,090 --> 00:48:57,489
In the beginning of the awakening of the
Kundalini, that’s what exactly I do,

253
00:48:57,489 --> 00:49:06,290
is through your fingertips, the awahana,
the invitation to the Kundalini, is sent.

254
00:49:06,290 --> 00:49:09,823
Unless and until it passes
through these centers

255
00:49:09,823 --> 00:49:16,556
it cannot open it out sufficiently
for the Kundalini to rise,

256
00:49:39,890 --> 00:49:43,323
and then the Kundalini rises.

257
00:49:43,323 --> 00:49:49,523
So the invitation first has to come
from the heart chakra here.

258
00:49:57,256 --> 00:50:00,623
So the desire has to come down first of all,

259
00:50:00,623 --> 00:50:05,623
the power of desire has to come down,
from the heart,

260
00:50:05,623 --> 00:50:09,056
to make the Kundalini rise.

261
00:50:16,590 --> 00:50:18,756
So the Kundalini acts,

262
00:50:18,756 --> 00:50:21,923
the power of action takes place.

263
00:50:26,923 --> 00:50:31,990
So the responsibility of England

264
00:50:31,990 --> 00:50:40,090
and the responsibility of Europe is very great.

265
00:50:47,690 --> 00:50:50,656
Unless and until all these chakras are cleared,

266
00:50:50,656 --> 00:50:54,823
Vishuddhi cannot be pushed aside.

267
00:51:03,456 --> 00:51:10,856
So we have to consolidate first
in Europe and also in England.

268
00:51:17,590 --> 00:51:21,090
I started it in England then in Europe.

269
00:51:21,090 --> 00:51:24,156
Once we have consolidated it well,

270
00:51:24,156 --> 00:51:30,823
I’m sure Sahaja Yoga will be
very easily established in America.

271
00:51:42,723 --> 00:51:46,323
India there’s no problem, as you know;

272
00:51:51,456 --> 00:51:55,090
and that is going to work out very easily

273
00:51:55,090 --> 00:51:57,956
and once India is awakened

274
00:51:57,956 --> 00:52:05,390
the Kundalini will start moving very fast,
with great dynamism.

275
00:52:15,290 --> 00:52:18,890
But first these upper chakras must be put right.

276
00:52:18,890 --> 00:52:21,990
Otherwise how can Kundalini come out?

277
00:52:31,990 --> 00:52:36,590
So, you realize your responsibility,

278
00:52:36,590 --> 00:52:40,356
that we have a force in India, no doubt.

279
00:52:40,356 --> 00:52:45,223
But how will it rise if there are obstructions?

280
00:52:45,223 --> 00:52:47,923
You are a part and parcel of this universe,

281
00:52:47,923 --> 00:52:50,923
you are not hanging somewhere else
from India,

282
00:52:50,923 --> 00:52:55,890
so India has to depend on you.

283
00:53:10,023 --> 00:53:14,023
For your sahasrara I have already made
all arrangements

284
00:53:14,023 --> 00:53:17,856
in the sense I am here in person.

285
00:53:24,190 --> 00:53:30,090
I have come down from Kailasha, on this Earth.

286
00:53:34,390 --> 00:53:40,156
So, that’s how I have arranged
the whole drama.

287
00:53:46,056 --> 00:53:52,856
But the middle actors are very important.

288
00:53:59,056 --> 00:54:03,023
They should not act like clowns

289
00:54:06,556 --> 00:54:09,123
or stupid idiotic people.

290
00:54:12,489 --> 00:54:18,590
It is becoming quite idiotic,
the atmosphere, I must say,

291
00:54:18,590 --> 00:54:23,190
you feel as if you are among
idiots or lunatics.

292
00:54:32,323 --> 00:54:37,290
So, these ridiculous things that are
happening around us should not impress us

293
00:54:37,290 --> 00:54:43,323
but we should really use them
for amusing ourselves.

294
00:54:52,823 --> 00:54:55,590
And you have reached that ascent

295
00:54:55,590 --> 00:55:00,623
that you can see these things are
coming there because of the decadence.

296
00:55:10,823 --> 00:55:17,790
And the decadence is the ruin,
is the destruction of the chakras also.

297
00:55:21,990 --> 00:55:26,489
So though it is stupidity, idiocity,

298
00:55:26,489 --> 00:55:30,690
we have to pick up people out of them,

299
00:55:30,690 --> 00:55:33,090
to support the chakras.

300
00:55:42,923 --> 00:55:50,990
And to be very careful with the people
who are not Sahajas

301
00:55:50,990 --> 00:55:54,690
who are sticking on in Sahaja Yoga.

302
00:56:02,123 --> 00:56:09,356
And now the time has come to throw them out
permanently and they are not to return back.

303
00:56:17,090 --> 00:56:22,690
Only the veeras, the courageous,
can worship the Mother.

304
00:56:28,023 --> 00:56:31,456
And I hope you are all that,

305
00:56:35,723 --> 00:56:38,290
and today is the great day

306
00:56:38,290 --> 00:56:47,190
when I am worshipped by
all the veeras and veeranganas.

307
00:56:53,156 --> 00:56:55,690
May God bless you all.

