now what we can do is to today what
should I tell you the practical side the
meditation all right let's see what his
meditation is what we have to do for a
meditation
the first thing we have got is the left
side is the money shot
is the power of your emotion all right
now emotions are connected with your
right side also rather say for example
if you are emotionally disturbed just
now we got disturbed
so our schwarz our breathing also
increased and we felt the whole body was
sort of reacting and the we were feeling
the reaction of the prana right side
also that it was trying to express
itself like we started the tears is the
water element and all that came in and
the whole emotion was so much boring out
and with that our prana was also
involved say for example if you're
frightened if you are frightened
it's alright if you are frightened too
much then what happens if you are
frightened then also you get your
breathing very fast in it so it is
connected yes coming them so it is
connected if you are frightened it is
connected with your prana in your
breathing and your whole system is
connected with your emotions physical
system if you cry too much or if you
weep too much or if you are a sad person
that shows on your face your wish you
teach a cross for sure but not only
another but also we should be then also
your agua
so all the chakras reflect the left side
in such a way that physical
manifestation is also so it proves that
both are very much connected so - we
have to somehow other resolve these two
sides within
the left and right side because if you
do not dissolve it you are left half way
here so you have to dissolve these two
things and to dissolve these what should
we do
what can we do in meditation can you
suggest
say we have got prana and mana now prana
represents the right side and the mana
Shakti is the left side all right
these two have to be dissolved layer
means dissolved now how do we do it to
dissolve these two things they are
connected with each other after
realization
so before meditation we give ourselves a
bad
all right beside is more recently at the
time supposing you are emotionally that
time mister then you put your right to
the left if you are that time disturbed
on the left side
I mean disturbed in the sense that if
your left side is frozen then you raise
your left side I'll give you our self
for balance before meditation now let us
see this side is less first of all put
your hands like this
are you alright
waiting coolbreeze waiting
better
are you getting in this
No
something moving always coming now I'm
still cool freeze it then it's good
breeze in your hat powerfully so once
you have given yourself a balance then
the best thing is to pay attention to
your emotions to manage to watch them
you can enlighten your emotions by
thinking of your mother right
just enlightened yes she will falter for
whatever are the problems in the manner
all right so once you get connected with
those emotions and you start looking at
them in your meditation
you will see these emotions are rising
within you and if you try to put these
emotions on your mother as I said the
lotus feet of your mother they will
start also resolving those emotions and
they'll become sort of expanded expanses
you will extend that in such a way that
you will feel you are in control this
emotion in control of them and by that
controlling those emotions your emotions
which are expanded enlightened are
powerful and these emotions when you
feel that way then the cause of those
emotions can be solved for example just
now you got emotionally stirred up
because I talked about say these
children naturally anybody would be now
when you are stirred up with that you
put that problem of those feelings that
are rising in you that those waves or
feelings that are coming at the lotus
feet of you so they get touched say by
that power you can say then these
emotions become enlightened and when
these emotions become enlightened they
have a power to solve the problem do you
see the path as if they have reached the
shore where they got the light and this
problem can resolve because now you are
not in an individual self you are in the
expanse you are in the summer stream and
because you have entered into that
position that's why you have got these
powers of entering to another person's
body to see the vibrations of another
person to raise the Kundalini
otherwise we put
so for you it is very easy to do it
because I am also sitting here in person
so easy to put these emotions just there
so that they get enlightened and your
wish is fulfilled because emotions are
not Reaper fishing
these are unfulfilled wishes now how
they do it otherwise it also this way
that you take up these emotions and put
them so that is these emotions are
actually the left side as I said if the
desire so the desire is taken any desire
and is put in the product now how do you
put it on the planner that you control
your pride that's why they do pranayama
see like you sit down now
very comfortably now you have a desire
to put your attention to that attention
is very important see now this attention
is to be put on to the product so the
emotions are there and then bring those
emotions and put them into your
attention means they are now you are
aware of them now what you do is to
watch your breathing see now try to
reduce your breathing it is it
in the sense that you have read out meat
for a while they will behave
for a long time when you breathe out so
in one minute
your breathing will be less than normal
all right try that breathe in now with
the emotion keep the attention on the
emotions you see so that the connection
is established
Oh
better see to Kundalini Rises
now when you are breathing to find that
there is a space in between which you
just leave it vacant
breathe in now leave it vacant now
breathe out
or leave it vacant
reading
to be there
then give it
keep outside obligate
now start breathing in such a way that
you stop your breathing
attention should be on the heart or
could be on the emotions
better
keep the breathing inside for a while
bring it out then outside for a while
then again then you'll find that for a
while you will not drink
you see you settle down the layer takes
place between your prana and Yoruba now
both the Shakti's becomes one now at
this stage when you are silent now you
think of arrangement
clock
just think of it is lust is no more than
so what is happening actually that this
layer the attention goes into the
intellects and enlightens the England
see the thought is not there try to find
your intellect within yourself now see
see where is my intellect try to fight
it
but there it's not working again try it
it is working but it has become this
emerged has become the collective now
enough did you follow that there's no
thought this exercise will give you this
thoughtless awareness establishment of
thoughtless action there is no fun
so the second lesson alright maybe