I bow to all the seekers of Truth.
Yesterday as I told you,
this is the knowledge of the roots.
We have the knowledge of the tree.
But if the tree grows and grows
and does not pay attention to its roots,
then there is always
a definite stage where the tree gets destroyed.
So the destruction is not going to come to us
from outside.
It is going to work out from within ourselves.
Through various diseases,
through various mishaps in our lives.
It is important to see
that you become the Spirit
so that you will understand the mysteries of life.
Even in the medical science
there are many things which cannot be explained by them.
Or in any science
whatever theories are propounded are all the time challenged.
They are not absolute.
So there is something lacking in human awareness
that we are not at an absolute point.
Now this beautiful arrangement is made within ourselves
during our evolutionary process.
But when we go to the left or to the right,
to the extremes, then what happens,
is that our centers which are like this,
get broken,
and we lose the connection with the whole.
As a result of that we develop
diseases which are psychosomatic, may be physical,
may be emotional.
But the Kundalini,
which is the vital force passes through the center
and brings the broken centers together,
and brings the attention in the center.
When our attention is on the left or on the right,
we go into different various funny experiences.
Like when we go to the right side,
we feel as if our body is
somewhere and we are flying in the air.
This we call as supraconscious experiences.
People start seeing the future,
living in the future.
But they do not know how it happens.
They have no control over it.
They have no scientific knowledge of it.
As if we are carried away by some force.
On the left hand side if you move too much,
then you develop,
of course, horrible diseases which are psychosomatic.
But also you become possessed by funny ideas
and you start jumping and gesticulating and
singing in a very miserable way.
So within us all these problems lie on the extremes of our being.
I’ll tell you how cancer is caused.
Supposing the person is in the center
there is no possibility of
his getting into cancer.
Supposing he goes too much to the right; he is over active, planning,
futuristic man.
Then his chakras move outward like this.
Then he becomes vulnerable to cancer.
Because his connection to the mains is lost.
But now, supposing somehow or other
he goes to the left, he gets a shock or meets with an accident
or he meets a bad ‘guru’, he goes to the left,
or he gets mesmerized.
Then he is triggered into cancer.
Now the doctors do say
that cancer is caused by triggering of…
they call it protein 52,
protein 54, protein 58.
52, 54, 58.
These are just the names given by them.
But they say that it is coming to us through the area
which is built within us since our creation.
That means there is an area which we call in Sahaja Yoga,
as collective subconscious,
where everything that is dead in the atmosphere
is stored.
From our creation.
And when anything from there
comes into our attention,
we start developing cancer;
because you have lost connection with the whole.
You become, the cells become on their own.
They start acting on their own.
That becomes, they become malignant.
Now supposing you can bring by any chance,
this centre, again these two,
two broken chakras into one centre,
then cancer can be cured.
Sahaja Yoga has cured many types of cancer inclusive of blood cancer.
But it is your own power.
It is nobody else’s power, it is your own power within you works it out.
And it has been now proved even by doctors,
as I told you yesterday that two doctors got their Phd,
in Sahaja Yoga, from Delhi University.
There is another thing we can discuss here about
the diseases which are caused due to over activity of the mind.
Here you can see in the centre is a round portion
which we call as the ‘Void’.
There resides the ten valences of human beings.
And if these ten valances are enlightened
you can never go into extremes.
But when you are overactive and extremely
futuristic then,
there is a center there which is
called as ‘Swadishthana’, the second centre,
has to work very hard;
which actually looks after the aortic plexus in our stomach,
in our viscera, in the stomach.
Now this chakra has one very important work to do
is to convert the fat of the stomach
for the use of the brain which is the grey cells.
But if you think too much and too much and too much,
you need this replacement all the time.
And this replacement is done by this chakra.
Now this chakra has also other things to be done,
like liver,
it has to look after the spleen,
the pancreas,
and intestines.
Also it has to look after the kidneys
and the lower end of the large intestines.
So when this gets busy with transforming
the cells for the grey cells, fat cells into grey cells,
it has no time for other functions.
As a result of that you get a very bad liver.
Your attention becomes very distorted.
And all the time you feel uneasy.
You don’t feel like eating your food, and even if you eat,
you feel like vomiting it.
But it can go further and you might get the cirrhosis of the liver,
skin troubles all kinds of things.
Specially, with a bad liver if you go for sun bathing,
you are sure to get skin cancer.
Too much oil and too much fatty foods
if you eat also you get very bad liver.
And maybe that you become very thin with it,
because the liver cannot consume any fats in your body.
Then there is also the pancreas,
which is responsible for absorbing our sugar.
That also goes out of order.
As a result of that you develop diabetes.
In an Indian village, a villager takes so much sugar
that he says that the spoon must stand in the cup.
But he never gets diabetes.
Because he does not sit down and think too much.
He deals with the life as it comes to him.
And he is above too much of thinking.
Then the third thing that happens to you is even more serious.
The spleen that is responsible for attending to your emergencies
produces more red blood corpuscles.
Supposing you have taken some food
and after that you start running immediately,
you get a pain in that area.
And that area becomes extremely sensitive.
But in modern times, we are all the time giving shocks to our spleen,
because our life is so hectic.
Early in the morning we read the newspapers, horrible news, one shock.
Then we are in a hurry, we have our lunch,
somehow our breakfast somehow,
get into the car, and then we see the big crowd
of cars and a jam.
Comes the second shock.
And like that, we go on shocking our system all the time.
Whatever arrogance human beings may have,
whatever may they think of themselves,
they must know that they are made very delicately
and very carefully.
They should not treat them like hippopotamus.
They are human beings.
And if they start treating themselves like that,
they end up with horrible diseases like blood cancer.
Then with the kidney you develop high blood pressures,
then kidney non-functioning,
then remove the kidney.
You get constipated.
All these things come to you because of over activity of the mind.
Actually there is no need to plan too much.
Because if you go on planning like this, it never works out.
You must keep it open to see how it works out.
I had… I was staying somewhere else, at one place,
and I had to go to some place very far away.
Now if I had gone all the way back,
as planned, I would have never reached you.
So I decided to come directly
and it has worked,
without disturbing my system.
Now we have watches in our hands, and all the time looking at the watch
and getting frightened of the time.
We have to save time.
But for what?
Like somebody in India was very anxious to catch a plane
and he wouldn’t get a ticket so he was very agitated.
I said, “But what is so necessary?”
He said, “I have to go and attend a ball”.
Waste of time.
For that he was so much jarring his own system.
And when you hear such people,
suddenly they collapse and die with heart.
Because if you become too much right sided,
the Spirit stops,
He dies, in a sense that it never dies but it sleeps off. It disappears.
Your heart becomes like a stone.
With your arrogance it is even worse.
And then the reflection of God is not there.
Such people have no compassion, no love
and no joy.
They are joy killers.
All this running about is for joy.
But it’s a joyless pursuit.
Then comes the left sided people,
who indulges into nonsensical romances
and indulge into all kinds of sufferings for nothing at all.
Like in Paris, when I first went,
they said, “Mother, you look such a happy person.
They are not going to like You.”
They think that joyous people are ignorant.
They don’t know what is happening in this world.
So I started My lecture with “Les Miserable”.
“Les Miserable”.
If you have a pub
at every fifth lamp post,
and a bad women standing at every third lamp post in Paris,
you are inviting trouble.
You see a person coming out of a pub and falling off on the street,
and you enter into the same pub.
You see people getting into the trouble with
funny sex habits,
but still you want to do that, yourself.
You are not a free person at all
and neither you are powerful.
You get tempted all the time to the forces of your destruction.
So that you have no discretion either,
nor understanding of your glory,
nor of your beauty,
that God had created you especially to enter into His kingdom.
So we live in our own paradise of destruction,
go on destroying ourselves gradually.
Nothing gives us happiness.
We run from
place to place to find happiness and joy.
Ultimately, I think, people have to put electrodes in their limbic area,
to feel joy like the monkeys do.
We don’t respect ourselves and we don’t try to understand ourselves.
Why are we created?
What is the purpose of our life?
What do we have to get out of life?
Such a ocean of joy is lying ahead
and we do not want to go to it.
This kind of things are happening
and that is why yesterday I told that Spanish people should now rise
and see and get the joy out of their lives.
A little journey of three to four feet of the Kundalini
brings forth this joy to you.
So I have to make a request to you.
As there is less time today,
I won’t be asking for questions today.
Yesterday we spent about one and a half an hour on useless questions.
So better get your Realization.
You don’t have to know all these things.
As you don’t have to know about the electricity,
you have to just put on the switch because it is all built in.
May God bless you all!
I come here every year and I am sure I will come next year also.
It is little bit cooperation you have to give Me.
As you have seen I have taken out the shoes
because the Mother Earth helps us a lot.
She sucks our problems much faster than we know of.
So, we should try to take out our shoes and put both the feet like this,
parallel, because left and right are two different energies.
Even the other day a lady had so much objection in taking out her shoes.
I just don’t understand.
There are so many wrong things we are doing,
people have no objection to that.
So don’t pay attention to frivolous things.
Now, please put your left hand towards Me like this,
which suggests symbolically
that you desire to have your Realization.
And those who do not want to have Realization should leave this hall,
and leave others in peace,
because they act negatively for others.
Now please put your left hand towards Me like this,
and put the right hand on your heart.
As I said, in the heart resides the Spirit.
Then you have to put your right hand
on the upper part your abdomen
on the left hand side.
This is the centre of your mastery.
Then you have to put your right hand in the lower part of your abdomen.
This is the centre of
the pure knowledge, manifesting through your central nervous system,
the knowledge of divine laws.
Then again we go back in the upper part of the abdomen,
on the left hand side.
Then we go again to the heart.
Then we go, take our hand in
the corner of your neck and turn your head to the right.
This is the center which catches when you feel guilty
and unnecessarily angry with yourself.
You have to be very pleasantly placed towards yourself.
Then we take our hand on
top of our, I mean on our forehead across, like this,
and press it on both the sides.
Now we take this hand on the backside of our head,
and put our head on this to rest and
put it upward like that our head.
Now we stretch our hand like this,
and put the center of our hand,
on top of the fontanel bone area.
Right hand, right hand.
And now move it,
your scalp.
Seven times. Keep your fingers up like that.
Now, please close your eyes.
I have already requested people who
don’t want to do Sahaja Yoga, should go away.
Please. There's not need to be so aggressive.
Please.
Still they don’t want to go; it’s very wrong
and very aggressive.
You cannot look at other people when you are not doing it.
Thank you very much.
Now, please close your eyes.
Don’t open your eyes. Put both the feet parallel on the Mother Earth.
Until I tell you don’t open your eyes.
Now please put your left hand towards Me and right hand
on your heart.
Now here ask Me a very fundamental question.
You may call Me Shri Mataji or you can call Me Mother.
“Mother am I the Spirit?”
Ask this question three times.
Now, if you are the Spirit,
you are your master.
So put your right hand in the upper part of your abdomen,
the left hand side and ask another fundamental question,
“Mother am I my own master?” Ask three times.
Now you are free people.
I cannot force on you anything,
leave alone the pure knowledge of the Divine.
So you have to ask for it.
So please bring your right hand
in the lower part of your abdomen,
in the left hand side.
And now please say,
“Mother, please give me pure knowledge of the Divine”.
Please say it six times.
There are six petals to this center.
Now as soon as you say these things,
your Kundalini starts moving.
To facilitate Her movement,
please raise your hand to the upper center,
which is in the upper portion of your abdomen, on the left hand side.
Now, here, you have to say
with full confidence
to facilitate the movement of the Kundalini,
“Mother I am my own master”. Say it ten times.
Now you have to know the greatest truth about you
is that you are the Spirit.
You are not this body, you are not this conditioning,
not this ego, not this mind.
But you are the Spirit.
So now please put your hand on your heart.
And with full confidence say,
twelve times, “Mother I am the Spirit”.
Have full confidence.
Now the Divine is the ocean of love
and compassion.
But above all It is the ocean of forgiveness.
Above all it is the forgiveness,
then you cannot make any mistakes which can’t be engulfed
by this great power of forgiveness of God.
So please first forgive yourself.
You have to love yourself
and you have to be pleasantly placed towards yourself.
Now put your hand on your shoulder
between the neck and your shoulder,
in the corner, and put your head to your right.
Here now you have to say,
with full confidence
for sixteen times,
“Mother I am not guilty at all”.
Sixteen times.
Now those who still want to feel guilty can punish themselves
by saying it 108 times.
Now please take your hand
on top of your forehead across
and bend your head a little.
Here you have to say
from your heart,
“Mother I forgive everyone”.
If you say it is difficult to forgive then know that it is a myth,
whether you forgive or if you don’t forgive.
But if you do not forgive,
then you play into wrong hands.
Yesterday I saw many people didn’t get Realization,
and when they came to Me and they said,
“Mother I forgive everyone”, they got it. So please do it now.
Forgive everything,
everyone.
Now, take your hand on the back side of your head
and put back your head, resting on that hand.
Here you have to say without feeling guilty,
“Mother”,
or “the Divine
if I have done any mistakes please forgive me”,
without counting your mistakes, without feeling guilty.
Now, stretch your hand
straight,
and put your centre of your palm
on top of your head.
Bend your head, stretch your fingers
and press your scalp,
move it seven times slowly.
Bend your head please.
Here also I cannot force you.
So you have to say “Mother,
please give me my Realization”, seven times.
Now, take down your hand.
Please open your eyes.
Now put your right hand towards Me.
Bend your head
and see for yourself if there is a cool breeze coming out of your head.
Now take your left hand like this.
Put your right hand on top of your head
and see for yourself if you are feeling the cool breeze.
Bend your head a little.
Now, again put your right hand towards Me
and see with your left hand if you can feel the cool breeze.
Now raise your both the hands,
high up. Raise your head.
Bend it back and ask the question,
“Mother is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?”
“Mother is this the Brahma Shakti?”
“Mother is this the love of God?”
Ask these questions three times.
Now, bring down your hands please.
Watch Me without thinking.
Now those who have felt the cool breeze
in the hands or in their heads,
please raise both your hands.
Most of those who came two days have got it.
Those who have come only today,
may not have got it.
So many of you have got your Realization.
Now it is now like a sprouting of the seed.
And you have to grow.
We have got a centre here,
where you should meet and grow.
Within one month’s time you will be a master.
You know we don’t take money, so we have very humble place.
And you have to be very humble yourself.
And please see that you all grow.
Some of you did not get Realization
or maybe you did not feel the cool breeze,
but might be feeling peaceful within.
If this centre is out of gear also you don’t feel the vibrations.
If you have not forgiven people, also you don’t feel the vibrations.
So you have to take it up seriously.
You are entering into a new world,
and not to be treated frivolously, childishly.
And I am sure all of you will develop that subtlety
and all the powers
by which you can to do miraculous things.
I am sorry today there is short of time, so I have to go.
But I hope you all will look after yourself.
You have a very good,
wise Sahaja Yogi here,
who is the leader of Spanish people.
You don’t have to spend any money.
Only you have to pay attention to yourself
and you have to attend the center.
You cannot do it individually. It is a collective happening.
Like one tree is supplying sap to all the leaves.
The leaf that develops a bark between
itself and the tree, falls off.
With little patience with yourself,
you will develop that subtle
being within yourself, by which you will
feel the joy of the Divine,
which is your right,
which you all should have.
May God bless you all.
Only thing I have to request, that don’t talk to anyone now.
Please go home in this silence
and don’t discuss and argue.
Because you lose your vibrations.
So I have to request you not to argue it out. You cannot argue it.
It has to work out.
Those who have not got also should not blame anyone.
May God bless you.
Finished at ten o’clock as you said it.
Where are My shoes?