Now, then you have to go further.
See you find yourself that your right side
is hot.
What you do is put your right side towards
the photograph
and the left side up towards the ether.
The ether takes away the heat.
But what actually happens is that
your right side gets the vibration and
the heat is pushed towards your left and passes
out into the ether.
Now this heat comes from too much futuristic
living.
Those people who are too much futuristic,
they have too much heat.
And too much heat has to go away,
and when this heat starts going away then
you are amazed how it works.
For that there are various things we have
to use,
but mainly for right-sided people they should
not use any light at all.
They should not sit in the sun.
They should sit in the moonlight.
They should read some poetry.
They should not tie up watches.
They should not look at time.
They should allow the time to pass,
and they should just become very, sort of
emotional people.
They should sing songs of bhakti.
They should not do Hatha Yoga.
There are so many things they should not do
if they are right sided.
You will be surprised how people have been
helped through this kind of a treatment,
which treats one side of your being.
On the left hand side people are the people
as you know are the ones who are docile,
who bear up lots of things from others
and cry and weep and all the time are on the
losers end.
Such people have problems also because all
their organs are lethargic
and they have problems of a lethargic heart,
lethargic liver, lethargic intestines.
Everything becomes very lethargic.
All these left side things can be cured.
Plus they might have some sort of a badha
in them,
in the sense they are possessed by someone.
Of course, some of them are possessed by right
side also.
Not that only the left side is possessed.
But from the right side also they are possessed.
And left sided possessions are of a peculiar
type,
because they give you pain in the body.
You get pains in the body.
Right sided person doesn’t get any pain
himself.
He gives pain to others.
He is very sarcastic, he is very aggressive,
he troubles others,
but the left sided people have pains themselves.
They get a pain here and a pain there and
pain here.
So left side has to be cleared, as you know
very well through the light.
Light is put before the photograph,
left hand towards the photograph, right hand
on the Mother Earth.
So the left hand gets the light
and the light passes through and the negativity
of the left side passes to the right hand,
and the right hand is on the Mother Earth.
The Mother Earth is the one who sucks in all
these negative forces of the left hand side.
So these are the two sides which we clear.
But once you have cleared these two sides
then you can use the photograph.
Sit with your both the hands towards the photograph
and put both the feet in the water,
little bit of salt in it and about five ten
minutes
you must allow the vibrations to clear you
out.
Then wipe your feet.
Put the water properly into some disposal
and then sit down for meditation.
If you can do that everyday, even ten minutes,
is more than sufficient.
Don’t have to do anything in an extreme
manner.
In the morning time,
you have to give yourself a bandhan when you
are going out.
Don’t go out without giving a bandhan.
And attention should be all the time inside,
in the sense that,
walking on the road people have habit of seeing
this, seeing that, seeing like that.
The attention gets frittered away.
What you should see is
you should see about three feet or four feet
at the most from the ground and not above.
Because you can see all the beautiful children,
flowers everything.
There is nothing very beautiful above that.
So better is to see only up three four feet
if possible, to fix your attention,
so the attention becomes concentrated.
And you feel very relaxed and relieved of
too much of wobbling of your eyes.
Eyes are very important.
Very important, and as you will notice, because
you are all realized souls,
that your eyes now have got a glint, a kind
of a light in the eye.
And that light shows that you are realized
souls.
But to keep it up you have to look at things
which are not anti God,
which are not dirty, which are not filthy,
which are against Sahaj religion,
which is against Sahaj culture.
If you can manage that, it is going to help
you a lot.