Now at Hamsa Chakra, this understanding must come
that you must balance both the nadis,
the left and the right.
Now to balance the left and the right,
the best way is to do some breathing,
is to take the air through one nostril
and keep it waiting here for a while
and then allow it to go out of the other.
Then you breathe in with this one,
allow it to stay here for a while and
then allow it to go down.
But it is to be done very slowly.
Not in a hurry, not too much.
Only thrice.
Best thing as I’ve told you is neti.
If not that, another thing I have seen
that those inhalers, you see that you get, are very good.
The neti thing that I’ve given you.
If you fill the water below the spout and fill it,
put in some two, three drops of one of those things
that you get for inhaling
and put that neti thing in one nose only,
and with another nose it goes up.
Then you come, bring it here, it goes up and clears it out.
It’s a very good thing.
If you do it every night before sleeping, in
three, four days you’ll be absolutely cleared out.
But the main thing is: it comes because
of imbalances in our temperaments.