Dziś świętujemy
Pudźę Shri Gauri.
Przyszła Ona na ziemię
wielokrotnie aby zniszczyć ludzi,
którzy robili złe rzeczy,
którzy próbowali zabić dobrych ludzi.
Zrobiła wszystko co było w jej mocy aby to osiągnąć,
i dzisiaj świętujemy Jej urodziny.
Wszyscy wiecie bardzo dużo o tym,
więc nie ma potrzeby powtarzać się,
ale musicie wiedzieć, że
Ona przyszła na tę ziemię, aby uratować was
od wszelkich problemów.
Dla Niej byliście ważni, bardzo ważni,
ponieważ wykonywaliście Pudźę do Dewi.
I właśnie dziś świętujemy Pudźę Dewi,
całym waszym sercem.
Ponieważ cokolwiek źli ludzie wam zrobili,
Ona przyszła aby ich zniszczyć.
A więc to jest wspaniały dzień abyście Jej podziękowali;
podziękowali Jej za ochronę
i za to, że rozumie
jak bardzo byliście torturowani.
Jestem szczęśliwa, że jesteście tu aby świętować Jej urodziny,
i aby oddać się Jej tak,
aby mogła zawsze,
zawsze was chronić
i dawać wam błogosławieństwa.
A więc niech Bóg was wszystkich błogosławi,
wasze dzieci,
wasze rodziny,
abyście osiągnęli ogromną radość i ochronę.
To bardzo miłe z waszej strony, że przybyliście dziś z tak daleka.
Jestem bardzo szczęśliwa, że was widzę.
Co więcej, mamy także jutrzejszy dzień
aby świętować.
Dzisiaj nie będzie żadnych pytań i odpowiedzi,
po prostu będziemy czcić Boginię, to wszystko
i poprosimy Ją aby nas chroniła
przed wszystkimi problemami z którymi się mierzymy.
Bardzo wam dziękuję.
-------------------- EN ---------------
Today we are going to celebrate
the Puja of Gauri.
She came on this earth
many-a-times to kill the people
who were doing wrong things,
who were trying to kill good people.
She has done Her level to do that,
and today we are celebrating Her birthday.
You all know so much about it
that I need not tell you,
but what you have to know is that
She came on this earth to save you
from all kinds of troubles.
For Her you were important, very important,
because you were doing Devi Puja.
And so we are celebrating today this Devi Puja,
with all our heart,
because whatever ill people did to you,
She came to destroy them.
So today is a very great day for you to thank Her,
thank Her for Her protection and
for Her understanding
as to what you have been tortured for.
I'm happy you are all here to celebrate Her birthday,
and to be surrendered to Her
so that She can always,
always protect you
and give you Her blessings.
So may God bless you all,
your children,
your families,
and that you bring great joy and protection.
It's very kind of you to have come today, so far away.
I'm very happy to see you.
Moreover, you have got tomorrow also
that you can celebrate.
Today we are not going to have any questions and solutions;
we are just going to worship the Goddess, that's all,
and request Her to protect us
from all kinds of problems that are facing us.
Thank you very much.