Very nice to see you all here for Easter Puja. Very nice. Such a pleasure, such a joy
As if I feel the resurrection working fast
The year
1990 has come now
as a special year for all of us
Sahaja Yoga is going to spread very fast, no doubt,
everywhere,
all over the world, I know that
It has to spread
And
also I told you that a new
jump has to be taken by all the Sahaja Yogis
To explain it
we'll say that Sahaja Yoga is spreading in a horizontal manner
The plane is horizontal and you are responsible for that work
You are working it out, no doubt
Because of you it has spread
Some of you have gone all out
to work it out, to spread it to villages, to surrounding places, different countries
Also the events,
world events, have helped us a lot and
Sahaja Yoga has worked
in a very big way. Maybe it will be difficult for us to
really balance it out
But
when we move horizontally
we must also know
that we have to move
vertically
Otherwise,
what would happen
is that we lose in quality
Quantity maybe quite a lot but we'll lack in quality
And if the quality goes down
then you will see many will fritter away
So we have to look after
our vertical ascent which is very important
If I tell you some of the things that have happened  in this short time after I left India
I'm  myself amazed that
in geometrical proportions, Sahaja Yoga is rising very hard
But that should not be complete satisfaction
Individually also we have to rise. And every one of you has to rise
Vertical ascent has to be achieved by all of you
Some might have lost a little bit,  some might have
been a little bit
away from
themselves
The attention might have frittered away quite a lot
but we have to know why we are here
and then it's very easy
We are here to be part and parcel of a very good very great revolution
Can you imagine that we are transforming human beings, it was never possible
A-mass transformation is going to take place that is how this world is going to change and you are part and parcel of that
but when you become part and parcel of that
you just forget sometimes
that we have many things which are trying to pull us down
So we are happy to see the spread of Sahaja Yoga, but we don't see vertically what we are losing
and
that I think is a greater loss, doesn't matter if there are two persons less or more. What is important is that
we should have
very deep Sahaja Yogis
otherwise Sahaja Yoga will fritter away
So many events are going to happen
we are on the stage
and we have to cooperate and coordinate and understand
See now for example to come here
David had a problem. He said, mother, it's just like a tempest, it's horrible
I was there a week back and he was quite upset about it
Everybody told me about this place, I said, all right let's see
and yesterday also I'm told it was raining but in Cambridge it was terrible
and I said, the wind will start and wind will blow on the wind
all the clouds were blown out
and there was clear sky, so the wind has started in a way and you can see it
but you must have your feet on the grounds
and this is what I find you people don't realize sometimes
what an important work you are doing
I mean what an important position you are and
and what?
an
achievement
you are going to have yourself
and what a
great boon you are going to bestow upon human beings
So when we come out of family life for example
we have come to Sahaja Yoga
giving up all these things
giving up all these mundane things, clothes, this that, house, a car
then family life, relationships, everything. We came here to seek truth and to be one with God
Not that you have to sort of
take to sanyaasa
but given up means you are detached
and you are attached to one principle that you have to achieve
Godliness within you
But when you come to Sahaja Yoga
I've seen the beauty of Sahaja Yoga, then again you want to go back
to those useless things
then you cannot explain why it happens like that
Like somebody gets married he gets lost with his wife
He gets a house, he gets lost with the house
He gets a car, he gets lost with the car
He gets a job, he gets lost with the job. He gets a factory, he gets money, he gets lost
So what have you given up?
The detachment is not there
When you have known there is no joy now in all these things, that's why you have come to Sahaja Yoga
Joy is in one thing is
to be connected to the Divine Power
Not to all these things, these are not important
or
you didn't come here out of hypocrisy or
you didn't come here for any gains
of a mean quality
You came for a very
precious thing, something of supreme value;
giving up all that is so useless
You are among them, you are there, but if you get attached to it again
then you lose lots of your energy and mine too
So the detachment that you had developed before coming to Sahaja Yoga
should be there. But what I find, once they get into Sahaja Yoga,
,they get a job, "Now I'm busy with my job. I can't do anything else"
Another will say, "I have a school to attend to". "I have got my children". Somebody will say, "It's my wife"
Then some becomes very romantic,they fall in love. All kinds of nonsense they do
When you have come in the boat, how can you jump back?
So it's very important to understand
that we are Sahaja Yogis
Nothing can attract us,
nothing can deter us, nothing can take away our attention
but one thing
that we are here for the emancipation of human
beings and that our own character, our own style, our own personality is going to change it
I'll give an example of that
When I was going
to Russia for the second time in the family they said, "You have been already there,
why do you want to go again,
after all, you've been there first and again you want to go for two three days. I mean a yoga
seminar can be looked after by other people who are there". I said, "No I have to go"
But they insisted and then I said, "You see I have a plan
that if I go there,
there will be lots of people from all these countries which are called as Eastern Bloc
and I think I can break it
through Sahaja Yogis, if they get their realization. I was just saying that we should get really some remarkable people to come
and they gave merely 45 minutes to speak to them
I spoke for about 35 minutes, I should say, or 32 minutes
and I then gave them Realization
Tremendous people, tremendous personality I touched
When I went out they all walked with me, nobody was there in the hall
to listen to anybody else. The whole seminar was over
And they gave me their address, they gave me their phone number, everything. And they were after me and
I had no paper, pencil; somebody was writing it
And I was very satisfied
I could see clearly in their personality that they are very deep people
As soon as they went back, the Paramchaitanya
triggered it
and you know what happened with the Eastern Bloc
Tremendous people there are, they are tremendous people
Russians are tremendous and these people are tremendous. Very high quality seekers
Same about
Hungary. Everybody were saying, "what about Hungary, Mother?" before that. I said," let one come from there"
And really one came quite sick, you know, thinned out sick person
He got his realization and here it is, Hungary is free. Same with Romania
So what is the difference in quality that we are supposed to become people from three countries,
and those who were in the shackles of
communism
I don't know, but maybe
they must have been great people to be born there perhaps
Because Lenin talked of stateless state and things like that, but I don't know what
to say. But
one thing for definite is they had no time to waste their attention here and there
No nonsenses of religion, no nonsenses of conditioning, no nonsenses of
all kinds of theories, no nonsenses of becoming hippies and no nonsenses of
becoming these punks and this and that and all sorts of nonsense
Nothing
Of course I don't say that when I went there I found people - at least 25% who were who are asking for
American jeans, but that's different- only 25%
But the rest of them,
just clean plates, absolutely clean plates
Very nicely combed their hair with oil and all that, very smart people
No inhibitions of asking me about themselves and
nothing of the kind. No hypocrisy, nothing. No fashions. No fashions
Very straightforward, simple, educated, dignified people
Nobody walking with funny gestures or anything, very dignified
They were supposed to be people
in the shackles of communism
And one person has written
the mathematical calculation of Shri Chakra and he very humbly came to me,  sat down, to know all about it
Their humility was, I can't explain to you
Even to touch the platform
with such humility and discipline they gave
Whatever it is, whatever the regime must have been to them or whatever it is
They are not abundant people
It's a kind of a proper discipline of their mind
The mind
is so receptive,
so humble
In this so-called freedom we have lost quite a lot of ourselves, I think. First of all
experimenting ourselves with all kinds of nonsense;
talking about things that we should not;
seeing things as in the name of freedom, which we should never see, as human beings
Anything people can do in a free country
I think, unless and until you have Realization, freedom has no meaning
because they get abandoned
Completely they abandon all their qualities, all their value systems, everything
So we come to a point to understand that we have harmed ourselves,
we have harmed our attentions
First,
one thing,
that in the family system,
the parents used to be cruel and funny and this and that
Now you have become Sahaja Yogis,
so now you are so much attached to your children
that it's also not good
This is my child, this is my wife, this is my house
How can it be now?
Now you have become a free bird. So,
today is the Easter day as we are celebrating today. And Easter time,
one has to remember that now we are free. We are not eggs anymore
inside the shell. We are now birds
We need not carry the yellow of the egg on our head
to boast about it. Now finished now, that's done
It's no more there
So why should we go and
try to become eggs again
What's the wisdom?
And then another shocking thing that I have seen is this that,
we have come out of a sense of
we have come out of sense of dominating others,
intimidating others,
making fun of others, hating others, all these bad things that we had
freedom to do
to talk rudely to others, we have freedom you know,
freedom to hurt
When we have given up all that, then I find that as Sahaja Yogis
people are still doing it
That role is over
Say now, you were a policeman, but now you have become a priest. I shouldn't say priest, but what should I say then?
They are equally bad! I should say, now you have become a Realized soul
So, now when you have become the Realized soul,
you are the bird. You are the real free bird, which has got wings, which has got eyes,
which can fly,
which does not have
those qualities which you had as eggs. It's completely transformed. It's finished
Its mythical. You cannot become that now
If a bird wants to become an egg, it will suffocate and die
This reverse direction is not possible, but why?
why to be in the reverse direction? you should ask question to ourselves
We have to ascend so,
in resurrection we have to learn detachment
It's only mental
I mean, I don't know, how can a bird be attached to an egg?
It could be attached to an egg thinking, "Oh, how cozy I was, I didn't have to fly"
Or something like that could be, you see. I mean only bad things there are to be an egg and to think about an egg
But I don't know how it can be attached or. On the contrary it would
abhor that life, "Oh baba,what I was, where I was
In the same way we should also feel
a
kind of glory that we are
But there's no vanity in it. It's a Pride.
is a
assumption
acceptance
You are sitting on a throne
Now you cannot enjoy a mud, can you?
So when we reverse back, when our mind goes in a reverse direction,
you have to understand that we are slipping out
That is very important
My experience of Australia was rather saddening because I found that it slipped out completely, all of them
Absolutely
slipped out. The leaders were like jailers and
the way they behaved and some of them who joined them and it was like a regime and it's horrible things
hitlerish
So I had to pull them back again onto the boat.
I had to work very hard, very very hard with them
This is so-called freedom that we have, that has ruined them
Another miracle took place that I went out
to a place called Cairns
which is a very far fetched place near Equator, at the tip of Australia
And they told me that the Great Barrier Reef is very close from here and there are fishes called as
Crown thorn
what do we call them Crown thorn
What fishes?
starfishes and these are eating all those little little animals that make those beautiful corals there
And that's when the regeneration has stopped from the 10 years. God knows from where they have come, shoals of them and shoals of them
I said, "I would like to go and see this Great Barrier Reef, let's see"
So went down, there was a boat which was to sink halfway. And halfway
we were sitting there and watching everything
They said you'll see those fishes there. I saw big big turtles and I saw
beautiful, very beautiful
fishes of such varieties, such colors, very gently passing
But not a single fish that starfish, not a single
I said,  "let's see, let's see" .So we went round and round quite a lot
Wanted to see one at least, what sort of a thing it is
Went around the whole thing, not a single thing. And this happened on
the 10th I was there. On the 17th we were travelling
in the plane, they announced a miracle has happened that all these fishes have disappeared and
some who were there are dying
Can you imagine?
So what I'm trying to tell you, that you have those eyes, you have that personality
that can trigger all these things
If 2-3 east German Sahaja Yogis who got realization
can go and trigger, and the Berlin Wall can fall down,
then with all these Sahaja Yogis I don't know what should happen
That you have, that power you have
That's why I say that vertical improvement has to be there
And then let that power act and trigger
You all can trigger it
individually and collectively,
but vertical program is less,
vertical understanding is less
Any number of Sahaja Yogis we may have,  but if they cannot trigger, then what's the use
So my request is that, we have to now pay attention to our vertical movement,
and to our attention
Same about marriages. I mean sometimes I feel I don't know why I married them, but they get lost
Imagine
I can't understand
You marry in Sahaja Yoga, you marry for Sahaja Yoga, you want to have children who are Sahaja Yogis, you want to have
Realized souls, you want to support Sahaja Yoga, and that's why you marry and you get lost in marriages
Somebody comes and ask me, "Mother, there's a very nice job I can get". "Alright, may God bless you"
The God blesses him is lost to Sahaja Yoga though
So these temptations
are there because we are not detached?
So on this great day, I have to tell you that now we have become birds
and we don't want to be eggs again by any chance
We're not going to go back to that state
and we have to trigger so many things
You all have come to England, the whole England should be triggered
There's another good news I must give you. I went down to Jaipur. Only one gentleman from
Delhi went down to Jaipur to organize
and
Jaipur people said, "it is very difficult you see here, this and that". He said, "No, I'll have the program in Govindji's mandir,
where nobody can have programme, "I'll go and see the maharani"
So, maharani would not meet him, he was insisting, sitting there, waiting for her
Ultimately he got a chance. He went and talked to her. He showed her my photograph. Immediately she took to me
She asked about Sahaja Yoga, "What is Sahaja Yoga?" then she said, "give me Realization"
She got Realization, the maharaja got Realization. They said, "Yes, we can have the program here". She said, "I'll come to the program"
She came down herself
She fell at my feet in the public,
sitting there all the time, her husband sitting there and
somebody offered them some water to drink.They said, " how can I?"
She's the goddess, I can't drink before her, she sat there
Imagine, she just got her Realization. What a depth
But that's not enough. They have one festival called Gangaur
That is a thing where they worship Gauri
That's the biggest festival where the queen, maharani, has to worship
the Gangauri. It's is a statue which goes round the whole of Jaipur State and everybody celebrates it
It's regarded as the biggest festival. So, she in the morning she came and touched my feet and she said,
"Mother, Can I worship you?". I said, "why?" "Because you are my Gangaur, really. That's just a statue
She made me stand the same way. She did everything. She made me eat betel
I don't eat all that, but she said," you have to, you are Gangaur
And she worshiped me and all her whole ritual she did for about 45 minutes and
then she said now I'll go and worship that statue
Nobody's allowed to go there. She took me there, she made me sit in a very nice place, like this decorated
How much she respected me
She's, you see, among all the maharajas, Jaipur is the
highest and that maharani is the highest lady. And they had lots of problems otherwise
They had lots of problems, now how this happened
This gentleman got his Realization in Delhi. I think, three four years back. He comes from Jaipur
He said,"Mother, we must have something in Jaipur. I said, "You go this time and try". Very powerful person
and
He went and saw her. He gave her Realization, he gave Realization to the maharaja,
and they had some case of
billions and billions
rupees worth of case in the court, which was not decided, and they were on the verge of losing it
But when she got her Realization, within eight days, that case was decided in their favor and this she
understood is a
very good omen
But just from Realization only, she completely got
drenched into Sahaja Yoga
But she triggered
So when some people say,"Mother I have still this problem", then this is you are not triggering it
You shouldn't have any problem. If you have any problem, then there's something wrong with you
that must be corrected
Not only that you are going to solve your problem, but you are going to trigger out
in such a manner that you are going to solve the problem of all the people,
all the world
Still we have one very big problem of fundamentalism
We don't have to talk about it, say anything, just go and stand before them and it will work out, depends on
You have to do it. If I could do everything I would not have asked you to come to Sahaja Yoga
But you came on your own, you've got on your own and now to stand on your own
So I feel that our vertical ascent is still very slow
and
we still are lost into the web of maya of
falling into a
little subtler pattern of our previous lives
Now we are dead to that life, we are a new person
forget it
There are so many things I can tell you about miracles, for example, we have cured AIDS now, we have cured AIDS, no doubt
AIDS can be cured through Sahaja Yoga. I mean I have cured it, of course. I don't know if you can cure it, you can
You can, if you can trigger it out
But to you other things are more important than Sahaja Yoga and to develop yourself into Sahaja Yoga
then you can't
There was one boy who came in Karnal
32 years, he could never even speak one word
He could not hear, he could not speak, not sound from him. His sound box was dead
And I said two mantras in his ears,
he started speaking nicely. It's all out in the newspapers
If I could do it, why not you people, just try
I've given you all my powers
They are at your disposal
But there's one thing, you have to be detached like me
You have to have concern for each other. Complete detachment
Let your attention be taken to us
Still you're worried about this and that, let's forget it
You are great,
no doubt,
but still the limitations you are carrying with you, you better give them up
I hope at this time
the atmosphere is so good
I'm very happy this is happening and they want you to really resurrect
Resurrect from the
sense of time,
sense of
aggressiveness,
sense of worldly things
Mundane useless rubbish they are
and fly out into the open sky. May God bless you all
When you all have your dinner and then we going to have some music program
Tomorrow is the puja
I hope this puja should trigger many things. I hope so. May God bless you