Is there somebody here who can translate?
A mature person.
You can sit here
But has he not come?
He should come for the puja, you know.
Everybody should come in.
When they are all here, then I will start.
Now, come forward. There's room here.
Those who can sit on the ground can sit in front.
Come. Nice!
You like it? Color is all right?
Where is a... who else will translate?
All right, you can come.
You do it in French and she can do it in Italian.
Arnau has ... come?
You are there. Who else?
The children can sit in front
- let the children sit in front.
All the four children could come later on,
when you start the puja.
Has everybody come?
Ah! Robotic motor-cars!
Great!
May God bless you. Exactly, that's what it is!
All right. First I would like to tell you about
the meaning of puja.
There are two aspects.
One is the aspect
that you have got your own
deities within yourself.
And these deities are to be awakened within you.
Deities are the different aspects of one God.
So on one side you have the Deities,
means the aspects of God,
which are all the time awakened.
On the other side you have your own Deities,
which are sometimes awakened, sometimes half-awakened,
sometimes sleeping and sometimes sick.
So you have to use two methods:
one to please the Deities of God,
and to ask them to bless your Deities,
or to ask them to awaken your Deities.
So by doing the puja, means when you offer anything
that you have got to offer,
anything that you offer is - say, flowers,
if you want to offer flower to God,
you don't have to speak anything,
you have to just offer, that "this is for You."
Anybody can understand offering,
for that you don't have to have even a tongue.
Even if a blind man is there, if he wants to give you something,
he can just give you like this.
And that expression is sufficient
for anybody to be convinced that he can offer it.
You don't have to say anything about it.
So now, when you offer a flower to God,
even if you don't say a mantra
it is offered - all right, it's given.
But whether it is accepted or not is a problem.
But now, when you are a realized soul and you offer anything,
it is acceptable to God even if you don't say anything.
But what about you getting any reward out of it?
After realization when you offer anything to God, He accepts,
because it's coming from a realized soul, so He accepts.
Now, how do we get
blessed by Him, by giving a flower to God?
Now if you don't say anything about it,
you just offer a flower,
then you might be rewarded with many flowers
automatically in life.
Or you may be, whatever material things you offer,
you may be blessed materially.
Then in a subtler way if you say something,
as you say for offering somebody
that humble way of saying that
"I'll be happy if You would accept this,"
will be even subtler results of that maybe,
which could be much wider, maybe much deeper.
Now, you do something symbolic
which is very, the essence, the principle of something.
Like flowers are the -
they represent the principle of the Mother Earth.
Now,
so the symbolicism of all the things
that we can offer to God has been meditated upon,
and has been found out.
So they use five things called as panchamruta,
as we have here.
Because if you have hit the principle,
then you have really hit the whole, isn't it.
Because spiritual well-being is a total well-being.
It's not just partly that your material well-being
or your physical well-being, or your emotional well-being,
or your mental well-being.
It's a total one, completely balanced into totality.
Now when you offer these other things like the,
we call them akshadas,
what do you call ?
Turmeric. Turmeric rice, you see, this yellow thing, you see.
When you offer this, you know, the yellow color
is that of the Swadisthana Chakra.
And rice is very dear to all the gods.
Now there's a trick in it, because it's a human trick.
Gods are fond of rice.
So they put turmeric on it,
means that "We offer to You a rice which is yellow-colored"
- means, "You should give us blessings of our creativity."
When you eat it, more creativity will flow
and we'll be blessed by that deity - it's a trick.
The whole thing of puja is the trick of human saints, you see,
how to trick God to give more blessings!
But whatever God likes, it has to be auspicious and holy.
So ultimately it works out for the
holiness of saints and their simple hearts.
Now, the puja cannot be done by a person who is not a realized soul.
A person who preaches also has to be a realized soul,
the one who does namaz has to be a realized soul,
the one who prays has to be a realized soul.
So all the utensils that are used are to be worshipped in a way
that they are to be holy things,
they are to be respected things.
You cannot use anything, say the one you are using in the bathroom
and you use the same thing for the puja, is absurd.
Three things are very important,
is a ghatah, means [UNCLEAR] the vessel,
vessel that contains the kundalini,
the vessel that contains the
primordial desire within us to get to God,
is first to be worshipped, our desire.
Is the ghatah, is the one made here.
And on top is called as a Shriphala.
Shriphala means this also has got water in it, if you  see,
the coconut represents the same thing.
Now in the subtler form it is
the water of all the rivers of the world.
And the coconut is the water of all the oceans.
The water from the ocean or sea
rises through the tree-trunk of the coconut,
and becomes the sweet water in the coconut.
It's a symbolic thing.
So this is the vessel called ghatah-puja, this is the ghatah-puja.
Now, I don't want to go to details today,
because we have to talk about Ganesha.
The same is - now that is water, all right.
Then we have to worship Ghanta (bell) and Shankha (shell).
These are two representing the sound.
Shell.
Actually the Shankha represents the ether.
Then we have the Deepa, means what?
It's the light, represents the light element, called as tejas.
Normally also to the Goddess they also give Her a fan,
which represents the air element.
So this is how all the five elements
are pleased beforehand, using them.
So the essences of these or the causal essences
of these five elements
should be pleased at this time,
should be supporting the puja.
Now there are also all kinds of other things,
like your family deities, you might be
worshipping in your family some deities.
They should not be also at this time upsetting the puja;
or maybe the forefathers who are dead.
All these things are to be quietened,
so that they should be told that this is a puja like this,
and you do not disturb us at this time.
Means even thoughts should not come,
their thoughts or their - any disturbances.
So everything is to be first made into peace.
Now this is the one aspect I have told you in short,
because it's a very long thing. If I have to speak about it
I'll have to speak at least three times,
and with three hours each time, still it may not be finished.
Now we come to the second aspect,
which question I asked you "What do you,
how do you get benefited by it?"
So apart from this technique, to have the best
effect of the blessings
or the best flow of the Grace within us,
we say mantras.
The sound of mantras,
the sound, the sound echo
into the being of God.
And they are re-echoed on our chakras,
and then the chakras start opening more.
So the flow of the Grace of God is received.
But only a realized soul should chant a mantra.
Because without connection, how will it reach God?
It is a vicious circle.
Now one may say that "Mother, you cannot get realization
unless and until you get the Grace of God.
And the chakras won't open by a person
who is not a realized soul.
And without opening the chakras you cannot get realization."
That's how the play of the Mother comes in,
and of all the saints, like you.
I would say the Sahaja yogis have to break this vicious circle.
You have to raise the kundalini yourself.
Once you raise the kundalini, the kundalini opens
the chakras a little bit,
because you have given your vibrations to the chakras.
So once she knows there is a Sahaja yogi standing
behind the seeker, she rises.
She knows you are her brothers and sisters,
and that you belong to the same family as she does.
She knows the land where she has to grow, you see,
so she can feel that, and then she rises in her dignity.
That's how she breaks this vicious circle.
That's why in the beginning we don't tell them about the mantras,
because in the mantras you have to accept Me as the Deity.
In this advent of Mine it is made compulsory
that you have to recognize Me.
Because this is very precarious,
the Resurrection Time we can call it,
or the time of your Last Judgment.
First the realization has to be given
without any recognition.
But not to those who are denying or insulting Me.
Under any circumstances they cannot get realization,
whatever you may try.
Even after realization if people start thinking against Me,
vibrations will stop,
because of Sahasrara.
And the heart has to be
completely in unison with Me,
otherwise Sahasrara is closed.
Now those people who are simple,
who are full of open heart, you see,
such people understand Me very well and
they just put Me in their hearts.
After realization,
after going through the understanding of Sahaja Yoga,
through their mental activity, also the intellectuals understand Me
and recognize Me in a little circuitous way.
After the puja, when they receive the blessings,
a very blissful state they achieve,
then they realize the value of puja also - afterwards.
Now in India,
where the puja system has been traditionally coming
and has been maintained quite a lot,
they understand it without any mental processes.
But when they meet somebody, an intellectual,
who has become a Sahaja yogi, you see
they can't understand them.
They don't want to listen about it,
the whole rigmarole of the whole movement of the brain.
And some of them who try, you see, a little westernized,
they try, you see; they develop an inferiority complex,
and they go to the left side.
But there is no need to understand it with mental,
I mean, to all the time analyzing through your mental process,
and then to understand everything,
and then become Sahaja yogis with the heart open.
This is rather very circuitous.
But what to do? They have gone that way,
so they have to come that way.
Because even if they become Sahaja yogis,
they start questioning and thinking about it,
and worrying about it.
So the false people just mesmerize them
and take advantage of that mesmerism.
So one should not feel bad.
If you feel like analyzing, you should go ahead with it,
because I cannot stop your speed,
I'm not going to mesmerize you.
In Sahaja Yoga the freedom is to be respected.
But we do not allow people to come for puja
who have not achieved a certain amount
of understanding mentally of Sahaja Yoga
- from the Western people, not in India,
but here there is a restriction.
Because supposing in India I do not explain to them,
they don't want to know.
They know that they'll get vibrations.
They already know about vibrations,
so I don't have to tell them "You will get more vibrations."
If they get more vibrations they know I am the Shakti,
that's all, I don't have to explain it.
Like as you can make out which is the best wine,
they can make out who is the real person.
They know the taste of it.
Now, once in a puja
I had about six thousand people that touched My Feet.
So I said, "In a puja now, please don't have
- the people need not touch My Feet." I said it.
But they thought it was Dhumal who suggested,
so they all got after his life.
They said, "You only want to take all the blessings
from Mother's Feet, and you didn't want us to take it",
and they got after him.
Another thing is, you see, in the West
I never used to make the panchamruta with My Feet but with My Hands,
because here people would think that
that's a dirty thing feet is,
and we should not have of the feet, you see.
But actually the Feet are very powerful,
and they can never be dirty.
Like the River Ganges has vibrations.
If you have the water of Ganges
you will see that it will never be dirtied.
On the contrary, whatever are inside that
because it's never sort of very kept clean,
whatever dirt has gone into it,
it settles down and doesn't dirty the thing at all.
It's very clean water, all the time vibrating.
So one must understand whatever is pure,
which is responsible for purity,
which is the source of purity,
can cleanse any impurity. So how it can be impure?
But with the brain if you think it, it's so limited.
You cannot think of something which is just
the embodiment of purity.
This is the point we have come now,
where I think I should talk about the Absolute.
That is Shri Ganesha.
Today is His Puja.
It's a very great thing
that this Puja we are doing in Geneva in Switzerland.
Geneva is the right Heart, I think.
The way it is against right Heart.
Everybody's life is a tragedy, like Rama and [UNCLEAR].
And that is why it is very important
that Shri Ganesha should be worshipped here.
Now Shri Ganesha, as you know,
is the embodiment of innocence.
Now Ganesha's color is red or orangish.
Because the child, when it is conceived as a fetus,
the first color it sees is orange
of the red wall of the mother's womb, of the blood.
In Sahaja Yoga, now you must have learnt
that every action has a reaction, which acts.
The color of the original,
we can say the primordial
Ganesha is just of the clay,
because He is made out of Mother Earth.
Now when the Gauri, the Mother of Ganesha created Him
to protect Her chastity while She was having Her bath,
She colored Him red, because everybody could see that
there's somebody sitting there to protect Her.
So when you see the red color around you as a fetus,
then you absorb that color,
and your Ganesha gets colored
with the red in the same beautiful manner.
Just it has a reaction of that getting red and it acts,
means red color of a Ganesha,
the one who has a red color of a Ganesha, frightens others.
They know there is Ganesha sitting there,
a pure, changed personality
with all the fieriness of the Ganesha is there.
Now this Ganesha when He is in a childhood,
as you see, when the child is born,
the children are extremely
protective or fiery, you can say,
about anybody touching their innocence.
When they are absolutely young they are not even aware of it.
But slightly, as soon as they start growing,
they become very aware and they don't like
their clothes to be taken out in the presence of others.
They become very shy of their innocence.
I mean, not shy, shyness is not -
in the sense of their nudity, very shy of their nudity,
so that their innocence should not be attacked.
If their innocence is not attacked and if they are pure,
if they see a nude woman they'll close their eyes.
They would not like to see a nude woman,
or a nude man.
So this is an innate understanding,
an intuitive understanding that it is important
that they must preserve their innocence.
Now, what is the innocence within us?
What does it do to us?
As it is, already I've told you that it gives us wisdom.
All kinds of stupidity we do with our ego;
as I was describing the president
and so many others at that age
and at that height of their positions,
it is because the Ganesha is missing completely.
We went to Brighton where they have a beach,
sort of a - beach where you can do nude things.
And My maid, she is innocent, you see, we went there,
and she couldn't understand, you see.
She asked Me, "But why are they doing it?"
But as you will find that in the West it's hard to find
a really a wise person.
You can say that the people are over-educated
and they are very well-equipped with other understanding
of the material side of life and all that.
But as far as the wisdom is concerned,
one can get shocked the way they are. I mean,
just don't understand, what's the wisdom behind it?
Because all their wisdom has become nothing but sex.
They always think of sex,
and they always want to understand all the nonsense of the sex.
If you start thinking about your sex,
naturally your innocence will be destroyed right there.
Because you cannot use your intelligence for sex.
I don't understand the wisdom how you can rationalize sex.
This is such a spontaneous thing.
And by thinking about it, are you going to enjoy it?
How can you?
It would be like saying that we can transform a flower
into a fruit by thinking.
And the more serious thing is this way,
that supposing you say "I can"
- of course you can never think like, I hope so, that
you can transform a flower into a fruit, I hope so.
But some people can think that
"I can shift," say for example,
"this thing from here to here, with my mind I can shift it."
Or materialize things.
So you know that you can do it, you believe that you can do it,
because some people have done it.
But as Sahaja yogis you know it is done by bhoots,
by dead spirits, they do it for you,
because they are busybodies trying to help you.
Now, same thing happens as far as sex is concerned.
When you want to have sex through your intellectual pursuits,
you get only the bhoots to do that for you.
Because when you project too much of your mind,
then it goes into areas where you catch them.
And they are sometimes very sly, sometimes depraved,
sometimes aggressive, all kinds of things you gather,
and the result is that the sex becomes a nonsense.
So many depraved people
are satisfied once they attack you,
and you have either a very excited sex,
that even if you rape hundred women you are not satisfied,
or you'll have an impotency of the worst type.
So I mean, you are always left dissatisfied.
All such people when they die they also become the same bhoots,
waiting for some sex fellow to come around, and jump on him.
Innocent persons also may not have any sex activity
for many years, even after marriage,
because they are so innocent.
It could be so also with very childlike people.
But here it's a science which is taught from childhood
- just imagine. What is the need?
Do the animals have to learn anything from childhood,
about sex? They produce children too.
(You have said?)
So the asceticism
is not what I am teaching.
First, the innocence is protective and red,
say till the age of, at the most, fifty years.
Then gradually, if the person is properly maturing,
not the stupid people but who are maturing properly,
after fifty it starts becoming orange.
It becomes orange.
Means when you get married this process
of this redness goes away
and it becomes, starts becoming orange.
That means the protection part is over.
Means, before marriage the virginity has to be preserved.
Till you meet the person with whom you are to be married,
that redness is the protection of that virginity.
Then, when you are married,
the protection part of it is not needed.
But it has to be only towards one person,
that's your husband or wife.
Then the proper maturity takes place,
and by the time you are about fifty years of age
it becomes orange - means there's detachment.
You don't feel like having any more sex life.
There's no need also.
And then you develop a,
what you call a
proper matured innocence which is,
can be compared with a
properly baked earthenware.
So old age is the really the golden age,
where a person has got that wisdom
shining through the complete behavior of that person.
But why - again, why to have this maturity,
why to have this innocence?
Again, because you are rational people,
so one can ask the question, why?
Innocence is the way you really give fun to others,
create the fun part of it.
The fun is created only through innocence.
And innocence is the only way you can really
emit also the fun.
Imagine this world without any fun, what would happen?
But people are very much confused with the fun
and the pleasures.
The pleasure is nice to begin with,
and horrible to end with.
But fun is a treasure.
Anything that is full of fun you remember all your life,
you can tell others, it's such an embodiment of fun-creation.
Yogi: There's no word in French for "fun"!
Can you imagine, this French language is diplomatic
- no word for "fun"!
Like I'll give you a simple example
how these children create fun out of something.
They make everything into a fun, you see.
And now, you see, even when they speak
or they say things also they create such a fun out of it.
The other day My youngest grandchild,
that's Anupama - she's hardly now six years -
was playing and she went up to the top of the house somewhere,
and then we heard a big thud, you see.
And My daughter, she's a very frantic mother,
always worried about her children's well-being.
Fun, eh?
And she couldn't even walk, you see,
her legs became heavy with worry,
and she was walking to find out what's coming down now.
So she shouted for the child and the child came running down,
she was quite all right.
So she shouted at her, and she said,
"What happened? Where did you go? Why did you go up?"
She just started shouting at her.
So this child looked at her, quite puzzled,
and she waited for her to stop her shouting.
And she said very quietly,
"I've not come all the way from Riadh here to die!"
So there are so many things which you write it down,
it's all fun, and natural fun
that they have out of everything.
You see, we can have now here all the children who are here,
there's so many things you can write them down,
how beautiful things they are doing,
and how there is a twinkle of a mischief in their eyes,
that they want to create a fun out of everything.
Fun is joy-giving, it gives you joy.
It's not just a sort of a coaxing in any way,
or a hurting in any way or anything sadistic in it,
but it's just a blossoming.
Yogi: Mother, do You think it's possible
if we don't translate any more,
because it takes too much time for that
I think so
Yogi: English words, we'll tell them at the end,
also the few who don't understand English,
we'll explain them at the end, what You have said.
All right for you? Because I'm coming to an end, Gregoire,
as I finish at twelve-thirty, so let's do it for today.
But the next time I think it's a better idea
to translate it later.
Just little bit I'll translate more, because we are coming
to an end, and that's why it's taken so much time, otherwise
it will be one-third of the time.
Yes, just translate this part what I've said is,
that fun is nothing but blossoming.
It doesn't tease anyone, it doesn't hurt anyone,
doesn't trouble anyone but just blossoms,
the whole thing, into fragrance.
It is the Divine's trick.
It has something higher than that also,
that if you are innocent,
you really can feel the joy.
So an innocent person can feel the joy
of something which a very serious
and a very rational person may never see.
An innocent person may laugh loudly at a thing,
to other people it may not be something funny.
So the fun-creation is not a dubious thing,
it's a very straightforward, simple,
a spontaneous blossoming.
Now in Geneva, people are really very serious about everything.
More so in Switzerland.
So much so that they commit suicide as a result.
Because you are money-oriented,
and you are also a sort of a,
take up a role of helping the whole world.
Means you are very ego-oriented,
because you want to help the whole world. Who are you to help?
And thirdly, you have a stupid military here
which is not needed at all.
Yogini: Mother, excuse me,
You know that yesterday it was in the newspapers
that there had been again a military airplane
which crashed in Switzerland, with two deaths.
With Your photo next to it.
It's too much to blame Me!
Yogini: He says, it was during a show
where they wanted to show off all the military strength.
That's the fun
- that's the fun, you see?
So everybody is happy about it, you see,
that this is the one how you see is funny.
Now to help the fun more, we have got Hanumana.
He helps the fun part of Shri Ganesh.
Like a,
like Ganesha who plays tricks
of fun on the people who are left-sided,
He plays His tricks on the right-sided people.
Like there is a person who was crying too much,
her husband is dead, "Now what to do? I am finished,"
this thing, that thing, you see
- and suddenly she sees her husband walking in the room!
But this only He does to the people who are innocent.
But to the cunning, He punishes.
He'll go on pouring all kinds of miseries,
one more than the other, and He'll say,
"Now cry more, and cry more. You want to cry?
All right, have it more, and have it more."
And Hanumana on His side -  say for example,
when Lakshmana was sick and He had to get some medicine
from one big mountain,
He brought the whole mountain, you see.
Because He said, "I had no time to find it, you see,
so better find it now," and brought the whole mountain.
He too is the same style,
can be very destructive
when it comes to egoistical people,
like Ravana - whole Lanka he burnt.
If Ganesha is painted red, He is painted orange.
And as Ganesha has to settle down permanently in one place,
He uses Saint Michael to run up and down the left side.
While Hanumana can run up and down,
He need not settle down at a place.
But though He is a settled Deity, Sthita,
is the one who is to be settled
- once He's settled, then He emits vibrations
which go everywhere.
He is the source of innocence.
He is the source of the vibrations.
He is everything, in a way.
When He ascends here as Mahaganesha within you,
and in God He descends as Ganesha
- from here, on the back.
So when you think too much about sex,
your eyes get ruined, because you are using Mahaganesha.
Your Mahaganesha is spoilt,
and your eyes starts wobbling.
The eyes lose innocence, purity,
and they start absorbing all that is filth.
The eyes which are pure and innocent
give innocence to others.
Not only that, but they are the eyes,
are the eyes through which the spirit looks out.
It has many combinations which I have no time to tell you,
but it's a very bad thing
that people get those unclean eyes, the bhootish eyes.
And anybody who is bhootish around
will turn their eyes to that person,
because it's a play of the satanic now playing now,
the negative.
And that is what we do when
we do not place Ganesha at right places.
If we have to make Ganesha reflected
in our Mahaganesha state at this point,
we should try to keep our eyes very clean,
so that you keep the seat of Mahaganesha clean.
In the Puja of Shri Ganesh
you must bring the soft grass also,
because durva, He's fond of Durva,
durva, that's called as durva- because the soft grass
is soothing to the eyes.
Not only that, but it gives you the green part
of the Swadisthana Chakra.
Which -  he exists when we have not started about thinking,
you have not started the thinking process.
That suggests that part of Swadisthana,
when you are not thinking,
the green part of it, the lower part of the Swadisthana is green.
So the green is the one:
at that stage we have not become human beings,
at that stage it represents the green of Swadisthana,
where it created the whole universe, everything.
Up to that it's green.
Then when it starts creating the ego
it becomes the yellow color, where it uses the sun,
the action part.
Not "uses" the sun but becomes active,
representing the sun side.
So the green represents actually the part of
Ganesha, part of Ganesha in a way,
because till then you are not thinking.
You are at a level
where you are close to the Mother Earth, you see.
So the Mother Earth is giving, you see.
The sun part has not started when the green is there,
because the Mother Earth gives this green.
Of course the sun makes it green, that's different point,
but that you don't start doing it.
When you start doing something yourself at a human level,
the whole thing becomes yellow.
So Swadisthana has two sides,
the physical and the mental side.
The physical side is the green side,
and the mental side is the yellow side.
So now we are today here to worship Shri Ganesh.
Now I would like you to get some grass from the [UNCLEAR]
some soft grass, because that's an important part of it.
So you should put your eyes onto the greenery
to improve your Ganesha.
And when  it is very warm,
then you can also walk barefeet on the green
in the morning-time, when the dew is on it.
Those who are very overactive
should take to the vegetarian diet,
it will help them to become more towards the balanced side.
Not as a fanaticism, but more on vegetables,
and eat animals which are very small ones,
so it's all right.
But today I've not talked about His vahana and all that,
because I have talked in other lectures.
His vahana - His conveyance - I have not talked about it,
because I've talked about it in other lectures of Mine about Him.
This is the best if you can find this,
like this kind, very thin one
this kind, this is good one.
This one, it's all right
You can get more now, just ...
With this the water is sprinkled on the Feet.
Those who have not washed My Feet
should wash My Feet today.
Oh, that's good, that's the thing!
He got it exactly what I mean, exactly the thing.
This is very good one, yes.
Oh, but still some of them are hard, doesn't matter.
It is this kind which has round,
the round blades.
You can take it out, some of them?
These round blades, the round blades.
This is the round one,
not the flat but the round.
Not with the edge, but they're round ones.
Now let him do it.
They're round, are they? Round?
Yes, that's it, that's it. That will do.
They are not round also. Round ones.
All right? They're all flat. There's one round.
No, this is flat too.
I don't think you have here in this country.
I think we should get some ...
This will do.
You just tie them with a string, that's all.
That will do, that is sufficient,
just to tie it with this, some sort of a stick.
Just tie it up with a little string round it,
and use it for sprinkling water.
They are called as durvan gulah,
means the seedlings, seedlings of that.
Yogi: Mother, this is used for Easter
What ?
Easter [UNCLEAR] challenger put the eggs in this kind of grass
for the children
Is it?
Yogi: Not in England
What do they do?
Yogi: The eggs for the children Easter,
put it in this kind of grass. [UNCLEAR]
Just see. Oh, that's correct!
Good.
Thank you.
Tie it up, this one also. Good.
Can you tie this with the string?
That's nice, that's good. Have you got some more?
It's better to have bigger ones, all right?
Because we haven't got much choice.
Now, those who have to wash Feet.
Those people who haven't washed My Feet should come forward.
Let her come, let her come.
I'm so happy you could come!
So nice to see you! All right.
Now, come here. One should do the washing,
and somebody should start doing this.
You can ask him. Yes, come along.
Good, good, good. Now, this will be after the puja, all right?
So all the four young children, where are they?
Where's Anand?
These have to wash Me first. Now, let Me see.
What about these four things I gave you,
for the children?
All right, where have the children gone, four of them?
No, one ...
All right, we'll have these four. Come along.
All right, now come along.
You - first of all the children should come
and wash My Feet, come along, first of all.
All the children, come along, come along!
Hold on. Wash My Feet. All right. Put some water,
I think ...
Where is she? Marie-Amelia, Marie-Amelia?
And also the yellow one you bring from there,
one yellow one ...
Rub it hard, rub it hard.
May God bless you all.
Good. Now, Wyson is younger to her, is he?
Barbara is younger one, all right. So, now.
Hallo ... this is for you ... all right?
Barbara, that should be given, dakshina, you see?
All right, according to the sizes
I have given them to them each. All right ...
Done, done!
Now, just take out the thing.
This should be given to the people for the head
- some leaders.
Ask the children, they'll do it, how to put it on the head.
Ask Lawrence to do it.
Something should be under My Feet:
a towel, somebody should do that.
I think somebody who knows this should be here.
Somebody to wipe My Feet.
Can you, the one who doesn't have a camera?
Come along.
The towels could be there, just to wipe My Feet.
Here, just to put it here. Tell them not to drop.
Just to put it there.
So they cannot be, has to be Chaturthi,
according to Indians. You see, Chaturthi.
It has to be also Chaturdashi,   it could be.
When was this rakhi?
Yogi: Seventeen days, sixteen days ago.
Sixteen days ago, so it is after rakhi...
Yogi: Two days after new moon, two days after new moon
But it is, has to be Chatur Dashi,
fourth day it has to be in Indian time,
because Chaturthi's the day he's established.
Because Indian, you see, is different a little bit.
Must be starting now. Twelve o'clock!
So you need the translators.
It's the Chaturthi, has to be. You see how it works out.
Now, those who have not washed My Feet have to come.
Now, what you do is to take that ... now first.
Use this for water ...
Those who have, who have not washed please come
... cold water for them to wash My Feet.
You have to wash My Feet.
You have to rub. You have to rub My Feet hard, hard.
Rub it. Rub it.
You rub My right, and ... the lower part, the lower part.
Rub it, yes, rub it. Rub it hard.
Hard, hard, hard. Rub it here.
Hard, hard, very hard.
Here ...
Just keep this water for drinking, not for put ... in,
but keep it in somewhere, a bottle or something.
Good, now.
You're all right. All right? That's right.
Now, you realize that by rubbing My Feet
you've got your vibrations more,
so rationally you understand.
May God bless you.
Are you getting more now?
May God bless.
Now others can come.
Not to hold, but to rub more.
Not to hold too much, but to rub it.
Have you been to Hare Rama, have you?
Yogi: No, he's not been.
But he does the mantras ...
Yogi: Yes, he was in Rome, and he was before also,
he is from Sicily.
Why his right Vishuddhi is catching? Right Vishuddhi?
Yogi: Ah, yes, he was smoking before, Mother,
but he doesn't smoke any more ...
Better now? ... Good.
Now he has to read about Ganesha's Atharva Sheersha.
Your fingers should be rubbed,
your fingers should be rubbed like this.
Your fingers are doing it, not Me.
You are to rub your fingers
so that they become more sensitive, all right?
Come here, come ...
Now, listen to what he's saying, all right?
... Now, he's reading. Now listen to him.
That means awakening of Christ within us,
awakening of Shri Ganesha within us.
Now enjoy yourself!
There are lots of yellow flowers here.
What is it - now the flowers?
You can put these first, I think, that will absorb easily.
Finished with towels. One on top.
Now, what is it, Gavin?
First of all the washing needs to be done,
better do it then, and pushpam ...
All the washing should be done first, then these.
So would you like them to wash My Feet or Hands?
Yogi: They've asked to ask for Your Feet.
All right. You come here.
Let somebody who is free sometimes.
You come along, you can do. Yes, ...
You come along too. These two can - you two here.
So what we can do is we can work out,
because they have to be Swiss - put it down there,
all right - and she's German, so ...
You come this side, all right?
Now, you pour the water.
You will be in charge of water, all right.
Now they will do the rest. Now tell them whatever is puja ...
Whatever Gavin says.
Pour Me some water in the hand.
See, there's a spoon here somewhere, a spoon.
So do that.
You have to pour it there, then pour more water.
This is [UNCLEAR]
so that your Mother doesn't feel thirsty, all right?
Now, what is it? ...
Same thing is about Amrut.
Yogi: Now we make the bath of five nectars.
It's called the Panchamrut, the five nectars.
First is the ghee.
You need more milk, but little hot milk.
Hot milk. Something hot.
Yogi: Second one's the milk.
Milk should be the last one, it's better.
See, because they are now heating up. What is the next?
Now, have they got the milk?
... with some water.
Yogi: I already asked for it, Mother.
Yogi: Sugar next, Mother?
Last, should be, because it's ....
They have got it ...
Yogini: It's too hot, Mother.
Put some water. You put some water ...
It's all right, I hope so.
Quite all right. Take a little cold water, then.
It's all right.
It's all right now, it's not so hot.
And if it becomes hot I'll tell you.
Put some sugar I think, in between, would be better,
and that will reduce some of the temperature.
Now pour some water over the whole thing. Water.
Pour some more water, a little bit.
So better clean it out.
And on the toes.
Thank you.
Vibrations are very nice.
Now, bring the towels.
Give her one, give her one towel.
Done.
Such vibrations there, and the hands are shaking!
Put it down ... because the hands are shaking with vibrations!
Just put it down.
Such vibrations are there.
Tremendous! Are they?
May God bless you. And this has vibrations also.
Just put it on your faces, you'll see the vibrations.
May God bless. You can push them down.
Let them see. On the faces they can see vibrations.
May God bless.
You have to be here with us.
You have to put flowers, you see.
Now, married ladies.
All right. Now, you put the ...
I think first the unmarried should put the kumkum.
Unmarried ladies.
In Sahaja Yoga you hardly find them!
We have seven, I think.
Three, four, five, six, seven - good.
Annie, come along, you're unmarried.
Or are you married?
It's just you have to try it, that's all.
You see now, what you have to put is all this ...
First put the line, it's best is to put the line straight,
like that. First put the line.
No, the front line - yes.
Best is to put the front line, then it's better. And now ...
Very red today, eh? From where did you get this?
Very red, isn't it? This kumkum is very red.
This is a special one. Shri Ganesha is there! ...
Yogi: Mother, shall we read these names now?
Yes - no, Ganesha's?
But I'll have to do the havana later on.
You can do hundred-and-eight of Devi's names.
Devi's names you can read, what Gregoire has given you.
That's a good one.
Gauri's names, yeah.
She's Gauri, you see, She's a Virgin.
Virgin is the Mother of Shri Ganesha.
So Her names can be read.
So put your hands with the ...
With your left hand ...
Rub it on. Rub it on.
You can read the names of the Virgin,
that Gregoire has given you.
You can read them in French, somebody, and in English.
Gregoire can do it, Gregoire will do it.
Yogi: I read the Latin, and then I translate in English?
Yes.
Now, the married ladies.
How many ... are here?
How many of you came?
Unmarried ladies, how many were here?
Seven.
So can you bring those plants,
seven plants should be given to those unmarried people.
Seven plants from outside ...
Plants,
plants that we bought ...
Seven of them, yeah.
You have? All right, I'll give them. Come along.
I want you to look after them. Unmarried ...
May God bless you ...
Bring one more.
And now, coming from the Heart!
That's the fun!
One more. We'll give one more.
We have got one more.
One more. Yes, she is there.
Two more are there? Two more? Two more of these.
Two, bring two more.
Two others, two virgins were here in the beginning:
Barbara and the other girl.
That's it. Both of you, yes.
They are in a special day of the virgins and the children ...
may God bless you.
Now, where is Barbara gone?
Genevieve never married?
Genevieve and Madeleine. They are virgins too.
They never married.
Madeleine was married?
You were married?
... Another virgin ...
And you can - how many more now, Gregoire?
Four? All right. Three more, all right.
Keep it now, we'll see about it.
Yogini: Mother, I am out of the ...?
But still you are a virgin.
Virgin is a virgin and she must be respected,
whatever may be the age, all right?
She wants one.
Now there are two boys, three boys left, is it?
Let them give, let them have, the three boys.
You see, they should not be left out.
That solves the problem, you see!
You should never make them unhappy.
Come along now, you are exactly three, for the three boys!
Come along the boys, where are they?
That is their day today!
All right, so may God bless you.
Look after this plant, all right?
Now where are the others? Other two boys.
Now there's one Matthew that -
Matthew never came for the puja?
Here. But he didn't come at the time of washing.
He should have come, what was he doing?
Where were you, Matthew, at the time?
But why didn't you come?
You are a boy, small little boy, all right?
Now this we can go to Wyson, Wyson you call it.
He's all right, because ... can't look after the plant.
You have to look after it immediately, I think.
Where is he gone? Just call Wyson, that's all.
Yogi: He's like a little angel!
This one has the finest touch ...
And how seriously he lifts his kundalini.
You should see the way he lifts it and how he ties it,
it's wonderful to see, you see, how he does it.
The greatest thing!
What about him now, he's going to be terrible now!
Some flowers?
One rose? Or some flowers?
It's all right, it's all right, he forgets it.
That's the beauty of the young people!
What's the right thing?
Camphor? Nothing, nothing serious. Nothing serious.
Let him have something to eat.
Now I have eaten something, now you can give to everybody
now, because for the children specially,
give it to children, the prasad.
I have taken the prasad. Now, what else?
Now for the married ladies.
Married ladies?
To the children, to the children, just to the children.
Where are the other married ladies?
Genevieve, come along. All of you who are married.
Now let's have two sets of people.
All of you can be seated. How many there are?
All right. We can manage everybody.
Who else is there? Good.
All the married ladies come forward. All right. Let's have it.
First of all use these bangles.
There's some bangles. All right.
Bangles. You see, pass it round to all the ladies
one by one, and then these bangles are there.
There's another one green also.
This is to be - not, not it's for you, it's for Me!
All right, there's another set.
There's one more; she will have it.
Now, done. Now, look, you put it in My Hand.
Now the red.
Now the green.
Thank you.
Now the red.
The green.
Now finished?
Red.
Green.
And red. Now, ah!
How they tinkle, you see? They create fun!
What's this? What's that?
You open out this bit.
Now, this is ... You put it on My Feet.
This is how ...
That's all. Now finished.
It's done. Now My Hand is to be done.
You draw the line first of all like that,
and the rest you have to fill it up with it.
See, draw the line, let's do it,
and then only this ...
and here, only up to this you draw the line,
and then fill it. All right?
With this finger, Agnya finger.
All the rest, we can fill it up now.