I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset I have to say that truth
is what it is.
You cannot change it, you cannot describe
it and you cannot conceptualize it.
It is, it has been and it will be.
Now whatever I’m going to tell you today,
you need not accept it blindfolded.
We have had enough of trouble with blind faiths,
but you must keep your mind open, like a scientist
and if it proves to be alright, if it proves
what I am saying, as honest people you must
accept it, because it is for the benevolence
of your being, for the benevolence of your
city, of your country, of the whole world.
Now, I would like to tell you what is the
truth.
The truth is, that you’re not this body,
this mind, this ego, these conditionings,
you’re not that.
But you are the pure spirit.
This is the first truth about you.
And the second truth is, that there is a all-pervading
power of Divine Love.
I hope you are all hearing me alright.
Are you alright?
There’s a all- pervading power of Divine
love.
Is called by various names in the scriptures.
For example in the Bible it’s called as
the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost, also all-pervading
power of Divine Love.
Is called as ‘ruhx’ in Koran, in Sanskrit
it is called as ‘Brahma Chaitanya’ or
‘Ritambara Pragnya’, by Patanjali Yoga
Shastra.
Names can be anything.
Means the same thing.
That there is a subtle power, very dynamic
power of Divine Love which does all living
work.
For example see these beautiful flowers here.
It’s a miracle, these flowers have come
out of a small plant and the plant has come
out of a little seed and every flower is different,
every type of a flower is different.
Then who runs our heart?
We never ask this question.
It’s a living process.
Who runs our heart?
The doctors will say it’s an autonomous
nervous system.
But what is this autonomous nervous system?
Who is the auto behind it?
Everything that is living we take it for granted.
Even the scientists don’t enter that area,
because they know they can’t find anything
there.
So how this living process is done, is a very
miraculous thing which we accept without knowing
about it, but is this all-pervading power,
which is very subtle and does this.
In every living action it is there.
Also it acts on the matter, in a way, like
vibrations we know isometric, symmetric, all
these vibrations are there.
Now to say that God doesn’t exist is very
easy.
To say that.
But it’s not proper, it’s not scientific,
because you have not found out if there is
God or not God.
Without seeing that without finding it, if
we just say that there is no God, then I think
is not proper.
There is a way to find it out.
Very simple way is as Stephen has already
told you, we have this kind of a mechanism
within us built in, during our evolutionary
process.
In the evolutionary process we have become
human beings.
But we do not know the absolute truth.
We don’t know.
That’s why the problem.
Some say communism is good, some say capitalism
is good, some say Christianity is good, some
say Islamic is good.
All kinds of things people talk.
That means everybody has a yarn in the head,
which they start putting before us.
It’s just a mental projection.
It is nothing to do with the Absolute.
If it was absolute [EVERY WOULD HAVE…del.]
everybody would have agreed to it or accepted
it.
Now, I am sitting before you.
Is a fact.
You know it for truth, so nobody’s going
to say that I am not sitting here.
In the same way if you know the absolute truth,
then there cannot be any quarrel, fights,
any arguments, no wars.
This is the state we have to reach now where
we all know the absolute truth.
And this is the absolute truth which I have
told you already – what you are.
As a result of this happening, when you get
connected through the awakening of this Kundalini,
this power is called Kundalini because ‘kundal’
means a coil.
It’s a Primordial Mother, expressing Herself
as a reflection.
We have a concept of a Father, alright.
We have a concept of a Son, alright.
But we have no Mother.
That’s the Holy Ghost.
Has to be.
But in all other religions except for Islam
and you can say the Jews.
Jews also have the concept of the Primordial
Mother.
They have Motherhood but they, I don’t know
why they evaded the problem of talking about
the Mother, the Primordial Mother.
So this is the reflection of the Primordial
Mother in your triangular bone which is called
as sacrum.
That means the Greeks knew that it was a sacred
bone why would they call it sacrum of all
the things?
And I found out it was so.
Now, the whole religion also the concept of
religion becoming mental, it has gone astray.
Religion is within.
You may be a Christian, Hindu, Muslim anything,
you can commit any sin.
If religion had anything in it, everyone who
follows a particular religion would have been
sinless.
But they are not.
So that means that religion has to be awakened
within us.
It has to be an innate religion.
Whatever religion it is it should be innate,
which is not innate.
And that’s why whatever religion we may
follow, we do not fall into line with what
is said in the religion.
Now, Sahaja Yoga, he must have told you ‘saha’
means ‘with’ and ‘ja’ is ‘born with
you’ – this right to become one with this
all-pervading power.
We have no idea at all how glorious we are,
what properties we have, what powers we have,
what is in us, we have no idea at all I would
say, what we are capable of.
Because we are still not one with that all-pervading
power.
Once this is awakened it passes through all
these six centers, nourishing them.
Now the centers, the energy centres are our
fundamentals.
The problems of the world if you see most
of them come from human beings.
Those who have no peace within how can they
have peace without?
In the same way there are so many things which
are said, which are not there.
We know about priests in every religion are,
about immoral, about.
Some are less some are more.
How can you be?
You are a priest, you are teaching something
nice and inside you are immoral.
It is in every religion.
It’s nothing new.
That means they are just preaching, it’s
just like a radio, something coming out but
nothing inside.
And that’s why many people feel that religion
is useless, God is useless.
That’s what they felt in communistic countries.
When we don’t know ourselves how can we
talk about anything?
Like we say this is my house, this is my car,
this is my wife, this is my husband.
Everything ‘my’ but where is this ‘I’
to which all this belongs?
So we have to go within, and how can we go
within, is the point.
To go within is impossible.
If I say that: ‘Please take your attention
inside,’ you cannot take it.
So this happening takes place that this Kundalini
rises.
By that happening your attention is pulled
inside and when She rises, She pierces through
this fontanel bone area, and you are in contact
with this all pervading power.
First thing happens that you start feeling
cool breeze coming on your fingertips.
You start feeling cool breeze coming out of
your own head.
You are amazed at it but the experience is
very peaceful.
You feel extremely relaxed, and the eyes start
sparkling.
As a result of this happening the first thing
happens to you that you become peaceful.
Absolutely.
How?
See actually we are thinking, all the time
our thoughts rise fall, rise fall.
In between these thoughts there’s a little
space.
When we are thinking we are thinking about
the future or about the past, not about the
present, we cannot think.
So when this Kundalini rises then these thoughts
get elongated, and this space increases, and
that’s the place where you become thoughtlessly
aware.
You are aware but you are thoughtless.
That’s the place, where you are in the present,
and you are peaceful.
And that’s the state where you grow spiritually.
You cannot do meditation, you have to be in
meditation.
Of course, you can’t pay for all this, is
something, I don’t know how many times I’ve
told people, you can’t pay for your living
process.
How much did we pay for our evolution?
How much, do we pay to Mother Earth for sprouting
the seeds?
So you can’t pay for it and it has been
so.
I don’t know why people were so enamoured
by people who were taking money.
I went to America, they said: ‘You don’t
take money so we don’t believe you.’
I was surprised.
What sort of a logic is this?
‘How much should you pay me?’
I said.
The whole concept is that, everything is money,
God is money, even your ascent is money, everything
you must pay.
And such funny ideas they had that, we are
what we are giving him metal or something,
we are giving him nothing but a Rolls Royce.
But he gives us the spirit.
What spirit is he giving you?
He is mesmerizing you.
That’s what he’s doing.
You are not free.
You are mesmerized and under mesmerism you
don’t understand what he’s doing to you.
And now thank God, ninety-nine percent of
them are getting exposed.
But now new are coming up like mushrooms but
still, if you understand that you can’t
pay for your evolutionary process, you have
understood me very well.
Now what happens when you get your realization
as I told you, the first thing happens that
you become thoughtlessly aware.
Is a state.
In Sanskrit called as nirvichara samadhi.
The second state is doubtless awareness.
When this connection is in the beginning little
loose, so, you have to work it out a little
bit.
Once you have worked it out and the connection
becomes really, permanent, then what you find
is a complete flow of that power within you.
A new state another a new dimension in your
awareness comes in.
That on your fingertips you can feel your
centers, means self knowledge.
You know where what’s the problem is.
And on the same way, on the same fingers you
can feel the centres of others.
So you are collectively conscious.
You know about others.
You don’t know what sort of dress they are
wearing, what sort of complexion they have,
what race they come from, but what you know
is what’s wrong with their centre, which
centre is in jeopardy.
Now, if you know how to correct those centers,
your problem is solved and the problem of
others also you can solve.
In that enlightenment, what do you see?
You see yourself away from yourself in the
sense that you start seeing, yourself as sometimes
as a stupid fellow.
Sometimes could be you might think, see that
you are doing such wrong things to yourself.
You are destroying yourself.
In Sahaja Yoga we never say: ‘Don’t do.’
We never say because half of the people will
run away.
So we say that alright let’s have the awakening.
Once you have the awakening then in that light
you see.
I’ll give an example.
Supposing I’m very obstinate, and think
no end of myself, and is carrying the snake
in my hand.
It’s darkness and somebody tells me that
this is a snake and it will bite you.
I say: ‘No.
[WHAT’S THE…del.]
What’s wrong?
Let me have, but it’s a rope.’
They said: ‘No, it’s a snake, please throw
it away.’
No.
Nobody will listen.
But if little light comes [IN THAT…del.]
in that room or in that hall or wherever it
is immediately you throw away that snake.
So you become your own guide, and you understand
yourself and you just give up all these things.
Without doing anything you just give it up.
In England we had great experiences of very
terrible drug addicts.
Overnight they gave up.
Overnight.
It’s very surprising.
All these problems, in the world today are
because of ignorance.
Once you have the light you just give up all
these things, without any difficulty, because
you find they’re destructive.
One doesn’t have to tell you don’t do
it don’t do it.
It just happens.
You are empowered.
That you can control yourself and you know
how to be with yourself.
But in the same way you can have an effect
on others.
Supposing two persons are quarreling and a
third person who’s a realized soul goes
there, suddenly the peace descends on them
and suddenly they give up fighting.
So the power that is all-pervading you should
understand, is such a dynamic power, is the
ocean of compassion, is the ocean of knowledge,
but above all it is the ocean of forgiveness.
So, when we feel very guilty, after realization
you get rid of all these troubles.
People have all kinds of problems incurred
upon themselves.
But in this light you see it so clearly and
it manages.
It just disappears.
Now what is our problem now of this world
is?
A scientist came to argue with me.
I said: ‘Answer only one question.
Why are you on this earth?’
He didn’t know what to say.
Madly he is finding out one thing, then another
thing and another thing.
But I said: ‘Why are you here?
Just to find these things or is there something
more?’
Couldn’t understand.
I said: ‘If I tell you, you’ll be happy
to know, you have to enter into the Kingdom
of God, to enjoy His bliss, to enjoy His love,
to enjoy His bounties.
This is why you are on this Earth.’
This is what it is, it answers this question
this way.
The second thing that happens to you.
That you know Absolute Truth.
Now supposing, somebody comes from India from
jail.
And wears a cloth of saffron color and starts
saying some sort of Sanskrit words.
He’ll become a big guru anywhere.
Because he shows off like that you see, carries
a drum of that kind.
He’ll become a big guru.
How will you know whether he’s a thief or
not?
What you have to do is to just put your hands
if you are realised souls.
Immediately you will feel, the burning of
this fellow.
Immediately you’ll know what sort of chakras
he is.
How cunning he is.
Immediately.
And after some times you don’t even have
to put your hands towards him.
Immediately you’ll know what sort of person
he is, what are his centers in danger, what
is happening to him.
Thus you can cure also physical ailments of
yourself and of others.
You are so relaxed.
Now see, I’m seventy-one years of age.
I’ve been coming to Perth, I don’t know
how many years I’ve been coming here.
And I’m travelling like this, I’m quite
all right.
Because, you don’t worry.
You are so relaxed.
I mean people say: ‘Mother, you are traveling
so much.’
I say: ‘I never travel, I’m just sitting
in the aeroplane, that’s all I know.’
If I start thinking: ‘I’m traveling, I’m
this.’
I never travel.
I’m just sitting nicely, I’m sitting here
in the same, in the drawing room, I’m sitting
there.
What is there like travelling?
What’s so special.
Like that you see you become so relaxed, in
your peace, that you don’t feel, your age,
you become so dynamic, and you become so compassionate.
You become extremely compassionate.
You become a very different person, very beautiful
person.
I’ve seen who are married in Sahaja Yoga,
people, are such good husband and wife.
Hardly any divorce.
One per cent maybe.
And they have beautiful children, who are
born realised.
In your Perth also you have some of them.
You should meet them, you’ll be happy to
meet them.
And so many problems which are so superficial
also pass out.
Children become so dynamic.
I know one of my relations had some problems
so he came to see Me.
And he got cured.
When he went back he told his son that I got
cured because of this.
So he said: ‘Alright, now I’m going to
do Sahaja Yoga.’
That boy, they had complained he’s not good
for studies and he stood first in the whole
of Uttar Pradesh State, such a huge place,
millions and millions appear for that matriculation
of theirs.
He stood first.
In our whole family nobody has come first.
We have first class, first many.
But not in the whole of UP, something so remarkable.
And the parents are surprised this boy never
used to study much.
Now he’s taken life so well, he’s so matured,
he’s so sensible.
This shows that all your capacities get enlightenment.
I’ve known, of very great artists coming
out of Sahaja Yoga.
In your Sydney also you have one girl who’s
gained a very big name out.
Then there are musicians, small children who
are becoming great musicians.
There are artists, there are musicians, there
are poets, orators, authors.
Suddenly, all their capacities start expressing
themselves.
There’s a fellow who is a chartered accountant,
he said I’ve never know any language very
well.
I’m a mathematician.
He writes such beautiful poems.
That is surprising.
How does he write?
Now the last song that they sung was written
in the sixteenth century by a tailor, who
got his realization and is the song says:
‘Oh Mother, give my yoga’ – means this
union with the Divine.
They are singing in the villages, everywhere
in India, but nobody knows what it means.
They don’t know what it means.
Because of Western education we have given
up all that is our, old knowledge, everything.
And we never bothered, to know what we have
in our country.
This Western life has increased so much, it
has grown so big.
Like a tree that becomes very big.
But it should seek its own roots, and it must
gets its nourishment.
If this is the knowledge of the roots, why
should we deny it.
Is very important.
As we learn science, from the West, the West
must learn, the knowledge of the roots.
And if it can be proved then why not?
Now there are three doctors who have got MD
degrees for Sahaja Yoga.
One has done on epilepsy, another has done
on physical fitness, third one has done on
cancer or something.
So now they have got MDs.
And there’s the fourth one who’s doing
some other research.
Asthma.
And they are very successful.
You don’t have to pay anything.
No medicine, nothing.
Just it works through your own powers.
About which you have no knowledge.
You don’t know what this power is like.
What it can give you.
So your attention itself becomes enlightened.
You pay attention to anyone after you have
achieved the state of thoughtless awareness,
doubtless awareness, then you will know what’s
wrong with that person.
Even of the dead, you will know what’s wrong
with that person.
Physically you will find out what’s wrong.
Mentally you will find out and spiritually
you can find out.
And all these three dimensions in us can found
out by ourselves and can be improved.
In the same way we can improve others through
our attention.
So dynamic, are our powers within ourselves.
And that’s what I’m saying we have to
know our glory.
For example this instrument, if it is not
connected to the mains it has no identity,
it has no meaning.
In the same way if we are not connected to
this, all-pervading power we have no meaning
to our life.
So people are trying to find identification
by coloring [COLORING…del.] their hair,
doing all kinds of things they do for identification.
Thank God it’s over now, all those.
Most of the fads are over.
Otherwise they used to always say one mantra:
‘What’s wrong?
What’s wrong?’
When you are wasting your energy, time: ‘What’s
wrong?’
Thank God recession has put them down a little
bit and they are not doing all these horrible
things they used to do.
So now the attention is more introspective.
I think so.
Of the young people especially I was shocked
the way some of the young people in England
were doing this, what do you call that I’ve
forgotten, with the red hair business and
wasting fifty pounds for that kind of a hairdress
which was quite funny you know and, they started
becoming blind.
So I said: ‘Why do you want to put this
horrible color, you are becoming blind?’
So they said: ‘What’s wrong?
Nothing wrong.’
Even if you say they are going to die: ‘So
what’s wrong?
In any way we have to die.’
I mean the whole brain had taken a recession
into itself.
It would not understand anything sensible.
But now somehow or other, people are maturing
and trying to understand that identity is
within ourselves.
Like now take a say a good television set
and take it to some remote village in India,
where they have never seen electricity.
And you tell them that from this you can see
films and things they’ll say: ‘Oh, now
you are telling us stories.
It’s just a box.’
That’s how we think we are just a box.
Unless and until we are connected, we cannot
know how great we are.
And that’s how we start condemning ourselves,
suffering from depression, this, that frustration.
These are all artificial.
And they just drop out once you know what
you are, what is your capacity, what you can
do, what are your powers.
So that, you get awakened and you can awaken
others also.
This is another power you get that you can
awaken other people.
You don’t have to ask Me to do that.
Anybody who is enlightened can do it.
Like one candle which is enlightened can enlighten
hundred candles.
In the same way you can also do it.
And once you start doing it the joy is tremendous.
Here in Perth we have many people who are
Sahaja Yogis and they are doing this work
here.
When I come only once a year here.
But I find that gradually they are maturing
very well.
And they have all the knowledge.
All the knowledge about yourself, about your
antaratma is called, the inside.
You should know everything about yourselves
and about others.
Not the outside.
But the inside of it.
What is it?
Why?
Why do I behave like this?
Why do I accept this?
Why I don’t accept like that?
You see your ego, you see all your conditionings,
you see everything clearly and you understand
what is good for you and you have power to
give up what you want to give up.
You are not powerless.
You are not under any habit.
All the habits drop out.
The best part of it, best part of it I would
say that you know absolute truth.
Also you can help others because in collective
consciousness you are there.
Your attention is enlightened.
But the best is that you jump into the ocean
of joy.
Joy is singular.
It is not like happiness and unhappiness.
Supposing somebody pampers our ego we are
very happy you see.
Somebody punctures it we are very unhappy.
But with joy you become a witness.
You see the whole thing as a witness.
And you are in a state where just you enjoy
everything.
Everything is so enjoyable, only thing little
bit, your vision is marred.
Once you get that, that joy, then nothing
can make you miserable.
If you see a problem of course you face it.
You face it bravely.
And you are not bothered.
And you are surprised that how you are helped
by so many blessings.
If you have to believe in yourself the blessings
come to you.
But you have to have faith in yourself.
Because also there’s a tendency: ‘Oh Mother,
I’m a sinner.
I’m this that.’
You see there’s nothing like that.
It’s all nonsense, people talk about sin,
sin, sin, sin.
After all you’re human beings.
You are not gods.
If you have done mistakes, so what?
What does it matter?
After all, this great power is there, which
is the ocean of forgiveness.
Ocean of forgiveness.
You don’t have to really torture yourself,
and go on saying as this is wrong with me
that is wrong with me.
Just have faith in yourself I’m telling
you and I’m sure this will work out tonight.
Of course I must say, that I respect your
freedom.
It cannot be forced on you.
It cannot be.
I respect your freedom.
And as a result it is you who has to say yes.
I cannot force on you.
So those who don’t want to have their realization
have to go away.
It helps you physically, mentally, emotionally.
I assure you it does.
Also spiritually it helps you a lot.
It works.
It’s your own power.
No doubt.
And there’s no complication with it, at
all.
No complication of any kind.
But if you don’t want to have it, how can
I force it on you?
It cannot be forced.
It’s a living process, of your choice, the
last breakthrough of your evolution.
That’s what I request you, that you should
just decide on this point yourself.
All religions have talked about it.
Christ has said: ‘Know thyself.’
In the Bible it is: ‘I’ll appear before
you like flames, like silent flames.’
You do see those chakras like that.
Every…Buddha has said it, everyone has said
the same thing.
Even in the Koran it is written that: ‘At
the time of resurrection, kiama, your hands
will speak and they’ll give witness against
you.’
I mean He has said it, much more clearly than
anybody else.
So all the religions have said that you have
to know yourself.
No doubt about it.
But no [RELIGION HAS …del.] outside religion
has tried that.
Nobody has tried to tell people you have to
know yourself.
They all have become either power oriented
or money oriented, not spirit oriented.
That’s the problem is.
So I would request people who don’t want
to have realization to go away, because it
won’t work out.
If you are not there it won’t.
It doesn’t work for people who are adamant,
who are arrogant, also for people who are
idiots you see, it doesn’t work out.
I’m sorry to say.
If you have some problem, physical, mental,
emotional, even spiritual then maybe, it might
be delayed but everybody gets it.
So far I’ve seen anybody who has come to
Sahaja Yoga has got it.
And got it very well.
So, I would request you … I know you all
have some questions also.
To be asked.
But I would say that, it is better that you
write them and send it over to Me.
Because just now the whole atmosphere is built
in and I think people should get their realization
first.
Then you’ll have no questions.
Because questions you see now, I’ve been
working for about twenty-three years, I know
all these mental acrobats, I know.
I can answer every question very well.
Make you laugh also.
But, the main thing is realization and if
you have this mental diversion then perhaps
maybe, you might miss the point.
So the best thing is that you get your realization
which is your right and then, we’ll talk
about it.
Now what one has to do is to take out the
shoes that’s all.
It’s not a too much of a thing doing this.
Because this Mother Earth takes away our problems.
So now we are on our way, to know how fantastic
we are and to enter into the Kingdom of God.
So we have to be very kind to ourselves.
See actually, I think, we must really have
respect for ourselves.
Very important.
There are three conditions.
The first one is, that, you have to forgive
yourself.
Just forgive yourself.
Means you should not feel guilty, at all.
Perhaps you don’t know if you feel guilty
what happens is on the left side this centre
catches and that gives you spondylitis.
It might also give you angina and maybe lethargic
organs.
It’s a terrible thing to have this centre
caught up.
So what’s the need to feel guilty?
I mean in anyway you are punishing yourself
for nothing at all.
So please don’t feel guilty.
I mean people feel guilty for all kinds of
nonsensical things.
Like somebody spilled, say coffee.
Finished.
All his life he’ll remember: ‘Oh my God,
I spilled the coffee on the carpet.’
It’s nothing important.
So please don’t feel guilty.
That’s one point.
That’s very important because if this centre
is caught up the Kundalini won’t rise.
Now the second condition is, that you have
to forgive everyone.
Now some say it’s very difficult to forgive
anyone.
Logically whether you forgive or don’t forgive
you don’t do anything.
What do you do?
Nothing.
But actually you play into wrong hands.
The persons who have harmed you or troubled
you or made you unhappy, are happy.
While you are torturing yourself.
Logically.
So why torture yourself for nothing at all?
Don’t even think about them.
To just say in general: ‘Mother, I forgive
everyone.’
Just say it.
And it will be done.
You’ll feel much lighter, I tell you.
Must forgive.
There’s a way to understand that, at this
moment you have to be free from all this nonsense.
Why?
Because this center is, like this – agnya.
The optic chiasma goes like this.
[SHRI MATAJI DEMONSTRATES] Like that it is.
If you don’t forgive it won’t open.
Now, it has to open like this, if the Kundalini
has to pass through it.
Now if you don’t forgive, this will remain
like this.
All your life you have tortured yourself and
at this moment you’ll miss the point.
So why not forgive?
Just forgive.
Forgive everyone.
And third.
The most important.
Is the condition that you all should have
confidence that you all can get your realization.
Whether you belong to Australia, India or
Timbuktu.
You all can get your realization tonight.
This is very important.
Have confidence in yourself.
Moreover, you have to know that this is not
an individual happening.
It’s not that you are getting your realization
and another isn’t.
It’s ‘en masse’.
That’s the new thing is an ‘en masse’
realization.
Say in Russia sixteen thousand people get
How it has worked out?
We should say God alone knows.
But it has worked out.
Now, once it happens, to you, you cannot sit
at home and say: ‘Oh yes Mother, I’m meditating.’
No, no.
You have to come to the collective.
You don’t have to pay anything.
No, no, no.
It’s not that this is introduction letter
and then your purses are polished off.
It’s not like that.
It is, it is just you have to attend.
You have to go for meditation with others,
collectively.
It’s a collective happening.
Supposing a nail is taken out of your finger.
It will never grow.
In the same way it’s a collective happening.
And Sahaja Yoga is working in sixty nations.
And the thousands and thousands of people
who are self realized.
They are all your part and parcel.
If one person gets into trouble in any place,
all of them will jump at it and try to see
that that person is saved.
So you have so many brothers and sisters.
Real brothers and sisters I should say.
They are not only blood relations but they
are spirit relations.
So, I have to request, that please don’t
finish it here.
Stephen told me he has a funny experience
of the Australians but it’s common with
everyone I must say.
That some people get it a very high experience
so they forget it.
They just enjoy it for while, til after one
year they come down when You are here and
they are not bothered.
But those who get little bit they just come
and say now what’s in it.
I’m getting burning here.
I’m doing this.
Why?
But those who get it in a big way should,
become easily doubtlessly aware people and
they have so many powers.
And they should do a lot.
Why?
They should help others who are feeling little
bit less.
So it is something, human nature I think,
the way it acts.
But it’s not Divine nature.
Divine nature is when you become Divine, then
you want to give.
You have the light.
You want to give.
Till this candle was not enlightened it was
alright, it was trying to get enlightened.
Once it was enlightened it is giving light.
When you have the light you have to give it
to others.
And that’s what is the most enjoyable thing.
For that you don’t have to pay, again.
But you have to give some time to yourself,
some respect to yourself, and some meaning
to your life.
You’ll be amazed how it will give you such
a joy that you can do all these things.
May God Bless You.
Now, I’ve told you again three conditions.
And I hope you have understood my three conditions
are very simple if you look at it because
all these things are there because of a myth.
It’s a myth.
That to feel guilty is a myth.
Not to forgive others is a myth.
And not to have confidence is another myth.
So we should get out of this and we should
have full confidence that we’ll get our
realization.
You all can get it I promise you.
All of you.
I hope you have taken out your shoes.
As Stephen has already told you there are
two powers, left and right, we have to put
both our feet like this on the Mother Earth.
Alright.
Now, please take out your shoes that’s all.
Now you have to put both the hands towards
Me like that.
Keep your eyes open.
For the time being.
You should be comfortable.
Very comfortable.
There should be no discomfort in your body.
Now please put your left hand towards me – on
your lap you can put it or sideways wherever
you feel comfortable and the right hand on
your heart.
Keep your eyes open because just now I’ll
tell you what is to be done.
This we have just to do that you should know
how we are clearing your centers.
Now we are working only on the left side with
your right hand and the left hand is towards
Me which indicates that you have a desire
because this is the power of desire, that
you have a desire that you get your realization.
So please put your right hand on your heart
now.
In the heart resides the spirit.
Now you take your right hand upper portion
of your abdomen on the left hand side and
press it.
If you are the spirit you become your own
master and this is the centre of your mastery
which is created by great masters, and prophets.
Now please take your right hand in the lower
portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
This is the centre of pure knowledge.
Means the knowledge about the laws which are
Divine.
Surprisingly the center is so low as that.
Now raise your right hand in the upper portion
of your abdomen again.
Then onto your heart.
Now raise your right hand in the corner of
your shoulder and your neck and put your head
to your right.
This is the center I’ve told you when you
feel guilty gets into jeopardy.
Now please take your right hand on top of
your forehead across, and put down your head.
This is the center where we have to forgive
everyone which we’ll do later on.
I’m just telling you now.
Now please take your right hand on the back
side of your head and push back your head.
Just for your satisfaction, here you have
to ask for forgiveness from the Divine Power.
Now the last center.
Is very important.
Stretch your hand fully and put the center
of your hand on top of the fontanel bone area
which was the soft bone on our head.
So now put down your head a little bit.
As far as possible if you can put it would
be nice.
Now press it hard by pushing back your fingers
and move your scalp.
Move your scalp more, clockwise.
Seven times.
Please move your clockwise hand to move the
scalp – seven times.
Put down your head please.
That’s all you have to do.
That’s all.
More than sufficient.
Now, you can call Me Shri Mataji or Mother,
whatever suits you.
Take out your spectacles will be better because,
it might help your eyesight also.
Now close your eyes.
Please close your eyes.
Put left hand towards Me, right hand on the
heart and put both the feet apart from each
other.
Be comfortable.
Now, here you have to ask Me a very fundamental
question about yourself.
Ask a question: ‘Mother am I the spirit?’
Ask the question in your heart.
‘Mother am I the spirit?’
Ask three times.
Now, as I told you if you are the spirit you
become your own master.
Now please take your right hand, on the upper
portion of your abdomen on the left-hand side
and press it and here you ask another question
three times: ‘Mother, am I my own master?’
I’ve told you that I respect your freedom
and you have to ask for pure knowledge.
I cannot force it on you.
So please take your right hand in the lower
portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
Here now press it hard and ask another question:
Again six times because, this center has got
six petals.
Ask six times for, pure knowledge: ‘Mother
please give me pure knowledge.’
Ask six times.
As soon as you ask for pure knowledge the
kundalini starts rising.
So, we have to open our upper centers with
full confidence.
Have full confidence in yourself.
Now please raise your right hand the upper
portion of your abdomen, on the left-hand
side.
Here, with full confidence you have to say
ten times: ‘Mother, I am my own master.’
Please say this ten times.
‘Mother, I am my own master.’
With full confidence.
I have already told you that you are the pure
spirit.
You are not this body, mind, emotions, egos,
conditionings.
But you are the pure spirit.
So now please put your right hand on your
heart and with full confidence you have to
say, twelve times in your heart: ‘Mother
I am the pure spirit.’
Please say it, with full confidence.
I have already told you that this all-pervading
power is the ocean of knowledge, ocean of
blessings but above all it is the ocean of
forgiveness.
So please forgive yourself and raise your
hand in the corner of your neck and your shoulder
and, on the left-hand side and turn your head
to your right.
Here you have to say with full confidence:
‘Mother I am not guilty, Mother I am not
guilty.’
Please say it, sixteen times.
I have already told you, if you forgive or
don’t forgive you don’t do anything.
But if you don’t forgive then, you play
into wrong hands and at this moment it’s
very important that you forgive because this
center of agnya is very constricted and has
to be opened out.
So please help yourself.
Now, raise your right hand on top of your
forehead across and please put down your head
as far as possible.
Here, it’s not how many times, but from
your heart you have to say: ‘Mother I forgive
everyone.’
Not how many times but from your heart: ‘Mother
I forgive everyone.’
In general.
You don’t remember each and every person.
You don’t have to think about any one of
them.
Just say in general from your heart.
This is very important.
Now, only for your satisfaction, without feeling
guilty, without counting your mistakes, please
put your right hand on the back side of your
head and push back your head.
Here, again you have to say from your heart,
not how many times: ‘Oh Divine Power, if
I have done any mistakes please forgive me.’
Just say that for your satisfaction.
Don’t feel guilty about it.
From your heart please say: ‘Oh Divine Power,
if I have done any mistake knowingly or unknowingly
please forgive me.’
Please push back your head.
Now the last center.
Please stretch your hand fully, your palm
specially and put the center of your palm
on top of the fontanel bone area, which was
a soft bone in your childhood.
Now, push back your fingers – very important,
that will give a nice pressure, now put down
your head.
Here again I cannot, cross over your freedom.
You have to ask for your self-realization.
I cannot force it on you.
So please try to move your hand clockwise,
seven times so that the scalp moves, nicely,
with the pressure and here you have to say,
seven times: ‘Mother, please give me my
self-realization.’
[SHRI MATAJI BREATHES INTO THE MICROPHONE]
Now please take down your hands.
Open your eyes slowly and put both the hands
towards Me like that.
Now, put the right hand towards Me and put
down your head and see with your left hand
if there’s a cool or a hot breeze coming
out of your fontanel bone area.
Don’t put it on top – above, above it.
Some people get it close and some people get
it very far.
So just try to see if there’s a hot or a
cold breeze coming out of your head.
This is the heat coming out of you.
If you have not forgiven the heat will be
there so please try to forgive now.
Now please put left hand towards Me.
Now bend your head again and see for yourself.
You have to see yourself, nobody’s going
to certify.
Please see if there’s a hot or a cool breeze
coming out of your head.
Again I would request you to forgive everyone
so that heat goes away.
Ultimately it will become cool, very cool.
Now lastly, with the right hand.
Now raise your both the hands towards the
sky.
Push back your head and ask one question,
one of these questions three times.
You can ask: ‘Mother, is this the cool breeze
of the Holy Ghost?’
‘Mother is this the all-pervading power
of Divine Love?’
Otherwise: ‘Mother is this the ruhx, is
this the paramachaitanya?’
Ask any one of these questions three times
– any one.
Now put down your hands, please.
Now put your hands like this towards Me.
You can wear your glasses also.
Put your hands like this.
And don’t think, just don’t think.
Watch Me, don’t think.
You can do it.
All those who have felt the cool breeze in
their hands please raise both your hands.
Just raise it like that, otherwise I can’t
see.
It’s very good.
Imagine.
Perth.
I bow to you all.
Really.
Bow to you.
You’ve received your connection.
No doubt.
I’m getting cool breeze from you.
And now only thing is you have to grow.
Some people haven’t got it so we’ll have
to look at them, what’s the problem is.
May be some problem there.
But most of you have got it.
Those who have got it or not got it, please
you must come and attend our follow-up places.
They have got some sort of a program after
this where they will explain to you everything.
And you will achieve your ultimate goal, is
to know everything about it.
Everything.
I promise you, you will get it.
But give some time to yourself.