Today, we are doing a special type of puja
which is performed in the glory of Ekadesha
Rudra.
Rudra is the destructive power of Shiva, of
the Spirit.
Now one power, which is His nature, is forgiveness.
He forgives, because we are human beings,
we commit mistakes,
we do wrong things, we get tempted,
our attention is disturbed – so he forgives
us.
He also forgives us when we spoil our chastity,
we do immoral things,
we do thieving, and we do things that
are against God,
talk against Him.
He also forgives our superficialities, jealousies,
our lust, our anger.
Also He forgives our attachments, petty jealousies,
vanities and also possessiveness.
He forgives our egoistical behaviour
and also our subordination to wrong things.
But every action has a reaction,
and when He forgives, He thinks that He has
given you a big grace-mark,
and that reaction builds up within Him
as a wrath, against those who are forgiven,
try to do greater mistakes.
Specially, after realisation,
because such a big blessing there is of the
realisation,
you’ve got the light and, in the light,
if you are holding onto a snake
then His wrath goes up because he sees how
stupid you have been.
What I am saying is that after realisation,
specially, He is much more sensitive
that, people who are forgiven and have been
given such a big thing
like Self-realisation, still they do wrong
things
then he is much more wrathful.
So, in the balance, the forgiveness starts
reducing and the wrathfulness starts increasing.
But when He forgives and, as a result of that
forgiveness
you feel the gratitude, then His blessings
start flowing towards you.
He gives you tremendous capacity to forgive
others.
He pacifies your anger, He pacifies your lust,
He pacifies your greed.
Like beautiful dew drop His blessings come
on our being and
we become really beautiful flowers,
and we start shining in the sunshine of His
blessings.
Now He uses His wrath or His destructive power
to destroy all that tries to trouble us.
He protects realised souls at every point,
in every way.
Negative forces try to attack a sahaja yogi
but they are all neutralised by His tremendous
power of protection.
Through his vibratory awareness we are guided
into right path.
All the beautiful blessings of His are described
in the Psalm 23
isn’t it, that’s the 23 Psalm ……
The Lord is my Shepherd”
Is all described how he looks after you as
a shepherd.
But He does not look after the evil people
He destroys them.
Those who enter into Sahaja Yoga [and] are
still carrying on with their evil nature
are destroyed.
Those who come to Sahaja Yoga and do not meditate
and do not rise He destroys,
or they are thrown out of Sahaja Yoga.
Those who murmur against God and live in a
way
that is not behoving a sahaja yogi, He removes
them from [it].
So by one force, He protects, by another force,
He throws away.
But His destructive forces when they are built
up too much, then we call it :
"Now the Ekadesha Rudra is active."
Now, this Ekadesha Rudra will be expressed
when the Kalki itself will start acting,
means the destructive power which will destroy
all
that is negative on this earth and save all
that is positive.
So it is very necessary for sahaja yogis
to expedite their ascent,
not to be satisfied with the social life or
married life
or with all the blessings that God has bestowed
upon you.
We always see, what God has done for us,
how He has been miraculous to us, but we have
to see what we have done to ourselves,
what are
we doing about our own ascent and growth.
Now the…out of the eleven centres……
Ekadesha, means eleven,
the five come from the right side of your
void,
and five from the left side of your void.
The first five on the left hand side come
from:
if you have bowed yourself to wrong gurus,
or if you have read wrong books,
or if you have been in the company of wrong
people,
or if you have been sympathetic towards people
who have been following wrong paths,
or you have been yourself one of the agents
or guru of these wrong people.
Now these five problems can be solved, if
we completely give up
whatever wrong we have been doing.
As Mohammed Sahib has said that you have to
beat the Shaitan, means the Satan,
with shoes;
but that has to be done not mechanically but
from your heart.
Like many people who come to Sahaja Yoga will
tell me,
“My father is following this guru; that
father is following that guru,”
and get involved with their father, sister,
this, that
and try to take them out from those gurus,
also get entangled.
Or some of them yield to others’ forces.
Like I know of Maureen, who was with me,
and her parents and parents-in-law said that
the child must be baptised,
and I told her, you cannot get this child
baptised
because it’s a realised soul.
But she could not, that way, stand up to that,
and she took the child for baptism
and the child became very funny – it was
really like a mad child.
Now then she gave up all that and so she has
saved.
But supposing she had another child and she
would have done the same thing,
the second child would have been something
very, very bad.
Now, the trouble with sahaja yogis is
that anybody who comes to Sahaja Yoga programme
thinks he is a sahaja yogi – is not so.
Either you should have very strong sensitivity,
or you should feel it in your body,
or with your intelligence you should understand
what is Sahaja Yoga.
A person who is still negative always gets
attracted towards other one
who is a very,very powerfully negative
and does not understand that the other person
is so powerfully negative,
but gets impressed.
Under such circumstances, such a person is
hit by that negative person
and Shiva cannot protect.
One should not have sympathy with anyone who
is negative,
whether he is mad, whether there is something
wrong with him,
whether he is your relation, or anything.
No sympathy of any kind, on the contrary a
kind of a anger
should be there for that person,
a kind of a detachment, angry detachment.
And this angry detachment is the only time
when you have to be angry.
But I have seen people who have anger for
very good sahaja yogis
but not for their own husbands or wives who
are extremely negative.
So when the Ekadesha Rudra starts acting on
these five sides
on the, we should say, on the right side it
moves,
because it comes from the left and moves to
the right side,
then a person starts becoming negative but
acting with his ego.
Such a person may take up a situation into
hands and say that
“I am such and such sahaja yogi and I am
so, we should do like this
and we should behave like this”, and start
dictating people.
[They] can do anything.
And some mediocres or some half baked sahaja
yogis
may try to understand [him],
but most will know that “This fellow is
going out,
now he’s on his way out!”
So, all these things lead to this left side
development,
or we can call it on the head, on the right
hand side of your medha,
this plate, brain-plate
is called as medha in Sanskrit language.
Now, the right sided one, comes from the idea
people have that,
“I am myself a big guru.”
They start preaching about Sahaja Yoga also,
as if
they have become great gurus.
We have known some people who give big lectures
in any programme and never allow
my tape to be played or anything.
They think they have now become experts.
Then some of them say that now we have become
so great
that we need not do any footsoaking or anything,
there’s no need to do meditation – there
are some like that also.
And then there are some who say
that "sin can never touch us, now we are sahaja
yogis,
we are very great evolved souls".
But the worst of all are those who just take
my name
saying that “Mother has said so and I am
telling you because Mother has said”
– when I have never said such a thing, is
all falsehood.
Now there are some people who use Sahaja Yoga
money
and exploit Sahaja Yoga in such a way, exploit
them, sahaja yogis also sometimes.
And such people become very inauspicious.
Anyone who tries such things will go out of
Sahaja Yoga
with disgrace.
But one should never go near such a person,
have nothing to do with such a person, have
no sympathies.
Because this inauspiciousness will hurt anyone
to any extent,
so better keep out of such people.
When these ten Ekadeshas are developed within
a person,
then definitely such a person gets diseases
like cancer
and incurable horrible diseases.
Specially, when the eleventh one which is
actually here,
which is the Viraatas chakra,
which is the collectivity,
when it is affected as well, then such a person
cannot get out of this disease.
But these…out of these even five are combined,
supposing, with Mooladhara or with Agnya,
then they get into very serious type of dirty
diseases.
That’s why, I always say that be careful
about your Agnya chakra,
because that is one of the worst things,
that, once it starts getting combined with
these Ekadeshas, part of the Ekadeshas,
then anything can happen to a person,
he can meet with a horrible accident,
he can suddenly be hit by someone, could be
murdered by someone,
anything can happen to such a person who has
got the right Agnya
and also any one of the Ekadeshas, right or
left.
That means, the five of these, if they, any
one of the five,
if they combine with Agnya Chakra,
the protective powers of God are minimum.
So, to keep your Agnya chakra alright,
say now I am speaking,
now you should watch Me constantly,
so that there is thoughtless awareness and
the Agnya chakra is soothed out.
But, don’t pay attention here and there
all the time.
Then you will find that, gradually, your attention
will neutralise
into thoughtless awareness,
and your attention would be fixed in such
a manner
that you don’t have to worry about anything.
In thoughtless awareness nobody can touch
you,
that is your fortress.
By meditation, one must establish thoughtless
awareness,
that is the sign that you are rising higher.
Many people do meditation and say, “Alright,
Mother we are doing.”
Mechanically, they do and say,
“I did this, I did this, and I did this!”
But did you achieve your thoughtless awareness,
minimum of minimum?
Have you felt your cool breeze coming out
of your head?
Otherwise, if you are doing something mechanically,
it is not going to help; help you or help
anyone.
So, after realisation, as you are very well
protected,
you have all the blessings and a great future,
you also have a great possibility of a complete
annihilation.
I would say, to give an analogy, you are climbing,
and everybody is supporting you to climb,
holding your hand,
and there are so many things by which you
are protected, to be taken upward,
there’s no possibility of falling off by
mistake also,
but if you try to remove your bondages with
Truth and Love
and all the time try to hit the people who
are trying to support you,
then you fall from a great height, greater
height.
I mean, the greater height you rise, the greater
you fall,
and with a greater force also, much more deeper.
But every effort is made by the Divine, every
support is given to you,
every care is taken.
Despite that, if you want to fall,
then from that height, is very dangerous.
But Ekadesha Rudra, at that time, at such
a time when somebody tries
to harm the cause of Sahaja Yoga,
after being in Sahaja Yoga,
then hits you so badly
that the whole attack is very widespread.
But the whole family can be protected if there
are few people of that family
doing Sahaja Yoga work; could be protected.
But in case the family that is against all
the time of sahaja yogis
and try to trouble them,
can be completely destroyed, in a very bad
way.
Now these Ekadesha Rudras come out of, as
I told you, from the Void.
So, we can say that the destruction part of
it comes from the Void mainly.
But these are the powers, all are given in
one person
that is the Mahavishnu, that is Lord Jesus
Christ.
Because He’s the support of the whole Universe,
He’s the personification of Omkara,
he’s the Personification of vibrations.
So when He gets angry then the whole Universe
starts breaking.
As He personifies the power of the Mother
which is penetrating into every atom, into
every molecule, and to every human being,
into every [thing] that is living and non-living:
once it gets disturbed the whole thing gets
into a jeopardy.
So the pleasing of Christ is very important.
Now Christ has said, “You have to be like
small children”
That is, the innocence, the purity of the
heart is the best way you can please Him.
As in the West, specially, people have developed
their brains too much,
they try to play about with words
and think that nobody knows what they are
doing.
All such people must know that everything
you do is known to God.
If you are not clean in heart,
it is very dangerous for anybody to pose
as if he’s a very good sahaja yogi.
Such people are not possessed, nor they are
conditioned, nor they are egoistical,
but they are very cunning clever people and
they are quite aware, as to what they are
doing.
But, there are people who get possessed also
and then they, in that , they try to destroy
themselves
or cry and weep and do all kinds of things.
There are some who think that if they hurt
themselves or do some sort of an extreme thing
then God will be happy -are sadly mistaken.
If you cannot enjoy in Sahaja Yoga,
then you should know that something is wrong
with you.
If you cannot feel happy in Sahaja Yoga
then you must know that there’s something
definitely wrong with you.
If you cannot enjoy the company of sahaja
yogis,
then it’s sure something is wrong with you.
If you cannot laugh and appreciate the greatness
of God,
then something wrong with you.
If you are still worried about negative people
and their problems
then know that there’s something wrong with
you.
If you have sympathies with negative people,
then also there’s something wrong with you.
But if you have anger for negative and all
that is negative
that is against Sahaja Yoga, then you are
there.
When this thing gets matured then you become
the power
of Ekadesha Rudra yourself.
Anybody who will try to insult you
or to do any harm, will collapse.
It has happened with many people who tried
to be insulting to Me
or tried to harm Me or anyway….
Sometimes I am quite worried about them.
So one has to be in such a way that they become
the Ekadesha.
Nobody can touch such people.
But such a person is full of compassion and
forgiveness.
As a result, Ekadesha acts much faster.
The more compassionate you are the more powerful
Ekadesha becomes.
The more collective you become, the more Ekadesha
acts.
Many people have a habit of receding back
into their exclusion
and saying “Oh we better be at home and
it’s alright,”
but they don’t know what they are missing.
Whatever may be your experience with others,
you should stick-on together,
always attend programmes, take leadership,
go ahead with it,
work it out and you will be blessed thousand-fold.
Ekadesha Rudra are all the powers, I would
say, of destruction, together.
Is the power, destructive power of Shri Ganesha.
It is destructive power of Brahma, Vishnu,
Mahesha.
It is the destructive power of the Mother.
Is the destructive power of the Ganesha…
and four of these are Bhairava and Hanumana,
Kartikeya and Ganesha.
Also the powers of Sadashiva and of the Adishakti.
All the destructive powers of all the incarnations
are Ekadeshas.
Now the last but not the least, is the destructive
power
of Hiranyagarbha which is the Collective Brahmadeva.
And this power when it acts, every atom explodes,
the whole atomic energy goes into a destructive
power.
So, thus, the complete total destructive power
is Ekadesha Rudra.
It’s extremely powerful, explosive, but
it’s not blind.
It’s very discriminative and extremely delicately
woven.
It avoids all the good points and attacks
the wrong things
and it hits at the right time, at the right
point,
direct, without hitting anything that is good
in between.
Now the glance of Ekadesha Rudra falls upon
someone,
say, for example, and there is something in
between which is divine or which is a positive
thing
[then] it penetrates through positive, without
harming the positive
and hits the negative.
It cools down somebody and burns another.
Not freezing, it doesn’t freeze, it cools
down.
So that is how it works with such care and
such delicacy.
And it is tremendously sharp also.
And it’s very painful.
It’s not like cutting the neck in one shot,
it goes on slowly, slowly.
All the horrible tortures that you have learnt
or heard about are expressions of Ekadesha
only.
For example, take the case of cancer.
In the cancer thing, the nose is removed,
the tongues are removed, then the gullet is
removed,
then everything goes on, one after [another],
being removed with terrible pain, you see.
Take leprosy for example, the lepers cannot
feel their fingers,
they cannot feel it, so the…any rat or anything
eats their fingers
they can’t feel it, so they start losing
their fingers,
that is how Ekadesha eats up people, devours.
But this wrathfulness of the Father can be
very gentle and could be very sweet,
when it comes to His own children.
The story is about the Mother
– once She got very angry, the Primordial
Mother.
And She was so angry, She wanted to destroy
the whole world with Her Ekadesha power
and She tried to destroy the whole world.
When She went into that mood, the Father Himself
felt that She is being
[a] bit too much angry.
So when She started destroying, and She was
going right and left,
He did not know what to do, so He took Her
child,
that means representing sahaja yogi, you can
say, representing Christ
or representing anyone of these great children
of Her’s, that he put the child
under Her feet.
So, when She was stamping,
suddenly She saw Her own child under Her feet
and Her such a big tongue came out.
She just stopped.
Balancing.
But this has happened only once.
So, after the Ekadesha Rudra, ultimately the
complete destruction comes
through the anger of Sadashiva.
When the final total destruction takes place.
So thus we have seen how Ekadesha Rudra acts
and how sahaja yogis have to become themselves
Ekadesha Rudra.
Now to develop this power
one has to develop a tremendous power of detachment,
power of detachment, detachment from negative.
For example, negativity can come from very
near people,
like brother, mother, sister, could come from
friends, could come from relatives.
It could come from a country, it could come
from your political ideas, economic ideas,
anything like that.
Any misidentification can destroy your power
of Ekadesha Rudra.
So it is not only sufficient to say that “I
am surrendered to Sahaja Yoga
and I am a sahaja yogi,”
but you must know mentally also what is Sahaja
Yoga.
So that, intelligently, you understand what
is Sahaja Yoga.
Because in the West specially people are over-intelligent
and if the light of Sahaja Yoga does not enter
into their intelligence
you can never overcome your attachments.
That doesn’t mean you talk too much about
Sahaja Yoga or you give lectures on that,
but mentally you should also understand what
is Sahaja Yoga.
Today is a special day when it has been asked
that
we should have Ekadesha Rudra puja,
and is for all kinds of false religious sects
and false gurus
and false religions, which are followed in
the name of God,
or any religion that does not say about Self-realisation
and does not achieve Self-realisation and
does not get connected with God, is false.
So any such thing that is just faith and talks
of God
but has no connection with God
cannot be a true religion.
Of course, it gives a balance to people,
but in giving that balance, if people live
on that money
and try to enjoy a wealth out of that money,
then it is not even at the very lower level
is religion.
Like a balance, you, see, religion has to
give a balance to begin with,
but in that balancing when
they tell, “You have to
be balanced,
but give me money for that,
you must give me money, give me all your purse,
give me everything,”
then that cannot be balanced, it does not
even have a slightest thing of the blessings
of God.
Or any religion that makes you bow to
anybody else but the incarnation,
is no religion.
That’s another one which is absolutely false.
The real religion will give you a balance
and will always talk
about the ascent.
But they will not ask for money or make one
man something great as venerated.
Thus, we should learn to discriminate between
falsehood, negative things
and real things.
Once you develop that discrimination through
vibratory awareness,
or through your intelligence, you are in the
control of yourself.
And then
you become that power
of Ekadesha,
when you establish your maturity.
Today, I bless you all, that
you all
become the
power of Ekadesha Rudra
and
you develop
that sincerity which takes you to that state.
May
God
Bless you.