I think you can go down. There are lots of seats still vacant.
I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset
I have to tell you that truth is what it is.
You cannot transform it, change it
and unfortunately at this human awareness you cannot know it.
Now whatever I am going to tell you today,
you need not believe blind folded. We have already
suffered a lot because of blind faith.
But if it is proved
then as honest people you have to accept it.
Because it is for the benevolence of your being,
for the benevolence of your society,
your city, your country and the world at large.
So one has to understand
that we have not known so far the Absolute Truth.
If we had known the Absolute Truth
there would not have been any problem whatsoever.
Because everybody would see the same truth.
There cannot be so many [dead] dogmas,
so many discussions, arguments, fights and wars.
If everybody sees the same point then who will fight?
For example I am sitting before you, you all see it clearly
and you know it.
So you are not going to fight that I am here or not.
For that we need a last breakthrough of our evolution.
As human beings, still, we have freedom to think whatever we like
but we haven’t got capacity to know the Absolute Truth.
If that is so and if there is a way out,
why not we try for it?
You have been already told about this,
this instrument that is within you.
I've never seen such a big one - today is the only...
In Australia everything is big I tell you.
Very nice.
I mean it can cover a very big hall as we had yesterday.
A day before we had three thousand three hundred people
and this would have been better there.
All right, as it is
this is the subtle instrument that is within us.
It's created through our evolutionary process.
As we learn, say, science and other things
from western countries, from Australia, from all
Japanese countries and all that.
We can see the civilization has grown so big
and we do not know our roots.
That’s why, what is happening is, people are waiting for a shock.
Already they are very much upset.
What has gone wrong with us that we should know our roots?
Now if these roots are coming from East or from India
why should we abhor it,
why should we condemn it?
Because it's very important
that we have to seek our roots
and this is the knowledge of the roots.
The human problems
actually cover all the global problems, most of it.
And to solve them
we have to see to this inner subtle instrument within us.
When these centers are in jeopardy,
then we get physical, mental, emotional, spiritual,
social, political, all problems -
because problems are caused by human beings
and human beings are in trouble because of these centers.
So if by chance,
you know how to correct your centers
and then to correct others' centers also,
you solve the problem.
Now this power that is being told as ‘Kundalini’,
is called ‘Kundalini’ because
‘Kundal’ means coils - it is coiled three and a half times.
It has some mathematical calculation.
Now this ‘Kundalini’ when She is awakened
She passes through these centers
and She enlightens them.
She nourishes them and She integrates.
Ultimately She pierces through your fontanel bone area -
in Sanskrit we call it ‘Brahmarandra’ -pierces through
and becomes one with this all pervading power.
So you achieve two results.
So the truth about you is that
you are not this body, mind, your ego, your conditionings.
Because you say this is my ego,
this is my conditioning, this is my house,
this is my wife, my husband.
So this ’my’, who is the ‘my’ there?
So you become the ‘I’, the ‘self’,
that is the ‘Spirit’, which you are!
And the second truth is that there is an All Pervading Power
which does all the living work.
Look at these beautiful flowers; it's a miracle, if you see?
They are different flowers from different seeds of certain heights,
certain shapes, certain colour
and you take it for granted.
You don’t even think about them how they have come out like that.
Who runs our heart?
The doctors will say: autonomous nervous system.
But who is the ‘auto’?
So we never question anything about living process,
because we can’t answer.
This living process
is done by a very subtle energy,
which we can call by any name,
is the ‘divine power of love’.
You can call it as ‘Ruh’ as in Koran,
you can call it as ‘Brahmachaitanya’ as in Sanskrit
and as ‘Ritambhara Pragya’ by Patanjali.
You can give it any name to it, is different but,
it is a power which we have never felt before
which is a subtle power which does all living work.
So, as if,
if you have not reached that source of energy,
the whole development outside is collapsing.
Also, supposing this instrument
is not connected to the mains,
then, it has no identity, it has no meaning. Why was it created?
And everywhere these days I find the seekers
are trying to find out their identity.
So what is your identity, is that you are the Spirit,
you are the ‘Spirit’ and this Spirit
is the ultimate that you have to become.
Once you become the Spirit,
in the light of the Spirit
you see the Truth.
First of all on your fingertips
you start feeling this cool breeze,
‘cool breeze of the Holy Ghost’, you can call it
or this ‘All pervading power of Divine Love’.
And when you start feeling that power,
is... your body acts like a computer.
You ask any question.
There are many people who don’t believe - there is no God.
I think it is very unscientific to say there is no God,
because you have not found out.
Without finding out how can you say there is no God?
They have all kinds of funny stories even about Christ.
They say He was not the son of God. How do you say?
You are not at that point where you can decide,
what is true, what is not.
Just mental projections,
they go on condemning all the great incarnations, and
all the great prophets, and seers and sages
because they are all blind.
Kabira says that, "O God, how am I to explain
to all these people who are blind in this world?"
Kaise samaja hu, sab jagah andha (Hindi to be checked).
So, Sahaja means, ‘Saha” means born,
‘saha’ means ‘with’, ‘ja’  ’born’.
Born with you is the right
to become a ‘yogi’, to have this union, ‘yoga’
with the Divine.
And it is very simple now.
In the modern times it's very simple.
In the olden days there were people
who were trying to give Realization, Self-Realization,
but they would have one or two disciples only.
And will...
they would not reveal the secrets about the ‘Kundalini’,
so clearly.
In the twelfth century
one great poet called Gyaneshwara,
he asked permission from his master -
his own brother was his master - that, "Allow me to talk about it.
And I will not do anything
but I'll just talk about it in my book,
‘Gyaneshwari’.
In the sixth chapter He wrote very clearly about it.
In Sanskrit we had, fourteen thousand years back
a great Markendeya who had written about it.
Sixth century also ‘Adi Shankaracharya’ wrote about it.
But it was all in Sanskrit, was not available to common people.
After this,
after the twelfth century
when he (Gyaneshwara) wrote it, the people who were in charge of religion
said that this is a
‘nishiddha’, means is something not to be read by anyone,
it's not, because they didn’t know what to do about it.
They had no idea, they had no knowledge.
They had no knowledge about the Divine
and they were in charge of religion, maybe making money.
So the second...
lot of people, saints came up in India
In the sixteenth century
who have talked about it,
all over the country, about this ‘Kundalini’.
In the Bible also it is written
that I will appear before you like ‘tongues of flames’,
and these look like tongues of flames,
very silent, beautiful.
In these colors as shown here, they look like.
And some people have described them, those who have been
moving round the circle.
But, to enter into it, to be -
supposing I see the light, I am not the light.
This is the point many people have missed,
that you have to be not to see something.
And once you become
then you have so many powers within you
that you start manifesting them.
The other day there were some these
‘born again’ people were just...
like mad, were there shouting, shouting.
I said, "You are not 'born again', what are you doing?"
You just call themselves ‘born again’, is not the way.
As we call ourselves Hindus, Muslims, Christians, this -
we are not!
We are really not because
anybody can commit any mistake,
can commit any sin -
you may belong to any religion.
So there's something missing within you and your religion.
It is not innately manifesting within you.
And that's the point we have to be
honest about it.
That our religion and ourselves
are not one with ourselves.
As we can see something,
are we righteous?
Innately are we righteous? We are not.
And there are temptations and temptations,
so what’s wrong?
We do all kinds of
things and as far as the religion is concerned,
still what you find
that the religion is not one with us.
And so many bad things are happening,
you see these Muslims being killed here,
these Israelis are being killed and this, I mean
it is really I can’t understand
how can you do it in the name of God.
Now this Bosnia problem is there and people are
dying and eating each other’s body,
that sort of thing. I mean, can you imagine in modern times
such things are happening all over the world?
And it disturbs you completely -
that "Why is it they don’t want to see the point?"
There's something missing.
With all that we have to understand that
if we have to solve the problem of religion,
one thing we must know, that all these religions
were born on the same tree of spirituality.
Only we have plucked the flowers.
and now we are fighting with the dead flowers.
Then where is the religion?
Religion is this part that is shown as the green colour.
You see the ten petals, the Ten commandments,
ten petals. And this is to be awakened.
That's only possible if this ‘Kundalini’ rises.
She is your own power.
She is your own individual mother.
She has recorded everything within Herself,
what you have been doing, what was your past
and what are your problems
and what are your conditionings.
All your ventures She knows.
It's like a tape recorder.
But She's your mother
and She is anxious to give you your second birth,
very anxious, because these are some special times.
I call them Blossom Time.
In the Bible they say it is ‘Last Judgment’
and in the Koran it is called ‘Khayyama’,
is the resurrection time - whatever you may call it.
This is a special time when you are born
and you are all seekers, you are born
to seek the Truth.
Be honest about it
that we have not yet achieved what we wanted
out of whatever religion we follow,
whatever way we worship God.
Some people have some sort of satisfaction
that, "No, no, no, Mother, we are very happy we have got this...
No, that's not so.
With this happening,
the first thing happens to you that
you develop a new dimension in your, your awareness.
Just now you are not even conscious of your centers.
Then you know your centers on your fingertips,
you can feel them also inside.
Like somebody will come and tell Me, "Mother,
my ‘Agnya’ is caught. Please clear it out.
Meaning what? "I am very egoistical.
My ego is troubling me."
Nobody would say that normally.
Nobody will even think he has ego.
But with this, you get separated
from yourself and you see yourself
and your problems.
So the first thing happens to you,
that you have self-knowledge.
And the second thing then happens to you,
that you have the knowledge of others.
That is the ‘collective consciousness’,
in which sitting down here you can find out
whose chakras are catching where,
what's happening where, what's wrong with somebody.
But you don’t talk the language
as we talk about, "Oh, this one is a corrupt man
or he is just like that, he has this problem".
No, we talk on chakras only.
This is what the disciples of Christ were talking,
the language of chakras.
You say that "this person has this problem,
this person has this problem".
And you start not criticizing, telling him anything,
but if you know how to correct your chakras,
you can correct yours and you can correct others.
This is the power you get which I call it as the
‘collective consciousness’.
Because who is the other?
Is what we say,
the ‘microcosm’ becomes the ‘macrocosm’.
The one drop becomes the ocean.
The consciousness of the ocean comes within.
This is what is just waiting at your threshold.
You can get it.
It's very easy because it’s your own power
and it manifests,
so that you discover how glorious you are,
how powerful you are.
When this power starts flowing through you
it corrects your chakras no doubt.
But also
in the light of your Spirit your attention becomes
very innocent.
Christ had said "Thou shall not have adulteress eyes".
I would like to see
any Christian nation where they don’t have
people of this kind.
So
your attention becomes innocent
and wherever you put your attention on,
then what happens? It acts, it works.
It works very well.
So you become a global personality,
universal personality.
You can spread your attention.
But you become so compassionate,
so compassionate that you never think of harming anyone.
But anything that is harming,
you just put your attention and correct it
in your own life and the lives of others.
It is unbelievable for people
to think that they can be that dynamic and
they can show those results - but they can.
Because all these powers are within you.
Please understand
that I have nothing to do with it. It's a living process.
Like in the Mother Earth
if you put one seed it sprouts by itself.
Because the seed has a capacity to sprout
and the Mother also has the capacity to sprout.
It's a built-in capacity.
And when the built-in capacity is there,
it just acts as a living process.
So far, at a human level
we have all limited memories, limited energies, limited,
we can call, intelligence and projection of mind -
and they are mostly artificial.
So you jump into reality and you understand what is reality is.
Yet you have not known the reality.
So confused.
What is reality?
And the reality is that you are the ‘Spirit’
and that this all pervading power
is flowing through you as realized souls.
As you know the absolute truth, you can find out about anyone
who comes and says, "All right this is religion, this is God",
or say, "This is correct"
in every area, in every part of your activities.
Who is the correct man? How will you know?
Who is the one who is telling you the lies and who the one
who is just deceiving you?
As it is, I am ashamed to say,
that from my country so many
have come to loot you,
take advantage of your ignorance.
But even there was one realized soul he would have pointed out
that, "These are all thieves, don’t go near them".
So this all pervading power is the ocean of knowledge.
I've seen people
who have been ordinary artists have become great artists,
even Australia;
musicians have become great musicians, talented.
But those who were government servants, as most of you might be,
who had nothing to do with art, maybe,
suddenly become artists, poets.
I was Myself surprised because I have always -
as you know my husband has been a
hard-boiled bureaucrat -
and I've seen it,
people transforming themselves into such beautiful personalities
and doing good work now,
working out everything so well.
So what happens, that
supposing you are standing in the water,
in the sea and you are getting drowned because of the waves,
but somehow you come on a boat,
then you can see the waves and enjoy them.
But in case you know how to swim,
if you know how to swim you can save others.
This is exactly what happens to you.
It is also true that most of the diseases get cured,
or if you are getting into any diseases,
immediately know that you are getting into this trouble,
immediately. It's not difficult.
Because on the centers you can feel it.
What center is going out of gear
and immediately you know.
If you know how to correct it, you are cured.
You don’t have to pay any medicine -
for medicine or anything.
Specially for diagnosis,
I mean, normally
a patient is killed before he is diagnosed, isn’t it?
But in this the diagnosis is so easy.
On your finger tips you can say what's wrong with you,
what's wrong with others.
And you become a very dynamic personality.
You must be knowing, I am 71 years of age.
And practically I am travelling every day.
Tomorrow I am going to New Zeeland early in the morning,
having a program in the evening.
This morning I came, I have a program.
It is working out all right; I mean nothing wrong with Me.
But I never think I am travelling,
I think I am there. As I'm sitting here on a chair,
I am sitting inside the aeroplane.
So the first thing that happens to you really is
a new state of your mind
which we call as ‘thoughtless awareness’.
That happens,
say, if you are thinking,
you are thinking about the future or the past.
If I tell you, "Stand in your present" - you cannot.
Present, you cannot, you cannot.
You are either thinking of the future or of the past.
And the thought comes like that, rises,
falls, again comes up, falls, like that.
Now we are jumping on the cusps of these thoughts.
But with the ‘Kundalini’ awakening, these thoughts elongate
and in between them is what we call is the pause,
the ‘vilamba’ where there is no thought.
And you are absolutely aware.
No thought - you are absolutely aware
and you are without any thought,
in your peace. That is how you achieve your peace.
It's no use having
peace foundations which I've seen.
Many people who have peace foundations, peace awards,
they are so hot-tempered
that if you have to talk to them
better have a barge pole in between.
They get awards for peace and peace and peace,
such a lot of money they have collected for peace,
but where is the peace? There is no peace within.
So first you achieve your peace and you watch.
As I said when you get onto a boat you watch.
And when you see the problem you solve it better.
If you are in it, you cannot.
So also one must know that
this All Pervading Power
is the source of all the blessings.
So many blessings are showered on you.
People are writing to Me every day,
at least hundred letters
saying, "This has happened Mother.
You know, this is my blessing.
This was a miracle, that was a miracle."
Now miracle has lost its power in Sahaja Yoga.
"This happened to me, this
happened to my health, this happened to my
writings, this happened to my....
I was going in the plane and what,
how I was saved and how in the
accident I was saved" - so many of them.
They can’t explain.
So that we talk of God who blesses us.
But we never felt that way so directly as we feel it now.
So much so that...
I was ....I told somebody that you better compile them.
Within months' time, he said, "Mother they have come up to my head.
Now you tell me what to compile."
I said, "Forget it".
Because the ocean of blessings,
believe Me, is ocean of blessings.
It's the ocean of compassion and love.
It forgives.
Above all it is the ocean of forgiveness
and it forgives.
So, such a great power
which is itself so powerful,
this energy starts flowing through you.
And it is everything is tangible.
Now if I say that
diseases are cured -
we have four doctors now in Delhi University
who have got their MD (Master’s Degree) in Sahaja Yoga.
It does cure, also cancer,
it cures so many diseases
that I cannot in this short lecture tell you.
But one should come as a seeker of truth,
not just to get yourself cured.
Because you will be cured today,
again you will have another disease.
Best is to get your Self-Realization fully
and establish yourself.
Sometimes these connections are loose
so you have to establish.
And most evident
is that you cannot pay.
You cannot pay for living work.
How much do you pay to Mother Earth?
So you cannot pay.
Everybody thinks
that God has a bank or something and He,
He earns money out of us.
That's your headache. Money is your headache not His.
So you don’t have to pay anything.
It's not like an introductory lecture here
and then you go back and start
paying somewhere else - not that.
You cannot pay for Self-Realization.
You can pay for this hall, maybe.
But you can't pay for this Self-Realization.
And once you realize
that what is your worth and value,
you really give up nonsensical things.
Like you belong to this group, you belong to that group
and you follow this type of methodology or that.
But what have you got? Now face it up.
What powers have you got?
Tomorrow you can get cancer,
you can get anything.
One can become mad.
I mean they are saying in America within ten years
65 per cent will be schizophrenic. Can you imagine?
Already I think they are very immature people
and if they become schizophrenic, what will happen to this world?
And they are so important.
So there's something going wrong,
we have to understand and we have to correct it.
The greatest thing that happens to you
that you enter into the kingdom of God.
No more in the kingdom
of any country, but in the kingdom of God
where you are
drowned in joy,
you are swimming in joy.
What is joy?
Joy is not like happiness or unhappiness.
If your ego is pampered you feel happy
and if your ego is punctured you feel unhappy.
But joy is singular.
You just enjoy, anything,
anything nice, beautiful without desiring to have it.
Now this power that is within you
is the primordial Mother
who is being reflected in you as ‘Kundalini’.
Surprisingly in many religions they have not talked
of the primordial Mother.
Like they have the father, the son and the Holy Ghost.
They have never said a word about the Mother,
the feminine part of it - I don’t know.
Especially with Bible, I think Mr Paul must have done it.
Cause I don’t know why he is in the Bible. He never saw even Christ.
All such things have happened.
Woman is the ‘shakti’, she's the power
and if you treat her like that then she
becomes something else. She is no more a woman.
Is a saying in Sanskrit, ’Yatra naryastu pujynte,
tatra ramante devanta’ [Sanskrit to be checked].
Where the women are respectable or respected,
respectable -
they have lost the sense of respectability, of chastity -
there reside Gods.
So all these things also, these ideas of
condemning men or women or this and that and
making divisions and divisions in this division, is never there.
It's the synthesis,
internal synthesis of the whole human beings, is the whole
world is going to take place.
As you know Sahaja Yoga is now working  in sixty nations.
Of course India, it is all right, because we in India we have this
tradition.
They know what is Self-Realization.
But in Russia
where they never knew who is God.
You won’t believe
that I can’t hold a program on such a small scale there.
Minimum of minimum, sixteen to eighteen thousand people,
a very learned, very learned people.
See, they are scientists and they are doctors.
And the scientists - I started on
science - they said, "Mother we know science, everything.
Now we don’t want to know anymore science.
You tell us why are we on this earth
and you tell us about divine laws.
We don’t want to hear any more about science, had enough of it."
Can you imagine they have bestowed
a very great honor on Me?
St. Petersburg University.
I don’t know if he has told you or not,
but surprisingly,
it's one of the oldest universities
and there have been only ten members so far been
and Einstein is one of them, you see.
I said how, I felt very amazed, was...
I felt very shy with the whole thing.
They said, "Why Einstein? Einstein only worked on matter,
you are working on human beings".
I said, "I am not working; it is their own desire
is working, their own power is..."
So they are so sensitive, I can't understand.
Seventy per cent of
Russians are extremely
sensitive to spirituality - all Eastern bloc.
We have been busy with our materialism, with our choices this...
Where have we landed?
And when they had the coup I was there,
and I asked, "Aren’t you worried?
Aren’t you worried about this coup?" They said,
"Why? Why should we worry?
We are in the kingdom of God, why should we worry?"
Simple answer.
Such lovely people they are!
They had never known Me, they had
never seen Me, I mean...
And no other ‘guru’ could stay there,
you will be surprised, they threw out all of them.
So this sensitivity comes I don’t know from where.
How they have understood that
reality is the thing we have to achieve now,
that we have to become the ‘Spirit’, the ‘soul’,
and not anything else.
I was amazed the way these people have reacted!
I don’t want to put a sort of a competition
for you or a challenge for you.
But definitely there's something -
despite their very bad government and everything,
how they have maintained themselves, so introspective.
I wish
people all over the world understand
that there are problems.
Your children have problems.
Other day I was reading that
you cannot avoid small children, teenage children
who are not taking drugs.
Why do they take drugs?
They are seeking something.
And they can’t find it - out of frustration.
But with Sahaja Yoga
people have given up drugs overnight -
I assure you - there are some sitting here like that.
Overnight they gave up drugs
and whatever damage it had caused them on their brains,
they have been recovered.
All these indulgences
that have suffered,
because of the genes, I think, genes, must be the [cause]...
The other day I read about the genes that
there are two protective genes within us.
Surprisingly they said
that Asians have them all the time.
So they take time to take to something like that.
One gene
protects you from being violent, angry,
hot tempered, cruel
corrupt, all kinds of things.
We can call it the father, the sin against the father.
And the another gene protects you from indulging
into destructive things: sex,
too much of it, I mean this all kinds of rapes and so many
horrible things that we have never heard of such things
that are going on in these countries,
where they are supposed to be developed.
And also indulging into
drugs and alcohol and all that.
This protective gene
is being absolutely awakened again I have seen
after Realization.
Whether you are an Asian or not, makes no difference.
But also look at these Germans.
They say that they are the highest race, you know they feel.
They are the ones who killed small little children in the
gas chamber and they saw them suffering.
How could they do it?
And they are supposed to be a very,
what you call them,
higher races. Max Muller says
that they came to India and wrote ‘Vedas’.
How can they write ‘Vedas’, these people?
They are not afraid of God,
the way they have behaved...
But now Sahaja Yogis, the Sahaja Yogis Germans, you should say,
the gentlest people you could think of, gentlest.
They won’t hurt you, I mean, they are so beautiful.
So this ‘Kundalini’ is the one, She cleanses all that,
makes you peaceful, joyous and collective.
Now I hope you all get your Realization tonight.
Have faith in yourself - that's the main thing.
You must have faith that you will all get Realization.
I know there are people who have some questions also.
These questions now I can answer - for the last
twenty four years I have been doing this kind of work
all over the world.
So I can answer,
because it's just a mental acrobat - I have become quite an expert.
But it is of no use.
By that thing you are not going to get to your Realization.
What you have to ask really is your Self-Realization.
This power is the power of pure desire.
All other desires, as you know, in economics,
that in general that they are not satiable.
You may be aware, may not be aware, but this desire is within you,
is to become the Spirit,
to become one with this All Pervading Power
and that acts, works and helps you.
Everything is tangible.
You will be amazed how it works,
how it helps you!
The second thing I have to tell you
that it is not an individual thing.
It is not that, you can say, "Oh!".
First day you may feel very happy
and very relaxed, on top of the world.
That's not important.
You have to come to the collective.
You must understand
the whole knowledge about your internal being
and you have to be with the collective to grow.
Like if I take out one, say
nail out of my fingers, it will never grow.
So it's the
whole being, is a living organism.
Only thing, you have to pay
some time, as time... for it.
They will tell you how to be in meditation, not to do meditation,
how to be in meditation.
So first you get the state of ‘thoughtless awareness’ -
we call it as ‘Nirvichar Samadhi’.
And then the state you get is called as ‘Nirvikalpa Samadhi’,
where you get all the powers of raising others' ‘Kundalini’,
giving them Realization, curing, everything.
Those who have never come to the stage become orators.
See these musicians singing Indian songs.
Can you imagine this?
I mean, English speaking people, so hard
for Indian music, I tell you,
especially for Indian words.
But when they sing, ask Indians,
they will tell you they sing like Indians...
It was so difficult to teach even one word
to the Englishmen in India -
one word. And now you see this.
What has happened to them?
How suddenly they have picked up
all the rhythm, all the thing, which is very difficult.
So...
all these powers which are within you,
you have to manifest
and enjoy your virtues, enjoy your virtues.
You don’t become proud, but you enjoy them.
You enjoy your generosity,
enjoy your compassion,
never feel that you are
taking too much trouble, you are doing this and that, nothing.
You think of others all the time and you live in peace
and create peace all around.
We have these people from sixty
nations; they come to India once a year.
I've never seen them quarrelling, fighting,
doing anything against each other - never.
How do they live from all different countries, from Chinese
to Africans, from Africans to English
and from English to Americans and Australians - so many?
In Sydney we have twenty two centers.
I must say Australia is one of our
very great country which has really
very enthusiastically has taken to Sahaja Yoga.
And I am sure also you all will.
We have a great story in our ‘Puranas’ about Australia
which sometimes I'll tell you.
So may God Bless you!
And you be confident that you will have your Realization just now.
You don’t have to do much - just it will take ten minutes more.
But, of course, I respect your freedom.
If you don’t want to have your Realization,
you should leave the hall. I cannot force on you.
It is something it cannot be forced.
I respect your freedom out and out.
So, if you want to go, you can go.
All of you want Realization - it's very good.
Now one thing that should not upset you,
because I've seen people get upset if I tell them
that you have to take out your shoes.
I hope you won’t be upset with that.
You need not take out your socks but your shoes.
I does, sometimes.
Don’t have to say any mantras, nothing,
and you don’t have to concentrate also.
Please don’t try to concentrate.
Just keep yourself open.
Don’t force yourself into anything.
As I am saying, telling you that
it has become so easy now -
you don’t have to go to Himalayas
and stand on your head or anything.
You have to be very comfortable
and also
you should be very much pleasantly placed toward yourself.
Because as I said, you are human beings,
you are at the epitomy of evolution.
And you are...  have a right to have this,
because you are born at this time with a special purpose.
So in no way you should condemn yourself.
This is the first condition.
Have full confidence.
The another thing is you shouldn’t feel guilty at this time;
please don’t feel guilty for anything.
It has become a fashion now to feel guilty for anything.
I mean, even, if supposing you spill some
coffee you go on feeling guilty for your life.
What's this going on?
You must value yourself.
This life is not meant
for feeling bad for small, small things.
It is very great, it’s very precious.
So please don’t have any guilt.
But if you have, then you catch on this center here.
And this is such a dangerous thing because it gives you
what we call as angina.
It may give you spondylitis. It may give you very lethargic organs.
So very dangerous is to feel guilt.
So why feel guilty unnecessarily?
I tell you if you were guilty, you would have been in jail.
Now you are sitting here, so don’t feel guilty about
anything whatsoever.
I assure you, you are not guilty.
So, you have to really forgive yourself.
Now, the most simple condition is this
that you have to forgive everyone.
People might say it's very difficult to forgive.
But, whether you forgive or not - I am telling the logic,
now think about it - whether you forgive or not what do you do?
I don’t do anything.
But when you don’t forgive, then you play into wrong hands.
Those who have troubled you, tortured you,
are not feeling bad.
But you are the one who is torturing yourself.
But at this time, the problem is that this centre of Agnya
which is like this, absolutely constructed like this, like a cross -
it is on the optic chiasma -
and if you don’t forgive, it won’t open at all.
But if you forgive
it will definitely open and the Kundalini will pass.
So, at this juncture you as it is
troubled yourself so much,
at this juncture please,
please forgive everyone in general.
Don’t even think about them because it is a headache.
It's a real headache even to think of these people.
So you just forgive in general.
Of course we'll tell you how to do it. It's very simple.
Now to begin with you keep your eyes open,
I'll show you how you have to
yourself enrich your own centers - very simple.
So please put your left hand towards Me like this comfortably.
You have to be comfortable. That’s very important.
Please both the feet apart from each other
because these are two powers, left and right.
Put your left hand towards Me on your lap,
just like this.
And now
we have to use our left side with our right hand.
Now please put your right hand on your heart.
This is the center where the Spirit resides.
If you become the Spirit,
you become your own master in the light of the Spirit.
So please take your right hand
in the upper portion of your abdomen, on the liver.
All of you should do it, please.
This is the center of your mastery
which is created by great prophets
and seers and sages.
Surprisingly the center of pure knowledge
is lower here on the left hand side
in the lower portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
Whatever you have done, forget it, forget it.
Now raise your right hand in the upper portion of your abdomen.
Now on your heart.
Now in the corner of your neck and shoulders.
As I have already told you
when this center catches what is the problem.
Turn your head to your right, please.
It’s very catching today.
Please don’t feel guilty for anything. You must...
There.
Please take your right hand on top of your forehead across
and bend your head slowly.
We have to be humble about it, you see.
So here you have to forgive everyone in general.
Now take back your right hand on the backside of your head
and push back your head as far as possible.
Here,
without counting your mistakes,
without feeling guilty, just for your satisfaction,
you will have to ask forgiveness
from this All Pervading Power.
Now please stretch your hand or palm fully.
Now we go to the last center,
so please put the centre of your palm
on top of the fontanel bone area
which was a soft bone in your childhood.
Now please put down your head.
Now push back your fingers nicely
so there's a good pressure on your scalp.
Now put down your head and you have to move, move the scalp
seven times clockwise very slowly.
That’s all we have to do actually.
But remember you have to push back your fingers.
Now you can take out your spectacles
because you have to close your eyes.
It might help also your eyesight.
Please,
before closing I must tell you again
that please put both the
legs apart from each other
and the left hand
towards Me on your lap comfortably in any way that you like.
And then now place your right hand on your heart.
Here, I've told you resides the Spirit.
You have to ask Me
a very fundamental question about yourself in your heart.
So please,
ask in your heart, three times.
You can call me ‘Mother’ or ‘Shri Mataji’ whatever you like.
“Mother, am I the Spirit?”
Ask this question three times in your heart.
"Mother, am I the Spirit?"
Now, I've told you if you become the ‘Spirit’,
you become your own master.
So now take down your right hand
in the upper portion of your abdomen
on the left hand side.
Here,
you have to ask another fundamental question.
“Mother, am I my master?”
Ask this question three times.
I have already told you
that I respect your freedom.
And I cannot force
divine pure knowledge on you.
So now
please take your right hand
in the lower portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
Here,
you have to ask six times,
because this center has got six petals,
“Mother, please give me pure knowledge”,
or you can say, “Mother please give me divine pure knowledge”.
Whatever is divine is pure.
Six times.
As soon as you start asking
for pure divine knowledge,
the ‘Kundalini’ starts rising like a primule.
Now we have to
open our higher centers
by our self-confidence,
for the Kundalini to pass through.
Now, take your right hand -
you are working only on the left hand side -
in the upper portion
of your abdomen, on the left hand side.
Press it hard.
Now, here with full confidence, please say ten times,
“Mother, I am my own master”.
The Kundalini wants
you to show yourself confidence.
Please say it ten times.
At the very outset, I've told you
that the truth is that you are not this body,
this mind, this ego, these feelings,
these emotions, these conditionings,
but you are the pure Spirit.
So, now raise your right hand on top of your heart.
And here you have to say again with full self-confidence,
“Mother, I am the pure Spirit”.
Please say it.
Please say it twelve times,
“Mother I am the pure Spirit”.
I have already told you
that this All Pervading Power
is the ocean of knowledge,
ocean of compassion,
ocean of blessings, but above all it is the ocean of forgiveness.
And whatever mistakes you might have committed,
are easily dissolved by this ocean of forgiveness.
So forgive yourself.
And put your right hand
in the corner of your neck and shoulder
and turn your head to your right.
Here,
with full confidence again,
you have to say sixteen times,
“Mother, I am not guilty at all”,
“Mother I am not guilty at all”. Please say this.
Is very important because this center
is catching very much tonight here.
Now I have told you
whether you forgive or you don’t forgive, you don’t do anything.
But if you don’t forgive,
then you play into wrong hands
and torture yourself.
Especially at this moment, you should forgive
all of them, without thinking about them, in general,
so that your center opens out.
Otherwise at this important moment,
you may miss your Self Realization.
It's very important
to forgive all of them from your heart.
Not how many times, it's not the point, from your heart.
So now please put your right hand
on you forehead across
and bend your head as much as you can.
And here,
you have to say,
not how many times, but from your heart,
“Mother, I forgive everyone in general”,
from your heart. Please say it from your heart.
And now
please put your right hand on the back side of your head
and push back your head as far as possible.
Here, without feeling guilty,
without counting your mistakes,
just for your satisfaction,
you have to say,
not how many times, but from your heart,
“Oh, Divine Power,
if I have done any mistake,
knowingly or unknowingly, please forgive me”.
Just say it from your heart.
“O Divine Power,
if I have done anything wrong,
knowingly or unknowingly, please forgive me”.
Now
please stretch your palms.
Put the center of your palm
on top of your fontanel bone area
which is a soft bone in your childhood.
Here again,
I cannot force Self-Realization on you. You have to ask for it.
So now push back your fingers - that's important -
and please put down your head.
Now move your scalp with this pressure,
seven times, saying
seven times,
“Mother, please give me my Self-Realization”,
because I cannot force it on you.
Please push back your fingers.
Bend your heads; please push back your fingers.
Keep your eyes shut, till I tell you
please keep them shut.
Please take down your hands
and try to open your eyes slowly.
Push both the hands towards Me.
Now,
put the left hand towards Me like this,
bend your head and see with the right hand
if there is a cool or a warm breeze-like energy
is coming out of your fontanel bone area.
Now don’t doubt, because air conditioning is not in your head.
So just see for yourself. Some people think it is air conditioning.
Some people get it hot.
Some people get it far,
some closer,
but don’t put your hand on top of your head,
away from it.
See for yourself,
and if it is hot, that means you have not yet forgiven.
So please forgive also.
Now,
please put your right hand. Now, bend your head nicely
and see for yourself with the left hand
if there's a cool or a hot breeze-like energy is coming
out of your fontanel bone area.
You have to move your hand up and down, sideways also. All right.
Now do it with the left hand again.
Little further. Some people get it further.
Bend your heads, that is important, bend your heads.
Now,
please put both your hands towards the sky.
Push back your head
and ask anyone of these three questions,
three times, anyone of them.
You can say, ”Mother,
is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?”,
or ”Mother, is this the
All Pervading Power of Divine Love?”,
or ”Mother, is this the Ruh
or Paramchaitanya?”.
Ask anyone of these questions, three times.
Now, just come down.
Now please put your hands like this
and watch Me without thinking.
Just watch Me without thinking.
All those who have felt
hot or cold breeze on their fingertips,
on their palms or out of their fontanel bone area,
please raise both your hands.
My God! Look at that.
I mean most of you.
May God bless you!
It's tremendous.
Some didn’t get it, very few,
but most of you have got it.
In any case all of you should get it.
And those who haven’t got
should please later on come to the stage and they will do it.
But in the meanwhile
we'll try something else
for Realization
and maybe that might help a little bit.
[Marathi].
See this might help.
This will be only five minutes experiment. Let's see.
Which song will you sing?
[Marathi].
This is the song they are going to sing,
was written - Namadeva -
by Namadeva in the sixteenth century
who went then to Punjab
and Guru Nanak Sahib, you see,
knew who he was and He asked him to write
poems in Punjabi language.
And he has done such big compilation, I know that.
This guru
was ...
he was just a tailor.
And he went to see, meet
another realized soul who was a potter.
And when he went and saw the potter kneading
the clay with his feet, he just stood there, watching him.
The potter’s name was Gora Kumbhar.
Looked at him and what does he say,
in Marathi says that, but meaning
that, I came to see here
the "formless",
but it is "in the form".
I see it "in the form".
I mean only a saint can say it to another saint.
That’s what happened
that he went up to Punjab
where Guru Nanak Sahib
called him, looked after him and asked him and they made beautiful,
I mean such beautiful songs there are and they are in Granth Sahib.
They are all in Granth Sahib.
[unclear].
This is the folk song
which was written, which says, “Oh, Mother, give me my Realization.
‘Jogwa’ means Yoga - "Please give me that".
All that they sang,
all the time they have been singing, even now,
but they don’t know what it is.
And they are saying, "Oh, Ambe" - means the Kundalini -
"please rise, rise".
And with you can also clap. It will help a lot, I am sure.
This will definitely consolidate your Self-Realization.
It is a village song. It’s a rustic...
Now you feel. Just try to feel now. Let's see.
You must be feeling more, just see.
All right?
Now again, let us see how many of you have really
felt on your finger tips
or from your fontanel bone area or on your palms.
Raise your both the hands.
Oh! So, who didn’t feel before, have felt it - so many of you.
Thank you very much. May God look after you.
And also have wisdom
to respect your freedom,
respect your new status.
The real freedom is now.
So you respect your Self-Realization
and become a fully self-realized personality.
That will help everywhere.
May God bless you all!
Thank you very much, it was wonderful.
You all have paper to know where the centers are
and I hope...
What's it?
...and where you are going to have
a follow-on program.
All right?
Please, please come.
Do you know?
What's it? They haven’t got paper already?
SY: They have, Shri Mataji.
SM: They all have?
Where are you having follow on?
Yes, yes, but when are having the follow on, where?
You don't know.
SY: As you go on out
there are leaflets there which will tell you...
all you need to know about follow-up programs.
Ah, we've got one here, finally.
There's a series of seven programs
beginning on Monday 11th of April
then for six consecutive Thursdays commencing
Thursday 14th of April
at seven thirty to nine thirty
the [Far placed Room], Gorman House Art Center
Ainslie Avenue, Braddon.
And there's a little bracket here, and we will provide
light refreshments to follow.
Again remind you that all Sahaja Yoga programs
are completely free.
There, if you have any questions you want to ask about that
there's two phone numbers here that
will tell you where to ring.
It really tells you everything you want to know
and you can pick up one of these up
as you go out the door.
Now they've got a big supply there.
One other thing, if is anybody here
who - as soon as Shri Mataji's left -
if there's anybody here who has not felt anything tonight,
I would like to try.
There's probably a very good reasons, as we explained to you earlier.
You have these centers - you can also have blocked centers -
they may be quite easily to clear, might be quite easy to clear and then
[unclear].
Before you leave here tonight
if are any of you didn't feel anything
we'll do our best to make sure you do.
Thank you.
We're having first series of seven follow up programs
at Gorman House.