Good evening ladies and gentlemen.
Mataji is on the way and will be with you in short time.
I thought it opportune
few minutes to run through by a recapitulation
the various aspects of the mechanism that lies within us
for those people who have come for the first time - excuse me -
many who might not have heard the earlier lecture in which
various aspects of the chakras and the two sides of the subtle body,
the left and the right side and then the central channel
were discussed and explained.
And perhaps I can recapitulate a little on the
nature or quality of the chakra that
is expressed and the purpose
of Kundalini awakening and the process of Self-Realisation.
Many of you will be familiar with the
word "chakra" but for those who are not,
it's simply an energy center within us at a very subtle level
which expresses itself in the gross
as the plexuses of the autonomic nervous system.
It expresses itself in seven plexuses.
We have the Mooladhara chakra
which is part of that chakra
which we refer to as the Kundalini
and which lies in the gross body at the area
right at the tip of the sacrum bone, at the coccyx,
and so it relates to the pelvic plexus, the sacral plexus,
the coccygeal plexus and one other plexus that
is located in that area.
So the Mooladhara chakra
is that center which controls our sex,
it controls the whole organic structure
both muscular and [skeletonic] of that area
so controls such organs as the prostate gland
and in men and women of course the sex organs themselves
and so diseases that are related to this area
are very much a matter of
equipped investigating and fixing
damage which may have occured at the Mooladhara chakra.
Also the psychosexual problems as well
could be very much affected and corrected
by Sahaja Yoga at this center.
So Mooladhara chakra is the base,
it is in fact the center which Mother has nominated
as Australia's part in the whole mechanism of this universe.
At a very subtle level
countries play a part in the whole nature of evolution
and in a very incomprehensible way.
But as you develop in Sahaja Yoga you begin to understand
Australia has a very vital role
as the root. Mooladhara means
the root, the root that on which everything stands.
And so as you deepen in Sahaja Yoga you'll understand
what vital role we have to play.
In fact India is that center which is in the sacrum bone
which is really a part of Mooladhara chakra
and it's the triangular bone in which the Kundalini sits.
It's the center of purity, it's the center of holiness
it's the center in which the Kundalini itself resides
dormant and sleeping as the residual energy
which at an appropiate time in our evolution
spiritually has to rise.
So closely connected is the Mooladhara
and the Kundalini
and they are considered the first chakra.
The quality as I said, of the Kundalini is purity and holiness.
The quality of the Mooladhara chakra is innocence
and out of innocence comes wisdom
and with that wisdom comes obedience.
All of these are qualities of the Mooladhara chakra,
which we find beginning to manifest
as this Kundalini energy begins to rise and purifies these centers.
This is the center which gets so badly damaged by
all sorts of negative forces which due to our
licentious life due to all sorts of
rather bizarre attitude towards sex,
all sorts of impure relationships,
all sorts of the unholy relationships
which can and do damage that center.
It's a center which is our chastity, both in men and women,
and if our chastity is assaulted,
then this center becomes quite badly damaged.
It can be fixed, of course. This is the whole point that
Self-Realization, that each of these centers
can be managed in such a way that any damage can be neutralized
and in such a way that the spiritual ascent can be a growing,
tremendous force within each one of us.
But the damage is there especially in the west.
Mother has often said that this center in Mooladhara
is the most damaged center in the west,
just as in India this center of Nabhi chakra
is the most damaged in the east.
If I say to you that the Mooladhara
damage represents a sin against the Mother,
the holiness, the purity, then you might begin to understand.
If I say that this center here,
where the damage has occurred in the east,
is in a way a sin against the Father
the all protective Father, the Father that looks after everything,
then when we see so much corruption
and so much graft and so much of this abuse in the east
we know that they must surely therefore doubt that
how the Father will in fact provide all that is necessary.
So we've gone about damaging our Mooladhara chakra in the west
and of course people in the east, through their corrupt activities,
through their acquisitive attitudes,
through their materialistic obsessions
have damaged so badly this center
which is referred to as Nabhi chakra.
Getting back to the Mooladhara chakra you noticed
how is connected to the left hand channel which rises
as you probably read in some of the readings [today],
as the Ida nadi,
as the left hand side of the subtle body.
And it rises and it becomes what we call the superego.
The next chakra of Swadisthan
is yellow, the yellow one. Just wait till Mother comes.
So this Swadisthana chakra, as Mother has explained,
it's the creativity within us,
it's the center which gives us our projections,
it's the center which makes us capable of thinking
and rationalizing and working things out.
It's also the source of the pure knowledge of the Divine.
It's also the place where all pure knowledge,
all the pure conditionings take place and settle themselves
in such a way that we become
ready for our spiritual ascent.
It's also the center which gets very badly damaged
by impure knowledge and by too much thinking,
and too much planning and too much analyzing and rationalizing.
You notice how it's connected on the right hand side
by this yellow channel which
is called as Pingala nadi and terminates in this yellow balloon
in the opposite side which constitutes our ego.
This ego is our rational brain, it's the part of our being which
thinks and mantains and analyzes.
It's also the side of our brain, if we like to put it that way,
which seeks power, ambition, wants to dominate
and in its worst form, aggress others.
So in a way this two channels have been there for our use
in our spiritual ascent but in so many ways we often abused them
by misusing the left side
through too much emphasis on emotional life,
too much emphasis on worship without the connection,
too much emphasis on our conditioning,
too much emphasis on using spirits,
all the things which we've talked about in the preceeding lectures.
Whereas on the right side we've damaged
those aspects of the chakras to the right
which relate to our projections, our overthinking,
our rational thoughts, our dominating attitudes
and all of those things which have
created so many imbalances in the chakra.
Because the chakra is a pure, vital center of energy,
intact and in its own way pure and untraveled.
What we do to it by imbalances of either to the left or to the right
we cause a constriction of or even sometimes a detachment
of part of that center in such a way that
we can even end up with such diseases as cancer.
Cancer is in fact a complete
brake down, a construction which is lead to a separation
of one aspect of the center, which in term causes
a separation in the cellular structure of the body
and of course run away cancer.
Is the uncollective, if you like,  expression of that damage.
Then we have the Nabhi chakra which is the centre, as I told you,
which is often quite badly damaged in the east
as much as the Mooladhara chakra
is the one which we damage in the west
so too the Nabhi chakra is the one which due to
too much emphasis on money, too much graft and corruption,
too much doubting that God the Father who look after us
and provide for us in every way
and so therefore damaging this center.
This is the problem of the Nabhi chakra.
But the essence of the Nabhi chakra relates to our evolution
it relates to the principle of the family life,
it relates to the means by which we evolve in other words.
Family structure is an integral part to the evolution
and so if Mother appeared to emphasize family life last evening,
if She appeared to emphasize motherhood,
if She appered to emphasis the quality of love within motherhood,
not child bearing but motherhood,
then understand what She is saying -
we have to evolve to higher beings.
When we move from the human stage,
when we move from the animal stage into the human stage
we knew that we had to move higher and higher.
Now we've reached that epitome of evolution as a human being
and we have to now reach the higher levels going further
of becoming a spiritual being.
Now if She is here to do the job,
if She is here to takes us through that next stage in our evolution
just keep yourself in that frame of mind where
it's a spontaneous happening that has to take place.
It's the terminal point, if you like, in the principle of evolution
as epitomized by this center here.
And so if She speaks forcefully
about the qualities of a loving mother,
if She speaks strongly about the nature of family life
and how it is broken down in the west
and if She openly admits that some aspects of Indian way of life
are not quite right,
but predominantly there are many areas which are
tremedously important and could be well emulated in our country
please understand She is not supporting
just in a nationalistic way the Indian way of life,
She is supporting those eternal qualities of evolution
which thank God had been retained in that country which is still,
potentially and in reality, the greatest spiritual country
that's now in existence in this world.
So this center is the center of our evolution
and it epitomizes the quality of joy through family life,
of satisfaction. It relates to our material wellbeing.
So if we don't have a good Nabhi chakra
quite often we'll have problems with money.
Or the other way around if we have problems with money
or are constantly obsessed about material things,
so too we will have a very damaged Nabhi chakra.
And of course all the organs that relate to this centers
have to be taken into account.
If you are suffering diseases
of the organs of say the stomach, the liver,
the spleen, the pancreas, the kidneys all of these areas,
it is either relating to the Nabhi chakra or the Swadisthana chakra.
And then the heart chakra in a word is the center of security,
the security within us.
In the center it's that center of security
of knowing with certitude that Almighty God,
through the quality of the Mother of the universe, Jagadamba,
that She will provide that nothing can assail you,
nothing can bring you down, that you become fearless,
that no matter whether you are a king or whether you are a beggar,
that nothing, nothing can assail you,
nothing can break the confidence that you are a human being
and that the Mother of the universe is looking after you.
That's the quality of the center heart, the sacred heart.
Then we have the left heart which relates to
the quality of motherhood,
that security again which a baby must feel in the womb,
which a child feels in the arms of the mother.
It's the quality of security, of that caliber.
And so if there's a dis-relationship between the mother
and those other members of the family
or you and your attitude towards your mother is not harmonious,
then this left heart center will be in trouble.
And so too on the right hand side is the center of the father.
the father is the protector, the father is the one who takes care
in a very firm, forthright way, as epitomized by Shri Rama.
The great incarnation of Vishnu who came on the earth to show
just how important it is to have that quality of fatherhood.
Responsibility to the society, responsibility to the family,
responsibilty to his wife and to his children.
And so this is the center in which the father becomes
that secure example within us
wherein we feel and those around us feel
that absolutely nothing can assail us, because we epitomize
that quality of fatherhood which gives that security.
And so diseases related to the lungs, the heart
and many other subtler, smaller organs in that area
are related to this center.
Then we have Vishudhi chakra about which Mataji spoke last night.
This is the center of the throat.
This is the center of Shri Krishna,
the next incarnation of Shri Vishnu.
And His incarnation was that of
showing us that we are part of the whole,
showing us that there is an All-pervading God,
showing us that we have to realize the Akbar, the Great.
Allah hu Akbar. God is great.
And we have to know with certitude that this All-Pervading God
is the one who gives us that spiritual ascent.
We have to have self-esteem, neither loving ourselves too much
nor loving ourselves too little.
And so it's the center of self-esteem.
On the one side if we are feeling guilty
or if we are feeling the desire
to constantly allow others to aggress us and to dominate us
we'll have problems on the left hand side.
If we are in fact loving ourselves too much
and not reflecting the Akbar,
if we are loving ourselves too much then we aggress others,
we become dominating, we use our language badly,
we are often very, very sharp with our tongue and very hot tempered.
This gives us problems on the right Vishuddhi and this may manifest
in most of you as stresses and tensions of the neck muscles,
it may relate to thyroid problems,
it may relate to coughs and colds in the throat and the bronchitis
and so it goes on. I need not to go far.
Then finally, not finally but second, last chakra
is the Agnya chakra which is known
possibly to many of you as the third eye.
This is in fact the center of the lord Jesus Christ.
It's the holiest of holy center
that it was opened two thousand years ago
by the lord Jesus Christ and His Mother Mary.
It's a center which establishes within our brain,
within our enlightened awareness the principle of Spirit.
It's the center which exemplifies
the purpose of Christ's incarnation
that not only that we had to crucify this ego,
which was so prevalent, but that the Spirit had to ascent,
that we are not this physical body, we are the Spirit.
And in order to achieve this we have to be forgiveness.
We have to be forgiveness first to ourselves
and to everyone around us.
This was the message of the lord Jesus Christ and His ascent
in the sense of His resurrection is the message at the Agnya chakra.
And so as the Kundalini passes through all these centers
and comes to Agnya chakra,
what actually happens is that these two
useful devices, up to this point,
these two useful balloons called ego and superego,
actually become absorbed, they become sucked in
at the time when the Kundalini rises and enlightens this center.
The egos are karmas
and the superego all of those sins so called
that we've committed in the past, all get sucked in
and so the message of Christ
that He died for our sins becomes a reality.
But until the Kundalini rises and passes this center,
this sucking in process cannot happen.
What Christ said cannot become an actualization
until you get your Realization,
until the spiritual ascent takes place.
So it's fundamental that this energy of the Holy Spirit within us,
this Kundalini should rise,
enlighten the centers and give us our second birth.
And where is the second birth take place?
It takes place at the Sahasrara.
So many times we've read of
so many things which relate to the top of the head.
So often we've puzzled ourselves over the nature
of this fontanel bone in a baby which pulsates
and which closes at the age of twelve and becomes calcified.
Thoughtful people who pondered on this - why is it calcified ?
What's the subtle reason for this?
And in what way does it disconnect us from the Divine?
The way in which we were born as a child.
This is the center which has been opened
in this era, in ths age, in your lifetime by Shri Mataji.
This is the center which had to come.
This is the center where the Spirit makes its final ascent
and put you in touch with
and you become part of the All-Pervading God.
And so when this center opens
you get the connection with the Divine.
What Christ said about being born again becomes an actualization.
It's not a self-certification, it's an actual experience
in which you begin to feel this energy
which is dormant and that is sacrum,
manifesting at the top of the head.
You feel it as a cool wind emitting from the top of the head and
as if blowing upwards onto the palm of the hand.
And you begin to feel it blowing onto the hands.
You feel it in fact as a fountain of energy
which flows down over your body and you enjoy the bliss.
At first you may feel heat, you may not feel that bliss or joy
but increasingly as the Kundalini rises
and you develop your Realization you begin to know the Brahma,
you begin to know the energy of God.
You become all of those things
which all the great incarnations said you had to become.
You become the Spirit.
And so if Mother is the One who can do the job
we shouldn't be too circumspect about it.
If She is the one who can raise the kundalini in thousands
and can convince a rather skeptical person like myself -
when I first got my Realization,
not by intellectual or rational reasoning
but by the simple joy on the faces of the people
who gave Me the Realization,
by seeing the transformation in their life,
by watching physical diseases disappear
in a relatively short time, quite often instantly.
I humble myself down and I say, "Perhaps She is this,
perhaps She is this, perhaps we are in the myths
at a time in our evolution when
a great incarnation is here on the earth.
Perhaps there are forces which very naturally at that time,
come to delude us and to mislead us
and I have to be careful about but [more than everything]
I have to be a little bit logic when say, "what if She is?"
So many people might
go away from a meeting like this and say
"Perhaps this is blasphemy".
Of course you are free to make up your mind but I urge you
to ask the question in your heart,
ask the question on the Kundalini, because you have that power.
You can put your hands up to Her
and if it's emitting those cool vibrations
then that cool vibration
is the flow of the energy of Almighty God which is telling you
that before you is sitting Truth.
You have to reach a logical conclusion but more than that
you have to experience something
which settles your mind at rest and says
"I have achieved the ultimate".
If Shri Mataji is the incarnation of the Holy Spirit,
and so many thousands of people around the world
now recognize that She is,
then is it right that we keep it in the dark?
Is it right that we don't announce it?
Is it right that perhaps in five years time when
so many people have reached that level of suffering
and confusion that it's almost an impossible task to retrace,
is it right that we withdraw and hold back and don't tell you?
In fact many of you who are so critical,
not in this audience but around the world,
will say "Why didn't you tell us? Why didn't you tell us?
If only you've told us we at least could have
made our own mind up and satisfied ourselves."
So if we declare
and utter
the very, very clear statement that Shri Mataji
is in our opinion the incarnation of the Holy Spirit,
see it through both sides.
If you want take it as a hypothesis.
If you feel the vibrations and are secure in that knowledge
that knowing who Mother is in your heart, enjoy it.
But [either] way whether you remain open as a scientist
keep it as a hypothesis,
or you feel Mother in your heart and you enjoy
the beginning of your final spiritual ascent,
whatever it is, don't be too hasty.
Don't judge, because it can [unclear] you
somebody who has never quite achieved
the final, the ultimate, that they wanted to achieve.
We often wonder how to speak to people too,
to arrive at logical conclusions.
It's always a difiicult thing, I think you must understand.
If Mataji is this being?
How to put it in such a way that
A who reached those logical conclusions
and B to don't allow the intellect to be, create such a barier
that it prevents you from the spiritual ascent?
Christ has said as well, you know,
that "I will send you a Counselor, a Comforter,
the Holy Spirit who will teach you all things."
If Mother is that,
what is She doing when She is teaching you all things?
What is She doing  when She is comforting you by
purifying these centers and by advising you
and couselling you so sweetly?
If She is the energy of the Holy Spirit,
God's manifestation, the power of God Almighty
then allow it to take place.
These things have been predicted so often
in Scriptures, which possibly many of us haven't read.
I 've now seen them, so many people have seen them around the world.
The Markandeya Purana,
in which is clearly stated that Adi Shakti had to take birth...
Yes, Mataji has asked me to introduce this in this way.
Yes, because you see, there is a little problem, all right?
I'll speak, I'll speak to you, I'll meet you all. May God bless you.
Have patience. Little bit he has to talk. It's important. All right?
The Markandeya Purana has clearly said Adi Shakti has to take birth.
So many Hindus who know this. Mohammed spoke of the Mehdi.
[unclear] for those who speak out of it.
There have been predictions,
there have been predictions which clearly said
and even to the point which the date was given
whether it's [unclear] people,
such as Jeane Dixon, or the real seers
such as happened two and three and five thousand years ago,
in which it was said that
at this time, at this very time
there would be a great Mahayogi
as it was said, who would take birth,
to lead people out of this confusion
and to give them Self Realization,
so that they in fact today will know their own master.
so that they could heal their own bodies,
so that you could close the hospitals.
All these things have been said in the Scriptures.
The Devi Bhagavatam, the Markandeya Purana.
Such great writers like Adi Shankaracharia said,
"Only by the grace of the Mother
can Self Realization be attained".
In other words even gurus themselves
have received the Self Realization at the Feet of the Holy Mother.
This is something which even in conventional catholicism although
unfortunately so much of conventional catholicism
is considered now to be rather,
I don`t know quite what word to use. But
rightful attitude within the church,
that so many Catholics believe,
strongly in the role of the Mother, the role of the Virgin Mary
and Her importance in the whole of life`s Christ.
It`s clearly been said but
as Mother has said Christ could not say very much at that time.
So I want you just to
think about this a little, but
when you reach the conclusion that perhaps She may be It,
perhaps, She may be It, give yourself a chance.
So many people are offended by
a direct state. It challenges the ego too much.
And when that happens,
what occurs is that a big barrier has placed across, at this point
and your Kundalini cannot rise. You cannot experience it.
So what you should do is desire from your heart
that "Mother, please give me my Realization."
Say it humbly, ask for it, and if it occurs
let it grow as an experience and as it grows
you can then find out the truth for yourself, in a very precise way
using the vibratory awareness which Mother will teach us.
At the session on Sunday, when we come
we will show you how to use the vibratory awareness,
how to balance up taking balances on the two sides.
But for now get the experience established.
Don't fall into the trap which so many of us are falling into
of creating a barrier at this point which prevents us
from even achieving the state of Self-Realization.
It`s the love of God, it's the energy of the Almighty God.
It's the pure bliss, it's the consciousness and it's the truth.
And you have to achieve it.
All the scriptures have said it so if
you have to achieve it, and if Mother can do the job,
just enjoy it and allow to become a spontaneous happening
in your own awareness and know it consciously
so that with your eyes closed
you begin to feel this vibration in the hand.
We switch the air conditioning off at the end of program as we know
so that you can really
tell your brain to go to sleep for a little while and just feel it.
This is what it is.
Ladies and gentlemen, sorry to take it so long but
I just wanted to
invite you to be a little more open,
because we will be the ones that are to play.
If we didn't tell you who Mother was, and you walked away from it,
if you are a genuine seeker. So we have to say it to you.
Ladies and gentlemen, Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi!
To all the seekers of truth I bow.
I must say Dr. Warren has done a good job.
Perhaps you don't understand that the situation is quite
different in the western countries.
I don't have to have any introduction in India,
nor anybody has to give any apologies all the time, you see,
trying to convince getting this,
that into the whole argument
to prove that I'm the truth and that I'm genuine,
that there is no hanky panky about Me.
It's very embarrassing for Me to say it.
And the background is like this, when I came to Australia this time
from all over the world, all the Sahaja Yogis who are in the west -
we have many in every country -
and they have wrote that
"this time Mother must say who She is, is important.
Because the questions like this, "Then how can You do it?
How can it be easy? Are You the one who is doing?
All kinds of questions come in.
And I just told them, "Please don't do it. It's not easy
for a western mind to accept it". You see, they'll all come on you.
And yesterday also I told you the same thing.
And it was accepted by many people
because they felt the cool breeze.
They did feel the cool breeze coming out of their heads
but some did not.
And because they did not feel it, they challenged
and they were angry about it
Now, the position is like this
that so far if your mind has been guiding you properly
there was no need for Me to say anything.
We are living in the atmosphere of great confusion.
Tremendous confusion exists.
We don't know what is good what is bad.
Some people say that it's better to have an unmarried life.
Some say it's better to have the married life,
some say it's better to keep the children out in the school,
some say it is not.
The governments don't understand whether communism is all right
or capitalism is all right. Economics is dwindling.
They don't understand what is happening.
So the result of all our enterprises is very confusing.
And we don't understand really what is right and what is wrong.
So we use whatever we think right, as the right.
But whatever we think as right,
is it coming from something absolute or from relative,
because we are conditioned people?
For a lady who, say, comes from a catholic church
she wouldn't like Me to tell her that
I am the Comforter or I am the Holy Ghost. She won't like it.
But I would ask her one question:
supposing if I am how will she recognize Me?
If supposing tomorrow Christ comes here
how would she recognize Christ? It's a very apologetic, you see,
low based type, which really I didn't want to start it,
because it takes you down to such a level
that you just don't want to talk about it.
But it happens with the western people.
You have to stoop down too low to convince them who you are.
Of course you are not going to crucify Me, I know,
but you'll crucify yourself if you don't accept it that's the point.
Because I have a concern,
I have to do this job
and I have to do it with great care that
you are very great seekers
you have been seeking truth for ages now
and the time has come for you to get it.
And this is the time your western ego stands up and says that
"How can that be? Why it is You? You see.
So I said, "All right, you do it, I don't mind.
if you can do it I do nothing.
The problem is this ego is such a
thing that we are never aware of it
we are never aware that it's a ego that is working it out.
Like Hitler. When he destroyed people,
he was never aware that he was doing it just to satisfy his ego.
He thought that what he was doing was right.
And all of them who do such things always believe that it is right.
So this is a problem. And then the question comes in that
"Mother you might be also doing it out of ego".
Possibly. One can say. That could be so.
But what is my gain out of that ego, is nothing.
As it is you know I'm a very happily married,
woman of a very rich family,
I don't need anything from you, I am in a very great position.
But why am I concerned is the point.
Now put your mind on this position,
"that just now we do not ask any questions".
"Let's have it first of all, let have our Spirit.
If She is saying "I'm going to give you the Spirit"
all right, have it. No harm.
Afterall I have done no harm to anyone so far.
There's none who can say
that I have harmed anyone or somebody has lost.
Today with me there was a little child with a limbed hand.
The child could never have been cured
through medicine as it is, could never have.
All the life the child would have had the limb like that.
But within ten minutes with Sahaja Yoga the child was cured.
It's a fact, I'm telling you the truth.
But that doesn't mean that you should believe Me.
But by believing Me you are not the loser.
On the contrary it is just the other way round.
The whole situation is the other way round thing.
It's like the river Ganges is flowing
and you have to fill your pitchers.
Now, they don't expect Me to fall at your feet.
"All right, you take your Realization". It's too much.
But I've done one thing, that the way other incarnations
came and talked - human beings are not easy people,
they are really complicated,
full of their ego. They live with their ego,
morning till evening they float within their ego.
So they are not going to accept anything
unless and until somehow you bring it down
to a point where they receive their Realization.
This is exactly My father told me
that "You have such and such vision, You have to do it.
But don't write about it and don't talk about it
till you have found out an en masse method
by which you can give en masse Realization. This is My job
for which I have come on this earth.
And he told Me that "If you write a book,
it will become another Bible.
If you say anything it will become another saying
and people will just use it to pamper their ego".
And they have crucified all the people like this.
Now while in India you see people understand
because they are educated as I told you.
There's this book
which is a prediction written by Brighmuni who is the,
I should say the originator of astrology in India,
thousands of years back.
And he wrote a book called Nadi Granth,
which was the original book he wrote, in which
he has mentioned about these things happening.
Was revised 300 years back
and was said that in 1970 this work will start by someone
and I started my work in 1970.
Because you do not know, it is so describing details
how to recognize the Holy Ghost.
Christians don't know much about Holy Ghost at all.
I would say that they don't want to know also.
They have never read any other book
to know what is the Holy Ghost is.
But there are all the descriptions in details given
as to how to recognize the Holy Ghost.
But I must admit that this work
I have never done before of giving en masse Realization.
This is the first time I have been able
successfully to do this job which I have to work out.
It's a great penance I have to go through
by which I learned
what problems human beings have,
their permutations, combinations, everything.
And they are so many that now you see you have seven chakras.
Seven chakras and three gunas so tewnty one.
Then raised to power, say all these centres
have got different, different number of petals
raised to power all these
you have permutations and combinations
so you can imagine how many permutations and combinations you have.
So first you have to be brought to the basic points,
you see, where the problem is, to the basics,
and then to realize what can one do
to take the Kundalini
out, here,
by which method one can do it. It's a technique.
It's the technique of the divine laws you see.
This is too subtle a work within us but the movement
of the Kundalini stops at the first point
or at the second point or at the third point.
Now what is the method by which you can raise it, you see?
Now this I had to first find out what's the problem
with the human beings are. So I did not only study human beings
but I also went to all these horrible bhoots
to find out what they are doing to you,
how they are. Very close I went to find out
how they are spoiling your chakras.
Then the drugs I studied with some people
who had taken drugs and all that, what is going wrong with them,
what is spoiling them.
Then there are people who had problems, physical problems.
To study the physical problem was very easy for Me
because I know what is this physical body is,
but I did not know what you say it in the medical terminology
because these are your words not of God.
So I studied medicine for that. Then the psychologists,
I thought the psychologists are creating another problem.
They are not understanding what they have to say.
Except for you, I would say the rest of them were half baked.
something wrong with them. So then I realized
that they are treating people who are pathologically
upset or who are pathological cases.
And they do not know how to protect themselves
from these pathological things you see,
and they just handle the situation as they have.
It's like putting your hand into the hole of a snake, you see
And then they are getting a bite and because of that you see
they become exactly the same what their patients are.
And then they start universalizing
that particular pathological problem to the whole world.
That a person, they meet a man who is a pervert,
say for example himself Freud was a perverted man
He had relations with his mother.
So first he must have met somebody.
I give him all the chance you see.
Maybe he is born like that I don't know
but he must have met someone whose mother
must have had bad relation or something like that
and he must have treated this fellow.
By treating him he must have got that upon himself.
Now he made it an universal
truth for everyone that everybody has this within them.
It's absolutely wrong.
It's an absolutely wrong staff.
I mean in India if you tell anybody
they'll laugh "God, we have nothing to do".
There was a gentleman, Freud fellow, he came
and started criticizing, something he wrote, an article,
and people wrote him back answer saying that Now you the Freudian,
you go back to England. You are not wanted here.
He's an Indian but they said,
We don't want you here.We understand all these things better."
Because traditionally Indian mind has understood so many things,
and this trial and error method that we know
that this is all nonsense people are talking.
But because you people are naive and great seekers,
moreover there is also ego problem,
I have to balance it somehow and that's why
today, because I told Dr. Warren that I had told you
that I don't want to tell these people and you were the people
who telephoned to Me and called to Me that Mother should be clear,
and we did it and there is an opposition. So now you pay for it.
And that's why he wanted to make an apology for everything.
There's nothing to be apologetic. There's nothing to be apologetic.
It is for you to receive it.  Is the, position is very different.
It is you who have to ask for it. It's My...
No gain for Me. I have nothing to gain from you.
I have to give you something. And when I have to give you something
then you have to get it yourself and not to doubt another.
What will you get by doubting?
What are you going to get out of it?
So first of all to put down your mind in proper shape
because it was too much of a shock yesterday to many people.
[Best done] there are people who said that "All right,
today let Warren talk about these things and pacify them", you see.
It's like pacifying a son-in-law who is angry.
All right, so this has worked out. I hope you people understand
that there is no need to feel disturbed.
We have to get our Realization.
On the contrary if you do not get it you must worry about it.
That's not a good thing.
You must all get your Realization.
Now this is the seventh chakra we were talking about.
Seventh chakra is the chakra where the limbic area
in the brain, you see the limbic area is there.
This limbic area is covered with all the seven chakras.
For example if you start from here
from the back where the protrusion is there,
is the Mooladhara chakra which is down here.
So when you people have problems with sex,
say, a person who has led a perverted sex life,
gradually, this chakra gets influenced
and a person becomes mentally soft, as you can say.
He starts getting you see hallucinations and
sometimes he loses his balance also.
[Descend] because the effect is on the brain.
So I'm just trying to explain to you these seven chakras
around the limbic area which is the Sahasrara,
the last chakra, and how it affects.
So now the second chakra is Swadisthana
which is round that Mooladhara, here at the back.
Now Swadisthana is the chakra
which as he said on the gross
looks after your liver, kidney, spleen, pancreas
and your uterus, on the gross, on the physical level.
Also is responsible for
giving you more creativity
future thinking and also can be damaged
if you do, overdo that
or if you try to take to something
that is unauthorized as God is concerned.
So it affects both ways.
Now when this happens what are the problems, let's say.
First problem comes in that when you
the central portion is out of gear
this center shows results on the brain here.
And the effect on the brain is that,
first supposing you are suffering from diabetes
- take one example of diabetes - your eyes will be affected.
You have seen diabetic people go on losing their eyesight gradually.
And they become big because it is on the optic lobe
sitting here and controls the optic lobe.
So when you get diabetic
that oppression of this centre
or you can say the lethargy
of this center,
makes your eyes week gradually
because there is something wrong in the void.
something wrong with the  Swadishtana chakra.
I will tell you in short, because seven chakras we have today.
So now the higher chakra than that is the Nabhi chakra.
Nabhi chakra is left and right on your head here at the back, here.
Now this is the centre of, as he said, of your seeking.
and you are seeking money
or you are seeking power or you are seeking love,
all these things get indicated in this part of your head.
And that's how the Nabhi chakra gets caught.
Now you can see when the Kundalini rises, also in the brain.
You can find out what chakra is catching because that is the portion
if you put your hand you'll find is still, still very hot.
The chakras which are all right, that portion in this line,
where the, all the centers are placed is soft.
But where the chakras are wrong you can see it there.
Now this is tallied also that you feel, on the left hand,
this is the Nabhi chakra's finger or the right hand.
Some sort of a sensation of burning, maybe numbness
or whatever it is to show that these chakras are out.
Also you can see that the Kundalini is rising
that the Kundalini has stopped there
and She is moving here and there
and you see the pulsation like that.
So it's all tallied up. You can see for yourself clearly.
So this is the Nabhi chakra which is very important
because it is your seeking. So it has to be put in balance.
After that comes the higher chakra, called the heart.
Is a very important chakra.
Because this chakra is placed in the center here.
This is actually is the fontanel bone area just in the center, here.
Now the pulsation of the Kundalini
is felt here first when She has not pierced through.
But when She pierces then you start feeling actually
the cool breeze coming out of that portion.
But in the beginning maybe due to the little friction
between the Kundalini and this portion of the head
maybe you might feel hot or because of other things also
inside the chakras.
But gradually Kundalini corrects you and you find
the cool breeze coming out of your head.
So this is a very important chakra is heart chakra.
Now this heart chakra is so made you'll be amazed,
that heart is the one which has the Spirit,
also it has the center heart,
which is the Mother's.
So this chakra is the most important chakra
in the last happening of the Kundalini.
Unless and until this breaks through it won't work out
So motherhood is important,
motherhood in your temperament and motherhood as a blessing to you,
all these things play a big part.
And that's why motherhood is very important
that you have to respect motherhood.
Freud did just the opposite, of insulting.
I mean this is anti-God activity
because the Kundalini won't come up
if you have no respect for motherhood.
Maybe your mother may be a bad woman, all right, but in general
you must have respect for motherhood.
Or if you are a mother or if you are a woman
you must have respect for yourself as a mother.
The men should also have respect for mother.
Motherhood is a very important part of Sahaja Yoga,
where you find that the heart chakra
is this called as the Brahmarandra.
Randra means the hole
and the Brahma is the divine power that is spread out.
So this is the hole which has to be broken
or is to be pierced through
and this is what is the actualization of baptism.
This is what is the real baptism.
It is not just artificial that anybody can put hand on your head
and say: "All right, now you are a Christian" or "You are a muslim"
or "You are a Jew". It is not so.
This has to actualize within you.
Now this happens when it comes up through this one.
In front of that here, if you find,
is a part of the Nabhi chakra a little bit here,
you can feel it sometimes.
But here actually is the Vishuddhi chakra, if you see.
This is the Vishuddhi chakra.
This is the Vishuddhi chakra means at this point
your throat is controlled.
But it is the center where this Vishuddhi chakra
Shri Krishna becomes the primordial Being, the Akbar.
So when you are not one with the whole,
when you are detached from the whole, this becomes very problematic.
Now, I have to tell you something about cancer,
because it is threatening the world today.
Is very simple, can be cured.
A little bit I will have to tell you about cancer,
how it develops in a person,
whether he may be a good man or a bad man is not the point.
As it is cancer is built up every moment and is broken up
because when the sympathetic nervous system
which is looked after by these two powers within us
goes into overactivity,
like the left and the right, the movement is so strong
that it breaks the chakra, and the chakra moves apart.
And the relationship with the whole,
which is here with the whole, with the Medulla oblongata
gets disconnected.
Then anything on the left or the right,
it is triggered by something, which I have told you before.
This triggering when it takes place, it really gets seperated
and the cells start growing on their own,
they become malignant, means they are separated from the whole.
Any man who behaves like that,
who is broken from the whole, who doesn't understand of the whole,
is a malignant person.
So the malignant cell starts growing in such a way
that that cell whenever it touches another cell,
that also becomes malignant.
You may develop a nose very big,
or ears very big, or a tongue very big,
not related to the general growth of your body.
So the controlling point of the whole is lost.
Now [this is come] when it starts, you see, this [thing] really
becomes a very big obstacle here, the Vishuddhi chakra.
Is very important.
But when it starts developing here the whole,
what you call, the pressure, comes up here,
which starts spreading on the sides.
Moreover to add to the problem, to add to the problem,
if you have been to wrong gurus, and wrong people
your void gets caught up, your void, the ten centers.
These are the ten centers here.
So we have eleven centers
and these are the destroying forces of Shri Kalki,
means our Lord Jesus Christ when he's going to come again,
on the white horse, is this one.
And this is called as sambar.
At the equal level of the head
and here there are eleven forces
which are the destructive forces which come into play.
Sometimes this side is more or sometimes this side is more,
But when it starts working out, it starts destroying you
and you may get any disease
which is really destructive gradually to you.
It can work out as any incurable diseases,
any disease that eats you off, all those things will start
and this portion of the head is a very important one.
You are not supposed to bend this before anyone.
You should not bend this before anyone,
but when you have found out the right person, you can do it.
Before Realization, I do not allow anybody
to touch My Feet, at any cost.
But if they are realized and approved as people
who have started their vibrations cool,
then only they are allowed to touch My Foot.
That has to be very discrete, you see,
because maybe the force is so much there, that you might faint.
So one has to be careful as to see if you can bear it.
So I was saying it is the other way round thing that works out.
Now what Sahaja Yoga does is that it's the power
that is flowing through the Sahaja Yogis who are here.
And even my photograph has the power. If it has it has.
This can be used
for giving vibrations to that part which is suffering.
or that center which is not all right.
People don't talk in the language as the doctors do.
They just say what center is out.
If they say Ekadesha is forming,
that means there's a possibility of it turning into a cancer.
Because cancer as I told you is built in, all the time,
with overactivity and again neutralised
by parasympathetic nervous system.
But the cancer that is going to settle down, is indicated here
and you start feeling a throbbing over here
of the Parashakti as it is called.
But not necessarily. It can be the other way round also,
when it is one of the symptoms, I would say,
but can be that, if you feel here that kind of a
heaviness or that kind of a pulsation here,
not necessarily that you are going for a cancer.
But it's one of the symptoms one can feel,
one of the sympthoms which you can.
But the best way is not to talk about the diseases,
but better to talk about the subtle thing, which are the chakras.
If your chakras are in perfect state,
if you can correct your chakras properly,
then you will have no problem of any kind.
So now we have here up to Vishuddhi chakra,
and this is the Agnya chakra
about which I have told you yesterday.
So we have all the seven chakras in the brain.
Now the kundalini is brought up through this Agnya chakra
and enters into this limbic area which is the kingdom of God.
But here all these seven chakras get related to each other,
because these are the seats of the chakras.
And that's how the integration start taking place.
When little bit of integration is worked up,
this opens out and the Kundalini passes out.
This is what is the real knowledge.
But people are so much enamored by their ego,
by their own ideas that anybody who says,
"All right you wear this dress you become a yogi.
You take this name you become a yogi.
Like this falsehood with which they live.
You should not live with falsehood,
because falsehood is not the way the life is. Life is reality.
And it is such a beautiful thing to know the reality.
because reality is nothing but glory and beauty.
One should not be convinced if somebody says
"All right you take this name. Your name is swami, such and such.
or they say you are a phalaan [Anand Kakad] like
This is not to be believed in,
because this is you are deceiving yourself.
There is no need to change your name. Nothing is needed.
The change comes within.
You should not be satisfied with this changing of the dress.
Supposing you wear a tail coat or you wear an ordinary coat
makes no difference inside, does it?
In the same way, if you color your clothes
and go round saying that: "I'm such a yogi" and all that...
Remember that this is misleading
Don't take to these things. You should not mislead yourself.
You must fix yourself up to it.
Now if you take drugs also, in the same way
it harms you very much in your awareness and your brain,
and you find that there is a problem on the right hand backwards.
Most of them must also give you on the right hand side a problem
because here the superego touches on the right hand side.
Now those people who are extremely aggressive
and have taken to aggressive methods and all that,
this left side gets caught up.
Now you must see, the nature has built within us
a beautiful balancing phenomenon.
Supposing you are a person who is very hard working.
You work very hard, you go for the future
and you do all kinds of things with your mind,
and all the time you are planning and this and that,
the right side you are working on.
Actually you are working through your brain
and your brain must go out.
But no all such people even till the end,
they'll go to their grave, they are very alert in the brains.
Nothing goes wrong with the brain but the heart.
Heart is the one that is caught up.
You'll be surprised that never a person who is mad,
gets a heart attack.
Because he is on the superego. Now, he is using his left side.
He is using his left side.
He should get his heart, but he gets his brain out.
Just imagine the balancing forces that are working in you.
Actually when you get your first attack
remember that you are overdoing it. Stop it at that moment.
It's an indication coming to you from nature.
But we know, we'll have an operation and again go like a big horse.
There's no need.
There's no need. But another thing is that in Sahaja Yoga
you really settle down in the center.
You don't have this problems of going to extremes,
or getting to extreme behaviors,
and you get to a point where you really realize
that you are the Spirit and you are the absolute being.
It's not any ego and superego
because then you don't say that I did this.
Like supposing there's a lady who came with Me to America
and she called herself a [moron].
And she said: "Mother, You must give him Realization".
I said: "I'm trying.
So breaking my hands on the working morning till evening
I'm trying but what to do, I can't do it now."
I said: "All right you are a realized soul, you give a certificate".
She said: "How can I give a false certificate?
Because it is not there". You start speaking in the third way.
You say: "It is not there." "It is not coming."
"It is not working." You don't say: "I'm not working it out."
You don't say that "I'm not doing it" or "I am doing it."
What you say that, "I'm trying but it doesn't come out",
"It doesn't come out". It, you start talking in a third way.
And that is what happens to you, you lose your ego.
In Sahaja Yoga also we have seen,
some people who come to Sahaja Yoga,
get into ego trips, because it's a habit.
It's a very bad habit in the West to get into ego trips.
You see, just they jump into some imaginary balloons,
I don't know what, and they start thinking: "I am this, I am that".
I'm quite frightened to see this fellow was quite a normal person
till yesterday. Now what has happened to him?
So you see this ego is such a thing
that if one egoistical person comes in
the another can take up from that person.
It's such a horrible stuff is.
They are very contagious, very contagious.
and that's how you will find that
one egoistical now, if the husband shouts the wife will shout.
And the wife shouts then the husband beats.
If supposing, one person just stops,
not shouting, it will calm down, definitely.
But the contagious disease goes on increasing
that the children become shouters. It goes on like that.
So the ego is a thing that one does not feel it,
does not understand it and it goes on destroying you, all the time.
And the ego gives you a self-importance, but not self-esteem.
It doesn't give you self-esteem.
It just gives you self importance, unlimited.
But what have you achieved?
So, to be the Spirit you become a humble person.
You need to become absolutely humble.
One gentleman once told Me
that, "I've heard you are doing such great things.
And I've known you for 25 years.
I did not know that you are Mataji Nirmala Devi.
I only knew you as Mrs. Shrivastava wife of such and such".
And he was the High Court,
Hague High Court's, German he is.
And so, I said "All right".
He said, "No, you are coming tomorrow to my house.
You have to give me Realization. I never knew."
So I said, "How did you come to know?" He said, "We have a...
He is from the royal family, another maharaja,
who had your photograph in his pocket.
And he took it out and put it to his head". So I said,
"What's the matter?" He said, "You see,
I have a very bad heart trouble and Mataji cured me.
So he said, "Look at the photograph". And he said, "Oh, God.
This is Mrs. Shrivastava.
I knew her for 25 years. I never knew she could even speak.
So She speaks and not only She speaks to all them
He said, "We can't believe it this woman could speak.
Because what I known her for this, is she's a very quiet person".
So for all practical purposes I'm a very quiet person.
And then he, you know, then came and he got his Realization.
And he's such a humble man, you won't believe.
He's such a humble man. He said "I've found it".
He's a very learned personality.
There is so many like that, we have an ambassador of Spain
who was another humble man, you see. And he came to Me and he said
"Mother give me Realization, I've come to know about it.
Of course on that level I don't talk to people.
He got his Realization
and if I'm sitting, say, on a chair he would not sit.
He will sit on the ground.
The governor of Kashmir, I think.
This is a very different style thing in India is.
I must tell you, we people are very different.
Even a garbage cleaner becomes such a big governor here
that it's impossible to talk. It's a very funny thing.
I'll tell you a story.
Once a garbage cleaner came to our house, you see.
And I said, "All right, this is an extra garbage, you throw it away"
So he said, "All right, I'm willing to throw it away, the garbage,
but how much are you going to pay me? I said, "All right,
if you say, I'll give you some 10 pounds or something.
He said, "You Indians, you don't know any laws, rules, regulations
this, that and started shouting at Me.
And this gentleman of the Hague High Court,
the chairman of Hague High Court, the judge was standing there.
He came out, he said, "Why are you talking so loudly to her?
This is not the way to talk to a lady.
He said, "What do you know about laws?"
He's the one who's in charge there.
"Oh, you Indians, I know how terrible you are,
you have no idea of laws".
You see, he was the one who was taking bribe from Me actually,
and he was telling off this fellow like this. There is no humility,
there's no respect.
A garbage cleaner talking like to the head
of the organization which is dealing with law,
who has written so many books on human laws, can you imagine?
There is no sense of proportion in people, that, what are we?
Why should we be so boastful, arrogant and rude.
It's not good, it's not human, it's like animals behavior.
It's not a good thing. We have to be gentle,
absolutely gentle, because we are human.
God has given us so much. What blessings God has given us.
I find Australians still very much better
than any other western people, I must tell you,
whatever people may say about you. That's my experience is.
And I always tell everybody "You have to learn a lot from them,
because they are innocent people, they are simple and innocent,
and all the time they want to know what's wrong with them.
They are simple people. They want to know about it.
But I'm just telling you be careful about this mister ego.
He's a horrible stuff, it always comes up for nothing at all,
and is of no use. It's an empty vessel that makes too much noise.
So now today, we are going to again have the session of Realization,
and this is the seven chakras on the limbic area.
When you get the Realization, all these chakras
get completely enlightened within you, as you progress,
and all your centers get absolutely enlightened,
and you get all these different deities awakened within you.
Then the power that, you see, you receive first, is
that you receive complete bliss and joy.
Of course in the west, people feel joy at the last I must say.
But mentally they understand, they become very equipped mentally.
Dr. Warren, who is sitting before you, he was the same.
I've seen with all of them.
First, they become mentally very equipped.
They know so much because, you see,
the whole knowledge comes into their head first,
for their brains are more developed.
While the people who have heart more developed
they first feel the joy.
You know the Fiji people who were here yesterday, day before,
I said: "How are you feeling?". "We are feeling the joy".
Ananda [ra], there's a joy coming out.
Because their hearts are open. So that is what happens to people
who are too much mentally involved.
This is what happens to them. And those who are
involved in the heart, they start feeling the joy, doesn't matter.
But the growth takes place, a transformation takes place.
Overnight people have given up their drugs,
their diseases, so many things have happened.
But you must know that truth can be little shattering,
to your preconceived ideas.
But God cannot remain with you as He wanted to be.
He is what He is, He will be what He has to be.
You cannot command God
that "You stay like this. Now I'm going to organize you."
He has organized everything for us, we cannot organize for Him.
He works the way He works, every time, every minute.
for Him is all perfect.
And for you also it will be because
you will be living in the present.
When you start living in the present, every moment is dynamic.
You really become a dynamic person, not a cabbage, not a mad man,
but a dynamic, wonderful person, who's rid of all his problems.
Dr. Warren himself had
blood pressure, I don't know all sorts of problems he had.
And it's all got corrected. But there are so many
who are sitting here, at least there are 30, 40 people
who will tell that, how they got cured of their problems.
So you all should just think that here is somebody
who is just here for your benefit.
And there's nothing to worry.
That's all he was trying to tell you
and I have to tell you the same.
But this Sahasrara has to open out.
In a way, if you start doubting Me, Sahasrara doesn't open.
Because I am there. I must tell you I'm in the Sahasrara.
That's the way, I am there.
You can find out later on when you find pressures on you head,
you have to take My name, otherwise doesn't open out.
What can I do about? I am there.
So you have to just not accept me or surrender
or what are you going to surrender?
Except for ego what do you have to surrender?
So there's nothing to be surrendered
nothing to be given to Me, nothing.
Just you have to take more, become deeper and deeper and deeper,
and a personality who is enriched.
But in Sahaja Yoga there are no courses,
nothing of the kind. You have to work it out,
come to the center, it's a collective happening,
It's not a single person, sitting at home.
You all have to come,
make your progress, progress further and further.
You'll be looked after very well, with love,
and you will see how people are transformed,
how gentle they are, how nice they are, how kind they are.
Maybe one of them may turn out to be egoistical,
so you just treat him as a mad man. Can be, you see,
who is used to this thing they go back, for again circle,
and again they come back. But doesn't matter.
So I have to request you that you must come on a Sunday
where I would like to meet you all and today let us see
how many of you feel the cool breeze.
Now I would request you to take out your shoes and sit in a way
that you are touching the Mother earth with both the feet.
Sahaja Yoga is only meant for true seekers,
not for people who are false people
or who want to satisfy themselves with falsehood.
You have to ask for truth and if you ask for truth, you will get it.
Now the first thing as I told you before,
you have to understand that
you should not feel guilty. That is very important.
Now somebody started arguing with Me,
that "God has told me to feel guilty". Now again I don't know
which God has told you. You see, all these ideas you you give up.
Please do not feel guilty at all, because
I'm saying that God is forgiveness, God is love.
He's anxious to give you Realisation.
He's extremely anxious that you should get it. The time has come.
This is the Last Judgement. You see the resurrection time.
You have to get it, there's no other way out
for Him also because He has to save His creation
and His creation are human beings.
So please for Heaven's sake do not feel guilty.
This is a very important time. If you are feeling guilty,
you just tell yourself that "Mother I'm not guilty".
That is the first condition,
that you should not feel guilty at all at this time.
All right. Then the second condition is that
you close your eyes and put your hands towards Me.
So that you understand that there is no mesmerism.
Or for what I should mesmerize you? There is no...
But you see you have to close your eyes and please
don't open your eyes, because when the Agnya chakra,
when your eyes are opened Agnya chakra
doesn't allow the Kundalini to pass through,
So please do not open your eyes till I tell you.
Because as I told you, there is no mesmerism, nothing.
It works like sunshine.
So just pur your hands towards Me like this,
on your lap, very comfortably. Very comfortably be seated.
Extremely comfortably you all should sit down.
Put both the hands with your fingers little bit stretched.
And close your eyes. You can remove your spectacles, will help you.
Or any malas(garlands) or anything you are wearing in your neck,
which is heavy. If there's something heavy, or may,
please take it out. Also one has to be
little bit loose in the waist.
If a, it's very tight something on the waist, you see,
may be not good.
So something, or in the neck, necktie or something,
should be also loosen.
Please put your hands towards Me. Just this.
Please take out your spectacles please,
because it affects your eyesight also,
It might improve your eyesight.
Both the hands towards Me.
Both the hands towards Me, like this, on your lap.
Now, as I told you, the left hand is the desire.
So keep the left hand as it is.
But as I tell you, you have to move the right hand.
But don't open your eyes, please.
Please don't open your eyes.
Just don't open your eyes, that is very important.
You must sit still and don't do any movements.
Just keep it still.
You need not bend your head or push it back.
Make it straight, that's all.
But no pressure on your neck.
Sit in a way that is comfortable to begin with.
Now, we have to put our right hand on the heart.
Just on the heart. And to say,
"Mother, I am the Spirit", with all confidence.
Say it thrice.
Because you are, you are the Spirit, no doubt.
And that Spirit has to manifest
to show you what glorious thing you are.
You are not your ego, you are not your mind,
you're not your body, but you are the Spirit,
the reflection of God Almighty within you.
So say it on your heart.
Steady down, steady, steady down.
Put your left hand towards Me, left hand towards Me, yes.
Steady down, steady. You must steady yourselves.
Now put down this right hand on the stomach, on the left hand side.
And with full confidence you have to say,
to awaken your principle of primordial master within you,
to say "Mother I am my own master, I am my own guru,
I am my own guide".
Ten times.
Because, if you are the Spirit
then the Spirit guides you through vibratory awareness.
And once you said, "I am the Spirit",
you have to accept all the aspects of Spirit
by saying that "the Spirit is my guide and I am the Spirit".
Please say it ten times.
Now put your attention
there where you have put your hand and say that,
"Mother I am the master, I am the guru, I am my own guide".
This is to awaken within you. Say it with confidence, please.
Now
put your left hand towards Me
and right hand towards the stomach, I said, on the stomach.
Press it with your fingers.
On the left side.
Now if you have said it ten times
you put the hand again on your heart.
Again go back to the same point, that you are the Spirit.
That's the second point. So you have to say,
"Mother, I am the Spirit", but twelve times,
because this center has got twelve subplexuses,
twelve petals. So you have to say, "Mother, I am the Spirit".
This is very good for all the people who have heart attacks,
heart troubles, heart problems, it's very good for them.
This is the mantra.
This is the chanting.
Now raise your right hand on the Vishuddhi chakra,
left side of your neck.
That's the Vishuddhi. Left hand side of your neck.
This is the center which goes out of gear in many people
because they feel guilty.
It's very simple. So you have to say: "Mother I am not guilty".
Left is very much catching.
For anything whatsoever.
Don't think of your guilt, of the past.
Forget it, because you are going to be transformed.
As I told you yesterday an egg has to become a bird.
Then does not matter, the egg whatever specks it has.
it's finished once the shell is out.
So just say sixteen times,
"Mother I am not guilty, I am not guilty".
Now you are entering into the temple of God
and a guilty person cannot enter.
Because you are the Spirit, how can you be guilty?
You cannot be guilty because you are the Spirit.
Come back to the same point. Because you are the Spirit
you cannot enter
into the idea of guilt.
Spirit is never attached to any such ideas.
Good.
Now put the right hand on your forehead.
Across. At this point you have to say:
"Mother, I forgive everyone". You have to forgive everyone.
Please forgive everyone,
because the Spirit is the forgiving force within us.
Christ forgave people who crucified Him.
And not only that, but he asked God,
His Father to forgive them,
for they did not know what they where doing.
In His name you have to forgive.
Forgive everyone. Just forgive everyone.
It's very easy to say that.
And you just say it and it works out. It's amazingly
powerful.
Now put this hand steadily on your head, on top of your head.
Now you'll find it's rather heavy in the center part.
Try to press it with your palm a little bit.
At this time, you have to say: "Mother, give me Realisation".
Because I cannot cross your freedom. You are free.
So you have to just say: "Mother, please give me my Realisation",
at this point.
Say it seven times, because there are seven centers.
Now just put you hand upper four inches
and see if there's a cool breeze coming in.
Now try with another hand. Put right hand down
and left hand you try if there's a cool breeze coming in.
I think it has worked out.
You can put both the hands towards Me now.
It's like raising the mountains I tell you.
It's really like raising the mountains.
Now put your both the hands up in the sky. Let's see.
Just like this, higher.
And ask the question, "Mother is this
the breeze of the Holy Ghost?".
Just ask in your heart,
"Is this the cool wind of the Holy Ghost?"
"Is this the Brahma shakti?
Is this the All Pervading power of God?"
Just ask the question.
Only these questions will give you answer as answer.
And now you can ask also, "Mother are you the Holy Ghost?"
Let's see. "Mother are you the Holy Ghost?" Ask three times.
It is start working faster with that question.
Felt it? Now put down your hands,
and see for yourself,.
Slowly open your eyes.
See if it works in your hand a kind of a sensation flowing in.
Now we'll then show you also
how to protect yourself,
because once you are realised, you're like that,
absolutely a newly born
or newly awakened seed.
So you are to be protected and how to protect yourself
nicely, and how to give Kundalini awakening,
both things Dr. Warren will show you,
how to raise your Kundalini yourself
and how to protect yourself when you go out.
And I hope you will make it convenient all of you
to come and see Me on Sunday.
Thank you.
Dr Warren: Just put the left hand at the level of the Kundalini,
and the right hand at above and at the front
take it down, back and up. This is the manner of turning it.
So lift it, putting your attention to the Kundalini,
take it right up, give it a twist,
and knot it once, and bring your hands down.
Again we raise it. Hands down at the Kundalini. Turn it.
Up,
and raise it
above the head and twist it, and knot it once.
And this time three times for the three channels."
Three sides, three gunas. - Dr Warren: "three knots".
Three powers.
Dr Warren: "Whirl it and knot it once.
Turn it
and knot it twice.
and knot it three times and just bring your hands down
and put them towards Mother.
Open your fingers out.
and see if you're feeling it.
Now ask them to give bandhan. [unclear]
Dr: Now the second aspect, as Mother said is to protect yourself.
We do this by what is called a bandhan.
It's like an umbrella we are putting over ourselves.
-Dr Warren: So we put our hand... -SM: Your aura is to be protected.
So the aura is to be protected.
Dr. Warren: "We put our left hand towards Mother
and our right hand over the side at the lowest chakra.
And we come over the top
and down once,
back twice, seven times.
Again over, three times
back over, four times,
back over, five times,
six and seven.
Put your hands back up, too.
You protected yourself by a bandhan,
which simply means a bond of love.
There is another thing one has to know, that
when this is a power of love flowing through your hands now,
it's a power of love.
We have to steady it of course, we have to know
what it is, how it works, how you have to give Realisation.
Now you can give realisation to people.
You can cure people. All these powers you have got now.
But first you must steady yourself.
Steadiness is very important in Sahaja Yoga, to begin with.
And then you will be amazed that if you are standing somewhere,
if there's an accident, accident will be avoided.
You tell somebody, the person will feel healed.
It's a tremendous thing because you're tremendous,
but you have to feel that within yourself.
You must practice it first of all
and then test it if you have got it or not.
But not with doubts, but with confidence
that you are now the saints.
You are the prophets as William Blake has said
that God of man is described these times, God of man,
will become prophets and the prophets
will later on, make others prophets.
And this is exactly what is happening.
Another person is William Blake
who has completely described Sahaja Yoga.
So I would like to meet you personally when you come there,
and I hope we'll be able to provide you with good lunch also.
It was very kind of you, all of you, to come down and meet Me.
I've been very anxious to meet you all. May God bless you.
What's it? Dr. Warren: It's o.k.
It's talking too much.
Dr. Warren: For those people who don't know the address,
I think it's well implanted in your mind
that 172 Albert Road,
Stratfield, 10 o'clock on Sunday.
And ask them to bring salt, sugar and oil.
Dr Warren: "As I've told before Mother's requested you to bring
salt, about half a pound, something like that.
Salt and sugar and a small bottle of water.
She will vibrate it for you to have your own vibrated drinking water
and some oil, because you may need it for massage purposes
or otherwise for healing.
so salt, sugar, about half a pound
a bottle of water and some oil.
it can be olive oil, it can be... SM: White sugar.
But white sugar please, white sugar.
More of the sugar cane, if they can get. Of the sugar cane?
Dr. Warren: Yes, it's that sugar. SM: That's what you get.
So 172 Albert Road,
Stratfield, on Sunday at 10 o'clock.
And we'll be there.
Those people who wish, you can come along and
Mother will be cooking some lunch so you can take lunch with us.
Thank you very much ladies and genlemen.
We look forward to see you there.