[Music]
the word guru comes from the one which
is magnetic the person who is magnetic
the one it attracts the attention of the
seekers is the Guru also it means the
heaviness or you can say a person who is
very steady who is very deep who has the
knowledge and who can act like the
mother earth for the power of magnetism
in the mother earth also is called as
magnetic but in sanskrit is guru to
occur sure means the attraction of the
heaviness of the mother but actually it
is a power of the mother earth that
makes us stand for he on our legs when
it is rotating with such a tremendous
speed otherwise he would be all thrown
away with that velocity that she is
moving we are still attached or we are
one in our balance is only because she
has
gravity this gravity has to be in a guru
gravity means a kind of a serious
understanding of oneself and one's own
responsibilities so a guru has to be
very steady in these modern times people
are very mobile all the time as you take
it all the time getting disturbed small
things happening here and there they get
it they meet people who are not of any
quality then they get disturbed these
disturbing qualities come from our
deficiency in our gravity a person who
has gravity does not get depressed
neither get excited not get overly
enthusiastic not easy
very sad or unhappy so he is in the
center he is in the center of his be the
most level we think a good guru is that
person who
just attraction towards themselves body
language or maybe other attractions
which are gross and that's why people
always go to the Guru's who are false
who are superficial but the one who is
above the gravity of the mother earth
the gross the subtle the subtle subtler
in the subtlest beyond all these
attractions that is the one is the Guru
where is your attention is important if
you are the Guru wearing your attention
if your attention is on the correction
and the nourishment of yourself are no
further then you are first of all the
sahaja yogi
and once you rise above the
gravitational force of materialism then
you could be called as the good you do
not need education for that in your city
education you need not read books you
need not do anything only thing is that
you have to have your value system
correctly in your value system you have
to first of all understand what is
auspiciousness what is divine beauty and
what is morality of the Spirit these
fittings are to be alive and how to be
part and parcel of your being so that
when people see you they should say it
here is a person you can see who has
that gravity here is the person who has
that you then he talks to others he
talks with them he doesn't talk to
frivolous things
useless things I think which are of very
basic level
in an all enter crisis I would say he
has a kind of a decency and a decoder so
not that the Guru himself has the value
system but through his lifestyle through
his own teachings through his own
behavior he radiates gravity plus dvdx
grammatical so either none of this
gravity
Evette discrimination let you know what
is your personality and what is the
water barometer you know how to
discriminate and this discrimination is
also actually innately comes from your
guru person now and then I suppose you
have constable you have come out of here
so that yeah transcendence all those
things through your amun-re but that
does not mean that you have developed
that gravity you have now achieved a
state if a flower is there and you push
it put the flower on the water it will
float
but when it becomes the fruit and
matures then you put it in the water it
does not feel it goes tick-tock
it does not get dissolved it keeps its
own identity that is what is to be done
now that you have to become the fruits
of reading now all of you can become
gurus every one of you can become goose
and can develop that great capacity to
be being one with that cosmic
consciousness completely out of the
clutches of the gravity of the earth
materialism without achieving that you
have no right to tell it anybody what is
to be done first it should be your
practice and preserve it in your own
life in your own example and then your
example is sufficient to convince others
and this is what they have to see if we
can develop that gravity within our
sense and understanding within okay well
happy resides within you the joy of
becoming sahaja Yogi's will be really
effect will be really understood and
will be enjoyed by all of it may God
bless you
[Music]
you