I bow to all the seekers of truth. You have
just now heard that within us lies the power
of our ascent, ascent to the Divine. Now maybe
there are some people who can say "How? How
do You say that? What's Your authority?"
Naturally, one can ask such a question. But
as a scientist we have to keep our minds open
to any knowledge. I say this is the knowledge
of the roots. Why? Whatever we have known
so far is the knowledge of the tree. It sounds
fantastic sometimes to people how can the
awakening of the Kundalini or the Holy Ghost
as described in the Bible can bring forth
this tremendous change; this transformation
and all the benefits of physical, mental,
emotional and material being within us. It's
impossible to believe because it's too fantastic.
But we don't realize that how fantastically
we are made by God Almighty.
We take Him so much for granted. When we make
a computer in this world we feel we have done
a great job. But do you know you yourself
you are a computer which knows without thinking.
I see you and I know I see you. I don't have
to go back to some sort of a programming to
find out what am I seeing; is also spontaneous
and living. All the living things are created
by the living God and then we know that we
have come to this stage of human awareness;
from here if we have to ascend, there must
be some method, mechanism within us.
Now some may say that why should we seek.
There's no why about it. Because you see the
confusion all along, you see what's happening
to people. There are so many thought waves
coming up like 'we must look after our health',
'we must look after our mind'. There are so
many sorts of theologies and also many intellectual
expositions and manifestations; that one gets
absolutely confounded and can't understand
where are we. Naturally in this confusion
one feels very frustrated and wants to find
out what are we here for? Any intelligent
sincere person, honest person thinks that
way. 'Why am I here?' Of course for the frivolous,
they can manage for some time. They can continue
for one or two lives till they become little
bit concerned but normally any intelligent
person would think that I have been made a
human being for what? What is the purpose
of my being a human being from the animal
stage? Then people say that you are a human
being now you forget about your creator; you
forget about anything like that and you think
you are the creator. You just believe that
you are the one who has to rule the whole
world. That's how we create a barrier between
ourselves and the truth. The truth exists
and God exists whether we believe in it or
not. Actually blind faith is not going to
take us to God. The faith has to be based
on experience which is called as 'shraddha'.
It has to be based on experience of the truth.
Supposing, I have not been to this room; I
have not seen it; I don't know what it is
and I started describing it and if you believe
Me, then I would say it's just a brain wash
and it has been nothing but a talk and talk
and talk about God throughout. The reason
was the human beings were not ready at that
time I should say to get to their Realization.
We had few people very few in the last say
sixth to the modern times.
I asked a Zen master, "How many realized souls
you had? 'Kashyapas'"
And he said, "We had altogether only twenty
four 'Kashyapas' from the sixth Century to
the thirteenth Century and we had none."
So I said, "Then what are you doing there?
You are a Zen Master and you are not a realized
soul."
So he said, "I am doing my job."
A priest, I must say John Clover is also a
priest; and a priest very well known personality
and I asked him, "What do you mean by Holy
Ghost?"
So he says, "I am agnostic."
I said, "Then, what are you doing in the church?"
So he says "I am doing my job."
I was surprised! What sort of a job you can
do when you do not know what you are talking?
You are professing something about which you
yourself are not sure. You yourself you are
not a free soul and you are talking about
freedom of the soul; is something like a advertising
department.
So people start wondering, is there anything
like God? And no wonder that so many have
discarded as nothing. But the time has come
now to prove the existence of God. The time
has now come to prove all the miracles of
the scriptures. At this time only there's
a controversy should come up that there were
no miracles and the time has come to prove
that. Isn't it surprising that spontaneously
at this time only all these intellectuals
are coming out with their novel ideas? And
that this is the time we can prove it that
there is God. We can prove it that there is
Kundalini, the Holy Ghost and we can prove
it that there is Spirit and that a human being
can ascend. I think the background is so dark
that the light will show better and that has
to happen. In these modern times, I find if
you talk to anybody about God, they will laugh
at you. Is not regarded fashionable to talk
about God but despite of all that in the modern
times we have the maximum numbers of seekers.
We never had so many seekers at any time.
Think of Christ, he had those twelve disciples
who did not believe in Him till they saw His
resurrection. I mean they did not believe
in Him fully, I mean to say. Look at Buddha
or look at anyone of these people. Mohammad
Saab, how they tortured his life? And they
all have talked about this time as the resurrection
time because before the doomsday the resurrection
has to come. But the people who are in-charge
of the, there are people who have taken their
charge in this world. Will not believe that
there can be redemption, that there could
be resurrection because it's a money making
proposition.
I met a Mayor today in the morning of another
place and he told Me, he asked Me actually
"Why people become so fanatic about religion?"
I said, "Because it is a money making proposition
everywhere".
Any money making proposition has to be fanatic
because you have to be successful money wise
and also compromising. It's an enterprise
and God doesn't understand money, that's the
worst part of it. He doesn't know what money
is. He does all that is living what human
beings do is nothing but they convert dead
to another dead. Now for example some tree
is dead, we make a bench out of it; from dead
to dead. But can we transform these flowers
into fruits? We do not. And the one who does
billions and billions of these at the time,
at the right time, proper seasons, who must
be that? Whatever we have done so far is the
dead work. But the work of God is the living
work and the living work of God is evident
in our own existence that we have become human
beings from amoeba stage and that if higher
ascent has to take place it has to take place
through some spontaneous happening meaning
living happening not by some artificial things
like in the Hindu religion we have a ceremony
called as 'munja' where the, at eight years
of age they say the child has now become a
Brahmin, means he has known the all pervading
power of Brahma, of Holy Ghost, certified.
As we have in Christian religion also in the
churches they'll put their hand and your head
and say now you have become Christian, Baptized.
How Sir? Just an exercise and we believe in
it. We accept the situation and we believe
that we are that. Mohammad Saab has said,
"You have to become the Pir."
There's no religion which has not said that
human awareness is for just balancing yourself.
That's the religion is. It's like trial and
error and trial and error; that you make mistakes
improve yourself, make mistakes improve yourself.
You move from one extreme to another as you
see here to the left or to the right and then
you come to the center and the central path
of ascent is within us and which we achieve
through our moderation and not through our
extremes and those who go to extremes and
become fanatic are people who are not religious
by any chance because religion must give you
a balance. That's the first thing one must
attain, attain through religion. Now within
us lies the power of our ascent and the path
of our ascent and on this path we have got
different centers which represent something
very subtle within us. As I told you this
is the knowledge of the roots.
Supposing a tree is sick we see the leaves
are falling. So we take one leaf. First of
all once if we pluck it out it is already
finished. But even on the tree we try to inject
something to the leaf, does it reach the whole
of the tree? It does not. If you have to cure
that tree, you have to go to the roots. In
the same way within ourselves these centers
are placed and the root has to be awakened
so that it passes through all these centers,
enlightens all these centers and give you
the ultimate that we call as the true Baptism
or Self Realization or in Sanskrit knowledge
they say 'Atma Sakshathkar'.
Now where does the Spirit reside? The Spirit
resides in our heart. Now this is a hypothesis
for you. You need not accept. But keep your
mind open for it. But the seat of God almighty
is on top of your head though the reflection
of that as the Spirit is in the heart. When
this Kundalini which is called as the Root
also or is called as the Holy Ghost, which
is the reflection of the Holy Ghost, which
is the power of God, which is the Primodial
Mother, which is your individual Mother rises
and when it touches that point the Spirit
in your heart starts emitting these cool vibrations.
First you feel it here coming out of your
head, the Cool Breeze. This happens. This
is not artificial you can even see in many
people the pulsation of the Kundalini very
clearly just like a heart or in that bone,
which is just a bone; pulsates like a heart,
when there is an obstruction in the higher
centers.
Now the subtle side of these centers are that
the first center is related to our innocence.
Have we bothered to find out how are we innocent
in our childhood? What is that creates innocence
within us? Then the second center that we
have is the center of Swadishthana which deals
with the creativity that we have. Now God
has made human beings in his image. He has
the same centers within Him which He reflects
within us. So with this center He has created
all this universe. This is for the creativity.
The third center within us, which is the naval
center, which looks after the solar plexus
on the gross, is called as the Nabhi Chakra
meaning the naval center and is responsible
for giving us the seeking. We should know
why do we seek. Why do we seek food to begin
with? We feel hungry, but how do we know that
we are hungry and that we want food? Even
a child knows that, even an animal knows that;
how? This is the center tells us that now
you are hungry better go and have some food.
And this is the center tells us now you better
seek some money, maybe some power, maybe all
the human things that we seek and waste our
life quite a lot in that. After that when
you are affluent when you have solved all
these mundane things like no more we are living
in the jungles like animals. Then we start
thinking that there must be something beyond
because I have got everything now but I haven't
got joy. I don't feel joyous. I am not satisfied,
what is that? When this seeking starts then
you are a special category of seekers for
which William Blake has clearly written very,
very clearly two hundred years back he said
that men of God will become prophets and they
will have powers to make others prophets and
that is today's Sahaja Yoga. This seeking
is a special category of people who we find
now a days all over the world. That's why
I said it at the very outset that you do not
find so many seekers, in the history of spirituality
so many seekers. But today there are thousands
and thousands; I would say millions and millions
of seekers. But what happens to them? Again
they get lost. Some start getting lost in
the intellectual understanding of God, finished.
How can you understand God with this limited
brain? He's unlimited. You have to go beyond
this mind to understand. What can we understand
of that God who does all these marvelous things
of living processes which we cannot do even
a wee bit with this brain of ours? So some
are lost in the books and some are lost in
the organized religions, finished.
Sunday morning have a nice dress, go to the
church, I have done my work as far as God
is concerned. Or I would say for a Hindu is
to go to the temple, take some money give
it to the Brahmin there, done. So they are
also lost in it. Then there are lots of markets
now a days. We have 'spiritualists' and we
have 'charismatics' and we have got 'seventh
day adventist' and 'born again'; all sorts.
They are only same people with different brands.
There's no difference between one human being
and another, even if you put any brand on
our head we are just the same. There is no
difference at all. They may profess something,
but whatever you profess is not within you.
So it is not what you profess is important,
but what you become. Becoming is the point.
What you become on your central nervous system.
That is the evolutionary impact. When we evolve
from animal to human state it is expressed
on our central nervous system. For example
if you have to take a dog through a dirty
lane, he has no objection, he just walks through.
But we cannot go. Now you bring a dog here
in a good garden, he's quite happy, he doesn't
know whether it is a beautiful garden of flowers
or it's a dirty lane. But for a human being
this awareness is there and he can feel it.
Now to human beings if you talk of sin this
that, they don't understand. They'll say,
"What's wrong? What's wrong?" "If I kill somebody
what's wrong?" "If I do like this what's wrong?"
Because the awareness is at that level. But
Christ, would He do such a thing? Buddha,
would He do such a thing? Khalil Gibran, would
he do such a thing? William Blake? No, why?
Because they are above us and their sense
and sensitivity has developed in such a manner
that they are the people who know what is
right and what is wrong.
So we live in a relative world. We must accept
this. We have no sense of absolute and even
if we have it is told to us from our fathers,
forefathers or in the church or in the temple
somewhere; is all conditioning. We do not
know for definite whether it is right or wrong
because we haven't got that awareness. So
what has to happen to you is that you have
to become collectively conscious that means
you can feel your own centers on your finger
tips. That is Self-Realization, you know your
Self and you should feel the centers of other
people on your finger tips and so that you
know what is wrong with another person or
what is wrong with you. But you are so much
separated from yourself like it becomes your
cloth, the whole body, the ego, the superego
that you know it is wrong and you clear it
out, if you know the technique. This is the
another meaning of the word Yoga.
The first meaning is that Yoga is the union
with the Divine; also Yoga means to be deft
in the art of God's love, in the technique
of Divine laws; this is the another meaning.
Yoga doesn't mean standing on your head. That's
just a misnomer, because some people have
got very little knowledge about things and
they start saying this is Yoga. But I mean
Patanjali who has talked about it thousands
of years back has described nothing but Sahaja
Yoga; is the spontaneous union, spontaneous
union with the Divine. That's what he has
described out and out but who reads that big
book. Yoga you can buy in three pages you
see. Stand on your head; bend your feet, but
why? We too have to do some exercises in Sahaja
Yoga but the Kundalini has to rise and tell
us where it is obstructed accordingly we do
the exercise. Supposing you have a trouble
on your head and you do the stomach exercises,
the stomach will be spoilt for nothing at
all. As it is you have a headache plus the
stomach is also spoilt. So it is a big science
one has to understand. But it is so simple
as a child. Now this child is a realized soul
he knows because you become the absolute.
Now if you want to know whether there is God
or not you just put your hands like this and
ask the question, "Mother is there God?" When
you ask the question you'll get tremendous
Cool Breeze flowing.
Is like a computer, an absolute computer.
Now you ask a question, "Was Christ the son
of God?" You get tremendous; but ask about
Rasputin "Was he a saint?" I don't want to
ask because it might burn My hand. That's
how you know the absolute. Afterwards you
don't need also to use the hands, just without
that you know and that is what the state one
has to achieve, that is the final break-through
we have to achieve because this modern times
as they say, these are the times that are
described as the resurrection time, the judgment
time and this is the time that people have
to judge themselves. Your own Spirit will
judge you. Nobody is going to put you on a
weighing machine to see what have you got.
Your own centers will be judged by you yourself.
You become your own master, your own Guru
and you judge yourself and correct it. You
judge others and correct it. But you don't
tell them, you speak in a strange language
as the disciples of Christ spoke. You talk
in the language of centers. Like you ask somebody,
"What's the matter with this person?" So he'll
say, "His left Vishuddhi is catching." Means
he feels guilty. If you feel guilty your left
Vishuddhi catches.
We went to Nottingham today and there was
a taxi fellow who came in. We sat in the car
and I knew he was a realized soul. And he
started talking to Me. He also took to Me
easily and he confessed to Me, "Mother I am
a healer." I knew he was a, everybody knew
that he was a realized soul. He did not know
much about it because he's not a Sahaja Yogi
to know all the deftness of it. But he knew
that he was something different and a very
gentle and a sweet personality he had.
And while talking I asked him, "What's the
matter with you? Why do you feel so guilty?"
He said, "I don't know but I feel like a criminal."
I said, "Why?"
"Because everybody thinks I am queer."
I said, "In a lunatic asylum if a saint man
goes everybody thinks that he is insane. So
you must not feel that way, you should have
all full confidence in yourself."
But he was so surprised that I could tell
all these things about him. I said, "Anybody
would say because we know what you feel on
your finger tips. It's nothing great that
we are doing."
Because supposing, dog cannot talk to us,
but supposing we tell the dog that this is
music, Indian music. He will ask, "How do
you know it is Indian music?"
Because we know, we can hear. You can't hear;
you cannot differentiate. But we don't take
such pride in saying that we know this color
or we know that thing and we know what is
art, what is not. We think it is our own right
to know and we know it. In the same way once
you get your Realization you just know it
because you become. So becoming is the main
thing that you become a realized soul, a saint,
a sage, a seer, but as a result of this awakening
because it passes through various centers,
into various layers. First thing that happens
to you; first thing I must say that you get
your physical body cured. That's how Sahaja
Yoga cures cancer. What is so great about
it? It does and it's only this Sahaja Yoga
that is going to cure cancer. Otherwise you'll
take chemotherapy, loose your hair, then they'll
cut your throat and cut your nose and you'll
end up by parts, you see and when one will
die it won't be in one piece. But in Sahaja
Yoga the Kundalini rises and she supplies
the necessary vital forces to all these centers
and you get cured. Practically everything
that is to be repaired can be repaired if
the stage is not very much advanced. If the
stage is very much advanced then the Divine
takes a decision that let this body die and
come back again in a fresher way. Then it
allows it to die. But mostly if it is in a
repairing stage without taking any medicine,
without going to any doctor, without anything
you can cure yourself. It's not difficult.
It transforms your personality in the sense
that your priorities change completely. I
don't have to tell you 'don't do this'. That
I will not say because then half of you may
run away. But it will happen in such a manner
that you yourself won't do that. I don't have
to tell you at all. Because firstly if you
try to do it you will lose your vibrations
you feel unhappy. You'll lose your joy and
peace and maybe your body may react and that
it may vomit out the thing or it may make
you very painful so that you just don't do
it. You become righteousness, you become virtuous
and you enjoy your virtues. You don't force
your virtues on others you just say that one
day he should get Realization. The concern
is as if a part of your body is sick and you
want to soothe it and put it right. No obligation,
nothing. If somebody is drowning himself actually
part of you is getting drowned that's why
you jump into it. But here actually you feel
the another person and if you know how to
cure that then there's no obligation at all
because there is a part and parcel of your
being. Supposing this finger is paining and
if I rub it. Am I obliging myself? But it
is so spontaneous it is so automatic that
the idea also doesn't come into your head
that you have obliged him. It's so simple.
This is the power of God's love. We have never
used that before because we were not capable
of doing that. All these wars and all these
problems of the world are because we are using
the power of hatred. We talk of peace but
how will you make peace on this earth when
the people are so disturbed?
The source of peace is the Spirit and if the
whole world or a part of it and a very wee
part of it accepts that they should have their
Spirit manifesting and they establish themselves
you'll see all these problems will vanish
into thin air. As it is in your private life
they vanish out. Everything becomes smooth
joyous happy. The relationships become very
pure and you really enjoy human beings for
the first time. Otherwise it is just we'll
say "Oh we are brothers, brothers, brothers.
We are sisters, we are this that." When it
comes to selfishness everything drops out
because it's just a mental projection. Even
countries will say we are all friends, we
are going to help, but when it comes to something
important they drop out. But this is no mental
projection, is reality. Become that and that
should happen to many, many people by that
a kind of a catalysism will take place and
the whole world has to be changed as promised.
Those days are ahead, is working out very
well, I have worked in this England for ten
years. In India hardly two years, but thousands
and thousands in the villages are now Sahaja
Yogis. They have given up all their bad habits.
They have become masters of themselves. Even
I would say in England we have quite a lot
of Sahaja Yogis, but still is a very important
place is England because it plays a very important
role in spirituality because it is the heart
of the universe and the heart has to pump
out the truth. It's pumping out all kind of
nonsense on the television.
Today on the television they gave Me hardly
thirty seconds first and then three minutes.
What do I do in three minutes, but for a joker
or a clown or for absolutely useless person
there will be hours together. This is the
problem that we have to face, but I am sure
when the chaos will be seen clearly people
will ask for the answer and when they seek
that they will receive what they are seeking.
That is a promise and the promise has to be
fulfilled. All that is promised in the scriptures
has to be fulfilled.
May God bless you all.
Now if you have any problems please ask me.
Today I had a very, very hectic day. The whole
day I have been moving from places to places
and somehow you have been so kind to come
here and I am sure we'll get the experience
tonight. But in any case if you have any questions
please ask. Is important.
From the seekers: May I ask a question Mataji?
Mother: Yes please.
From the seekers: Is it possible to awaken
Kundalini without a spring guidance like You
because You are not available to us so only
by reading books?
Mother: Yes it is possible. Only
Sahaja Yogi: 'Only by reading books' she said
Mother: By reading books. No, no, no not at
all. Kabir Das has said "Padhi, padhi pandita
murakha bhayei". That by reading too much
even the learned have become stupid.
Seeker: So how could we have Divine guidance
like You?
Mother: What you have to do first of all is
to know that it's a living process and for
any living process you don't need mental understanding.
Just I have talked to you because after all
you are very intelligent people. But supposing
we want to sprout a seed what do we do? We
put it in the Mother Earth and it sprouts.
Do we give it a lecture before hand? All right
do we do anything? It is built-in in the seed
as well as in the Mother Earth the capacity
to do it. So of course you have to have somebody
who has the capacity. Satguru is the real
Guru. But these days they are all in the market;
all making money. First thing is no money
can be paid for sprouting of the seed; first
principle. Ninety nine point nine percent
[99.9%] will drop out on that point and is
said that 'Sahib Milaye'. The one who makes
you meet the Divine is the Guru. The one who
talks and gives lecture is not the Guru. But
these days there are some very great Gurus
but they are hiding themselves in the Himalayas
and I sent one of them with great request
to America that please go and do some work
in America I won't be able to go. He stayed
in New York for three days and ran back into
Himalayas. He said, "The people are at a very
lower level you see, they just talk of dollar."
He ran away. So they don't want to deal just
now perhaps maybe after sometime if they see
that the area is all right, they may come
down. But there are many great saints all
over the world. But sort of they have receded
themselves. First you all become saints and
they will all come to join.
Seeker: To become saint is very difficult.
Mother: Who told you that?
Seeker: Afreed
Mother: It is the easiest thing. Living process
is the easiest. But we are so difficult we
don't want to eat like this we want to go
round and eat, then say...It is the simplest
thing. 'Sahaja Samadhi Lago', Sahaja you get
it. Is said by everyone who said it is difficult?
Who has said it tell me? No one. 'Ek hi akshar
premaka pade so pandita ho'.
Who has said it? Did Christ say so? Did Buddha
say so? Nobody said. But they could not do
it because people were difficult. So they
said all right go ahead, carry on. Krishna
at the very outset of Gita he said that you
find yourself. You become a 'sthita pragya'.
You become a realized soul, at the very outset.
But Arjuna says, "But how You are telling
me to go on war and here You are telling me
to become 'saakshi', the witness?"
Krishna was a Father. He said, 'This gentleman
won't understand in a straight way.' Because
Krishna is a special incarnation of diplomacy,
he understand how human beings are, like a
Father you see. He won't tell straight forward.
He will say 'all right you want to do it go
ahead.' You want to jump in the sea go ahead.
So He said, "All right," it's very interesting
we don't understand Gita also without Realization.
Like a father who comes out of his house and
sees his son trying to drive the cart.
So he says, "All right you want to drive the
cart please put the horse before the cart."
But the son says, "No I can put the horse
behind and drive the cart."
He said, "All right do it no harm. Only put
your attention there."
So he says that, "All right you do all your
work, but put it at the Lotus Feet of the
God."
You cannot do it, is an absurd condition.
You cannot do it; absurd condition. But when
you get your Realization you don't say "I
do it". You say, "It's going", "it's coming",
"it's working", "it's happening". You become
a third person; 'akarm'. The second he said
about 'bhakti' is the devotion. He said 'pushpam;
all the flowers and fruits and all these you
give Me, I take them' but where did He play?
On the word 'ananya' means you have to do
the devotion when you are not the other 'ananya'.
Now when are you like that? When you are one
within and also is logical that unless and
until you are connected within what sort of
a bhakti [devotion] you are doing here? You
must be connected. Only 'bhakti' you can do
is to say that "Connect me". But otherwise
if you are not connected, if the telephone
is not connected what are you telephoning?
Is as simple as that, is very logical. So
the whole 'Karma Yoga' and 'Bhakti Yoga' is
nothing but that you get your Self-Realization
first. Now this is the problem with human
beings that they want to live on words, but
how long? Nothing is difficult. So far I have
not seen it is a difficult thing to do. It
has worked out.
Any other question please?
[From the audience someone asks a question
related to astrology, the question is not
audible]
Mother: Is of no consequence.
Seeker: Is of no consequence?
Mother: No consequence
This is very subtle, above everything else,
makes no difference. But later on I find because
we are problematic people and the Kundalini
comes down to help you in different places.
And I find that sometimes the people how they
are made at their birth by astrology behave
in different manners. But still the sign and
all these things that are so gross do not
bind you. You just throw them away and get
out of it. So it's nothing important. You
go beyond all stars, beyond all science and
things. It is of help in a way; for example
they cast My horoscope in India and they discovered
something about Me and which is something
very fantastic I should say. It has something.
For example: discovering this, you may think
'what is it discovering this?' 'What was the
use of the Kundalini has nothing to do it?'
But today only on the radio I could give Realization
to many people. On the television you can
give Realization to people. So this is also
useful. Everything is achieved for Self-Realization.
Science has achieved everything for Self-Realization.
It is at the service of God and whatever is
not is all destructive. Even I would say atom
bomb is important otherwise people would never
have thought of God.
Seeker: Yes; On to religion, Catholics why
is it that they make such a do of the Pope?
He's only flesh and blood.
Mother: What do they do?
Sahaja Yogi: Why do Christians and Catholicism
particularly make such a thing of the Pope?
He's only flesh and blood.
Mother: You better go and ask them. About
this Pope John, I went with My Husband to
Cranko and being a VIP or something, they
asked Me, "What would You like to see?"
I said, "I would like to see some good Church."
So they took Me to Cranko where this fellow
was the Cardinal and they held some sort of
a mass. I was sitting there and then I shook
hands with him and had tea with him and I
rose his Kundalini. It came and went back
in the same shot. But sometimes when he is
talking sense, the Kundalini is up there;
you see it come up and goes down. Still he's
not established himself; the same fellow who
became the Pope. But why they make out of
it is this because Mr. Paul who is in the
Bible. I don't know why he's there; has done
all this. Now first you must ask Me a question
'Why Mother Mr. Paul is there in the Bible?'
Can you explain to Me that?
He never saw Christ; he had nothing to do
with Christ. Now I am asking you a simple
question you see, from God's side. Somebody
must ask from God's side also sometimes some
questions. All right now this gentleman was
just torturing Christians, he becomes epileptic,
he sees some cross as he says. Whatever it
is, sees something so what? And then he is
in the Bible. How come? Now he is not a free
soul. If you accept Paul, this I had said
long time back, you will have to give up Christ
and that's what is happening today. All right
and even Protestants because I took My birth
in Protestants, among Protestants. I know
them. I know about all of them - Christians
and Hindus and Muslims and every one, are
all funny fanatics. But the Protestants are
very sophisticated fanatics. It's impossible
to talk to them, specially in India. Oh baba!
They are so sophisticated, they've done all
the science of the Bible. They've made science
out of Bible. Bible is so great how can you
put it in the science? Science is a wee part
of it. You agree there with Me? So now first
let us accept we are first and foremost human
beings and we have to become super human beings
as realized souls. Whether you are Christian,
Catholics, Hindus, Muslims anything. It should
be such, how can it be different? Does God
know that you went to a Anglican Church or
to another Church? Does he, will he know?
Accha tell Me, do you think he will know all
these things? Do you think? Somebody must
be keeping a record. Do you think so? I mean
is it not ridiculous the way we fight about
these things. Can He keep record of all these
things?
And it's not only about Christians, it's same
in Hindus. Hindus are very fanatic, Sikhs
are fanatics, Muslims are fanatics; all blind
people are there. But they are good people
you know? They believe in it. They are innocent;
they believe that what they believe into is
the truth. They have to just know that the
truth is universal and is for everyone. You
cannot claim anyone as your own. Actually
by that you've killed the truth. Like a tree
has many flowers, living flowers you pluck
some of them saying this; this is mine, this
is mine and the flower dies and that ugly
flower becomes your fanatic religion. It's
not a living flower. In Sahaja Yoga we know
that all Prophets were right. What They said
were right; we believe in Them. We use Them
on these different centers and all the incarnations
we use, but as far as the outside religions
are concerned we think they need some cleansing
and light. Then everything will be all right.
You are Catholic? I mean you educated, I am
sorry now you are no. But whether the education
was in Catholic Church? If you want to hear
about Christians, go and ask Muslims. If you
want to hear about Muslims, go and ask Hindus.
If you want to hear about Hindus, go and ask
Buddhist. You'll get the full picture about
them. You see we can see what others are we
don't see what we are. True.
Sahaja Yogi: Any other question? Mother's
going to give you the experience tonight,
so why don't we do it now? Just lift your
shoes off so that your feet...
Mother: You better take out your shoes. That's
all I make humble request, that's all. I hope
it's not difficult to take them out. I'll
stand up I think. Paul, can you help Me please?
Sahaja Yogi: She wants to stand....
Mother: There are lots of saints behind sitting
there and you all have to become saints. For
that just you have to put your hands on your
lap as they do for Namaz like that because
these fingers as you will see there are indicative
of your sympathetic nervous systems, left
and right and they form centers. So just put
your hands like this. Now this hand represents
the power of desire as you will see on the
left hand side and this hand represents the
power of action. Now what we have to do is
to release our own centers by giving help
to them and the Kundalini will then rise immediately
because if the centers are augmented or constricted
then Kundalini has to fight it. To make things
easier for Her, we'll have to put our hand,
right hand on different centers, which I'll
tell you, which is very simple. You don't
have to do much about it.
So now the right hand that is the power of
action we'll be using for touching different
parts like the heart, the stomach, the lower
part of the stomach, then here at the base
of the neck like this and then here on the
forehead. Ultimately on top of our head where
the bone was soft, the fontanel bone area.
That's all. It's very simple one by one I
will tell you. Another thing very important
is that you should not open your eyes till
I tell you because the happening has to take
place within. Your attention should be inside
and not outside. It will be sucked in. You
don't have to do, don't fight with it, don't
fight with your thoughts, don't fight with
anything. Just let it loose it will work out.
You have to sit comfortably in a straight
manner without being lousy or without being
over alert. Just sit in a very comfortable
manner with your left hand towards Me and
the right hand on the heart. You may take
out your spectacles or anything because you
have to keep your eyes shut all the time.
It helps also the eye sight. Now put the left
hand on your heart.
Sahaja Yogi: Right hand
Mother: I am sorry put your right hand on
the heart and left hand towards Me.
At the very outset I have to tell you one
thing that you should not feel guilty about
anything because that's one of the biggest
hurdles in the West. So before saying anything
you have to tell yourself that 'I am not guilty,
I am not guilty, I am not guilty'. Close your
eyes and say that. You are not to put your
neck very much backwards or forward or in
any abnormal way, but sit comfortably. Now,
on the heart you have to put your right hand
and all the time keep the left hand towards
Me. At this stage you have to ask Me a question
because I said you are a computer and this
is a very absolute question. You can call
Me Mother or Shri Mataji whatever suits you.
'Mother, am I the Spirit?' Ask this question,
three times. Please don't open your eyes,
keep the left hand towards Myself and put
your right hand on your stomach in the upper-part;
in the upper-part of the abdomen on the left
hand side. We have to just look after the
left hand side of our centers. So put the
right hand on the left hand side of the upper
part of your stomach. Here lies the center
of mastery; the Guru, the Prophets. So here
you have to say, because you have already
asked a question that 'Mother, am I the Spirit?'
You have to ask now another question relevantly
with it. 'Mother, am I my own Guru?' Because
if you are the master, if you are the Spirit,
automatically you become the master. Unless
and until you are the Spirit you do not become
the master. So the second question should
be 'Mother am I my own master? Am I my own
Guru? Mother, am I the Prophet?' Three times
please.
Now, now we start with the real asking by
putting our right hand in the lower part of
our abdomen in the left hand side. The right
hand on the lower part of our abdomen, stomach,
on the left hand side and press it a little
bit. Here now is the beginning of asking for
the true knowledge, for the true technique,
for the pure knowledge. So please ask Me six
times because this center is very important
and has six petals, six sub plexuses it controls.
Please ask six times because I cannot force
you to do it unless and until you ask for
it because you are free. To respect your freedom
I have tell you that you have to ask 'Mother
may I have the true knowledge, the pure knowledge
of the Spirit?' six times. Now you must be
confident about it, you should not be diffident,
you should ask with full confidence.
Now, six times. Please don't feel guilty and
be confident. Now we have to raise it so we
go back to the same position on the left side
of our stomach in the upper part. Please put
your right hand on the upper part of your
abdomen on the left hand side. Now here you
have to assert with full confidence. Ten times
you have to say because there are ten valences
we have, we have Ten Commandments and ten
times the Primordial Master incarnated on
this Earth. So we have to say ten times in
full confidence 'Mother I am my own master.
Mother I am my own Guru. Mother I am the Prophet'.
Now please say it ten times. Don't feel guilty,
please don't feel guilty.
[Mother blows Cool Breeze twice.]
Now ten times; raise your right hand after
saying ten times, to your heart. Again here
there are twelve sub plexuses, so you have
to assert with full confidence by saying 'Mother
I am the Spirit', which is the truth. Without
feeling guilty you must say that because God
is the ocean of love, he is the ocean of compassion.
He is the ocean of forgiveness and what kind
of guilt you can have? What kind of sin you
can commit that He cannot forgive? So don't
try to count your sins and count your mistakes
and count your guilt just say, 'Mother I am
the Spirit'.
Now saying this about twelve times you raise
your right hand at the base of the neck and
press it hard on the shoulder. This center
is always caught up. So again I have to say
that for sixteen times you have to say, 'Mother
I am not guilty' and if you have the habit
of feeling guilty too much better say it hundred
and eight times to punish your self. I am
assuring you that you are not guilty but if
you want to say that again and again all right
go ahead with it for hundred and eight times.
Don't feel guilty otherwise you'll miss the
point.
[ Shri Mataji guides someone in the audience]
From the front hold it from the front not
from the back, 'saamne se hath lijiye, aise
pichese nahin, saamne se haath lijiye', tell
him. That gentleman also, that one. Haan!
Better from the front, much better.
Sixteen times; believe in yourself. Have faith
in yourself, forgive yourself. First of all
you forgive yourself. Or at the most you can
say that 'O Lord forgive me', but don't feel
guilty while saying that.
[Mother to Sahaja Yogi: You shouldn't disturb,
I know what to do. I don't want to listen
to you.]
Now... you have to raise your hand up to your
forehead
and here you have to say in a very simple
words, 'Mother I forgive everything, I forgive
everyone' with full heart in it. Now some
people told Me it's very difficult and this
and that but actually when you don't forgive,
what do you do? Or when you forgive what do
you do? Nothing, it's all mythical. On the
contrary you are torturing yourself by not
forgiving. So please say from your heart,
'Mother I forgive everyone'; on your forehead.
Now, now raise your hand on top of your head,
put it on the fontanel bone area, your palm
and press it and move it clockwise, your scalp.
At this point you have to say, 'Mother please
give me my Realization' because I cannot cross
your freedom again. This you have to say seven
times. But before doing that please say that,
'If I have done anything wrong, O Lord please
forgive me'. Without feeling guilty again;
three times. Now seven times you say, 'Mother
please give me my Self-Realization' because
I cannot cross.
[Mother blows the Cool Breeze twice...]
[What heat baap re...]
Now take down that hand.
[Mother blows Cool Breeze twice.]
Now put the left hand on top of your head
about four inches above and see for yourself
if there's a Cool Breeze coming in.
[Mother blows Cool Breeze seven times]
Now change your hands and see for yourself
if there's a Cool Breeze coming in. Right
side is clear, good. Now left side. Again
change your hands and see if there is a Cool
Breeze coming. Ah! better.
Mother to Sahaja Yogi: You have to ask the
master question, Holy Ghost; later not just
now.
Mother: Now those who are not feeling the
Cool Breeze raise your hands please. Please
raise them high so that they could see. Now
the Sahaja Yogis will come and attend to you.
Now don't get upset with them. If you are
not feeling the Cool Breeze raise your hands
and if you are feeling it you got it. She's
got it, Vishuddhi, it is, she feels guilty.
You felt it? Have you felt it? Not yet? All
right; Aapko nahin hua? Aarahe hai. Some have
felt, some have not felt doesn't matter.
Sahaja Yogi: Just describe again what they
should feel
Mother: You should feel a Cool Breeze coming
out of your head like a cooler. There might
be hot coming in doesn't matter. You got it?
Sahaja Yogi: ...He's got a Cool Breeze coming
from his hand into his head.
Mother: Correct! Now just see if it is coming
from your head or not. Just check. Tell him
to say that 'Mother come in my head'. This
lady, Derrick you go, just come and see. It's
better now, see. You may ask 'Is this the
Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost?' What about
this lady? Ya, no somebody should attend to
her and this one. Is there some another way
someone should come and attend to this lady?
'Aaapka nahin hua? Ho gaye? Aaraha hai? Ho
gaye paar? Paar utara gaye sant jana re. Haan'
From the audience: There's slight tingling
on this palm.
Mother: In the left hand? Ask him to ask the
question of Holy Ghost. On the left hand if
they have tingling you can very easily do
that.
Sahaja Yogi: Anyone who's getting the tingling
or not getting the vibrations on the left
hand...
Mother: No, no let them tell them privately;
don't make it open
Sahaja Yogi:...just put your left hand to
Mother.
Mother: Ask the question
Sahaja Yogi: Give me the Cool Breeze of the
Holy Ghost.
Mother: No, 'Are You the, Mother are You the
Holy Ghost?' I am asking to ask 'Mother are
You the Holy Ghost?' Aa raha hai (it's coming?)
left hand towards Me. Left hand towards Me.
From the audience: 'Mother, are You the Holy
Ghost? Are You the Holy Spirit?
Mother: All right the tingling has gone, the
answer has come, now recognize. May God bless
you. Now this gentleman, what about the one
who was worried about the Pope? Did he feel
the Cool Breeze? This lady she's got it. What
about you?
Lady from the seekers: ...tingle
Mother: tingle on both the hands?
Lady: ..On both the hands
Mother: She has both the hands give her a
bandhan. Haan ab bas shanti dharo, chit mein
hi shanti. This gentleman - Maria? You have
not forgiven; keep your eyes open and watch
Me and say 'Mother I forgive'.
Seeker: Mother I forgive everyone. Mother
I forgive everyone.
Sahaja Yogi: Getting less tingle? Just say
it again ..., while looking at Mother.
Mother: Ho gaya jagaran? Have got it. You
got it sir? Inke bhi ho gaya (he also got
it). Aap unke sar pe dekhiye aura (you see
on top of his head, aura). Haan has he got
it? Tingling left? Ask him to ask the question
of the Holy Ghost, you ask.
Just enjoy don't think about it; just enjoy
yourself, you got it. Now you have to establish
yourself that's the most important part and
in Leicester we have a very powerful Sahaja
Yogi, .. has spoken to you.
Sahaja Yogi: Just say 'Shri Mataji are You
the Holy Ghost? Shri Mataji are You the Holy
Ghost?'
Mother: Holy Ghost mane [means] Adi Shakti.
Haan
Sahaja Yogi: You are feeling it on your left
hand?
Mother: That's the answer. What about this
lady? She got it? She's got it.
Sahaja Yogi: ...she is Sahaja Yogi
What about her? Haan what about this one,
this gentleman with spectacles? Is she all
right...? Good. Dekhiye sab paar hogaye. Tell
him not to feel guilty. This gentleman here
Sahaja Yogi: Yellow shirt
Mother: Yellow shirt, please don't feel guilty.
What about the gentleman behind.....he's all
right, he's got it, he's got it. John you
better get their names, who belong to Leicester.
Maria, Maria come. Gavin I saw I think?
Sahaja Yogini: Yes he's here.
Mother: He's here; all right, all right. What
do you say comes up and down? Tie it up, tie
it up. Gavin...
Sahaja Yogi: ..he's the Indian gentleman
Mother: Haan he's what? Ask him to pull his
ears.
Sahaja Yogi: He's feeling it now, he pulled
his ears. Please work in silence. Please work
in silence. Please work in silence.
Sahaja yogi: It's very important that you
should follow-up this experience. There is
a center in Leicester and at that center they
can teach you very simple techniques some
of which you've seen being done now to purify
and remove these blockages in the charkas.
They'll teach you how to raise your Kundalini
how to establish it, how to develop your vibrations
and then ultimately how to cure yourself,
how to cure others and how to give others
self-realization. It's so simple that you
have to work it out together. John is going
to be here ultimately and meanwhile they are
going to have regular meetings so that you
can follow it up. John will tell you little
more.
[Mother: Agya; she has very bad Agya. Ask
her to forgive everyone.]
John: We'll be holding meetings every Thursday
evening at his place; probably in the other
room but in this building, 7.30 Thursday evenings.
If you come along we can help you to maintain
this experience and also to deepen it because
what's happened this evening is like a seed
as I say it's not become a old tree yet. It's
still a seed so by nurturing it, protecting
it, watering it so on. It will enable it to
grow and that's what you can do at these meetings.
Very soon you can learn as much as the Sahaja
Yogis here have learnt, maybe even more hopefully
by Shri Mataji's blessings. There's an address
list that we are taking if you'd like to leave
us your name and address we can then get in
touch and you know in any other big meetings
we can send you a post card reminding you
where our regular meetings are and we'll also
put in the address of the center, the Sahaja
Yoga center and then if you have any problems
any [stage?] or anything like that you can
contact us and we can tell you what to do
and so on. Thank you very much
[Mother: So I am very thankful for all this...What
was the name of the gentleman on the TV?
Sahaja yogi: The interviewer?
Mother: No the other person. He's the main
person...
Sahaja yogi: He's the editor, the film editor.]
Mother: Now I have to tell you one thing,
you should not discuss about your realization
too much. Please Sahaja Yogis also should
know. You see you are all Sahaja Yogis and
you have achieved it, but they are still just,
they have just gone into it. So try to understand,
they are not like you that whatever is the
situation you keep there. They, you have attained
it, they have to attain still. So keep quiet
and another thing is please don't think about
it don't talk about it too much. Work it out.
Its not that by talking is will work out on
the contrary the more you'll think about it
the worse it will be. It's like a small little
plant, a little shoot. We have to be now careful
with it, respect it and gradually when you'll
be coming to those meetings you'll develop
it. While the Sahaja Yogis who are here, all
are experts and whatever may happen even there's
earthquake...