The Shakti of forgiveness too is great.
You should also learn to forgive.
I see that, in Sahaja Yoga people forgive very little.
Learn to forgive,
Without forgiving, you cannot get realisation on your own.
For example, if somebody has hurt you,
and you didn't forgive him, then what did you do?
You didn't do anything.
If you didn't forgive, means, you didn't do anything.
Even if you forgive, strictly speaking means you didn't do anything.
But if you say, i forgive,
then by not forgiving, you were playing in other's hands
he loses all his Shakti.
The destructive power gets destroyed.
But those who are forgiving,
their Shakti is so powerful, that wherever they stand,
because of their forgiveness, people can become pious.
Their vices of numerous births, can be washed out.
From all previous birth's
whatsoever problems, they have accumulated, can be over,
because, he they have forgiven.
Redemption from all sins is obtained only by kshma Shakti.
Many a times, we say to God, "You are ocean of forgiveness !"
We also say, that you are the remover of sins.
We also say, "Destroy our papaas."
How can He do? Only by forgiveness !
By his uttering only one word 'forgive',
by his one sight, by the sight of forgiveness only,
all the sins are destroyed.
But because we have not seen such people,
We don't even think about such people,
We can't even believe, that such people can be in the world.
We have to find such people today.
And you know, what you were, are not today.
and what you are today, you won't be like that tomorrow.
Tommorow, such people will be in Sahaja Yoga,
who have kindness, forgiveness and peacefulness.
All these Shakhtis, are ignited.
On account of those, We will get all type of
comfort, pleasure and peace in the whole universe.
Those who have said,"I will do this, i will do that,
will bring all the comfort to the world,"
and many have said, that the world should be filled with happiness.
Marx has said, and you have come to know that many saints have said,
that whole world should be joyful. How can it be?
There is only one way.
When a human being, in his ascent, will find his Kundalini awakened
then his mental, spiritual and physical, material assets
not only this much, but in all respects
his Shakti will be so transformable,
that he will be able to transform every thing.
If there is any problem he will transform it
if there is a wave he will transform it
if there is a mountain he can climb it.
This great Shakti can come inside your being through Kundalini,
because you have achieved your Spirit.
So to receive this Shakti,
the small small laws of Sahaja Yoga should be followed.
First of all, forgive your self,
first of all, love yourself,
First of all know your self esteem.