When we say we are seeking, we must know that
we are a special category of people. People
were seeking before also. They were seeking
power, money, possessions, affluence, every
sort of thing. Still they are not satisfied
- those who have got it. And so those who
are seeking the truth are the highest, highest
of all in the evolution. They are the ones
who are going to jump into that higher state
which is called as self-realization.
If you are not seeking, then nobody can force
seeking on you. It cannot be done. Even by
force, if you take somebody to the beautiful
lake of nectar of God's love and even if you
force the person to drink it, it is you who
has to enjoy it and unless and until you have
the seeking, you will not have the sensitivity
to enjoy that nectar. And truth is what it
is. We cannot change it, we cannot organize
it, we cannot transform it. It is, it has
been, it will be.
And what is the truth? The truth is that God
loves us, that His divine power of love is
all-pervading, is everywhere, that this power
is acting all the time - it is a living power
of a living God - and that this power does
all the things that we call as living work
of God. A flower is transformed into a fruit
by this power. This body we get out of that
power. From amoeba to this stage we have come
out of that power. The whole world is created
out of that power. In everything that power
resides and works out, sorts out, co-ordinates
things for us. Above all, it is the love of
God. It's the compassion of God.
We human beings have not got the comprehension
of His love; we try to see Him through our
own angles, through our short sight, through
our blinkers that we have got. He is the ocean,
ocean of love. All the oceans put together
cannot be compared with that ocean of love,
that ocean of forgiveness, an ocean of complete
well-being for us. Only thing, we have to
jump into it. We have to enter into His kingdom.
That is what one has to do. When it is accomplished,
then you are just there. You are looked after.
That is the domain of God I am talking about
and there, when you enter in, as a by-product,
all kinds of well-being are blessed upon you,
just they are bestowed upon you. You just
get them automatically. But this happening
also is not our doing. This also is the doing
of God. He has arranged us in this way that
you can see in the chart - this is the life
tree - or you (can) say the tree of life as
described.
And this is the one that is within us already
placed. All these centers, which are subtle
centers, are expressed outside as gross centers.
When this residual force of Kundalini, which
people must have explained to you, from that
sacred bone or sacrum rises and pierces through
all these centers, it enlightens all of them
one by one. By that enlightenment only, you
get your physical well-being, your mental
well-being, your emotional well-being and
ultimately, your spiritual well being. That
means you become the spirit. Once you become
that absolute, the absolute, then all relativity
drops off. We actually live in a relative
world which is false, which is not true.
This power has its own telecommunication.
It's so tremendous that it is unbelievable
that such a power exists around us and we
are not aware of it. We are not aware of many
things. We are not aware that this Mother
Earth is moving with such a tremendous speed.
We are standing on top of that; nothing happens
to you. We are not aware of the gravity. We
are not aware of many things because God is
so kind, so gentle and so thoughtful that
He wants us to live happily as human beings.
So He doesn't want us to hear some things
which are not good for us, for our ears, so
He makes the frequency of these things so
sharp that we can't hear with these ears.
Some of them, He makes them so low that you
can't hear. Only what you can hear and enjoy
He makes you hear.
But we in our freedom have done a lot of wrong
to ourselves, to each other, to our society,
to the whole world. Once we realize, this
freedom is nothing but is our ego, our ego,
which has created this problem for all other
people. Then we have also another thing where
we get conditioned, which creates the superego.
Now in our activity, which is the right side
sympathetic nervous system, we accumulate
this horrible thing called ego, because when
we act, we think we are doing it, we are in-charge.
We are not. He is in charge. We are really
doing nothing. What are we doing?
Like the people ask me, "Mother how can you
cure everything so easily?" It's simple. How
do you make a flower into a fruit? To us,
we take it for granted. We are not bothered
to find out, but can you do it? It's so difficult.
Can you do it? We can't. But if it is God's
power, it can do it. So if you also have the
God's power flowing in you, which will happen
to you as soon as you get your realization,
you can do it; anybody can do it.
It's very simple. Like any instrument, when
it is put to the mains, it starts acting and
then we can see that it is an instrument.
Otherwise it looks like some funny stuff here.
It has to be put to the mains. The instrument
is ready, but within us these two things,
called the ego and superego as a result of
our activity and as a result of our conditioning,
are accumulated in our brain. These two are
to be sucked in. That's very important because
when they grow, these two elements - or two,
we can, say balloon-like structures - they
make a very strong gap filled with calcium
and you become an egg. Another becomes an
egg. Third person becomes an egg. You develop
your I-ness - I am this, I am that. All kinds
of misidentifications start coming on us.
When this is to be sucked, what should we
do? That's the question. What are we to do?
To raise the Kundalini. As I said, it is a
living process and you cannot do any living
work - so just can't do it. It is as simple
as that. You yourself can't do it.
But somebody who is enlightened, who is the
light, can enlighten another light, because
that light is ready, just ready, but you need
an enlightened light to enlighten that light.
Once that light is enlightened, that light
can enlighten another light. But the problem
is when the light which is enlightened tries
to say that "You are to be enlightened," immediately
you hit that person. You don't like it because
ego is there, which is ignorance. That's how
people like Christ were crucified. What wrong
did He do to people except that, see, He said,
"I am the light?" It's true. He was the light.
No doubt that He was the son of God. It's
true, He was the son of God which you can
prove - on vibrations. By this Sahaja Yoga,
you can prove it what He was. He was that,
but that time people killed Him. Why? Only
because He said, "I am the light," and that
you were to be enlightened by Him.
You allowed him to live only for four years,
and when He was killed, when He was crucified,
you took advantage out of that and made all
kinds of artificial things out of it. He could
not explain many things which He talked. He
could not say anything. On the cross He said,
"It has been accomplished." What has been
accomplished? Nobody thinks about it - what
has been accomplished. So we have to take
reference from other people, those who have
been deeper than us, who have gone into it,
who have found out certain things about Christ.
And they say that Christ accomplished the
greatest thing, the greatest feat, because
He was nothing but Omkara. He was nothing
but the vibrations. That's why He had no body
and only He could accomplish it. And what
did He do? Is to accomplish Himself on this
cross where we have this ego and superego.
Of course they say that He said he died for
our sins. How did He die for our sins? We
say that He died for our sins. We accept it,
yes, because Churches are telling, people
are telling, Bible is telling. But how? He
suffered for us. Then why are we suffering?
But when He said, "You are to be born again,"
we don't pay any attention to that. For that
you have found out an escape. You take your
child to the church and they put some water
artificially and you accept, "All right, we
are born again."
I met people who are certified born again.
They quarrel with me and fought with me for
nothing at all. I said, "How are you born
again? If you are born again, that means an
egg becomes a bird. Have you become something
different? Is there any transformation in
you? How do you believe? Why are you so self-opinionated?
If you are born again, what happens to you?
What happens to you? What is born again in
you?" Born again is nothing but the Kundalini
awakening, which rises on top of your head
and here is the seat of your Spirit. Of course,
it resides in your heart, but the seat of
the Spirit is here, and once it touches that
seat, immediately you start feeling that subtle
thing which is all-pervading within you. For
the first time you feel this cool breeze of
the Holy Ghost. Holy Ghost is nothing but
the power of God, the power of His love, which
is called as Adi Shakti in Sanskrit language.
We don't have to accept anything else from
outside, any dictionary we don't have to accept
to give answers to things, to mysteries that
we have been suffering all these days. Once
this cross, which is between the ego and superego
is enlightened, Christ is awakened there.
He sucks in both these things, your karmas,
your actions and your conditionings, your
sins. It is sucked in. There is no more for
you to suffer. Why do you want to suffer?
Some people have started another theory that
we must suffer if we have to go to Christ.
Why? Did He not suffer for you sufficiently?
Did He not do that? He has done it, then why
suffer? Be joyous that He established himself
there at that point. In the Hindu scriptures,
He is called as Maha Vishnu. But if I tell
this to them that this was Christ, they won't
believe Me. If I tell this to Christians,
they won't believe Me.
They don't want to believe it because for
them Christ is their contract. They have a
contract with Christ, as if they are the contractors
of Christ. Nobody dare say anything about
Christ. It's only they who are the Christians,
and they who are the Hindus, they who are
the Sikhs, they who are the Muslims and they
don't know anything about reality. Just fighting
morning till evening in the name of God, the
One who is the ocean of love, compassion and
bliss. They are so disturbed, so upset, so
violent that one can easily see there is nowhere
the blessings of God. There is no blissful
state. There is no peace in them. Because
there is no peace within, how can you have
the peace without?
And this is what it is that one should understand
- that in the name of God, many things have
been done which are absolutely against it.
They are anti-God activities because if you
become a fanatic, you are anti-God, absolutely
anti-God. You have to see that God exists
for the whole universe. Nobody can take His
contract and can organize it. When I say this,
of course there will be people who are interested
in things with which they are identified.
They want to carry on with that kind of identification;
maybe they get some money out of it, maybe
some sort of a name or something free.
But what is most important is your Spirit.
Why identify with anything else but your own
spirit? You cannot get money out of it. No.
The joy of Spirit is the reward of Spirit.
Why do you want money? Why do you want fame
for it? Why do you want anything of these
worldly things that are so transitory, temporary,
will finish off? Why not ask for something
that is eternal? Why not ask for the eternal
life of Spirit? And that if you ask, it is
at your door steps, you can get it. It's very
simple and easy. When you say it is simple,
people can't understand. They think, "How
can it be? You have to stand on your head
for one life then you have to stand on one
leg for one life." That's the idea they have
got about Christ. There is no need to do that
- Christ has done it for you. Believe me,
He has done it.
So now, how to understand it is simple? In
this room, say, there are so many lights and
we all can see each other. The room is enlightened.
But what did you do? You just switched on
one switch, very simple. If you ask anybody,
"How do I put the light on?" I just put. There
is a light there. Just switch on. That's how
you get the light. But for a person who has
never seen electricity, it must be a wonder.
How just switching on light, so simple. It
is not in a way. It is made simple for you,
but there is a big organization behind it.
There is a big history behind it and there
are so many people who are working it out.
There is a big machinery. In the same way,
whatever looks so simple to us is tremendous,
is great.
But God Almighty with His care and tenderness
doesn't want you to know anything about it.
Forget it. You just jump into it. You just
enter into the kingdom of God and enjoy the
bliss, that's all. Why do you want to bother
about these things? Of course, as we are very
thought-oriented, people want to know about
it. That's why one has to talk about these
things. But best is to get your enlightenment
first and then talk of it.
It's a headache to talk about the electricity
and about its history, where it enters and
the problems they have had and then after
all these when you have tumbled down, fallen
down, everybody hit each other, kicked each
other, then say, "All right, now it's very
simple. Just put on the light." It's better
to be other way round, that I say, "All right,
put on the light, and then we'll talk about
it."
I am so happy to see so many people in Cambridge
today, really very happy because I have been
here before also. But we had no response.
I was surprised. Here where there are many
false gurus are working out their tricks.
People have collected thousands of pounds
from this place, Cambridge, which is the seat
of learning. Here so many educated people
live, intelligent people live - have been
befooled completely and have been pampered.
Their ego has been pampered. They have gone
into such trips which are very dangerous.
We had somebody from Cambridge in Sahaja Yoga,
very well educated person, got into epilepsy,
going to such a horrible fellow. Lost all
his money, everything, bankrupt and also epileptic.
Educated, very well educated, first class
boy, ruined for his life. But why it happens
to us, we must think. Why we are enamored
by such people? Because we believe in the
superficial thing; because it is being advertised
in such a way. These people come with a circus
because they have to attract you. They have
to attract you for their purses. They have
to attract you for their own powers because
they want that people should be dominated
by them because they can extract money.
Their interests are very low, base and we
don't see it. We don't understand it. They
pamper our ego. They talk of big things, "We
are going to make you a minister. We are going
to do this." We say, "All right." We follow
all this nonsense. Imagine. This ego is such
a tricky thing. It plays tricks not only with
others but plays with yourself also. It cheats
you. The so-called intelligence of the ego
can cheat you and that's how many people are
lost. Those who are seekers of ages are lost
because these horrible satanic forces know
how to play the trick, how to play the trick
with you and how to take you to their own
domain of satanic forces by which they could
extract all your blood.
I am so sorry when I hear that these things
have been happening all over. But in the places
where there has been the seat of love, the
Goddess Saraswati reigns, where people educate
themselves, all these thing have come slowly
and settled down. There are other things also
which are very dangerous. Like people who
are, call themselves, psychologists. They
can be very dangerous people. They are unauthorized.
They have no idea about the psyche. They don't
know that psyche also has another side, which
is the right side, which is the ego.
They can be very dangerously placed - person
like Freud. I don't know how people believe
in him. In England, there are so many Freudians.
I am surprised because I used to think that
at least English are the wisest among all
the Europeans. But more than the place where
he was born and worked out in Vienna, there
are more in England. It is most surprising,
what has happened to our wisdom. Even logically
we can see that he was a hopeless case. First
of all, he had bad relations with his mother.
Can you imagine? He had no sublimity of any
kind. He was worse than an animal. And secondly
that he died of cancer in such a miserable
condition. And he was nothing but a miserable
personality. How can you follow a man like
that blindfolded because he suggested that
you are a sex point. All your relations are
based on sex. There is nothing sublime. Now
see where is the sex point. It is the last
- here there is the red - and here resides
the innocence. This first center, which is
the innocence within us, is the child within
us, is looking after the Mother Kundalini
that you have. She is your Mother. Everybody
has their own Mother settled down in their
sacrum bone, so sweetly, waiting for an opportunity
to get this realization. She is going to give
you your second birth and she is going to
work it out and this innocence of yours which
you may kill any amount, it's still there
and they attack that innocence.
Today I find in all the western countries
there is a big attack coming on their innocence,
on the children. They do not understand that
there is - sex has nothing to do with your
evolution. It is not important for your evolution.
Of course a married sex which is a sensible
sex, which has a sanction with the collective,
is very important, no doubt, for the society
and everything. But here if you play about
with your sex, it's a dangerous game. It gives
you all kinds of diseases; it gives you impotency,
all sorts of other problems and worst of all,
insecurity in the whole atmosphere especially
for the children.
This is what it is. We have not been able
to use our brains. Use your brains. God has
given you brains, come to logical conclusion.
Like the Mayor yesterday asked me, "What do
you do with them?" I said, "First I will bring
them to logical conclusion." See what should
we expect. We have known that Christ has said
that, it is written, "Thou shall not commit
adultery." I say, "Thou shall not have adulterous
eyes." Are we Christians aware of these warnings?
Not to have adulterous eyes, just the opposite
we have. So that the eyes should be clean.
There should be no lust in our eyes. It is
to be at that point, not at the eye level,
not at the brain level. It is at that point
and it should reside there. There is placed
your innocence, because innocence guards you
against all wrong doings, all wrong things
that you do with your sex, and that's how
you get into troubles and you have problems.
Yesterday we had people there, many people
came and as the radio fellow has told me that
you better talk about how you cure people.
They will be very much interested. I told
them all how it happens and we did cure so
many people there, of many problems and so
many things can be cured and if you want , you
can get My tape to know about them, how it
happens and what chakras give you this. But
in short I'll tell you how we develop problems
within ourselves.
Now one thing I would say, that when I am
discussing this, human mind is so funny that
immediately they start reflecting upon themselves.
Firstly they will feel guilty. "Oh, I have
done this". Immediately they will start thinking
that, "I have got cancer," or, "I have got
leukemia," or "I have got that." So if I tell
you about the symptoms, it can be very critical.
There is a very interesting book I read long
time back when I was a child, "Three Men in
a Boat." I am sure all of you must have read
it. It's a very interesting one. In that a
character of one gentleman who said that never
read Materia Medica, the book about medicine.
Once he read it and he thought he had every
disease, every disease except for housewife's
knee and the doctor was amazed when he told
he has this disease, he has that disease.
He said, "Why not a housewife's knee?" He
said, "Because I am not a housewife." Otherwise
he had practically every disease and he wanted
a medicine for that. doctor was - that time
doctors were wiser I think, he didn't want
to take money out of him - so he said, "All
right, I have given you the medicine but you
have to take it when you go away from here.
Go to your bedroom and then you can take this
medicine." He went home and opened that and
there was nothing but a paper, and on the
paper it was written, "You are the greatest
fool I have ever come across. Never read Materia
Medica again and you are absolutely healthy."
So when you start telling them how the diseases
are caused, also people can start thinking,
"Oh, I must be having this trouble and that
trouble." Nothing of the kind. Please don't
think like that. I am just telling you because
you should not go into it again and it should
not happen to you in future, not in the past.
And those who have had problems also can be
cured. It's not difficult. It can be cured.
When you get your enlightenment, you can cure
people. You can also cure. It's not difficult.
So, now we start from the imbalances that
we have. For example, a human being has another
funny habit - is to go to extremes. If you
tell him, now in the Newspapers or, say, in
the TV it appears that your legs should be
like this, the measurement of the legs appear,
or the measurement of the body appears, all
the ladies will try to be that, to become
like the form that is given. But why? It is,
it might be some sort of an enterprise that
people are trying to sell something just to
make you thin or fat or whatever it is and
that's why they are publishing these things.
Why just you go into it headlong? May not
be required at all for you. Now when they
do it, they do it so much, so much overdo
it that they develop really the problems which
never existed in them .They were normal people
and suddenly they become sick people.
So in this way, we have so many extremes we
go to. For example, we are people who are
right-sided and left-sided as you can see
here, the people who are emotionally very
rich and who go to the emotional extremes
and the people who are more mentally rich
and who go to the mental side more. Those
who have any desire and just work with their
desires and weep for it and they are the most
unhappy and the most miserable people - I
couldn't get this and I couldn't get that
- they are the left-sided people. The right-sided
people are that "Why did he get that?" "I
must also get it." Such aggressive people
are right-sided.
Now the people who are on the left hand side
think of their past, "I was so very happy.
Now I have married this wretched man and I
am very weak." The man will say, "I have married
this wretched woman," or some sort of a thing.
They go on worrying about themselves for nothing
at all and making themselves miserable. So,
we have two types of people. The another,
one extreme case we can say, is Hitler. Hitler
was the one who was so aggressive. He used
his aggressive policies. He got people who
were dead who were aggressive and used them
to entice, to become aggressive. They could
not see through. They could not understand
that they are not a special race and they
became such racists which one can't understand
with Human understanding that how can there
be a race superiority when God has created
all of us. It's nonsense. It's absolute nonsense.
It has no meaning, no basis. It's not natural.
God has created everybody separately in a
different way but this kind of a thing comes
into the mind. Then you are identified with
certain ideas on the right hand side that
you are an aggressive person.
On the left hand side, as I told you, a person
makes himself miserable because he thinks
of the past, but on the right hand side, the
people make others miserable and aggressive
sort of. Both sides are wrong. You have to
be in the center, neither in the future, nor
in the past. So how to be in the center is
the problem. By saying it or by brain-washing
it, it cannot happen. For that the Kundalini
has to rise but you have to keep the balance.
You shouldn't go to the extreme of anything.
You should not become identified or clubbed
with something which is not normal. We should
treat it with normalcy about it. Like if you
ask a person now, "You have to do Hatha Yoga"
There is a new system that has started, Hatha
Yoga, without knowing what this Hatha Yoga
is. What was the basis of Hatha Yoga? There
are Ashtangas and all these things have to
be done. I have seen people doing only that
little part of it, the Vayayama, which is
so indiscriminate, which has no sense as to
what chakras are catching, where is the Kundalini,
what is the problem. Such people can develop
heart problems, tremendous heart problems
they can develop, and they can be extremely
negative people because though they appear
to be very positive, they can be very, very
dry. They can develop divorces. They can be
very aggressive. A time will come when they
will have no emotions. Even when their own
child dies, they will not feel it. They can
be very, very dry. Now we don't see that dryness
in the back. We do not see that that we are
not feeling the emotions of another person.
We do not think that that is important.
Left-sided people are the other way round,
as I told you. But when they go to the extreme,
first they go into their subconscious. In
this they see what had happened and they think
of their previous lives and all that and then
they can go into the collective sub-conscious
if they go on pressing it too much. Or some
of the people who are interested in their
purse, all such base things, can entice them,
can hypnotize them, completely hypnotize them
and push them on to the left side.
Now cancer develops on the left side. Leukemia
develops from the left side. Multiple sclerosis
develops from the left side. I haven't seen
one patient who has come to me, who is having
cancer, having leukemia or multiple sclerosis
who is a right-sided person. And ultimately
they can be epileptic, or they can become
lunatic or schizophrenic. All those things
can happen to them.
The right-sided person, on the contrary, will
get a heart attack. He'll get a heart attack.
Definitely he'll get a heart attack, if he
goes too much with it. But first of all he
might develop a liver, very bad liver, hot
temper with it. He may develop a pancreas
trouble that could be the diabetes. He could
develop the spleen trouble which could be
a kind of a leukemia which comes out of speediness
but it has to triggered by the left side so
it is between the - first the anemia and all
that will happen and ultimately he can get
leukemia after that. And many children also
become patients of leukemia because their
parents are speedy. Extremely speedy people
get leukemia because they are all the time
acting on emergency. Simultaneously, they
are working on various things like, you are
driving, you are eating, you are listening
to the radio - horrid news. Early in the morning
you see in the newspaper, all horrid thing
are there. They will never give a good news.
You'll be amazed. We have been trying to tell
people that we have found out solutions to
many things - please publish at least one
line, half a line - but they would not.
But if there is a calamity somewhere, a horrible
thing happened, early in the morning, you
open the newspaper, it's the only thing that
is talked of. You become so much upset that
emergencies that... Then you have your breakfast,
you have to catch the train, you have to rush
up, you rush up, then you find that your train
is delayed, you start shouting. Specially
you all get worked up. Ultimately what happens
is that your spleen goes out of gear. It becomes
crazy. When it becomes crazy - it's a speedometer
- it controls our speed and you become so
speedy that nothing can fit into you and the
speed of the production of red blood corpuscles
is so much increased that they become malignant.
But of course the triggering, as I said, comes
from the left side.
So sometimes the right side can create a condition
for the left side to act - can also be just
the left side can work out. If a person is
affected, say, by a position, if he lives
near a funeral place or some place where there
is a cemetery or in the churches also you
have all the dead bodies there - I mean it's
something I can't understand. People don't
know about that. Why to put in the churches,
the dead bodies?
I mean, normally, anybody who dies must be
cremated except for the realized souls. Realized
souls are to be buried. It's a simple thing,
because they give fragrance to the Mother
Earth, they give fragrance to everyone. But
if you bury a person who is not a realized
soul - supposing he is an evil genius - you
know about this that the souls wander about.
And I have lived, since I have come to London,
always near a church. I have found all these
souls coming up in the night and they are
horrible things and we walk over them. They
are sleeping there and we trod on them. It's
a wrong thing. People have no idea as to how
to deal with the dead and that's how people
have also created a double problem. The cemetery
is in the city. The center of the city, there
will be a cemetery. All children are going
there. Everybody is going there. Pregnant
women are going there and these busy bodies
can attack you. It's a fact. They exist. There
is no doubt about it. Even the doctors say
that there are proteins which they call as
Protein 52 and Protein 58, like that, and
these are the proteins which invade us, our
being by which cancer is triggered. And what
they say that this comes to us from an area
which is built within us since our creation,
means from collective sub-conscious. But,
I mean, they cannot put it together as I am
putting it because they see things from outside
(and) I see things from inside.
Now when I tell about this, people don't like
it but it's a fact. You should not play about
with spirits. These spiritualists, these charismatics
and this sect and that sect..., Penticostals
are nothing but possessions and these possessions
can be horrible and most of the lunatics and
all these people are with possessions. You
must have seen a woman walking. Suddenly she
becomes blank. Her eyes are open, nothing
wrong with her. Doctors can't cure. She can
be easily cured if you can remove the possession
from her. These are all horrible things, which
can ruin your life and you do not understand
why doctors cannot understand because they
don't understand that there can be spirits.
They don't want to accept it. You can't see
the spirit until and unless you become a Spirit.
That is the problem, is that in English language
there are three meanings of the word spirit.
One is the Spirit that is Atma. Another is
the spirit which is dead and the one that
you drink is also spirit. So you can understand
how can you have three words, which are just
opposite each other meaning the same? Now
I am praying (to) the Spirit which is in the
heart, which is the reflection of God almighty.
But this Spirit, unless and until it is awakened,
no use talking about it. Better have it done
so that you know how beautiful you are, how
God has created you with such beauty, care,
and you are all there intact. Nothing is missing.
You don't have to worry about it. You just
don't have to think about it. "Oh, Mother,
how can I be? I have done this. I have done
that." Please don't think. First thing that
I always say before starting the program,
before the demonstration of it or before the
manifestation of it, that first of all say
in your heart of hearts, "Mother, I am not
guilty." That's one thing, this idea that
you are guilty, is absurd. It has no meaning
at all. It is not even a speck in that Ocean
which cleanses you.
So you don't have to say that - that, "I am
guilty." Please, for heaven's sake, all of
you have to say that in your hearts before
we start any program further. Because how
can you be guilty? As He is the compassion
- you can't imagine what compassion He has.
He is forgiving. He is complete forgiveness.
At that time if you have to feel guilty, you
really insult His power of forgiveness. So
we should not feel guilty about anything.
Whatever has happened has happened. Forget
the past, doesn't matter. It is a very important
time, important moment you have arrived. The
time of resurrection has come. The time of
blossom has come. You have to become the truth.
It has to work out and it will work out. May
God bless you all.
I would request you, if you have any questions,
you can ask me questions. But don't ask irrelevant
questions and, you see, offensive questions.
That's very wrong because, you see, I have
nothing to get out of you - nothing I tell
you - except that little politics about it
that I am a Capitalist in the sense that I
have all the powers within myself and I am
a Communist because I can't live without sharing
it. That's the problem and that's why I am
here and so people should not ask questions
which are offensive for nothing at all.
If you want to get it, you can get it. I cannot
force you as I have told you in the very beginning.
It cannot be forced. I cannot promise you.
I am sure it will work out, if you little
bit co-operate with me. So be kind to yourself
and be open. You need not have blind faith
about me, not at all, not at all, but you
should be open to receive. If it works, well
and good. If it doesn't work we'll see it
the next time, doesn't matter. I am going
to be in London at least for three years more.
I hope so. May God bless you all.
Now please ask me some questions.
Q. When you say that spiritualists ....spirits
are wrong..is it wrong for someone who knows
the secret to try and do something about it
....what is so wrong with it?
Shri Mataji: You see the spirits are the dead
spirits, are the people who belong to another
country. They belong to another state. All
right? They are in the subconscious area.
If you start allowing them to walk into our
lives, there will be many who will come around
as immigrants, you see. And you don't know
what they are up to and they will attack you.
Moreover, those people who are realized souls
or of higher nature never stay back. They
know that this is over and we should go back.
Moreover, it is our responsibility also to
see that we do not trouble them. I mean, we
have used them; they have lived with us. Now
we should give them their freedom. By keeping
them around, we torture them. We trouble them.
And sometimes they can be very, very troubled.
Even if they are good people, we really trouble
them. Let them go. That's not the time that
they should be here and they will be back
again. Why trouble them? It is because you
are identified with them.
Now about sickness, people say that for sickness,
I have known people who are spiritualists,
who try to cure. But what they do is to remove
one spirit and put another one into it. If
a person, say, he is a person who is wasting
money, say in horse riding, so if you remove
him from there, he'll become an alcoholic.
If not, he'll start beating his wife. Because
there is no transformation, you see. There
is a gap always if you ....so it is better
not to have some sort of a screw there which
is always to be replaced by something else.
So these spiritualists, also those who try
to heal, are just giving you relief in the
physical being. Physical being is not so important.
It is part of it but we are not only physical
beings. We are also mental beings and emotional
beings. If you try to be only physical being,
do everything only for the physical side,
then you forget the spirit. And the spirits
get angry with you. So you are three of these
things which are to be integrated through
your spiritual ascent. All right? So that's
why in any case that kind of a work is of
no help in any way to ask because ultimately
we have to see to the general good of everyone
.
I have seen spiritualists who have been acting
as spiritualist end up their lives very miserably,
most of them. Not only that but whenever they
are in a program you get tremendous heat from
them. All those people who have tried such
tricks... I'll give you a very good example
of Doctor [unclear: Lang or Land Side B 11:35],
who was, who died - late Doctor [Unclear:
Land or Lang] International Curative Centre
was in London, I don't know if it is still
existing or not. I came to know about it because
so many people in India suffered from that
curative center. And they came to me. I had
no idea. Now this gentleman died long time
back and his spirit entered into a soldier,
not into his son, but to a soldier in Vietnam
or something. And this soldier, now they write
all this story, I mean they are very frank
and honest - I must say they are not hiding
anything. So this gentleman came to England
and told the son that I am the father and
he told him secrets where things are and all
that and he convinced him that he was the
father. He said that you open a clinic with
this name - Late Doctor [Unclear: Land or
Lang] International Curative Centre.
Now what they used to do, you see, he got
hold of many doctors who were sort of unhappy
or some sort of thing or those who were lingering
behind. So, he used those spirits and what
he did by using those spirits, he used to
write a letter, which I have seen myself,
in many cases, that at this time, at this
hour, we will enter into your body. I mean,
they frankly told. They didn't say that "We
are going to do anything divine, and we'll
enter into your body and when we enter into
your body, then what will happen, that you'll
start shaking. Don't be worried. It is we
who are in you, and once it happens," - it
would happen after three months or four months
but they would give exact timing - "and then
you'll feel better."
Now these people who came to me suffered from
tremendous nervous trouble. And out of all
these who came, even one percent I could not
cure - one percent. They were such gone cases.
They had a miserable old age and I still know
of a lady; she just lays down in her bed and
goes into tremors and things and nobody can
help her. I haven't got time to pay so much
attention to one individual only. So it's
a miserable case. Every time I go there, she
meets me. I put her right. Again she goes
back to her bed (and) again she gets ill.
It's a very long process. I am not here to
cure you, I must tell you very frankly, but
to give you realization. But as a by-product
of that, you all get cured. That's it. Just
as a by- product of that, you get cured.
Moreover, you must understand that God is
the source of all common sense. He will only
cure such lamps which will be His lights later
on because we don't look after lamps which
are gone cases. So they can be born again.
But God looks after those people who can give
His light to all. Of course, many people get
cured. I have seen in London, the first wave
of Sahaja Yoga started - we have thousands
of them they got cured. But out of them very
few really took up Sahaja Yoga and helped
others. They just forgot. Of course, they
have tremendous respect for Me. When I go
to India; they all fill the hall and all that
is there. But they are doing nothing for Sahaja
Yoga. They are not doing anything curing for
others. They are not raising their Kundalini.
They are not giving realization.
It's really... sometimes I feel that so many
people have been cured, so much God has done
for them, but they don't understand why God
has done it for them . It is to give it to
others. You don't have to do so much for Sahaja
Yoga. You don't have to pay a single pi [short
form of Paise]. Nothing is needed. Only thing
is, God has given you this power. All right,
just give it to others. That's all. It's very
simple. And you feel so happy. You are so
employed by God that you do not feel bored
at all. It's such a wonderful thing.
But one must accept that if He has been kind
to us we have to be kind to others. It will
just automatically work, no doubt. It works.
I know people get cured, no doubt about it.
Any other question please? Yes, please - little
loudly....can you say loudly, please?
Q. Why is the picture sitting on the table
lying next to you?
Shri Mataji: Why? You don't like it? It's
a question really something I can't understand.
You see, if I am something, if this picture
is My true picture, then why not have it?
All the pictures you have of Christ are not
His own. Very few people have seen Him and
also there is no one who has taken His picture.
Actually, when I see the pictures of Christ
I get a shock. I said, "How can this be Christ?"
I mean, this miserable creature cannot be
Christ at all, but you don't mind having all
these things around.
Even the cross that you have can be horrible,
made of plastic, made of this, made of that.
That gives horrible vibrations to you. You
don't know anything about it. With this picture,
you'll be surprised, the person who first
got realization got through this picture.
In this picture there are vibrations. When
you will get realized, you will know that
only this picture has that vibration because
the real thing it is - thank God that science
has given us the real thing. If there were
cameras before, we would have had pictures
of all those great people. Because there were
no photographs they said, "Better not have
any pictures." Because all the pictures were
imaginary, done by people who wanted to have
some money. With this picture, many people
have been cured. All right? Especially in
Australia, a miracle happened. That's how
media took me over.
There was a lady, a friend of a very big journalist
and a businessman there who was in coma and
doctors said she has got a brain trouble and
she cannot come back to her normal condition.
There is a damage in her brain and she is
dying. Then everybody had given up hopes and
there was one Sahaja Yogini and she said,
"All right, you just allow me to put this
photograph under her pillow." And you'll be
surprised: she came to consciousness next
day. By the time I reached there, she was
very conscious. So all the media was there
to receive me in Australia. I was surprised
because media is the last which attends to
anything that is real. I was Myself aghast
to see them there. But it's one thing, no
doubt, and it's really true and it happened
and now that woman is walking about. You can
write to her and find out. So this is what
it is.
It's a very good thing that has happened that
we can take pictures now because I think,
I cannot meet everyone in this world but they
can at least see my picture. People get cured
by this picture. What's wrong? Supposing your
picture was like that, I would like to put
it there. But is it like that? That's the
point. You see some people say, "Why you are
doing it?" I say, "Better you do it. I would
like to retire." Actually, today my husband
was very angry with me. He said, "Why are
you there on Saturdays? Why don't you come?"
I said, "Now it has been advertised too much.
I just can't come." He is not, he wants me
there for some purpose and he was not very
happy about it.
So I would be very happy if you could sit
down here and do the job. You see, I'll be
very happy. I'll retire. But you can't do
it. And why to feel bad if I can do it? Because
you can do many more things that I cannot.
For example, I can't drive, I don't know how
to write a check, I don't know anything that
you know. So many things there are that I
do not know. You'll be amazed. I am so simple
that people can call me a rustic woman because
I don't know many things that you know. But
I know one thing: that is awakening of your
Kundalini, and then another thing is that
this photograph also knows you somehow.
Yes please?
Q; How did you discover such a quick way of
self realization?
Shri Mataji: Must be something about Me, sir.
You better find out. It's true. It's true.
But something about Me, definitely. You see,
whatever our education is, you have come to
us with wisdom and all that, it has come to
us through other English writers and western
writers. But if you really go into the literature,
you will know that it is already prophesized.
Even William Blake has prophesized absolutely
about Sahaja Yoga. He said that God of men
[men of god?] will become prophets and they
will have powers to make others prophets.
But who reads Blake? No one;they read Freud.
He's described to such a detail about Sahaja
Yoga that sometimes I am amazed. No Indian
seer has seen that what William Blake has
seen.
But our mentality is funny because once he
had his exhibition; I went to see his exhibition
and people were looking at nude women that
he had painted. He was innocent. He didn't
paint any nudity; he just painted women without
any dress, just the body. But they were looking
at the nude women. So, look at our mentality.
Looking at William Blake also we praise him
because he has painted women without dress.
He was innocent.
It has to be done. The time has come. At the
beginning of life, I know there were hardly
one or two people, but today is the time,
a time where many have to become. As you know,
on the tree of life there were few flowers.
Now there has to be many flowers because the
blossom time has come and it has to be simple.
But supposing it is simple, must you not accept?
It's like my grandmother saying, "I don't
believe you can go to moon. How can it be
possible?" It's like that. It's a jet age.
If there is speed outside, if the tree is
growing outside too much, something must have
grown inside: the roots. And this is the knowledge
of the roots which you do not know, which
you should know, how it has grown, what it
is sucking. All right? If it is so, why not
have it?
I mean, if I say there's a diamond, will you
refuse it? You'll say, "All right, if it's
diamond then let us see." It's more than all
the diamonds put together. It's true. It is
very simple to understand if you see God's
point of view. This creation has to have a
meaning. And you are going to give it the
meaning. If it doesn't work out, this creation,
it is going to destroy, because human beings
are going to be destroyed. You can see that.
You can see around what is the situation is.
Q: [Unclear Side B 22:57]
Shri Mataji: It's a little confused question
because, you see... but I understand what
you are trying to say, that people are seeing
it through now because they are intelligent.
They are seeing through and it has reached
a certain culminating point, you see. All
these philosophies have reached certain culminating
point and they are seeing that, what is the
result. Now the time has come for them to
see the result of all their mental projections
we have had about everything. So people are
thinking that there must be an answer to all
this. Whatever we have done may have been
little wrong or something has been more linear.
It is not expanding us and it is not giving
us what was promised to us. So they are thinking
about it and they are going down to find out
the answers. That's why there is a seeking,
no doubt. But it is also the plan that they
should be here, that they should be on this
earth at this time.
All, so many things have worked out. But the
reason is that there is confusion today. In
this confusion only, you are going to find
it out. If you were not confused, if you were
sure that you are doing the right thing and
you have done whatever is right which was
before this, then you would not have thought
of it. But just now people are seeing that
we are relatively living: "This is also right.
This is also right." How can that be? If right
is one then it should be one. So people are
thinking about it. They are seeking. In this
seeking they might do mistakes. And people
might do many mistakes like going to wrong
gurus, might spend money for it, may become
bankrupts, might go to drugs, might do this
punk rock... all kinds of things. They are
nothing but expression of that feeling within
that there is something beyond.
It's true that this confusion has led to this
seeking. No doubt about it. Because they are
all challenged. These philosophies are challenged.
Everything is challenged. And people see that
it has given no result. Our forefathers did
the same; we are doing the same. What's the
use? We have to reach somewhere. For example,
Jung has talked of universal unconsciousness
much before I came. They have prepared the
stage for Sahaja Yoga, I should say. All right?
Q: [Unclear : something about another guru...
Side B 25:51].
Shri Mataji: Oh, now don't ask about them.
What do you think about him? What have they
done? What good have they done to you? In
general, there is one principle you must apply
to all of them. On the gross, anybody who
is interested in your money is not your guru;
he is a parasite, on the gross. In the subtle,
anybody who doesn't manifest your powers has
no powers of his own. These two you apply
to every guru and don't ask Me individual
question. The one who is interested in Rolls
Royce, I mean if you think him to be a guru,
I must say this is something surprising. Very
surprising. It's a [not clear: sounds like
paras attitude Side B 26:52]
Yes, he can... [probably Mother permitting
someone from the audience to ask a question]
Q:[unclear question. Sounds like: I wonder
whether you have anything in your faith which
corresponds to the Apostles? In the Scriptures?
Do you have any Apostles? Side B 27:46]
Shri Mataji:. It's again confused, my child,
but doesn't matter. Let's see now...they had
a hot air on their head. Did you say so? When
was it? Where was it written? You saw it in
pictures?
Reply : In the scriptures. [unclear: Pentecost
Side B 27:53]. He sent out twelve men to do
his work.
Shri Mataji: Yes, it's all right. Now, I'll
tell you what. You see, hot air will come
out of everybody's head now. Even you are
sitting here. Because there is heat within
you. First the hot air will come out. You
see, Christ tried to give them realization
but they didn't believe Him. Believe me that
they never believed Him till he got His resurrection.
No, till they got His resurrection you see.
Till He got his resurrection, they were still
like this you see, little half baked, not
fully there. And that's why the hot air came
out .
You will see now, gradually as you'll settle
down in Sahaja Yoga, when you will be fully
equipped, when your vibrations will flow well,
it will be cool breeze. Otherwise, hot air
comes out. You see, with people who have...
most of you will first have hot air, no doubt
about it because there is heat within you.
Now, I will tell you people very frankly about
it that when it is hot, say for example take
Helium, Helium is a gas - you know that. When
it is hot, all the molecules in it fight within,
revolt against each other. They are absolutely
volatile. But when it cools down, they become
collective and they move in a collective way.
Even in science it has been shown and it is
the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost which has
been described in the Bible also. So it should
be a cool breeze because even the Apostles
that Christ had, they did not get their realization
fully because they were doubting Him. Not
doubting, I would say they did not have that
faith till they saw He was resurrected. And
after resurrection to have faith was rather
wrong, isn't it? Untimely, I should say.
I can understand that. That time, you see,
this was not there. I mean, to talk of realization
itself in that country was something so out
of the blue. They were fishermen, not Cambridge
students, and you could not explain to them.
But still they were simple people and they
were honest, no doubt about it. But to their
honesty, they could not understand how...
what this man is saying about self-realization
or of second birth, you see. And so they doubted
- was all right at that time. But today it
is not all right because once you get realization,
you see for yourself. All right?
Q: [Unclear: also had this experience after
the resurrection Side B 30:10]
Shri Mataji: You see, they had faith with
Him. But I wouldn't say they got realization,
except for John, I would say; but others,
I am not very sure. Because the way they write
about His works, it's something an outsider
writes, you see. It's just a ... not a person
who is innate. You see, when they write, that's
not there, I find. But the worst of all I
feel is about St. Paul who should not be there
at all. He had nothing to do with Christ.
I can't understand why he is there because
according to Sahaja Yoga standard, he was
a supra-conscious personality. I don't know
why he put them there because he saw a cross
or he did all this. He was the one who was
killing all the Christians to begin with and
then suddenly, I don't know how - it was a
Roman trick perhaps to put him there - I don't
know why but somehow I cannot explain it.
[Interruption by an audience - UNCLEAR Side
B 31:01]
No, that's not the experience. Experience
is different. The experience you can get it.
You see, the other day only one lady saw a
cross on me. She saw auras. Another one saw
something else; that's not the thing. That's
not reality.
Q: You are saying his experience did not exist
but yours is existing.
Shree Mataji: Yes, because that you can also
get an experience. Supposing you are taking
LSD; supposing, all right? Anybody is taking
LSD, they come and see Me. They just see lights
coming out of Me. They don't see Me at all.
[Interruption UNCLEAR Side B 31:41]
Shri Mataji: You see, you also are taking
too much time of others. All right? Now leave
it. You come and see Me, we'll talk about
it. You see, we should see what have we got
out of it. All these discussions and these
dogmas - what have you got? You see, what
are we going to achieve out of it? Just think
of it. What is the use? You have to get the
reality. Why discuss all these things? We
have so many clergies here who have been studying
Bible and all that and they are now fed up.
Their heads are off now. This dogma, that
dogma, this, that - it's over now. Finish
it. Just get the reality first then we'll
talk about it. All right? You just get the
reality, then.
Q: [Unclear Side B 32:27]
Shri Mataji: Of course, that you will be in
meditation. You cannot meditate; you get into
meditation. That is the most meditative state.
Now, so I will tell you what happens to you,
all right? Let me talk on that. That's a better
question, a very good question.
First when the Kundalini rises - all right?
- you won't feel anything, most of you won't
feel anything, but some of you may feel. You
may feel heat in the body. You may feel kind
of a, some people might feel the throbbing
in the back in the spinal cord, might feel,
little, not much. It's not very painful or
anything. Don't be frightened of anything.
Then it will rise. Some of you might feel
the rising, because if there are obstructions
you can feel the rising. If there isn't any
obstruction, if you are not misidentified,
if you are not extremist, if you are in the
center, normally it shoots off in the split
of a second.
When it shoots off, what do you feel is, you
feel a cool breeze coming out of your head.
But normally, as I have seen, people are complicated.
There are complications in the physical, mental
or emotional being. People are not so balanced.
Mostly they have liver problems or such things
like that. You might get heat coming out.
First the heat comes; quite a lot of heat
might come. When the heat disappears, then
you start feeling the cool coming and you
feel very nice inside. Then the bliss starts
coming. You start feeling absolutely relaxed
and you feel in your hands the cool breeze
is coming. But first of all you feel on the
head. You should feel yourself. Nobody is
going to certify it for you. There is no falsehood
about it. It's a thing that you have to feel
it.
And once it happens to you then you can develop
it. Because though the Kundalini at the first
shot comes out but then She tries to look
after your different organs if they are sick,
your mind if it is overloaded, or anything
that is wrong it creates a balance [unclear
Side B 34:42]... So you have to just know
how to reestablish it yourself because it
is your own. Everything is your own. It's
- you can think like this that this light
is your own. It is your own lamp. I just have
come because I have got the flame in Me, perhaps.
Then I put the lamp. Your light is enlightened.
Now you look after your light. It's your light,
it's everything yours. The power is yours.
It's your mother. It's your own spirit. And
then you work it out. Unless and until you
work it out, you will not know whether it
is true or not.
You have to work it out. Now you should not
be identified with anything, that's one thing
is true; because you have not seen the reality
so far. Say, for example, Mr X says, "This
one says so." All right, must have said it
but he is not here. Today he is not here;
it is I who am sitting here. All right? So
it is better that what I am saying you better
receive it because it's nice to live with
the past. Like, people want to believe in
the past because it is easy to handle the
past, or live with the future because it is
easy, or live with somebody who has written
a book or something he had done to us. But
why not believe in yourself that so far you
have not got anything of your own and I am
saying that you have to get it of your own.
That's the main point I am trying to say,
that you must not believe into anything till
you have found it yourself within your self.
That's what it is. And if you are identified
with other things which you have been doing
- most of the people who have paid to some
Guru or some thing, get very much identified
with them. But what have they given you? Have
they given you any powers? Nothing. Can you
feel another person? In collective consciousness,
you should be able to feel another person.
After realization, immediately you can start
feeling another person and yourself. Immediately
you can feel, but you need sensitivity which
we lack quite a lot in the Western world because
the [unclear sounds like 'light is very small'
Side B 36:36].
But in India I have seen people get realization
(and) immediately they start feeling it like
that. It's very easy to cure Indians, I must
say, but difficult to cure Western people.
They are very complicated, ego-oriented, over-read,
all that is there. But once the Western get
it, they settle down much faster, much better,
much deeply than Indians do. It's like if
you have the teeth, you don't have the food;
and if you have the food, you don't have the
teeth. It's a funny combination, this world
is.
Q: [unclear Side B 37:04]
All right, let's have it. Now see what sort
of thing you work out in Cambridge. All right?
So all of us should forget all about these
things. Be honest to yourself and fair to
yourself. So far, by doing all these things
you haven't found yourself. Accept this fact.
I have nothing to gain out of you. I haven't
even written a single line, a book, nothing.
So you must know that it is your own. I am
just like a banker who is cashing your checks.
Better have them cashed, for which you don't
have to pay anything. You don't have to put
in any effort, nothing. But once you are realized
then you will know what is to be done. But
first get your lights on.
All right, now just co-operate with me as
I tell you, without much questioning. I am
not going to tell you anything horrid nor
am I going to trouble you by anything. It
is your own blessing just waiting at your
door step. Can you believe Me now? If you
can believe only this much that I am genuine,
it will work out. May God bless you.
All right, now put your hands towards Me and
if it is not very inconvenient, please take
out your shoes because this Mother Earth also
helps us. It's better to take out your shoes;
it helps. If you are sitting on the ground,
it's all right. You have to touch your Mother
Earth with your feet so if you can take out
your shoes easily, it will work out faster.
Moreover, it is a very tight thing on the
feet. Now this is the question of language
of hands which is an international language
always, but this is the language where the
hands get enlightened and the hands have to
speak. As Mohammad Sahib has said it clearly,
"At the time of resurrection, your hands will
speak". So, your hands have to speak and that's
how we have to see how our hands will be speaking.
So these centers which are shown here are
represented in your fingers. So, these are
five, six and seven, this side left and right.
Once these centers are enlightened, then you
can feel yourself and feel others. To begin
with, we do not understand what it is because
it is too great a thing. But once we start
using it, we are amazed how we start transforming,
how things start happening to us.
All right, now just put your hands straight
like this. Sit comfortably. Be comfortable.
If you have anything tight, please make it
a little loose. It's better. Not that it makes
any difference; it's very subtle. But why
I am asking you because attention goes there
if it is something tight. On the waist also
if there is something tight you see the attention
is gone. Make yourself comfortable. That's
the main point, be comfortable so that for
a while you could be with yourself comfortably.
If you are wearing any big malas and all that,
please take it out. It's better. It's heavy.
Anything like that, please take it out. It
will help us. Just first get yourself realized
and then you start understanding.
Now, after this I have to tell you one more
thing that you have to keep your eyes shut.
The reason is that when the Kundalini rises
above this which it wants to pierce through,
at that time it presses this point and the
pupils go into dilatation first before it
is piercing it and that's why, if the eyes
are open and the Kundalini is passing through,
She may stop. So please keep your eyes shut,
that's all. Just keep your eyes shut till
I tell you to open them. And if you have spectacles
and all that, you can also keep them safe
because you don't have to see Me anymore till
I ask you to open your eyes. So it's better
to keep so that you don't have problems of
your spectacles.
Now close your eyes. Now don't open your eyes
as I requested you. Please don't open your
eyes, that's all. Because this is just the
opposite of hypnosis. In hypnosis, they make
you open your eyes and put their eyes into
your eyes and do all these things. What's
happening? Now, no gesticulations, nothing
abnormal has to be done. Whatever has to happen
will happen within. Nothing abnormal thing
has to be done. Nobody has to jump, shout
or scream - that's all nonsense. You are not
to do anything like that, not to turn your
necks or anything. Just keep quiet. If you
cannot keep quiet, it's better that you go
out for the time being. But just keep quiet.
That's very important not to disturb others.