in the West we have become very speedy
no doubt and to bring down the spell
speed we have to use meditative process
that we feel our peace within ourselves
also the thoughts are bombarding our
minds and we react very fast
to others and to these thoughts so one
has to be aware one has to be knowing
what is happening within yourself that
the thoughts are bombarding you you are
trying to ascend and you find it very
difficult to get rid of the thoughts the
thought process can start by your
conditioning or by your ego only two
problems
and you are the one who is under the
challenge
so you have got these simple people in
the village who start watching
everything but they do not react if you
do not react then your thoughts will
give up so the first thing should be to
watch yourself that you are not reacting
but you are are experiencing and
enjoying the silence the subtleties the
beauty the glory of your being as well
as whatever is around you don't have to
force yourself to break this habit but
just to be on the watch out
it's not necessary to talk too much
about it also not it is necessary to
think about anything because supposing
you see a tree soul it's a tree only
what are we going to think about it and
whatever we may think about it it's
going to be the tree so there's no harm
in appearing little bit stupid doesn't
matter but this is the basic thing is
that when we start analyzing we are
breaking our own nerves and poisoning
our own mind and brain so to watch
something without analysis without
thinking about it is reality if you can
achieve that point where you watch
everything without reacting you are in
relative
and then only the penetration into the
subtleties of your surroundings of your
relationships your friendships the whole
universe dance upon you so to judge
others to think of others what they are
doing what's wrong with them about
anything whatsoever
you may think is wrong he's not going to
be corrected like I know some people who
are specially bureaucrats they are
traveling supposing by the car then they
will say I think you see this road
should have gone this way or I think it
would have been nice if this house was
facing the other way but it's not see it
is not going to face it is going to be
the way it is so what is the use of
wasting your brain your mind your
thought in suggesting thump something
which doesn't work out and never going
to work out either so when we start like
I think these trees should have been a
little taller but they are not
I think
that the crows should stop their noise
they will not so just accept it
acceptance is the way we are going to
enjoy but acceptance doesn't mean
tolerance because tolerance means you
have to work very hard to accept that
the trees are of the same height they
can't grow it's too much worry and you
say I have to tolerate it you see
because my mind doesn't accept
so acceptance as it is whatever you see
acceptance and that is how people grow I
have seen those who start accepting
that's the sign that's the sign of their
strength and their depth like the
propensity of this mother earth she is
what she is and she bears whatever is
there if you put a heavy thing on her
she'll put equal and opposite force and
wear it she doesn't say I'm tolerating
it I am exerting any pressure
she's just accepting so the witnessing
and awareness develops when we start
just accepting things as they're I think
don't work
I think it would have been better like
this doesn't work out then second
problem is I like now I like to eat a
cake but there is no cake what to do now
whatever is there enjoy it as a cake but
if you go on thinking like that I like
whatever is not here you can never be
happy as simple as that you have to say
I like whatever is there I enjoy
whatever is there there that's the
reality whatever doesn't exist if you
like it so what can anybody do about it
works out in so many ways in so many
facets in life that advantage is taken
by people because we become so
vulnerable to our likes and dislikes
that the enterpreneur take over and they
create likes and dislikes in our heads
and put ideas every day I've seen it now
how they do it through television
through newspaper there is that so then
you say now I like this but from where
this liking has come is the conditioning
which is put into her head
so you are a slave of that condition I
only like roses and I don't like any
other flower why why you don't like any
other flower and for such things
whatever we have we miss the joy so the
second part should be that enjoyability
why am I here it's not a very
comfortable place by any chance so why
am I here to enjoy each other to enjoy
your own being the more divergence you
have outside appealing to your ego and
conditioning the more your mind is busy
with that then you cannot enjoy anything