[Shri Mataji talks aside to a yogi and asks
him
if he has got the 108 Names of the Guru
to read them during the puja]
Alright. So today first we have Ganesh Puja
because Ganesha is innocence
and we have to establish Him in any place
where we want to start
a work or do anything about it, because He
is innocence and innocence was created
before everything else was created.
Is the most powerful power, I should say,
innocence.
And then we’ll do the Guru Puja which is
actually
the Adi Guru, the Primordial Master, who
incarnated on this Earth many a times.
And, as you know, as Dattatreya He was born,
as Janaka, Nanaka and many others.
That principle is within us and that is
very important
that we should develop the principle
of Guru Nanak or Janak
or anyone of these primordial masters.
Because if the Spirit is the master,
we have to become the master of ourselves.
And the power of the masters are
that they are essences of the innocence –
of the creator,
of the sustainer and the destroyer.
They are the innocence of all these. Out
of them – this great personality –
innocence of these three personalities
was created this great incarnation.
And their innocence is shown by their
detachment to things – they live everywhere
just like other human beings – married,
living in the families,
but absolutely detached. Unless and until
this principle is awakened in you,
you cannot do Sahaja Yoga.
First of all, this principle of Guru must
be awakened in you which gives you balance
and then the ascent has to be brought in
through the Spirit, the Atma.
That is done by the Shakti, by
the Kundalini Herself.
She’s the Shakti, She’s the womb. She’s
the one Who nourishes, first of all.
She nourishes that power within us,
nourishes us, nourishes all our chakras.
By which She cures our mental, emotional,
physical, spiritual being.
Because sometimes we bow to wrong type
of people,
our spiritual being is also very much hurt.
And after that, after She has achieved
that,
then She ascends through your fontanel bone
and gives you the Self Realization.
So it is She who is the giver of your
moksha.
She is the one who is the giver of
the peace, of the joy,
and this Mother of yours resides in you
and She gives you the Realization.
So we worship Her as the power within you,
so that you are empowered,
you become powerful. But this power makes
you the master.
When She comes in the Void area, She makes
you the Master
because She enlightens that Guru principle
within you and you become the Master,
you become the master of yourself and by
that you become the Master of others also.
The one who is not the Master of oneself
cannot be the Master of others.
So it works out, first of all, on you and
then it radiates.
And that radiation makes others also accept
you as the guru.
The dynamism and that compassionate
attitude
all develops through this Guru principle.
But this is the blessing of the Kundalini,
the Womb, the Mother,
the one who we call as Aquarius.
This is residing within us and we have to
just accept
Her manifestation and welcome Her with
open heart.
And know that today is the day when we are
expecting human beings
to rise to that level where they become
compassion, love, affection.
This is the new awareness with which we are
going to be
completely fulfilled and unless and until
that happens
there’s no chance for the emancipation,
no doubt about it.
We have worked out so many things in so
many places
and every place, I find, has a different
problem.
The most difficult, I find, is America,
it’s like Mathura
where Shri Krishna had to go and establish
Himself,
that was the Kingdom of Shri Krishna and
where Kamsa was ruling.
So the people in Mathura were the most
difficult people because they were governed
by devils and the devils have a capacity
to dominate good people.
They’re all so dominated that even where
Shri Krishna lived,
they tried to go and harm Him and kill Him
and all that.
And all the dynamism of these people from
Mathura was killed by Kamsa
who was to be killed by Shri Krishna.
Surprisingly, the first day I came to New
York for the puja,
the first day it was written “Parivartani
Ekadashi”.
Now “Ekadesha” is the power with which
the people are going to be destroyed.
Now that is “Parivartani” means the one
by which you are going to be transformed.
So, how is it the power that is going
to destroy is going to transform you.
Firstly, it will destroy all that is
oppressive, all that kills your dynamism,
all that makes you slave, that is going
to be destroyed.
Secondly, people will be frightened,
the halfbaked ones
who are neither here nor there, that we’ll
be destroyed and that awe will change them.
Thirdly, when you see that your kith and
kin are going to be destroyed,
then you’ll have much more compassion,
much more tolerance for them
and you’ll try to save them all. So that is
what it is,
where Shri Krishna had to raise a complete
mountain on His fingertip,
you see like this, to the right side,
“Govardhandhari” He was called.
That is what is my job here, is to raise
the mountain again
and raise it on my finger tip like that.
But this finger has to be strong
and this finger is nothing but the Sahaja
Yogis of America and they have to help
by their dynamic behaviour and by their
proper understanding, responsibility
as the people belonging to this great
nation of Fatherhood.
This is the finger of the Father and that
Fatherhood has to be dynamic,
has to be overpowering and has to be very
responsible.
And in that responsibility you learn so
many things –
so that’s my job is, that’s my goal is.
She (tv host) asked me in the TV,
“What is your goal, Mother?” I didn’t tell
her that I have to raise
the mountain on my finger, you see, she
would never have understood that.
But that is what one has to do here.
To raise the mountain and I find it’s like
that – Mountainous.
And base of the mountain seems to be Houston
which is the most difficult part of it,
they just don’t move, they just don’t move,
its jada it's very, very ‘tamasic’,
it’s so full of ignorance and so full
of heaviness.
That is the most difficult part and that’s
why – for Houston specially –
we should do a nice puja to the Kundalini
that She rises in Houston.
May God bless you all.
Can you give me the handkerchief.
Yogi: Today it’s said it’s Anant
Chaturdashi. Shri Mataji: Uh?
Yogi: Anant Chaturdashi.
Shri Mataji: Today? Ah-ah!
That’s great! Yes, must be. I was wondering
Anant Chaturdashi.
Anant Chaturdashi is the day when we
‘visarjan’– dissolve Shri Ganesha
in the water.
(Hindi : it’s that day we put the Ganesha
in to the water)
Because He’s established for ten days and
after ten days, He’s born on the fourth,
after ten days He’s dissolved in the water
so that everywhere His Power is spread
through the water. That’s why no wonder
there was a puja.
Ganesha settled down into the water.
That is Ananta Chaturdashi. Ananta is the,
is Shri Ganesha.
Ananta means which cannot be destroyed.
Innocence cannot be destroyed.
And that is why is the Ganesh Chaturdashi
means the day
when Ganesha is dissolved in the water,
in the ocean or He is created, worshipped
for ten days and again given back.
So it’s a very great day today, I should
say, like the resurrection of Christ
that you are,
you had Christ here, He lived with you,
and then went back to His Father. Father is
the ocean
and that’s what in India they do, establish
Him on the fourth day
and on the tenth day they put Him back
to the ocean.
Yogi: We used to do the same thing in
our school. Shri Mataji: Beg your pardon?
Yogi: I said we used to do the same
thing in our school. Shri Mataji: Eh?
Yogi: We used to do the same thing in our
school.
Other yogi: He says that he did the same in
his school, they used to make the Ganesha.
Shri Mataji: Really? What school?
Yogi: (School name).
Yogi: So we used to have a statue and four
of the guys used to carry them on.
Shri Mataji: But no one understands. They
just do it without understanding
what they are doing about it. So it’s
a thing, even in India
how many people know about Ganesha,
no one knows.
Yogini: In Maharastra. Shri Mataji: In
Maharastra, they worship Him a lot
but they don’t know much about it. They
don’t know how much He’s important,
about what He represents, how did He came
on this earth, nothing they know.
We have become very superficial that way.
But at least it keeps your attention by
doing all these things, “there”.
You see, this is the advantage of in India,
the children have to be little bit
pinned down to a thing they, by festivals
and all that they try to then find out
what is this, what is that. Their attention
is more there, not outside so much,
you see, that’s the thing is.