you must know that you do presently
trying to buy some of
do I ever complain about food
summer
my show patience
now the best way would be to play
prayers for sahaja yoga
play with your heart first of all you
must ask for strength give me strength
so that I be genuine I will deceive my
we are deceiving ourselves morning to be
give me strength that I faced myself and
see with my heart that I try to because
these are defects which are not your own
they are outside then the second thing
you asked for is a sweet heart by which
I become communicative you means give me
that beauty of
the plan you asked that will not give me
the sense of security of my spirit so
that I do not feel insecure by which I
trouble others all the time you make
sense of my own dignity so that I do not
feel that I am vindicated
somebody has it if you are a tired
nobody it's only you will be the true by
your foolishness and talk to them ask
for strength that give me mine with this
date give me satisfaction a second let
me feel my satisfaction from what I
whatever I have whatever I eat
everything takes of my attention away
from all these you know that your
attention is in this trouble and those
who are very much interested in food
that in any case whatever you make up
in anything like this wherever my
attention is please give me strength to
pull it back turn it over
teach me how to avoid things that tempt
take it away my toys
give me replaced it by which I see the
whole drama let me never spite others
and criticize let me see my stakes not
others
let me see why people are not happy with
you mister you have a very sweet dog
and the sweet nature so that other life
Michael
they enjoy Michael let me be like a
flower and not like a thorn into play
where are these flowers are going to
hurt don't ask for the biggest birth it
should stop that please keep me away
from evil that means me I guess that I'm
superior to others I'm better than
others or even a little it takes away my
maintenance and my humility here we
natural humility by which I can
penetrate into the hearts of you just
try to burn your head and you go up to
your heart you have to bend your head
just to them your head and there is your
heart very slices very vivid if you are
hurting your ego or you are hurting
somebody chemo is just sick well behind
the silver the song a mystical man so
try to understand that these things have
to go it's best just to pray and ask for
help grant is a very big thing but with
your heart pray that God give us
strength and that group that we can
place our mother sometime
you want to please our mother you want
to see her happy
the only things that will really give me
happiness but the way I love you love