Evening Program, Eve of Mahashivaratri Puja
Australia, 25 February 1995
[Shri Mataji's talk starts at the end of
the evening program: minute 02:34:50)
Congratulations to Brian Bell and to
all the…
I said congratulations to Brian Bell
and to all the actors and actresses.
To be very frank I never think of my past.
So I was wondering what is this drama
going about.
The most important thing in this life is
to enlighten as many people as possible.
I am very much thankful to you
for expressing your joy,
your talents to express the reality.
Reality is not in which what we believe but
it is beyond.
But the way people believe in reality is
something illusion, illusionary.
That is the curse of Kali Yuga.
I must say it is brought out very well,
the way you showed people around, but not
easy to convince so easily, I tell you.
Now it’s different. It used to be very
difficult in the beginning –
too many arguments and all kinds of funny
answers and questions.
Now life has changed I think – we are so
many, so many good Sahaja Yogis,
and in Australia I am sure it’s going to be
a very tremendous success.
I was surprised at the way people had
to stand outside in that big hall,
shows the awakening is spreading
and people are now trying to understand
that there is something beyond.
It’s only your behaviour, it’s only your
vibrations which has created this.
If I could do everything myself alone,
I would not have needed anyone.
But no I can’t do it, I have to have
channels, and I have to do it through you.
When the channels are so good, they are
working it out for me.
Now I look back sometimes because just now
you were showing the past
that first coming to Australia I just
thought
it’s a Ganesha’s land and things will
work out.
It has, I must say, it has worked out very
well.
So many people are showing their talents.
It’s amazing how they can sing Indian songs
or do these Indian dancing, it’s very
amazing.
And this play of Shiva was also another
great achievement I think
in expressing how all the religions said
the same thing.
But as you know people have misinterpreted
for their own purposes.
I am so very happy all of you had found out
the reality about yourself,
the reality about life and the Spirit that
is within you.
I never expected so much to happen in my
lifetime, I thank you for that.
May God bless you all.