I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset we have to understand that
truth is what it is. We cannot conceptualize
it. We cannot organize it. And we cannot use
it for our own purposes. Moreover, with the
blinkers on both the sides like a horse, with
all our conditionings, we cannot find the
truth. We have to be free people. We have
to be open-minded people, like scientists,
to see for ourselves what is the truth. If
somebody preaches something, professes something,
says something, is not to be accepted blindfolded.
As I told you yesterday, that the essence
of all the religions is to find the eternal
and to treat the transitory in its own understanding
and in its own limitations. That’s why we
have lost our balance. If we are really the
people who want to know the truth, we have
to know that at human awareness we cannot
know it. It becomes a concept.
You have to have the spiritual awareness,
but spiritual awareness is a state of your
being, where you become the spirit. Again
the word I’ll say – “become.” It’s
not artificially certifying somebody that
now you have become a Hindu or a Christian
or a Muslim, you become anything. Because
you may be a Muslim, Christian, Hindu, anything,
you can commit any sin. You can do anything
that is wrong. Nothing from inside is going
to stop you. So all these things have become
so much outward that now there are people
who have started saying there is no God, there
is nothing like religion, which is not true.
First of all when we say there is nothing,
or there is not God, we should find out, have
we been able to find out about it or just
in our ego we are saying there is no God?
Have we been able to work it out to see if
there is God or not? You do not judge God
by the people who talk about God. Anybody
can talk about God because they think there’s
no law that can catch them. They can talk
against Him, they can talk for Him, they can
do the way they like. They can even make money
by talking against God and against all the
prophets – that’s a very good way of making
money, blackmail. But does that mean that
whatever is written is a bible, or whatever
is black and white, is to be taken that seriously?
So first of all, we have to be little independent
to be free, to know that if you have to know
the spirit - as they said “know thyself”
- then you have to know it on your central
nervous system. As I can feel this is cold
or hot, you have to feel the divine power
which is all-pervading, which is the truth,
which manifests the truth, because it is the
love of God. You have to first feel it on
your central nervous system, which is the
bodha.
Now one may say that in the West we have advanced
so much, all right. We have gone too far with
everything. But if we see, when we started
with science, what have we produced? Hydrogen
bomb, atom bomb, all kinds of devils sitting
on our heads. You take to any enterprise that
we did, we go to extremes. There is no balance.
Any mental projection is linear, it moves
in one line and then recoils back, and then
you are shocked. Now you have got acid rain.
You produced machinery, all right. Machinery
is for you, you are not for machinery. And
thus, there is no balance between you and
the machinery, no balance between you and
the science. It is just like going amok with
anything that you get into your hand. And
this balance you can only have when you become
the spirit. You see beautiful chandeliers
here, beautifully made, but unless and until
there is light what is the meaning of these
chandeliers? Nothing. In the same way, if
you do not have the light of the spirit shining
in your attention, you will not know your
meaning. Like this instrument – unless and
until it is connected to the mains, it is
useless. Unless and until we are connected
to the mains, we do not know the absolute,
and that’s why all these problems are there.
Now when I am talking about this instrument,
which lies within us, one has to again know
that this is the knowledge of the roots. And
to know the knowledge of the roots, you have
to become a subtler personality. With a gross
mind, you cannot see it. To become the subtler
personality, minimum of minimum, you have
to know that so far you have not known the
roots. If you had known, there would be no
problem. But there’s something has gone
wrong somewhere in every human enterprise,
even in religions, that’s why today we find
this kind of a farce going on. And what is
gone wrong is that we have to seek the eternal.
Maybe it might look a little different, for
example Buddha and Mahavira did not talk about
God at all. I also did not talk about God
for four years, at least three years. As soon
as you talk of God, again people start jumping,
“When can we become God?” – this is
the first question.
So first you become the self –the first
step. That’s why they did not talk. They
said first you become yourself. Unless and
until you have your eyes, how can you see
the colors? So first have your eyes. It is
for your benevolence that you better get what
you deserve, what is your own. It’s your
birthright as a human being to become the
spirit. That is what Sahaja Yoga is – Saha
means “with” and ja is “born.” Born
with you is the right to get this yoga, is
the union with the Divine. It’s your birthright
as a human being. You are as I told you at
the epitome of evolution. And it has to work
out, but please open your hearts and open
your minds. Just open it and see for yourself,
it will work, I know. Yesterday it has worked.
It is going to work out today also. But by
thinking about it, you cannot conceptualize.
This is the biggest problem of our seeking
that we run after some sort of a concept.
Now here you have seen this instrument is
the most beautiful instrument that is created
within us during the process of our evolution.
The first one is the most beautiful one because
it stands for our innocence. This innocence
is the one which gives us real support, real
strength. And you’ll be surprised it is
never destroyed. It may be overshadowed, there
may be clouds. Maybe it may look to be a very
dark sky. Maybe a hopeless case. Some people
might say that we have destroyed our innocence.
It cannot be destroyed. Whatever you might
have done, this is one center which cannot
be destroyed. You may have problems with it
but it cannot be destroyed. It is such a wonderful
center you have got, which has got four petals,
which looks after the pelvic plexus, looks
after all the excretion within us.
In our own freedom, so-called, we do all kinds
of things which may not be benevolent for
ourselves, doesn’t matter. Kundalini cannot
be destroyed - the source which is going to
give you the self-realization, I say She is
your individual Mother. And this Mother is
such a loving Mother and She knows each and
everything about you - from your past, from
your past lives - She knows you very well.
She is just waiting for a chance that She
can be awakened and She can give you your
second birth. When you were born, your mother
suffered for you – you did not suffer.
So to say that Kundalini awakening gives this
kind of a nonsense and that kind of a nonsense
is all falsehood. Absolutely falsehood. And
it is so absurd that how can a mother give
you problems? I mean, I don’t know about
some mothers are funny also – that’s all
human problems. But this is a Divine Mother.
She’s not going to give you trouble. But
these problems that have come are coming from
people who have no authority, who have no
education, who do not know what Kundalini
is. Some say it is in the stomach, some say
in the head, some say in the legs. Those who
have no character of their own, because they
have to be pure people themselves, try all
kinds of nonsensical tricks and create problems
on the sympathetic nervous system and they
call it as something that it is the problem
of the Kundalini. Kundalini will never give
you any problems. On the contrary, when She
rises and when you get your awakening, the
first thing that is established is thoughtless
awareness.
For when a thought rises, falls, another thought
rises, falls, and the Kundalini makes the
thoughts smaller and in between at the present.
It makes you stop in the present and you grow
in the present, and the thoughts, if you want
to think you can think, if you don’t want
to think, it is not like a madhouse going
on all the time, you don’t know how to stop
it. This works out with the Kundalini’s
awakening when She crosses this center of
ours, which we call as Agnya chakra.
Now we should not have, again I say, blinkers
about Christ. Let us see what people have
to say about Christ in other shastras and
scriptures. Who was He? Because people did
not allow Him to manifest for more than four
years and in four years what can you do? You
cannot do anything. I must tell you in London
I came, My husband was selected for a job
and that’s how we are here, and for four
years I was struggling with seven of them,
just struggling. Giving realization was such
a difficult subject to the English people
at that time. They are hard nuts, I know.
But once they break, they are the best. I
think the best are the hardest. And it worked,
it clicked.
I am surprised that I had to work very hard
but they are such a foundation of Sahaja Yoga.
Immediately they went all out and very scholarly
also – a lot of scholarship in them. Found
out all about Kundalini, everything from wherever
– your libraries are so well-equipped. And
I was surprised, it was all there. They studied
Sanskrit. Now can you imagine these people
English singing Sanskrit song with that speed?
They could not even say one sentence in Hindi
when they were in India. Three hundred years
they were there, they could not speak one
sentence you will be surprised. We had to
tell them in English how to speak Hindi. Like
you have to say “open the door” – is
in Hindi, is darwaja khol do. They couldn’t
say it. So we had to say, “there was a banker”
or something like that – means “close
the door” – “there was a banker.”
They couldn’t speak Hindi. Sanskrit is very
far off. And now look at them, what has happened
to them. And Indian music is such a difficult
music, you have to really, it is a question
of penance, tremendous penance. Now we have
people who play beautiful tabla, beautiful
instruments not only but sing so well. Swiss,
the hardest nuts you can ever think of, they
are - you’ll be amazed the Swiss the way
they sing, tremendous manifestation in such
a short time. Of course they can also sing
English very well, they know English music
very well, or should say Western music very
well. But to learn this difficult melodies
of India is remarkable. I am myself surprised
at this.
So what happens in the second center when
it enters, you just become dynamic, because
the second center is for aesthetics and for
creativity. Now we have, like My brother who
was a chartered accountant, he was very bad
at all the languages. Very bad, of course
Sanskrit was out of question. Now he is making
poetry in Sanskrit and in Urdu language and
also in Marathi, which is the most difficult
language. This is the second center. When
Kundalini nourishes that center, like a very
beautiful Mother she nourishes. You must have
heard about some great artists – Amjad Ali,
he was here – after realization he became
such a great artist. There are so many artists.
In India, they understand. They want to sing
before Me. I mean I don’t know how to say
that now only one person can sing. Because
their Kundalini goes up, and the creativity
becomes so tremendously active and so dynamic.
At the same time, that person becomes very
mild, very sweet, very compassionate. Like
there’s one great singer. She’s a Muslim
lady, I will not name her.
She wanted to sing and she sent Me word, “Please
allow me to sing in Your birthday.”
And I said, “All right, give her a chance.”
So she came down. And the lady who was playing
harmonium – she came and told Me, “This
lady is just an atom bomb, You don’t know
how she gets angry if there’s one note I
play wrong.”
I saw her but she was very silently playing
– nothing doing, she never got angry with
anyone. So in the interval, this lady comes
and tells Me, “That see in Your presence,
I don’t know what has happened to this lady.
This tiger has become like a cow. How is it?”
I said, “See her Kundalini has come up.”
So this violence, this anger, this temper
is not your creation, it’s the creation
of your liver. Your liver is little out of
order because of many things, and the temper
is there. Now when the temper is too much,
you don’t know what to do. I mean you can
do whatever you like. In your temper after
all, it’s like a drunken personality. You
have to approach a person in a temper with
a barge pole. But all this temper, everything,
becomes so cool and so beautiful. It’s very
surprising. A very dynamic person becomes
extremely compassionate, extremely compassionate,
and I’ve had such beautiful experiences
of their compassion that it’s not easy to
describe.
Now also they say that there are certain nationalities
which has got a trait like this and a trait
like that, everything dissolves. Everything
dissolves because of this center which is
so creative and which also gives you the manifestation
of pure knowledge - pure knowledge. For example
you start feeling on your finger tips – you
just start feeling on your finger tips. Like
today only, somebody came and told Me, “That
Mataji my Agnya is catching.” Agnya is this
center - means “I’ve got my ego on.”
Will anybody say like that? On the contrary
if you tell somebody, “You have got your
ego,” they’ll show you that they have
their ego on. It’s very dangerous to say
to somebody that your ego is on. But just
because of self knowledge - pure knowledge
- you know that this Mr. Ego is sitting here
and I cannot cross through and there’s a
blockage here, which I have to take it out.
It’s so innate within you, everything, only
thing is your connection has to be made.
Once the connection is made, immediately you
know about yourself. And this center which
is responsible for creating all kinds of funny
thoughts and horrible creativity becomes so
benevolent, so soothing, so beautiful.
Apart from that, as I told you just now, these
people who could not even say one word in
Hindi language have started singing Sanskrit
and this - specially the one they sang, the
first one - many Indians cannot sing that
way I can tell you, they can’t. It’s not
easy. It’s a very great tongue twister first
of all the language is. Apart from that, to
sing in such a correct pronunciation is so
difficult but they have done it. So in Sahaja
Yoga, an artist who is struggling today may
become a great artist tomorrow. But still
I would say these are temptations. You’ll
become a great artist, you’ll start earning
more money, this, that…but that’s not
the one. You have to really be satisfied with,
you will never be satisfied with that.
So you move to the third center which we call
as the Nabhi chakra. This center is, on one
side, is made of water and another side with
fire. Around it are our ten valencies, which
we can call as our innate religion within
ourselves. Now this Nabhi itself - or we can
call the solar plexus or we can say the Navel
chakra - gives us, as soon as the Kundalini
rises, she awakens this and the light when
it spreads, you become religious. I don’t
have to tell you anything, you just become.
I don’t have to say that you don’t take
drugs. You just don’t take it. Overnight
I have seen people have given up drugs. Overnight,
alcoholism. Overnight, everything. And they
enjoy their virtues. That’s the best part
of it. Some people think, well then what is
the fun? What is this that you take something
in the pub and next day you have hangover.
Here you take something and next day you are
much better off. It never comes down. It never
gives you a reaction. It’s not artificial.
It’s not intoxicating. It is from your nerves
it’s bubbling out.
So this is the center which is very important
in us because most of us have a problem with
this center. And here we have a capacity by
this center that we enjoy our generosity.
Now all matter whatever it is - we are materialistic,
materialistic, it is a good idea to be materialistic.
But the matter is, the aesthetics of matters
are, that you can give it to others suggesting
your love in it. I think that’s the only
thing the matter can do. And in a very special
way you can express that love. For example,
somebody likes a particular thing - you go
all the way to get it and give that small
thing, very small thing, to the person and
the joy, not out of the money that you have
spent, but the feelings you have expressed
of knowing what that person would love. And
this kind of a depth develops within you.
Such lovable beautiful society you enter into.
And you don’t need anything because everybody
is looking after your needs. Now I have told
them I love flowers because I don’t take
anything else. So you must see whenever I
come My house is so filled with flowers that
My husband was saying, “Let us go live in
the garden and let the flowers be here.”
So you see the joy of giving, comes from this
center. And whatever you eat, whatever you
have to eat, whatever is good for you, you
eat. You don’t have to bother as to what
to eat, what not to eat – you just eat whatever
is good for you, benevolent for you. You become
so wise and also you please others. You don’t
displease others by saying, “This is bad
food, I want that.” ’I want’ goes away.
What do you want?
[speaks aside]
So the, like you could say a candle which
is not enlightened, is waiting to be enlightened,
is asking for the light – “I want light.”
But once it is enlightened, it gives light
to others, automatically - supposed to be.
In the same way you also start giving your
light, your love, your joy to others, automatically.
I don’t have to tell you. Nobody has to
go through any Ten Commandments anymore. Those
days are gone. Now automatically you become
like that - very beautiful people, very affectionate
and glorious, I should say. If you see the
glow on the face of Sahaja Yogis, the face
itself is radiant. Many people drop out their
ten years to twenty years in their age and
they are so enthusiastic, never get tired,
especially in England I’ve seen – or also
in the West I would say everywhere – people
get very really tired.
On the television also you find people will
come and sit down “huh…” Young people,
they’ll talk ten times, they’ll say “huh…
Why are we so tired?” Because we think too
much. All energy is wasted in thinking, so
no energy left to enjoy anything whatsoever.
For example, you have to have people for dinner,
they think what to bring, how to make it formal,
what to do, this thing, that thing, so agitated
and so nervous about the whole thing – when
the guests come in, they feel like running
away. Because so much of tension of thinking,
thinking, thinking….. Planning, planning,
planning, planning, planning… Ultimately
the whole joy has disappeared.
So the second center which is there, it does
a very miraculous thing, is to provide the
grey cells in our brain, when we are using
it for thinking, and also it looks after your
liver, your pancreas, your spleen, your kidneys
and lower part of your abdomen. Instead of
doing that, poor thing is busy only sending
grey cells to your brain because thinking,
thinking, thinking, thinking, like mad. So
you develop all other diseases – liver trouble,
which is very common. Then you develop diabetes
– very common. Yesterday at least there
were ten people who said we have diabetes.
Now diabetes you do not develop by taking
too much sugar – take it from Me. In India
if you go to a village, you’ll see that
he takes sugar in such a manner that in the
cup the spoon must stand at right angles,
otherwise he won’t take it. But he never
gets diabetes. The reason is he doesn’t
think of tomorrow - he just works hard, eats
his food and sleeps off, nicely. He doesn’t
take sleeping pills either. So this diabetes
comes by over-thinking and can be easily cured
if you can take to Sahaja Yoga, which I’ll
tell you how we’ll stop our thinking at
this, I’ve already told you, at this point.
Then the third disease which is even more
dangerous than this, is the disease which
we call as blood cancer. Blood cancer is caused
only to people who think too much. It can
even be to the children if the mother is very
meticulous, particular about her carpets or
her house, everything you know and even a
rat doesn’t enter that house. But she is
very careful that all her things are properly
done, her sink doesn’t have even so much
of, little bit of a spot left in it. All the
time, thinking, planning, thinking, planning.
This affects the child and a child also can
get blood cancer. Blood cancer you get it
because your spleen is a speedometer- is the
one which gives you the rhythm of life, rhythm
of life. Now when we are hectic people, all
the time under shock, then this goes out of
order.
For example in the morning we get up and see
the newspaper and what you find, these Iranians
have killed someone – such a shock. Then
an accident, then… I mean newspaper will
never give good news, will they? Will they
give news, how many people got realization
or something is working out all, all right?
No something horrible that should shock your
heads, shock your limbic area – otherwise
you’ll not take it seriously. So, once you
read that, you don’t know your system is
a very delicate system, it gets a shock. And
then you get into your car, without taking
your breakfast, or maybe in your hand is the
breakfast because you are late. On the way
there is a jam – you are shouting, screaming
- somehow or other you reach the office and
there is the boss barking.
This is how we live, under complete tension.
We are supposed to be free people. In the
night if you sing loudly the neighbor will
come and put you to the police station. I
mean you can’t do anything. There’s no
freedom. You have to be bound by the watch.
This is the time, exact you have to reach
there. So all these things, pressures, and
all these things work on us and we become
hectic. And for emergency, this spleen is
the one which releases red blood corpuscles
– RBCs. But if you are all the time like
this hectic, that poor spleen becomes mad.
It doesn’t know what to do. It starts producing
more cells, more cells and then it thinks
it’s a mad person I am fixed with because
I don’t know when to act, when not to act.
So the vulnerability is there, and suddenly
with some other shock, you might get blood
cancer and then the doctors will certify you
are going to die after one month. Finished,
prepare for your burial. And the whole house
is crying. But we have cured, I mean Sahaja
Yoga has cured blood cancer of many people
just by this Kundalini awakening because as
soon as the Kundalini is awakened, too much
movement this side and that side, this all
the time going on, in the center – this
is the left and the right side of the sympathetic
– so just the Kundalini passes through,
strings through and brings it back and nourishes
it. The problem is over. And though they were
certified to be dead, after even four years
they are all right, working all right, the
certificate is cancelled. Even vulnerability
to cancer, or to all incurable diseases, are
because of these centers going out of place.
Now we have the center which we call here
as the heart center. It controls the left
and right, both – so we have a left and
right heart in Sahaja Yoga. As you know that,
this sternum bone creates the antibodies for
you. And these antibodies fight your diseases.
So when this center goes out, this is the
center which sends all the messages to these
antibodies. Now this is the center of a mother.
When your motherhood is challenged, you develop
breast cancer.
Supposing a man is a flirt and his wife is
worried, she might get a breast cancer, because
her motherhood is challenged and her sense
of security is very disturbed. As a result
of that, she gets this problem. Also if you
are too much of a thinker, and you think too
much and you’re very, what we call the right-sided,
the futuristic planner, I mean people plan
it for ten years. They plan even their deaths,
what dress they are going to wear and where
they are going to be buried, up to that point.
All this futuristic planning creates such
tremendous heat in the body because the liver,
which is supposed to absorb all the heat,
is neglected by this center. As a result that
heat travels up and you develop asthma. Now
we had yesterday, at least five or six people
who came with asthma. Asthma is absolutely
curable. But do you know this is the center
of a husband, or of the father. Now if I am
telling you, you should not be shocked, because
later on you’ll find it.
Now if you are a bad husband, you can get
asthma. Or if your wife is a shrew, you might
get an asthma. Or if you are a very bad father,
you might get an asthma. Or if your father
is not kind to you, you might get an asthma.
If you have not forgiven your father, you
might get asthma. Now can you believe it,
just forgiving your father, you can get out
of your asthma permanently. Sahaja Yoga has
cured asthma of so many people. Believe it
or not, it works. It looks so funny but our
relationships, our parents we have chosen
when we came on this Earth. I know they are
wrong, they are obstinate, they’re headstrong,
they may be drunkards, whatever they are.
But even if you leave them, because so many
people leave the parents, still forgive them
and forget. Otherwise you carry the problems
with you.
The left heart is the place of the mother.
Now if your mother has been hard with you,
if you have had very bad experiences, you
will have problems of the left heart. Center
heart is very important where your sense of
security should be established. You’ll be
surprised in the disease called AIDS, it is
the center heart which is out. We have tried
to cure, and we cured also 3, 4 people from
AIDS, but they have no will-power to continue
with Sahaja Yoga, they want to die. And they
have made a big martyrdom out of it, you see
they are martyrs, great martyrs of a great
principle they have established. It’s impossible
to convince to them, that this is unnatural
that you are doing and that you should give
it up and you should live, why should you
die? No, we are martyrs for such a big principle
we have established. To do something out of
the way and new is the modern fashion. Anything
- will do something with the hair, with the
nose, with the eyes, with the ears, with the
clothes. That’s all you can do. To such
an extent that they do not realize that whatever
is new may not be good for you.
For example, everyday we eat our dinner. Supposing
we want to eat the table because it is new
– is it a sensible thing? Anything that
is new, is not good. But anything that is
old, may not be good also. So you have to
have that wisdom which comes to you through
Sahaja Yoga. There is no other way out - you
have to become the spirit, and you have to
see in the light of the spirit, what is right
and what is wrong.
So then wecome to this center which is, we
call as the Vishuddhi – this has sixteen
petals, looks after the cervical plexus. Now
this is a very very important center and this
is the center is for communication. For example,
when you talk, you communicate through your
hands. You shake hands, you touch somebody,
and you can communicate. Even if you cannot
talk, with your hands you can communicate.
Also when we think we are very responsible,
this center goes out. Like some people were
traveling by plane - they were from villages,
they did not know what was a plane. They were
told to take less luggage because it should
not be a weight for the plane. So they got
into the plane and put all of the luggage
on their heads. And they said that “We are
trying to reduce the weight of the plane.”
In the same way, we are also... actually the
One - which is all-pervading power, which
has created us, created this universe and
has brought us to this level of human beings
- is doing everything. But we think we are
responsible, we have to do it. But once you
become a Sahaja Yogi you just do it, no doubt.
But you don’t think that you are doing anything.
You just say its happening. And what a beautiful
feeling it is. Then you don’t have blood
pressures, you don’t have headaches, you
don’t have tensions – no, because we are
not doing it. It is just done and you find
it’s all done.
Now on this center when we come, as I’ve
told you, your thinking is controlled by you,
you can control. If you want you can think
or you don’t think. But in that silence
you feel your peace. If there’s too much
of crowds, too much of problems, suddenly
you become the witness. You start seeing everything.
Seeing the problem, what it is. Unless and
until you can see the problem you cannot solve
it. Because you are in the problem, you just
get upset. But if you are out of the problem,
you can see it. And that’s what happens
to you when you become thoughtlessly aware
when this center opens out.
Last but not the least is the center of limbic
area which is very important. Now I do not
know it has been discovered or not, but it
will be very soon discovered, that very strong
things like cracks and all that have got sulfuric
acid in it, and that doesn’t go anywhere
in the body, just rushes into the limbic area.
Now this limbic area is a hollow place which
has got all cells here very sensitive to joy
and happiness. But they become numb, so numb
that ordinary music you cannot hear - somebody
has to scream at you, has to shout at you,
he has to jump on it, otherwise you cannot
enjoy. Then it has to be worse and worse and
worse and worse… I don’t know now with
cracks, later on they might develop something
even more poisonous, because it has to excite
this limbic area which is such an important
thing. But as soon as the Kundalini enters
into that area, limbic area, she soothes it
and it opens - opens like a lotus, thousand
petalled lotus. It opens and then the Kundalini
emerges out of your fontanelle bone area and
gets connected to the all-pervading power.
Then you start feeling the cool breeze in
your hands. You can feel it all over. Some
people in the beginning who felt cool breeze,
could not believe it – so they closed doors,
everything and sat down to see, still they
were feeling it. But it works, works in the
sense that you get empowered. You become peaceful,
you become the witness, you become the wise
and you become empowered that you can give
realizations to others like this, that you
can raise the Kundalini like this and you
can establish that connection. You can do
it. And this is what is your right to have
it. This is what will give you meaning. Otherwise
so far whatever we have been doing is very
frustrating.
Now yesterday I said some questions can be
asked but I haven’t seen any questions whatsoever.
That means you have no questions? Or there
are some questions we can deal with it for
about 5 minutes. There’s one there, please..
Question: INAUDIBLE, but someone else (a yogi
near Mother?) repeats the question:
[What is the process by which you one stops
thinking?]
It’s very simple. When the Kundalini settles
down there, what happens, as I told you, there
is Christ – Christ is awakened and He sucks
in these two institutions which you see there,
the yellow and the blue. These are – one
is, the blue one is our conditioning and the
yellow one is our ego. So both these are sucked
in like that. These are sucked in because
it is said that He died for our sins, didn’t
He? He suffered for us. Now also that’s
why yesterday I’ve said are we going to
suffer more than Him? We don’t have to suffer.
Only awaken Him at Agnya. We are all right,
this is the process, it opens out. All right?
That’s why I said you must forgive, because
He said you have to forgive and when you forgive
you can ask for forgiveness, that’s why
we do both the things – one in the front
and one in the back.
Please get up.
[How do you raise the Kundalini?]
Automatically, I’ll tell you how. Please,
you see like if you have to sprout a seed
you have to just put it in the Mother Earth.
How do you do it? The Mother Earth has got
the capacity and the seed is built-in within
it. Now it is all built-in within you, all
right. And just you are here, I can raise
it – anybody can raise it, those who have
got the capacity – Sahaja Yogis can raise
your Kundalini also.
[Question from the floor, : You talk about
always thinking. You talk about, like, if
you think too much, you can actually create
illness and the problems in your life. How
do You organize Your time and Your work and
everything, but You don’t think about it?]
Oh, because the Divine Power does for Me.
Everything is done by Divine Power. Why should
I think – let it think for Me. You see I
travel every day – I sleep at 2 o’clock
in the night, get up about 5 o’clock in
the morning and I travel everywhere. And I’m
now 67 years of age, all right, so what. Divine
Power is looking after Me, it’s working
out everything. I am just moving about nicely
enjoying everything.
But you have to believe that you can get realization.
You need not believe in the Divine Power,
but you just first believe that you can get
realization and you get it and get in connection
with it. It just works. It is the subtlest
of subtle.
[Yogi, repeating the question: How can we
utilize the divine power in our relationships
and all the problems?]
You see first of all you have to give to others.
Unless and until you open one door, all right
that’s Divine Power there. But unless and
until you open other door, it won’t come
in your life. So you have to open the other
door also. There’s where we fail, we want
to use Sahaja Yoga for our own purpose, for
our own – my brother, my sister, my son,
all sorts of my, my, my… There there’s
problem – but open it out. Everything works
out. You must learn to give. This is free.
[Question inaudible]
It is situated on top of the brain where it
is above the brain, and it is covered with,
the doctors say that it is 988 nerves - because
I don’t want to quarrel with them. But there
are 1000 nerves which cover it. And when it
is enlightened you’ll be surprised, you’ll
see a beautiful lotus opening in all colors,
very very silent flames, and they are so peace-giving,
looks so beautiful. Because when any nerve
gets enlightened, the light of that flame
looks like a petal. It’s very beautiful,
it is. But it has to open out. Just now it
is covered by our conditioning and our ego.
Like we have become like an egg we can say.
That’s why in Sanskrit language, a person
who has known the brahma, the all-pervading
power, is called as dvijaha and a bird is
also called as dvijaha - means born twice.
First as an egg, then it becomes a bird – human
being and a realized soul. These are the two
stages.
[Question inaudible]
You see the thing is that now there are social
conditions which are very bad, people are
homeless, they are on the streets. Now thinking
about it you are not going to help them, are
you? No. Which is the best way is to empower
yourself, all right? Now see for example,
in the villages of India where I work, people
have given them alcohol, they have given up
all bad habits, they have become very dynamic,
they have become very well off, they are living
very well. In London, if you want to work,
I am sure you can get a home, no problem.
You see the Asians who have come here, I am
an Asian though I didn’t come as an immigrant,
they are becoming very rich, because they
work very hard, very hard, so those who want
to… in London. But in India it may not be.
But despite that, after Sahaja Yoga they have
improved so much – they have become so dynamic,
they have become so hopeful of life. But if
you just think that life is good for nothing,
let us now drink and be merry then it won’t
work out.
These homeless and all these conditions are
all such – because it is an artificial condition
you know, many people have houses but they
don’t want to give it for people to live.
Now if those people get transformation, they
won’t behave like that. You see the whole
behavior will change when the emancipation
of the society comes up. But I have seen in
the villages of India there’s a complete
transformation. The social conditions are
much worse but Indians are more satisfied
people, they are not so much. Here even, supposing
you offer a house, they will say, “No, I
don’t like this house.” You offer a job,
they’ll say, “I don’t want this job.”
All these things are there – also too much
of choices. But if you decide, London is not
difficult place I tell you to work hard and
get a house, not difficult, they can do it.
But people don’t work here, don’t work.
There are so many old people who haven’t
got anybody to help them. But these people
will never go and help them. They can earn.
This is a place where anybody can earn I think,
because I know people, Asians, who have come
here without any money are very rich today
- all have got big big cars, nice houses,
this, that. You can see that they are very
hardworking.
And then divorces, everybody third day if
you divorce someone what will happen to you?
You’ll end up without a home. No respect
for the wife, the wife has no respect for
the house. All upside down society. There’s
a big quarrel going on between husband and
wife – how can you have a home with this
husband and wife fighting? Even TV if you
open, nothing but fighting - you just don’t
want to hear anyone. See we had to decide
on certain things – that if we have to make
a home, then we have to understand our role
in life.
For a woman and a man, I agree, they are equal,
no doubt. But they are like two wheels of
a chariot which has some distance but they
are not similar. And no use fighting with
each other – when you can’t live without
each other, why should you fight? And the
children are on the streets. Every child I
find 18 years of age is out of the house.
I mean here the little children are killed
– why? In India, I cannot think of such
a thing. The reason, though they are very
poor, the reason is they know what is love.
And that is what I feel that the society has
to little bit take to Sahaja Yoga.
Now we have so many marriages in Sahaja Yoga
– I mean 1% marriages fail, 1%. They have
beautiful children, they are living very well,
they have good houses. Those who were really
hippies had nothing, are having nice houses
and everything they have. Also some of them,
were “Oh, so I am now fortunately, I am
without job.” And I said, “What, you are
very fortunate?” “Yea, now I am without
job. Very happy about it.” So I told the
gentleman that if you are not going to stick
to one job, you are not going to come to Sahaja
Yoga. And that fellow today has a big car,
a nice wife, children and a house.
So all these ideas of stupid freedom must
be given up. One has to come to a balance
and value your life. You must value it. Human
life is very valuable. With what great difficulty
God has created you and what are we doing
with it? The whole society has to take a turn
and think of living happily – if the husband
and wife, I mean such a relationship, husband
and wife cannot live together, then how do
we expect this world to have United Nations?
We cannot – it is falsehood.
In Sahaja Yoga we don’t have divorces – we
have sometimes, sometimes we have, is allowed.
But that is mostly when they are married beforehand
– fallen in love, now they are rising in
love, falling in love again, again falling,
rising in love again… how many times they
fall in love God only knows. It’s a funny
stuff going on. We have to face the reality.
So just worrying about these things, what
we should do, is to first of all become wise
and understand the problems. We can all solve
it. It is very simple, it is very simple to
solve the problems.
First of all we have to enter into the Kingdom
of God. And secondly, that it solves your
problems. Just worrying about poor people,
it’s also a kind of a fashion these days.
Because when I went to Switzerland, I met
a lady. She said, “I am very guilty.”
I said, “Why?”
“Because of Afghanistan.”
I said, “Are you Afghani?”
“No, but I am guilty about Afghanistan.”
“What have you got to do with Afghanistan?”
“Nothing.”
So it’s kind of an idea - what are we doing
about it? But a Sahaja Yogi does, Sahaja Yogi
finds out ways and methods of creating a convenient
life – a life where you can earn, you can
live… we do it – we have done, I have
so many examples. Because it’s a collective
life also you help each other. We didn’t
have rich people in Sahaja Yoga many because
they seldom come to Sahaja Yoga. They go to
false gurus because they can purchase the
guru – they can’t purchase Me. So mostly
the rich never come here. Bureaucrats also
don’t come, politicians don’t come. So
those people who come to Me are the people
who can easily solve the problem because they
are so collective, they can solve the problem.
You’ll be surprised, I went to Turkey – My
husband was not so for it – everybody said,
“That’s a Muslim country, this, that.”
I went to a Muslim country that was Turkey,
and a woman, I just said I must go. But I
was surprised, they worshipped Mother, they
worshipped their mothers. And they were so
beautiful – so many. In one shot, we got
70 people – serious Sahaja Yogis. But do
you know when I reached there, people from
America, from Australia, from all over the
world arrived there in Turkey to help Me.
I mean I was so enamored to see My children
coming, arriving there on their own - those
who could afford it. And the Turkish people
were so beautiful, I tell you. I found they
are the same everywhere.
There’s only a skin deep difference, I tell
you, otherwise we are just the same. So all
these problems can be easily solved – there’s
nothing so serious about it. There is
a very great thing no doubt, but unless and
until you are connected, it is like telephoning
without connection. There are people in India
who’ll go on saying “Rama Rama Rama Rama
Rama” like that. And the chakra of Rama
itself will be caught. They’ll be saying
“Shiva Shiva Shiva Shiva” and the heart
chakra, where Shiva resides, it will be caught.
The reason is, supposing you want to meet
the Queen – now if you go to Buckingham
Palace and go on saying “Elizabeth, Elizabeth,
Elizabeth” – you’ll be arrested! And
you’ll end up in a jail!
So you must have some connection, there should
be some protocol. Now if it is for kings and
prime ministers, what about God? He’s not
in your pocket. But once you are realized,
even once you take the name, it is sufficient.
What is there? He’s at your disposal all
the time there. But you have to have connection.
Now you are the citizens say of England, or
some place, all right so your government is
looking after you. Whether you are satisfied
or not is not the point. But they are looking
after you. But if you enter into the Kingdom
of God, then see the efficiency of this Kingdom.
You’ll be amazed if I tell you how things
work out. So amazing
it is, so amazing. See first of all they say
Kundalini has to rise. Then it sometimes comes
back to the centers which are needing more
help. So it is like a rope you can say, which
has many strings in it, very thin ones just
like a hair, and one by one they open out.
So first, very few of them pierce through,
open out the Sahasrara, by which you relax
and the chakras open out more. It goes on
like that. But once you are connected properly
then there’s no problem. But it is instantaneous,
no doubt about it. But for that you have to
come to our centers, don’t have to pay anything,
just spend some time and you have to master
it, that’s all.
There’s a question, what purpose do we have
on this planet?
The purpose of our existence is to prove that
God’s creation is the most successful thing.
That’s the purpose.
About Me, I will not talk - I am sorry. You
better get your realization and try to find
out about Me, because those who have talked
- you see human beings are mad people, you
don’t know. Christ said “I am the Son
of God” – which He was no doubt. And He
saidthat, “I am the door” – which He
was, no doubt. But they crucified Him. They
gave poison to Mohammed Sahib. They killed
so many saints. I know human beings very well,
so please I am not going to talk to you about
Myself at all. You better get your self-realization
- try to know Me. Because I have to do some
jobs, all right and for that, I want to live.
People are really sometimes so funny. Even
otherwise they behave in such a funny manner
that I can’t understand. As if I am going
to take away their property or something.
I am here to give you something that is very
important. Sort of you can say I am here to
complete the work of Christ, Mohammed and
all of them.
Yes please…. When you will give to others,
you will receive the blessings. That’s what
it is absolutely 100%. He said so many things.
I mean just explaining Sahaja Yoga throughout
I think.
[Question inaudible]
That
should not be the question just now, all right.
Because to say anything about it, you know
what happens with people. So this can be discussed
later on, when we get our self-realization.
Certain things at a level can be discussed
and this is what happened with all of them
because they had very little time to talk
to you. And that’s why everything has been
misinterpreted, misused, because to understand
the truth, to bear it also, one has to have
self-realization. This I have found out. If
you are not a self realized person you can’t
bear the truth, you cannot – it’s too
much for human mind to grasp and to allow
it to be a part and parcel of their understanding.
Truth is too much for them.
So the first thing should be that we get our
self-realization. Yes, my child…
[Initial question inaudible.
Mother: Can you get up, please?
Questioner: Yes, of course
Mother: Thank you.
Questioner: Do the colors of the chakras change
all the time?[… INAUDIBLE]
But the auras you see sometimes are these
colors only. But sometimes you are more strong
with one center, so that color shows. They
do not change, they are just the same.
All right I think now it is 10 o’clock so
we’ll take about 10 minutes more and let
us finish with our self-realization which
is going to take only 10 minutes. Those who
do not want to have should please leave, they
should not sit here and just watch other people.
That’s the only kindness I request of them
– that if you do not want to have self-realization,
it’s better that you should leave. Those
people who are standing, could not get place,
can come here or you can also give them places
if you want to give some places. No, not for
Sahaja Yogis, I said for others – for others,
for outsiders, Sahaja Yogis can stand up.
At the very outset you have to now understand
that we are going to enter into the Kingdom
of God and hence we have to little bit unload
ourselves. One of the conditions is that we
should not feel guilty – one should not
feel guilty at all. Yesterday, same problem
I said, but you were still feeling guilty.
Also it’s a fashion. Also I think the language
is such – all the time sorry, sorry, sorry,
sorry… Even when we used to receive telephones
we used to say “I beg your pardon.” But
now it is sorry, sorry, sorry – ten times
sorry. What is there to be so sorry?
So we have to be pleasantly placed towards
ourselves. We have to respect ourselves. We
have to be happy about ourselves. This is
first thing is not to feel guilty about anything
- just believe that you have done nothing
wrong which cannot be dissolved by this great
power of forgiveness. Please believe Me. But
if you want to stick onto a feeling like that
– “No, no, I am guilty” – it’s only
mental. Animals don’t feel guilty about
anything – a dog will bark, tiger will eat
anything that it wants to. It’s only human
beings who feel that way – that I’ve done
this wrong, I’ve done that wrong. All right,
so not to feel guilty that’s one point.
The second one is to forgive everyone, which
is very difficult for many people. I don’t
know how many mounds of unhappiness is in
the head because we cannot forgive. Mounds,
it’s not kilos and kilos. Yesterday I found
most of them had not forgiven and I had to
go on putting balm on their heads to take
out. So you must cooperate. Just forgive,
just forgive everyone. First of all forgive
yourself and forgive everyone. And be pleasantly
placed towards yourself. There’s no Greek
tragedy going on here – no tragedy. We are
in a very beautiful atmosphere and we are
going to go into the most beautiful area within
ourselves, that is our spirit. So we have
to be very light about it.
All right, with all this understanding, I
have to request you that we have to take out
your shoes because this Mother Earth also
helps us a lot. And not to be serious – not
to be serious about it. It’s not frivolous,
but it’s fun.
So you have to put your left hand towards
Me, which represents your desire to get realization.
If all the Sahaja Yogis could also sit down
it would be very nice. Please be seated and
don’t move about. Left hand towards Me like
that – be comfortable, if you want you can
put it on your lap or you can put it up if
you want to. Then the right hand needs to
be used for nourishing your centers on the
left-hand side. Now I’ll show you how we’ll
be nourishing. Before that, please remember
that put your both the feet apart from each
other – not too much, but slightly. Now,
left hand towards Me. I’ll show you before
and then we can close our eyes and work it
out.
Put your right hand on your heart – in the
heart resides the Spirit and Kundalini is
the reflection of the Holy Ghost, of the Adi
Shakti, within us, while the Spirit is the
reflection of God Almighty. So we put our
attention to our heart first. Then we take
our right hand in the upper portion of our
abdomen on the left-hand side and press it
hard. This is the center of our mastery. We
take down our right hand on the lower portion
of our abdomen and press it hard. This is
the center of pure knowledge that manifests
on our central nervous system. We take back
our hand in the upper portion of our abdomen.
And again we take it in the heart, in the
upper portion of our heart. Then we take it
in the corner of our neck and our shoulder
and put your head to the right. This is the
center we catch when we feel guilty. Then
we take our hand on our forehead and slowly
bring down our head on it to rest. Here we
press it on both the sides and this is the
center to forgive. We take back our hand on
the back side of our head and put our head
resting on it - this is the center for asking
forgiveness without feeling guilty. We stretch
our hand, with the center of our palm, we
put it on our head in the soft bone area of
our childhood, called as fontanelle bone area,
and slowly we put down our head. Here we stretch
our fingers and move our scalp carefully with
pressure, slowly, clockwise, seven times.
That’s all we have to do.
Now please close your eyes and don’t open
them until I ask you to open because attention
has to go inside. Put your left hand towards
Me. Now first you will feel thoughtless – so
don’t fight with your thoughts. Automatically
everything will work out. Don’t fight with
your thoughts, just keep watching and ultimately
you will feel cool breeze coming out of your
fontanelle bone area and you’ll also start
feeling cool breeze all around you which is
the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost, the cool
breeze of the all-pervading power as described
by Adi Shankaracharya, Salilam, salilam – it’s
cool, and cool.
So now, we put our left hand this way towards
Me and the right hand on the heart. Here you
have to ask Me a very fundamental question,
three times – “Mother, am I the Spirit?”
In your heart, ask the question “Mother,
am I the Spirit?” If you are the spirit
you are your master, because in the light
of your spirit you know what is right and
what is wrong – you can guide yourself.
So put your right hand in the upper portion
of your abdomen on the left-hand side, and
here please ask Me a question again three
times – “Mother, am I my own master?”
“Mother, am I my own master?”
As I have told you that I will not cross your
freedom, I respect your freedom, and only
if you want I can bestow this pure knowledge
on yourself, otherwise I cannot. So please
put your right hand in the lower portion of
your abdomen and ask the question, “Mother”
- or you can request “Mother please give
me pure knowledge.” Say this six times because
this center has got six petals. “Mother,
please give me pure knowledge.”
Now all the prophets of the past and the saints
and seers have built up for us a center of
mastery. But to open the center we have to
have all the confidence, so please raise your
hand and put it in the upper portion of your
abdomen on the left-hand side and say with
full confidence to nourish this center, ten
times, “Mother, I am my own master.” Please
say this ten times.
Now we have to know that we are not this body,
we are not this mind, we are not these emotions,
we are not this intellect. We are not our
conditionings or are we our ego. We are pure
spirit. So now raise your hand to your heart
and with full confidence say twelve times
“Mother, I am the spirit.” Please say
twelve times, “Mother, I am the spirit.”
You have to know that this Divine Power is
the ocean of love and compassion. It is the
ocean of joy and bliss but above all it is
the ocean of forgiveness, so there is no mistake
that you have committed which cannot be dissolved
by this ocean. So please forgive yourself
and put your right hand in the corner of your
neck and your shoulder and turn your head
to your right. Here you have to say with complete
confidence again, “Shri Mataji, I am not
guilty at all.” Or you can call Me Mother
– “Mother, I am not guilty at all.”
Sixteen times- please say this sixteen times.
Now one has to know whether you forgive someone
or don’t forgive, you don’t do anything
– it’s a myth. But if you don’t forgive,
then you play into wrong hands. So put your
right hand on your forehead and please bend
your head, resting on the hand as much as
you can and now press it on both the sides.
And here please, please, say it from your
heart “Mother, I forgive everyone.” Please
say it from your heart - please say it, otherwise
again I will have to work very hard on you.
So please say it from your heart – “Mother,
I forgive everyone.” You are not going to
miss your self-realization for not forgiving,
please. How many lives you have been seeking
the truth that this time you are not going
to miss it out.
Now take back your hand on the back side of
your head and push back
your head as much as you can resting on
your
hand
and here for your own satisfaction, without
feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes,
please say, “Oh Divine, if
I
have done any mistakes, please forgive me.”
TAPE ENDS