Now, we have decided not to have\h
too many marriages in Switzerland,\h\h
because, as you see now, we cannot go up\h
to that point where we can have marriages.
It’s all full of snow, you cannot have\h
fire, you cannot have all the arrangements.
Even a garland of flowers\h
may cost you fifty pounds.
And it’s not going to be cheaper marriage,\h
in the sense that everything is so expensive,\h\h
even if you find out in the market.
Now I have to make a request to you people: those\h
who want to get married in Switzerland should be\h\h
mostly the people who want to remarry, or those\h
people who can not at all afford to go to India.
But try to help the people who do not have enough\h
to go to India, that they get married in India.
It’s much easier, it’s much\h
[inaudible], much more simple.
All right?
So, if you understand that, if you can go\h
to India and if you have leave, then do it.
It’s better to do it there.
And you need not jump…They say that [Indian\h
saying], means a person who is very anxious\h\h
to get married, doesn’t even raise the\h
head-dress here, he ties upon his knee.
So one should not be that much excited.
Take a very sensible view of the whole\h
thing, those who want to get married.
And we have decided on the people\h
who could marry in Switzerland.
So those who have no money or something,\h\h
apart from this you should try to help\h
them if possible, every way possible.
I will also try to help.
Now another thing I have to say\h
is that you all have to send some\h\h
money for My travel, because I have to travel now.
We have been traveling throughout\h
England, again I have to travel;\h\h
and if there is no travel money,\h
you know who has to pay the amount.
But the people will be again\h
replacing the money of the travel,\h\h
which will again be there ready for other travel.
As it is, for India and all\h
that, you don’t have to pay.
But, I think that, if you decide that I have to\h
travel, that you should pay for My traveling,\h\h
then it is better that you should\h
send some money for the traveling.
We have been all over the country and, so\h
far, nobody has paid anything for travel.
So please try to send the\h
traveling money to Gavin Brown,\h\h
and all the money that you want to\h
contribute to him and the travel.
Now another one, we have decided\h
now to keep the emergency money.
Plus, if you people donate\h
more than the travel money,\h\h
or the money you want to donate for the programs\h
and all that, should be in the emergency money.
It can be used for other things\h
like mailing, for photography\h\h
or any kind of such expenses where you\h
have to have a hall – all these things.
Certain people, like Isle of Wight people have\h
sent five-hundred pounds for the program, within\h\h
three persons it was too much so I decided to\h
pay half of it to them back to the travel money.
Then we have to buy one tape recorder which will\h
cost about sixteen hundred, fifty in the market,\h\h
for which we have money – not the whole but we\h
have lot of it – and we have to buy that also.
So the only now money left with us is\h
emergency money and the travel money.
Out of it, the travel money is very limited.
If I have to travel, then either I pay and\h
then we reimburse, or something like happens.
It’s a big problem, because how\h
to adjust it and how to do it?
So keep it free from all these problems.
If you people donate some money for\h
the travel money to Gavin Brown,\h\h
it will be easier, which will\h
be again replaced by the people.
But just now the traveling is\h
important, for which you have to pay.
And the rest of it, just now, is that we\h
don’t have to pay much for anything else.
So that all the money should transfer to\h\h
the travel money – for the time\h
being, only for the time being.