So, the religion should be inside.
That's Sufism.
"Sufi" word comes from "safw" [clear].
Mother, Mr. Emin is teaching at the Marmara University
and teaching the interpretations of all the Quran.
Good.
Yes.
But, you see, Quran also is very much recent.
Kuranda bir ayet var.
O, hak diyor
Alahın yasaklarından çekinselerdi,
yani Allahın emirlerini yerine getirselerdi,
yasaklarından çekinselerdi yani yapmasalardı
gökten üzerlerine bereket yağdığını göreceklerdi.
Yani kuralları çiğnemeselerdi ve Allahın emirlerini yapsalardı.
Yogi: He is interpreting words from the Quran saying,
if people want to follow the regulations of Quran,
they would notice that Lakshmi would come to them.
It’s not that way. You see.
Yani bilmiyorum,
Evet inansalardı, inansalardı
ve yasakları çiğnemeselerdi,
Yogi: If they would believe and would not break the rules,
they would see the benefits.
Gökteki bereket kapılarının üzerlerine açıldığını göreceklerdi.
They would notice that the doors of heaven
would be opened to them and that Lakshmi would come to them.
To whom?
Yogi: To the people.
To those who are following the rules,
those who are  following strickly the Quran.
There’s no doubt about it.
But what I feel about the whole thing is that
that Koran was written after forty years
of  death of Muhammad Sahib.
And also-
Yok, ..... hayatında yazdı bunu.
and you cannot remember.
But despite that, I find Quran is perfect.
But there are many subtler things that are missing.
Now, for example, Muhammad Sahib
has said that he went on a white horse,
through the seven heavens.
Now that people don't understand.
Anlamazlar
So, that is the, he has described exactly what happens
when the Kundalini rises.
Hiç giden gelen yok aslında.
Bir yere gitmiş gelmiş değildir.
What he says?
He says that actually, he is not travelling somewhere
No, no, no, it is within yourself.
Kendi içindeki dünyaları fethederek
Within yourself, he crosses.
O Miraç tamamen ruhani bir hadise..
Yes, but that is what is Sahaja Yoga.
That is what, yes.
Aynı, Aynı
But what has happened that
because of poetry,
as people don't understand.
And they are misinterpreting. Mainly, they are misinterpreting.
Yok, dini dışarıda arıyorlar.
People look, are searching the religion outside, not inside.
That's the point.
Nokta bu.
That's the point. But what he has said -
Ama tasavvuf ehli biliyor
onun ruhani bir seyaghat olduğunu.
Sufis know that this journey is a spiritual journey.
Yes, of course. But the trouble is people
don't understand and they are misled.
Because people want to make money out of them.
Or they want to gain some sort of a violence or something
and they are just bringing a bad name to
uran initially and also to Muhammad Sahib.
Ama zaten o ruhani seyahat yani 1,5 milyar
müslümanın hepsini sorunu değil.
Her insan iç dünyasına dönüp te o miracı zaten yaşayamaz.
He believes that...
Yani avamın problemi değildir.
Avamın böyle bir problemi yoktur.
the people, the common people is not
seeking the Miraj within himself.
That's it.
Biz ona havas diyoruz işte tasavvufen
That's true. That is the main thing
that we talk about in Sahaja Yoga
that, "You know thyself" is said in the Quran also.
Hepsinde öyle.
So, when you have not known yourself,
you are not a müslüman.
Without knowing yourself, what are you surrendering to God?
It's an important thing that first you know yourself.
Can you believe that all religions have said the same thing?
Christ has said the same, Krishna has said the same,
Rama has said the same,
Zoroaster has said the same thing all
of them have said the same thing.
Krishna, Adem Aleyhisselama daha yakındır.
Adem Aleyhisselama, ilk dine daha yakındır.
Krishna, Krishna, yes, very close to Adam to Adam's religion.
But Adam, they did not know "Ruh".
Yok, hiç birisi yazmamıştır, çocukları yazmamış.
O zamanın şairleri de kitap yazmıyordu.
He believes that the poets from that time didn't have "Ruh" either.
True, I agree. But, you see, whether
it is Krishna or anyone of these people,
they are all just the same.
And they are building up
human beings to find out about themselves.
And also, Sufis are like that.
Şimdiki eğitimde de öyle bir şey yok.
Biz eşyayı yanıyoruz ama, insanı
tanıtmaya gelince kimse bir şey bilmiyor.
Yani bunun en ileri ülkelerdeki resmi eğitim, okullarda öğretilen şeyler
siz  tercüme edebilirsiniz
Orada da insanın kendisini tanımasına yönelik bir şey yoktur.
İşte ahlak, duşarıya dönük bir takım kurallar var.
burnunu karıştırmayacaksın, yere tükürmeyeceksin falan gibi.
Ama iç dünyamıza ait bir bilgi vermiyor,
bugünkü modern eğitim de bir şey vermiyor.
The education today is only teaching ............
the outside, the material, not the inside.
Yes, correct. I agree with you.
But outside was worked out, I don't know.
But it has to be worked out inside.
Because, when it is worked inside,
as it is said that, "At the time of "Qiyamah" [Resurrection],
your hands will speak" and they speak actually.
So, by outside -
Şimdi de konuşuyor ellerimiz, ayaklarımız.
Now our hands and feet are speaking also.
Haa?
He says, "Now our hands and feet are speaking also".
Ah, that's the thing, but they are very few and they are the Sufis.
İşte konuşuyor da dinleyen yok.
They are speaking but very few are listening.
Also, you should know what do
they mean, what are they saying.
And that is what is explained in Sahaja Yoga.
You can verify it.
Hz Mevlananın bir sözü var.
He is Mevlevi by the way.
Hum?
He is from the part of Mevlevi, Mevlana.
Jalal addin Rumi.
Whirling dervish.
O diyor ki; şimdi sohbet ediyor.
O diyor ki...
But he also didn't say how you become,
Ben mi?
how, what to do-
Uzun bir macera.
You see, whatever he was, he was great.
And he has written about his own understanding and feelings.
He should tell you about his feelings, how he became Mevlevi?
He didn't say that.
No, he says that Mevlana, he didn't explain openly how to become.
No, no, no, he didn't, he didn't.
He didn't.
I agree, what he has done, he said is-
what is has talked that after becoming a Realized soul,
what ??????  think what you talk
and it's like, you can say, the Chinese
system of Tao, same thing, same thing.
Tao also is a system in which he describes
what happens to a person who is a Tao.
The one who is a Realized soul,
what happens to him?
How he is above everything,
how he works out, how he has no fear.
But that is what you are saying how it is.
But how to achieve it? They never told.
Açıklıyorlar, açıklıyorlar Mesnevide var.
How human beings achieve it?
And that too, collectively.
Toplulukların ulaşması, şeydir, biraz zor.
Evvela şey olması lazım, arzu duyması lazım o topluluklatki bütün hepsinin
Toplumun arzusu dünya nimetlerinedir, dünya lezzetlerinedir.
The people, common people, have no desire to achieve a spiritual thing.
No, no, no. Not now. Now it's a different thing.
Because the world is so much full of struggle and strike and all that.
This has started.
All over the world, there are thousands of people-
O zamanda öyleydi. Mevlananın zamanıda da savaş vardı.
Moğollar bütün Türk illerini istila ederek geliyorlardı.
Mevlana da kaçtığı için geldi Konya'ya.
During the time of Mevlana it was also very much struggle.
The Moghuls were invading that land
and he escaped and came to Anatolia.
But this is a special time. It's already predicted in our scriptures also.
In Indian scriptures, that this is the time where people will get their Self-realization collectively.
In your Italy only, in your country only, there are so many who have got it.
He says, "Inch' Allah" [If God wants it].
Türkiyenin öbür islam ülkelerinden farklı durumu var.
Bizde İslamı ayakta tutan tasavvuf kültürüdür.
He believes that the fundamentals of Islam in Turkey is the Sufism.
Yani bir Suudi Arabistan'dan hatta  Mısır'dan, Libya'dan
Afrika ülkelereinden çok farklıdır.
But one Sufi cannot make others Sufis, it's the point.
But in Sahaja Yoga, we can make thousands.
Ama şimdi o dergahlar kapandığı için herşeyi konuşmak mümkün.
Yapıyorlardı. Yapmadılar ama hepsinde silsile var, şecere var.
Yani yukarıya doğru etkileşim olarak gidiyor. Mesela bir kişi
10 tane halife bırakıyor, onun şeyi halifelere bakıyor.
Binlerce dergah var.
Yalnız İstanbul 500 bin nüfusken
ki bunun yarısı müslüman nüfusudur o zaman.
He knows the point as Istanbul was
only five hundred thousand people.
Only the half of five hundred thousand
people were Muslims at that time.
520 tane tekke ve dergah vardı.
They were five hundred and twenty Sufi centres.
I know, I know that's why it's so important for me.
But to give it collectively and to give
the pure knowledge is very important.
Kitlelere vermek için şu,
kitlelere kültürü veririsiniz,
ama sufi yapamazsınız. Sufi için ayrıca eğitim, mezheb lazım.
Yani şimdi siz çok çok hijyen, yani sağlık kültürü veririsiniz kitlelere.
ama bir kulak mütehassısı yetiştiremezsiniz kitlelerin içinden.
Bu özel bir eğitim tıp gibidir.
Emin hocam Shri Mataji de onu anlatmaya çalışıyor.
İnsanlara bu bilgiyi nasıl aktarırsınız onu anlatmaya çalışıyor
Yüzeysel bir kültür verirsiniz ama çok .... olur.
Evet yani, biraz günahtan sakınmayı,
biraz kendine dikkat etmeyi falan verirsiniz.
Mikroptan sakınmayı, temizlik kültürü falan gibi...
It's spontaneous awaking, without effort.
It's not  coming from the brain, it's coming from inside
and it is happening in no time, like this.
Şimdi şöyle bir küçük fark var orada, yakalanması gereken
Sahaja Yoga bilgi ve söyledikleri olarak
İslamdan farklı hiç bir şey söylemiyor.
Yok ben farklı demiyorum, şimdi büyük kalabalıkları...
Onu anlatmaya çalışıyorum
...Sufi yapmak, yani böyle binlerce
yüzbinlerce Mevlana yetiştirmek
yok böyle bir şey yani.
Peygamber bile kendisine inananaları peygamber yapamıyor.
Ama belli bir yere kadar getiriyor işte.
Aliler yetişiyor, Ebu Bekirler yetişiyor.
Ama bunlar sonra gidiyor.
Sonra şey vardır,
Kaynaktan uzaklaştıkça
etki alanından kurtulma vardır.
Hz İbrahim peygamberdi, İsmail de onun oğluydu.
Her ikisi de kendisini Allaha adamış insanlardı.
Ama diyor ki kuranı kerimde,
bir zaman geldi ki onun çocukları
namazı da terkettiler, ibadeti de terkettiler.
ve günaha daldılar,
kötü yola düştüler diyor.
Şimdi onların hepsini biliyor Shri Mataji de
bir sistem anlatacak
nasıl olacağını anlatacak size müsade ederseniz.
Estağfurullah, hayır yani kalabalıkların işi değil.
bu çok arzulu, çok istekli
ve bu işe inanmış olması,
bağlanmış olması
kendini bu işe vermiş olanların eğitimidir.
Ama şimdiki iletişim araçları ile kültürünü verebiliriz.
Mevlananın yerinde eğer televizyon olsaydı
böyle onbeş yirmi kişi ile değil de
belki binlerce insana ulaşabilirdi.
In Sahaja Yoga, we don't need to do
big penances, tapasya, dancing, this and that.
It is just a spontaneous happening.
In her presence, the Kundalini awakens,
goes up and we get this enlightenment.
And then the full knowledge of Muhammad,
Jesus, come to us spontaneously.
Complete, absolute.
Şimdi sizin söylediğiniz...
Without effort.
entellektüel kısmı işin. Televizyonda falan anlatılabilecek
bilgiler kültürler tamamen akli iş.
Shri Mataji'nin  varlığı ve getirdiği tüm insanlara
bu iç uyanış dediğimiz
ki adı da bunun kundalini diye isimlendirilen iç enerji
Shri Mataji'nin varlığı ve öğretileri sayesinde
spontane bir şekilde anında uyandırılması
ve bu enerjinin anında uyandırılması ile
o bilgiye olan, o bilgiyi otomatikman
bir kere zaten o arzu
saf arzu yoksa bir  kişide zaten bu olmuyor.
Orada haklısınız.
Ama o arzu içinde olan herkes
Shri Mataji'nin sahaja yoga yollarıyla
spontane bir uyanış yaşıyor ve bu kundalini dediğimiz
enerjisinin uyanması ile ortaya çıkan bir durum
Bu aydınlanma diyelim,
enerjisel aydınlanmayı yaşadığı zaman bir kişi
ondan sonraki bilgileri absorbe etmesi
çok daha kolay oluyor.
ve Shri Mataji bu dönemde de
şunu ısrarla söylüyor yıllardır dünyada
bu bütün öğretilerde, sufizmde de böyle
değişik hindu öğretilerinde de böyle
daha değişik derin spiritüel bilgilerde de böyle.
Yani bir elit tabaka var
ve bu elit tabaka ancak buna varabilir
kitleler varamazın
tersini iddia ediyor.
Kendisi bir şey söyledi:
Peygamber efendimiz ruhani miracı anlattı
fakat onu dinleyenler, daha kendi
hayatındayken beyaz atın üzerine bindi
gökyüzüne çıktı uçtu gitti, çyle anladılar.
neyse...
Yani herkesin doğru anlaması diye bir şey yok.
In thousands, all over the world,
they just put the hands like this
and the get awakened.
They see, you see the eyes sparkling.
Ben onun söylediklerine itiraz etmiyorum.
Mesele çok zor olduğunu anlatmaya çalışıyorum.
What, Shri Mataji, he is trying to tell us is that it's not to
to  come against what we are saying,
it's just that from his knowledge,
But he is a Sufi and he is my son.
From his knowledge, what he thinks that
it is very difficult because he doesn't know.
Ah, yes. It used to be not now
Ben fakültede hocayım.
4 sene çocuğa ders veriyorum.
Bunun içerisinde diyelim ki 80 kişilik sınıf,
8 tanesi, 4. sene sonunda
benim talebem gibi beni anlıyor,
70 tanesi yine anlamıyor.
He says when he is educating the children in school,
he is teaching them Quran,
and he starts with eighty of them, and after
four years he says that only eight of them
come out with full understanding of what I'm telling now.
No, you go the other way round.
Sahaja Yoga is the other way round.
First, we make them the Sufis
and then we give them the Quran.
Şimdi Sahaja Yogada tek teknik farklı
diyor anlayış farkı olmasa bile,
Biz öncelikle Shri Mataji'nin varlığı ve öğretileri ile
bu aydınlanma önce yaşanıyor, bilgi arkadan geliyor.
Bilgi ile aydınlanma değil,
Önce enerjisi ile, kundalinisi ile aydınlanma sağlanıp
arkasından o aydınlanmaya kavuşanların bilgilendirilmesi
That's the way it is.
Tam ters çalışıyor.
Ben anlıyorum, ben onun görevini anlıyorum.
Şimdi mesela aklıma geliyor söylüyorum şimdi,
mesela kendileri Hindu
değil, değil
hindistanda da..., efendim,
Hindu değil
Esası, doğuşu Hristiyan.
ama bu öğretilerin içinde...
Yani Hindistanlı değil midir?
Hindistanlı.
Tamam.
Only after the awakening, the scriptures can be understood.
Hindistanlı değil mi?
Şimdi kendi dilini bildiği
içinde yaşadığı,
kültürünü tanıdığı
toplumda ne kadr etkili olabiliyor?
Şu anda çok hızlı oluyor.
Bırakın Hindistanı, dünyada oluyor.
Yani gittiğiniz zaman şaşırabileceğiniz boyutta
milyonlar, yüzbinlerle karşılaitırabileceğiniz...
Hayır şimdi ben partizanları demiyorum,
sevenleri çok
ben de sempati duyuyorum mesela,
okudum güzel bir şey
When she gave conferences, many professors,
university professors, teachers of Quran,
they came to Shri Mataji and they said,
"The way you explain, Shri Mataji, the Quran,
it was never understood before" and never had...
Fundamentalist, so many fundamentalists.
I remember ...
First, you give them the experience
of the All-pervading Power of "Ruh".
Once they get the experience, then they go deep.
Yani önce kapıyı açıyorsun,
Sonra lambayı yakıp içeriyi düzene koyuyorsun.
Aynen öyle.
Now he says, "First, open the door"
And then get it. It's correct. Correct! That's all it is.
Ama işte her kapı kolay açılmıyor.
Paslanmış oluyor kilit.
Not every door gets opened easily. Some of them are really rustic.
But Shri Mataji has the key.
To all the doors.
She has the master key.
Çok yüksek bir görev üstlenmiş.
Bu her babayiğidin yapacağı iş değil.
İnşallah farikalı olur, başarılı olur.
Yani oan dua ediyoruz,
He understands your mission is very high and ultimate
and he hopes all the best to your mission.
He has to get many Sufis.
If you want to change the world,
you can't manage with one or two.
Even to understand Quran or Bible or anything,
you have to have that eyes.
In Sahaja Yoga also, also "vidya" [knowledge],
is what are all the centres are there,
what are the problems of the centres.
And we have seen that people have cured physically, mentally.
And also, they become what they call, thoughtlessly aware.
So, all the religions have talked about it.
It's not only Quran, it's not only Bible, it's not only Gita.
All the religions have said the same thing.
Promlemleri çözeceksiniz, ruhi problemleri.
What she said?
She is asking, "How is that possible?"
It’s possible because God has made within us all the arrangements.
He is a great organizer.
And we have within us that power
that's the Mother Power
which rises and pierces through your fontanelle bone area
and makes you one connection with that All-pervading Power, the "Ruh"
Excuse-me, here in Sufism, also there is a terminology for that moment.
It is called "Ana al-Haqq" [I am the Truth]
In this religion.
"Ana al-Haqq", saying, I am God. Saying, I am God.
I am religion.
I am religion, I am God.
Yok, "I am God" demez.
Yani ben Allahın bir bütünüyüm, parçasıyım.
Ben de Allahın parçasıyım.
Ben hakikatim der.
No, no, you become. Actually, you become.
Yes, the Truth. I am the Truth.
You become. You don't have to have a certificate.
You just become. First, your hands start speaking.
You know what are these centres are within you.
Every knowledge, perfect knowledge within is available