In Sahaja Yoga the Guru puja has a very different
significance from any other guru puja.
When you worship your Guru you are also worshiping
the Guru within you.
This is not in any other guru-disciple system
because, in you, the Guru, the Master has
been awakened.
And so, when you are worshipping your Guru,
then this Master within you is also worshipped,
you respect it, you glorify it, you awaken
it, and you manifest it.
This we have to realise that – in Sahaja
Yoga – if you are a Sahaja Yogi.
Now, the quality of Guru, first and foremost,
is that he makes you meet God: means he raises
the Kundalini and establish the relation between
the All-pervading Power.
And as your Guru is Adi Shakti, you make that
person meet, also, the Adi Shakti.
So you have a double advantage that, at the
same time, when you give them Realisation,
not only that you make them feel the union
with the Divine Power, but you can make them
meet the Divinity Itself, the source of Divine
Power.
So your responsibility, as Sahaja Yogis, is
very great because in you is there is the
Guru.
Now in our mantras we say that, “Mother,
I am my own Guru."
But, saying that, do we realise that: if I
am my own Guru, this “I” and “my Guru,”
between the two, what have I achieved?
Where am I?
Can I guide myself?
Have I got the light of the Spirit on my attention
so well established and manifested that I
can guide myself and guide others later on?
First of all, in the Guru principle it is
important that you see to yourself – the
introspection: Can I be my own Guru?
Have I become my own Guru?
Now, in your case, your Guru is a Mother,
a woman, so, it has to be among women that
the development of their Guru qualities have
to be very well manifested.
But it’s just the way it is not.
For them, they are still the mothers or they
are the wives or they are Sahaja Yoginis.
But they don’t realise that you are also
the Gurus.
And, because your Mother is a Guru, because
She is a woman; and you have to be also of
that quality, that people should say, “Look
at this woman, she’s such a Guru."
But still, as I hear from the different leaders
that the ladies are absolutely still very
much far away and are very few who can be
called as real Sahaja Yoginis.
It’s a sad thing to hear.
Because if you still keep to all these mundane
things of womanhood and the drawbacks of womanhood,
which has come out of domination maybe, because
of always they were shown to be something
lower.
Specially in the Christian religion they were
never regarded as something holy.
They have this kind of a diffidence in them
that they don’t understand that dharma can
be established more by women than by men.
And the Guru’s work is to establish the
dharma – in the society, in the family,
in relationships.
All these Gurus, which are representing all
these great symbols here, have done nothing
but have established dharma.
But, first of all, before establishing the
dharma, we should watch ourselves – have
we got dharma within ourselves or not?
First of all, the quality of a person who
has dharma is that he listens to others, he
obeys.
And this is something [that] has gone wrong
with the Western women, I think, that they
have forgotten how to listen to others, how
to obey others.
That’s why their children also don’t obey
them.
Obedience, if you do not have, nobody’s
going to obey you.
First, you must learn to obey.
A person like Kabira, because he was born
of a unknown cast, people didn’t know what
he was born from, and he could not go directly
to any Guru.
So, he heard about Ramanand, a great Guru
of those days, who used to go to the river
Ganges every morning to have his bath.
So one day on his steps Kabira kept lying,
and in the darkness the Guru could not see,
and he touched him with his feet.
He said, “Who are you?”
So he said, “I’m Kabir, and I’m your
disciple."
And he caught hold of his feet.
And when he caught hold of his feet, he [Ramanand]
said, “Alright, come along!”
And then he became such a great saint in India.
People know him more than they know his Guru;
he became so great.
The basic thing is humility.
Yesterday you saw how the musician (Nishat
Khan) was humble.
All the time he was humble.
He didn’t know how to express his humility
every time.
All the time he was humble.
Because in humility only you can receive the
blessings, you can receive the quality that
is of your Guru.
Now, for a Guru as you have seen that, in
My own way, in My own image, you have to come
up.
First of all your life should be absolutely
transparent.
Transparency is the essence of Sahaja Yoga.
Everybody should know what you are doing,
where you are going, what is the way you live,
what is the way you are behaving.
I have seen people, who are gurus, also in
the sense that we call them leaders, or we
can call them sub-gurus, or they can not be
called as priest, but I can say ‘communication
centres’ as they are.
In them you find that they are very fussy
type of people.
Always think about their body, always think
about their comfort, always grudge about – nobody
looked after them – as if they suffer from
persecution-mania!
Or they will grudge about food, “I didn’t
eat my food for one day!”
Doesn’t matter!
For a Guru it’s better to starve for about
three, four days nicely, so that you get over
this idea of hunger.
You’ll be surprised since I’m here I have
not eaten anything much, and just drinking
something, because just the Guru has no hunger.
Because it is in your stomach the Guru, vibrations,
are so much that you don’t feel like eating
anything.
So then, what do you eat and how do you eat
and all these things that we have given up
to come to Sahaja Yoga.
So even if leaders have this nonsense in their
head [like] what do you get to eat!
I mean, this is the basics, absolutely!
And when I hear some people telling Me, oh,
what did they eat and how did they eat and
all!
It’s like I feel they are like tourists
in Sahaja Yoga.
Just come in Sahaja Yoga like tourists, you
see, to see places and go round and to know
where you get, in what restaurant, you get
good food and cheaply.
All this is so basically, absolutely not a
manifestation of Guru Principle.
Now you have seen your Guru as She is.
I do not know what I eat, what they give Me,
what I want.
They go on giving Me whatever they think I
like, and I just don’t know if I like that
thing or not, or what is it.
If they ask Me, “Mother, what will You have?”
I said, “What will I have, I don’t know
really, what will I have?
Anything!”
So there has to be no choices.
First of all not to waste your attention on
choices.
Of course, only on vibrations.
I mean, supposing, you go to a restaurant,
find all kinds of funny vibrations there,
people are getting drunk or anything, then
of course you should say.
But all the choices must be based on vibrations
and not on material things.
That you get something nice there, “Let’s
go there,” and they’ll travel for fifty
miles to go eat something nonsensical.
It should be all nonsense for all Sahaja Yogis.
And when I said “Sahaja Yogi” it means
also Sahaja Yoginis.
So the food part of it is aswadha.
You should not have any taste for any special
food.
Specially in France to say that people may
not like, but French are very, very conscientious
or aware about the food part.
I don’t know how far they make really good
food, but at least they think they eat very
good food.
So, the eating of good food is a kind of a
addiction.
It’s a kind of an addiction; it’s something
like drug – that you must have good food.
So Zen started this system of what they call
the tea ceremony.
In the tea ceremony what they did, I mean,
I have been through that and it’s really
quite a test of people.
With Me it was alright, but the rest of them
got really frightened.
That in the tea ceremony whatever rituals
they do they give you a tea, which is so bitter,
and we can say [like] quinine raised to power
108!
It’s like that.
And they give you very nicely, handle you
with such ritual that you have to take it.
So first they say, “You see the cup without
thinking."
So he tried to make thoughtless awareness
through the cup.
I don’t know how much one can achieve with
that.
But that tea if you take once, your tongue
is good for anything.
And to compensate it they give you something
sweet, which is again sweetness raised to
power 108, so sweet that it becomes bitter!
So sweet.
So this is just to conquer the tongue [that]
Zen must have thought that better give them
this tea ceremony where there is no tea, there’s
nothing but just you really give such shocks
to your tongue, so that after that you can
eat whatever you get.
And that’s why you must know that Japanese
can eat anything.
They have solved their food problem because
they can eat anything!
They can just fish out some crabs or could
be some prawns, just peel them out like peanuts
and eat them like that.
I think Zen has solved this problem for them,
because they have food shortage and this is
how they can eat everything: they can eat
the bark of the tree, they can eat the snake,
they can eat the lizards, they can eat the
frogs, everything they can eat, so all their
eating problems are solved in that country
by Zen, I think, because you have no taste.
But in this I think the worst are, in the
whole world are Indians.
They are the fussiest people for food.
Because their women have spoiled them.
They know very good cooking and they know
how to handle their husbands by cooking very
well.
And the way they cook food for them, you see,
the men have to go back to Indian food.
Even if they travel the whole world, they’ll
need Indian food, they can’t get over their
tongues.
It is such a big conditioning in India of
food that I just don’t know how will they
get out, the, absolutely, the basics which
are important.
Gandhiji tried that very much in the ashram
(laughing).
He used to give horrid food, boiled food with
the oil of mustard on top and then nobody
could eat that.
Raw!
And he used to make everybody eat that.
Not only that, he would make them clean the
bathrooms, WC’s, everything so that you
get rid of your nose also, that you need everything.
Because so many people you will, while eating
also in India will put something to their
noses, and they smell everything.
So they are oversensitive to their tongue
and to their nose.
But not to their eyes, to eyes they are not.
For eyes I would say the most sensitive people
are Japanese and Chinese and also the Western
people are very much sensitive because they
don’t like to see anything dirty, filthy
or ugly.
Indians won’t mind any dirt, filth, anything,
just like dogs and what you call, horses or
buffalos!
They can walk through any dirt, filth – anything!
Nothing matters to them, anything ugly, any
ugly building or an ugly dress or anything
is alright for them.
It doesn’t matter, to their eyes it doesn’t
matter at all.
Only thing [is that] kitchen should be clean
and they are all the time in the kitchen.
So we don’t have to learn all these bad
things from Indians.
There are some good things they have, but
there are certain things [which] are very
bad conditionings.
And the next to that are, I think, the French.
But if you eat English food you can become
quite good because there’s no taste in English
food (laughter and applause).
So, I have no problem anywhere because I think
I have no taste at all and I can eat anything
any way it is cooked, it’s alright, I don’t
bother about what is cooked, what is not cooked.
But if you have some French people for a dinner
in a restaurant they will spend forty-five
minutes deciding what they are going to eat,
and what a waste of energy!
Forty-five minutes just to decide what they
are going to eat!
After all what is so great, what you are going
to eat?
It’s all there.
Just one thing that everybody should have.
So for Sahaja Yogis it’s important to give
up this idea, “I will have this."
First of all nobody should ask, “What will
you have?”
To Me also.
I do not like people asking Me questions [like],
“What will You have?”
Because I’ve to think about it and I want
to be in Nirvichara (laughter and applause).
So, this is a, one, big ordeal, which we do
not understand: how much we are attached to
food.
And food goes in the stomach.
And not only that it spoils our guru system,
but also spoils our physical system.
So we should try not to look at food.
That’s why fasting was told to the all the
people who wanted to develop their Gurupada,
so that they should not fast.
But they do not fast normally because they
think of food, so there’s no fasting.
I mean, fasting means that you go into nirvichara
and don’t think of food.
But they are all the time thinking of food,
so it has no meaning and you are just the
same whether you eat it or not, your mind
is eating it all the time.
Then you start thinking, “When will I end
my fast and know where will I go to have what?”
So this is a very basic thing that we should
get rid of our habits, of our conditionings
– what we are going to have and what food
we are going to have.
Our children also should be given a proper
training about it that – it’s alright,
sometimes there is no salt, sometimes there’s
no sugar, doesn’t matter.
And sometimes there’s nothing, doesn’t
matter.
Nothing [is] important for a Sahaja Yogi,
you can live without food for days together,
no problem.
So for a Sahaja Yogi there’s nothing like
taste of food and hunger.
There’s only one hunger is to be purified,
to be clean.
This is one of the things that dirties our
mind, we should say, that we think about food
all the time.
Even in Russia I found people carried all
Indian things there, they were cooking all
Indian things, and I am, poor thing, I can’t
eat anything.
So they cooked, brought everything for Me,
thinking I’m an Indian, but they don’t
know I am Zen – I cannot, I do not, have
sense of taste.
So once, to get over taste one has to work
out.
It’s an experiment you have to do with ourselves.
Unless and until we introspect ourselves and
do experiments we cannot rise.
Because though the Kundalini is trying her
level best, but your conditionings are so
great that it cannot pierce through and cannot
make you onto that Guru level.
If you see the lives of all these Gurus: they
were married, they had children, they lived
a normal life but in their own personal life
they were absolutely detached people.
So, first detachment should come from food.
And there whatever you like you just don’t
eat.
That’s the best way.
Because already because of liking something…supposing
if somebody’s fond of ice-cream.
He must have already spoiled his liver; so
then, give [it] up now.
If you like pasta, give up pasta.
If you like something else, just give up,
don’t ask for it and don’t eat it at all;
so that, you see, your mind will get little
bit detached from it.
It’s very easy to achieve this detachment,
I think, if you work it out in a sensible
way.
Just try to punish your body.
You see, if you are your Guru, you better
take hold of first of all your body and your
conditionings.
You have to treat your body with this thing.
I am told many girls who have married abroad
are still making their Indian food and eating
that.
It’s horrible it is!
They should starve.
If they starve for say about five, six days
or maybe eight days, then they’ll eat any
food in any case.
That’s why the fasting is given.
So one should adjust oneself to any kind of
food you can have.
And if you want to survive then you eat anything,
so just make it a point that you get rid of
this very simple conditioning you have – of
liking the food that you want to eat and you
don’t want to have anything else.
I think as Sahaja Yogini or Sahaja Yogi who
cannot get rid of this little thing, then
how can you call him a Sahaja Yogi?
I don’t know.
He’s very asahaj.
Because the other day I met one lady.
I said, “What is the matter, where have
you been?”
She said, “I have been looking out for some
sort of an Indian ingredient."
I said, “How can you get it here in this
Spain?
You cannot."
“Why?”
“Because they asked me to make Indian food."
“Alright.
Then without that can’t you make Indian
food?
What is the need to run all the way, whole
day for a one small little thing called hing
(asafoetida)?”
There’s a big name for that, it’s a small
little thing.
Just to get that she had to run all over the
places to get it!
So for people who are Sahaja Yogis if they
are sahaj, whatever is available you can make
something nice out of it and eat it.
So that shows what?
It shows sagacity, shows trupti (तृप्ति
– contentment), shows your satisfaction.
And that is one of the manifestations of a
Guru that he’s a satisfied soul.
He’s just self-contained, he doesn’t bother.
Now, for example, some people, specially in
the West, thank God, they are not spoiled
by their wives so much.
They don’t have so much of conditioning,
they can eat anything.
I’ve seen that when they come on the India
tour, all the Indians say, “Horrid food
was given and the poor things were eating
that horrid food and this and that."
And I asked them, “Which place you like
the best?”
They said, “Brahmapuri."
I said, “Eh?
They were saying Brahmapuri had the worst
food and everybody is complaining."
“No, no.
Brahmapuri was the best, because we could
bathe in the river and we could sing and we
could enjoy it!”
You see, that’s the sign of one thing, to
get rid of your bad habits of food business.
Now the second part is for the body you need
comforts.
I must congratulate the Western Sahaja Yogis
that they may be coming from any walk of life
– I must say, the Indians have to learn
from them – they may be coming from any
position or status.
All of them enjoy the comfort of the Spirit
when they travel in the Tour.
They do not ask for, “I haven’t got a
chair, I haven’t got a bed, I haven’t
got a proper things here."
In this way, you see, you will realise that
the body comfort is of no importance.
It’s, we have just spoilt our body, there’s
no need, no need.
Body you put it anywhere, will sleep in any
case.
If you cannot sleep for two nights, alright,
put on some music for one night or two nights
as we had here, you will sleep anyway! (laughter
and applause as everybody fell asleep during
the Nishat Khan performance the night before)
So this is the second point is that we have
to give up body comfort.
But the third point where I think the Western
people falter is their materialistic attitude.
Materialistic attitude and their fondness
of their eyes.
So one of them is the worst of all.
I mean, the worst in worst of all is that
you can never have, that’s such a big blot
if you have that is to have a roving eye and
things like that.
It’s out of question.
That’s out of question for women or for
men.
They are not Sahaja Yogis by any chance.
They have to have very clean eyes.
That part is alright.
And the second part is the greed, lust and
greed.
Of course, with Sahaja Yoga maybe the lust
part is over, but greed is still there with
so many who get lost.
So I would say Indians do not have this lust
problem, but they still have greed, greed
problem – means they want to buy something
like a radio or some electrical stuff they
must buy.
If they come abroad they must buy something.
It’s alright, if you get it, well and good,
if they don’t get it, well and good.
It should be [that attitude].
But for a Westerner, you see, he would not
like to give up his furniture, which his great
grandmother had it.
Though he can’t sit on it because it’s
so old.
If he sits on it, it will be break.
But he must keep it to show off that, “I
had a great grandmother who gave this unique
chair."
According to Indian standards it’s junk!
Absolute junk.
Because it is good for nothing you put it
in the drawing room, nobody can sit on it
and it looks junky.
But according to the Western mind the older
it is, the better – whether it is a junk
or anything – he’ll have so many junks
in the house and they will sell like hot cakes.
Because there’s a very subtle materialistic
attitude towards matter that, “This will
sell like hot cakes if I sell it,” because
there must be another mad Westerner who would
like to buy that junk.
You see?
So this junk that you have in the house it’s
better to get rid of, because God knows how
many people must have used [it].
It’s like a grave in the house.
It’s a grave.
So to have then also the antique jewellery.
Antique jewellery is another mad, antique
is a – what you can say – is the fad or
addiction of the Western people – antique.
For us nothing is antique because we still
produce antique things, beautiful things so
Indians don’t understand the value of antiques.
They don’t understand how these people are
so mad after torn things and broken things
and dirty things and filthy things!
But the Western mind has been brought up that
way.
Now, in these antique things I have seen that,
once I went to somebody’s house, you see,
and he asked Me with very great honour to
sit on his chair.
And as soon as I sat on the chair I thought
there were snakes and there were scorpions
all biting Me.
I got a fright, I got up.
I said, “What is it?”
He said, “This is from great, great, great
grandmother, you see, she gave us this thing."
I said, “It will break, I better sit outside."
(laughter)
So this also madness of this antique is so
much that it is unbelievable how people go
into it.
So there’s a joke in India there’s a very
great writer called as Premchand, he wrote
about two Englishmen going on the road of
Benares when they were hit by a lota (metal
pot), that they use for their bathrooms, fell
on their feet.
And it fell on their feet.
And jokingly he says, “on the feet where
all the bureaucrats fall."
Means, all Indian bureaucrats used to fall
at the feet of the English at that time!
So he made a joke.
But doesn’t matter.
Then the English, you see, looked at that
thing and they were very angry and immediately
they took to law, “You have to come to the
courts, you have to come to the police and
we’re going to report this has fallen there,
it has hit us,” and all that.
So there was a clever man, he knew the English
or the Western mind, he said, “Sir, do you
know this, this lota has very valuable!”
He said, “Why?”
“Because this one was used by Akbar the
Great.
So ancient it is.
” He said, “Really?”
“Yes it is and, you know, you just don’t
quarrel with them.
And ask them for this lota."
And he told in Indian language to them that,
“I have befooled these people, I have told
them that this lota belonged to Akbar and
you have to take this lota and use this lota
to just to befool them."
So then they asked, “But alright, we’ll
forgive you, we’ll not take you to any courts
or anything, but you just give us this lota."
They said, “No, we can’t."
He said, “Why?”
“Because it’s such an antique piece, you
see."
In India you won’t find anybody respecting
antique pieces, especially in Benares nobody
bothers.
(Laughter) So they said, “Really?”, “Yes,
it belonged to Akbar and, you know, my father
was, my forefathers worked with him, so he
gave us this lota, we can’t give you, we
are sorry, you see."
“No, no, no, no, please give us, you see,
and we’ll no take you to the police."
“Alright, you charge us, whatever money
you charge us,” and all that.
In those days they paid one thousand rupees,
you see, this is equal to, now, one crore
(10 million), I think.
They gave, these English paid them and bought
that lota, which had nothing to do with Akbar
or anyone.
So this madness of antique has to go away
from our minds.
It’s such a built-in thing within us, that
we always talk of antiquities.
Perhaps maybe because of wars everything was
destroyed and whatever was in the olden times
was something very beautiful and good and
now we are not making very good things, perhaps,
maybe that is the reason.
But now we are making nice things, we can
make.
Now in England I was surprised the old crafts
are coming up, everywhere I go the old crafts
are coming up.
So to respect antiques means you just stop
making the old craft revive.
Because you pay so much to the antiques, the
same thing made today won’t fetch the same
price as it was.
Now this has ruined our creativity, ruined
our handwork and it has ruined our whole – I
think the quality of our life, because the
way we are mad after antiques.
So this also should go from your head that
anything antique is something good.
It’s a very superficial value – if you
see to it.
Because people think that antique is something
expensive.
It’s just a marketing style that people
have felt that this is expensive, that is
expensive, so it’s something great to wear
something stupid and to say that, “this
is antique jewellery,” and go about.
I mean, God knows how many people must have
used it and must have worn it and what must
be the feelings of that person.
So we have to understand that this conditioning
that we have in our heads, that we must have
something antiques with us, keep something
of such value.
I mean, these questions never arose before,
so it’s not written in any books.
Anyone of the books of the Gurus is not written
that, “Don’t care for antiques."
They have written, “Don’t drink, don’t
smoke,” all other things which spoils your
Nabhi.
They’ve written all these things.
But they have not written that, “Don’t
worry about antiques so much."
You see, and I find that’s a craze nowadays
and so we have to tell people that we have
to be careful.
Moreover I feel the way people have gone to
drugs and that, maybe that because they used
so much antiques that the bhoots from the
antiques must have caught them.
Can’t understand that why people are so
melancholy, all the time crying, weeping,
and all that.
So the conditionings of these matter as we
think it to be is to be absolutely taken out.
Of course, I mean in certain countries we
should say that the antique things [that]
were made were good and nice.
But, only because something is antique it
should not be respected, [but] because of
its intrinsic value of aesthetics, it’s
alright.
But one has to see first of all the vibrations
of everything.
If the vibrations are good then you should
accept, otherwise not, because we have the
language of vibrations and we have to use
the language of vibrations.
Once you start using the language of vibrations
you’ll be surprised how you will get the
complete picture as to what is to be done.
So to get rid of these three conditionings
too, for our body is very important.
And the worst thing for a Sahaja Yogi [is]
to think that he’s sick: is a, sort of a,
tarnishing the name of Sahaja Yoga.
If you still feel you are sick you better
get out of Sahaja Yoga!
Because either you get well or you are not
a Sahaja Yogi, one of the two things.
If you are a Sahaja Yogi you have to see that
you get well and if there are certain problems
also – doesn’t matter.
Now, for example, supposing, I have certain
problems, which I know, because of Sahaja
Yoga, because of My position as the Mother,
position as Adi Shakti: certain physical things
I have to face, parasympathetic working I
have to face, but I go through it!
Is accepted.
You have to accept your body as it is and
you are not to sort of say that, “I’m
not well,” and “There’s something wrong
with me,” and go on complaining like some
old hag!
Never think you are old, first of all.
Never think that you have gone old or you
are no good.
Look at your Mother.
I never think that way.
Yesterday half of you were sleeping, still
I was alert and listening to the music and
today I’m again alert here.
So if you have a Guru then that image should
be with you that: “Look at our Mother.
She’s so old, how much She travels, how
much She does!”
Alright, you might say, She’s the Adi Shakti!
But little bit of shakti you too have.
And that shakti is to be shown by your full
dynamism.
If you have no dynamism and if you still feel
very weak that means you are not a Sahaja
Yogi.
So just ask for, ask for any amount of energy
– it can come to you.
That dynamism, it should be there.
Now this I would say, for the physical self
that one has to know that you are all younger
and getting younger and younger, but not the
stupidity of youth, but gravity, the gravity
of the age.
Actually I have seen children who are born
realised, they are very grave, they won’t
do anything that is not dignified.
And they will never, I’ve never heard them
talking to some of – the Sahaja Yoginis
have a bad habit of talking, “tuk, tuk,
tuk, tuk, tuk, tuk,” among themselves.
It’s a very bad habit.
Which shows that they [are] still very much
lacking.
Just wearing saris or wearing bindis you do
not become a Sahaja Yogini.
First of all, what is the gravity?
You should only speak whenever it is necessary.
So I have seen these Sahaja Yogis who are
born realised children they stand like this
before Me.
And they say very few words, but beautiful
words they speak.
And say things, which you can remember all
the time.
They just do not go on wasting anything.
And they are extremely obedient.
So from them one can learn that these are
born realised and the way their Guru principle
is acting, are we also acting the same way?
Or we are doing something that is not good
for our ascent?
So even after coming to Sahaja Yoga if you
do not try hard to introspect yourself, you
have missed the point that you compare yourself
with your Guru – all the time.
Now.
Then everything has to be understood in the
right perspective that we are Sahaja Yogis.
Now for a Sahaja Yogi first and foremost thing
[is] that he has to have love.
First.
For others, not for himself.
If you are all the time worried about yourself,
“My body is such, my this thing such, and
I have to do this and that,” then you don’t
love others.
But do you see to the comfort of others?
Do you feel the compassion of other Sahaja
Yogis?
Do you feel, “What have I to bring for them?
What is missing in them?”
Do you work it out?
Do you go out of the way to help them?
First of all Sahaja Yogi s.
Now Sahaja Yogis are different things.
I have seen many Sahaja Yogis will go and
take the side of the non-Sahaja Yogis and
try to debase the Sahaja Yogis.
Is a very wrong thing.
You belong to this new race and the people
who do not belong to this new race and if
they are attacking anybody: these are your
hands, your feet, your head, and if they attack
it, it is duty bound that you help them instead
of helping the others.
Maybe something wrong with this person, doesn’t
matter.
You need not show all the fair play there.
In that place you should support a Sahaja
Yogi out and out.
Later on you may correct and you may tell
that person, “You should not have done like
this, it was wrong."
So this dignity and this understanding comes
only through silence.
But if you are chirping all the time, talking
“tuk, tuk, tuk, tuk, tuk, tuk, tuk, tuk,”
it can never, never can make you a deeper
person.
You’ll be just flying in the air with all
that.
So for women now is best is to take to mauna,
is to keep quiet, just keep quiet.
They all the time want to talk.
This I’ve heard from all the leaders that
is a big problem with women.
They just go on talking stories, telling stories.
But if you ask them to come and speak, they
will start shaking.
How many can give speeches?
Women?
If you understand that if you cannot give
a speech, you better not talk also.
You should be able to give a speech because
your Mother is a woman, She gives speeches.
Why can’t you give some speech?
You cannot.
If I make you stand here, you’ll be shaking,
I know that.
But if it comes to murmuring souls, you are
there.
So that is one thing women have to be very
careful [about].
And as today is the Guru puja I have to tell
you things, not as a Mother but as your Guru.
That, if you have to ascend the best thing
is for you to stop talking.
“Maunam sarvatha sadhanam."
‘Maun’ means to keep quiet.
It gives you all kinds of facilities, just
keep quiet.
If somebody’s talking too much, just keep
quiet.
If somebody’s trying to criticise, keep
That’s your silence, that’s your right,
that’s your domain that you can keep silent.
Just watch that person.
If it comes then to answer, then you can answer
better.
But if somebody’s trying to attack ,you
just keep silent.
But this silence has to be established and
one should only establish by not talking too
much.
I have seen also when I am sitting here, I
have seen women talking among themselves,
and this is very wrong.
You must learn the silence.
Like yesterday I saw so many ladies also were
walking out, walking in.
In the church will you do that?
You won’t do it.
In the church there is no Christ, there’s
a horrible priest sitting there, but you cannot
do it.
You all keep quiet, you sit there nicely.
I’ve never seen anybody walking out here
and there and doing all kinds of things, putting
the children in front like that, making them
sleep.
Never!
Can you do that in the church?
What a discipline people observe in that church,
which is an artificial place.
And where you are now, that kind of a silence
has to be there and that kind of understanding,
that depth, that awe has to be there.
But because we have not yet developed that
Guru thing.
If we had developed it then immediately it
will work out.
You will see your gravity will show in your
behaviour.
So this is for our attention not to be wasted.
To discuss somebody, to discuss about others’
characters, we have no business.
Do we discuss the character of one hand to
another hand?
To discuss about what has happened about marriages,
things like that.
Also marriage is just…in Sahaja Yoga it’s
not such an important thing.
Some people pay too much attention to marriage,
you see, and marriage becomes a headache.
Also then, “What about my marriage?”
Then again ten minutes you see that person,
“What about my marriage?”
Again after ten minutes, “What about my
marriage?”
You want to run away.
I mean, you see, it’s something becomes
like a mania for people, “What should we
do?”
And the whole thing is, all depends, and the
whole programming depends on how you are going
to get married.
So you have come to Sahaja Yoga, you are sanyasis.
You are not married people in a way.
You are married only to Sahaja Yoga, that’s
your husband, that’s your wife.
And the so-called husband and wife are there.
But if they are not Sahaja Yogis then you
are unmarried, definitely.
So too much attention is paid in Sahaja Yoga
to marriages.
I have seen that before, marriage, before
Sahaja Yoga, marriage was a joke; every third
day there was a divorce and people would run
away and do all kinds of things.
Then when they got married after Sahaja Yoga
they are the greatest romantic people ever
known in the whole world!
I mean, all ‘Romeo, Juliets’ going about.
I just don’t understand.
Even in the Indian villages people complain
that, “What sort of these people are?
I mean, they have no sense at all and the
way they go round, are they the saints?”
So that saintliness, that sanyasta, that asceticism
has to be expressed in our married life.
I don’t mean that you don’t have relationship
with your husband but in a very private way.
It’s has to be extremely private and it
should not be such a great thing to go into
romanticism.
You’ll ruin the whole of Sahaja Yoga in
the West if you start doing that nonsense!
Because also there’s an idea about it that,
you see, you fall in love.
But then you’ll fall!
That’s the first point is.
You will fall [but] you want to rise.
So this attachment and this worry about the
husband and this and that, I mean, you can
carry on with any kind of a husband and wife
if you are a Sahaja Yogi, should be able to.
I mean, I know that’s very simple.
It’s a…your husband is a study, wife is
a study, that’s all.
You study a person, what sort of a person
he is.
But for that you have to have the witness
state and you have to see, you have to be
detached.
So in marriages one has to be detached.
But, on the contrary, I find that just after
the marriage they want to organise some special
thing for them to go to some sort of a honeymoon
or some sort of a thing!
I don’t know how these ideas crawl up.
These are coming from the old conditionings
of things and after honeymoon they come and
say, “Mother, this marriage is not going
to work out."
So it’s better to do slow and steady and
then decide.
Because you just jump into honeymoon mood
and come back and say, “Mother, this, I
have started thinking and I don’t think."
I know of a lady who was jumping with a Indian
gentleman and she was on her way to Australia.
In Singapore, she telephones that, “Mother,
I don’t think this marriage will work out."
And here everybody complained to Me, “Mother,
these two are behaving in such a manner that
Indians are rather embarrassed."
So the sense of shame you must learn from
Indians.
They never… husband and wife never sit together
in India, is regarded as bad manners and it
should be with you also.
That, even in the puja, even in anything they
are sitting in the public, what is the need
to show your relationship in the public?
It’s only in the private.
This is one of the things one, if you start
understanding, there will be a proper adjustment.
Men should be with men in the public, women
should be with the women together.
But the women or men, whatever they are, whatever
are their bad, bad points should not be brought
back.
Like, I would say the men have jealousies
and they have power orientation and they discuss
about leadership and they, every, they get
a shock if you tell them that you are not
going to be a leader, as if they think leadership
is something very concrete.
It’s the greatest myth ever going, is this
leadership!
There’s nothing like leaders in this Sahaja
Yoga, it’s just a joke.
And your Mother is very good at playing serious
jokes.
So be careful!
Don’t be childish about it.
You have to understand that this is a big
joke going on and it’s just a testing point
and if I test you wrong, you can tell Me,
but I think this has worked well, because
I can test people very well on that level
and immediately I know when the person gets
onto the horse of ego.
So, for your mental attitude, has to be different
and our priorities have to change.
Our priorities have to change.
What are our priorities?
First and foremost thing is our ascent, is
the first priority.
For our ascent whatever is needed has to be
done.
If you have to punish your body, alright.
If you have to punish yourself, alright.
If you have a conditioning, get rid of it.
Just introspect yourself, that is Self-realisation,
is to know yourself.
When you know yourself and know what is clinging
onto it, just to remove it completely.
Work it out the way you like.
You see, it is very important that the body,
mind, everything should be your slaves.
Nothing should dominate you.
You should be on top of everything.
How dare your body ask for anything?
How dare your mind tells you anything?
How this conditioning works on you?
“I am a Sahaja Yogi, I’m above everything."
Like the lotuses have come out of the ponds,
you have come out of it.
We have so many proofs to show that you are
realised souls.
I’ll show you some photographs that I have
to show that there is light.
I can put light into you, they are all enlightened
people.
But in My presence if you become the light,
you must carry the light outside.
Not only in My presence, but when you go out.
But one of the reasons, I think, when I tell
something people just start thinking about
whom Mother is talking, they never think,
“She is talking about me."
That’s the only way you can penetrate within
yourself when you see that, “Mother is talking
about me, She’s correcting me all alone
and She’s telling me."
Then only it will penetrate and it will work
out.
The priorities have to be changed and the
first and foremost is your ascent and the
Spirit and Sahaja Yoga.
The rest is negligible, nothing important.
Then the faith that there is this All-pervading
Power, which is looking after us, is very
important.
This time the musicians came all the way.
I must tell you the story of their travel.
They came and they said that there’s a train
from Kiev and they also bought the tickets
so got into the train and they were off-loaded
before the Hungarian border.
They didn’t know what to do, they had no
visas, nothing and not so much money also.
They thought, “We are on the train."
They said, “No, you have to go cross over
and go to Budapest,” and they didn’t know
where, they were standing on the road.
And, but they were all laughing and enjoying,
“must be something in store for us."
Nobody felt that they were in trouble or in
anything.
So surrendered.
“So, suddenly,” they said, “the custom
people came and surrounded them,” and they
said, “What’s the matter, how are you
here with all these bags and baggages?”
So they said, “Why are you here?”
They said, “We have come for a concert and
this, and musicians we are and all."
And some or other they started melting away.
And then they gave them Realisation!
Six of them got Realisation.
Now can you believe: the power of love.
And the custom officers they offered their
own cars, took them down to the other side.
It’s never happened with custom officers!
Imagine!
It would be like shaving their teeth off,
I tell you, the way (laughing) if you can
do that to the custom officer!
But it happened.
And they came to the other side and left them
there.
Now they didn’t know what to do.
They wanted to go to Budapest, they had to
walk about two miles or something to the station.
So they were waiting there well, they said
that, “Mother, You sent maybe, two Yugoslavs
came in a big bus of 49 people – all vacant."
They stopped the bus and said, “What is
it, why are you here?”
So they said, “This is our problem and we
have to go."
So they got into the bus.
When he was driving them down, they thought
of talking to him that, “Why not you take
us to Milan?”
And they managed! (laughter) And they were
in Milan.
It’s so remarkable.
So to have faith completely in yourself and
in that Power, which is surrounding you.
And once you have that faith you will realise
that, though it is so helpful to you, it is
so kind to you, on the same level if you think
it, it can be very harmful.
So then never listen to the Guru ninda, means
anybody talks anything ill about your Guru,
just put your hands to your ears, absolutely
immediately.
I have known of a person who did that [and]
got cancer, another now in jail, another one
there.
So anybody is saying like that, just put your
hands.
Because now you know that – what is your
Guru.
So you should never hear anything against
your Guru from anyone.
The other day one gentleman asked Me a question,
a newsman.
He said that, “I am told you have made a
castle for Yourself."
I said, “I have paid for it, I have made
it also.
It was a horrid place, no doubt.
But there are only Sahaja Yogis staying there,
I am not staying there.
That’s the best part."
But that’s all I said.
But on the contrary, they never go and ask
these questions to any gurus on anything.
Because the disciples say, “Yes, so what?
We want to give to our guru money and this
and that."
They never ask.
But, through Sahaja Yoga, or [by] Myself,
I have cured so many people of incurable diseases
– I could have minted money.
For curing one cancer patient I could have
made a castle, Myself.
So when people say like that you should say,
“Do you know how many people She has cured?
How much money She could have taken from them
if She was a doctor or She was a false Guru?
How much money She would have made out of
all of them?”
Then they will understand.
You see, because they are being materialistic
they talk like that.
And their attitude is very different and so,
to tell them off is the best way.
Because I have seen that these press people
are absolutely harassed by the disciples of
the false Gurus.
Just they cannot criticise, they cannot say
a word against such false Gurus.
While I find that Sahaja Yogis still lack
that complete faith in themselves and complete
assertion.
Where you have to assert you must assert.
For example, anybody says something wrong
against Me, you have to assert; must say,
“No, not possible.
It’s not!”
But I have seen some people asking Me funny
questions who are ‘Sahaja Yogis’ also!
So the first part is that to see how much
we are sensitive to spirituality.
I have seen Sahaja Yogis supporting somebody
who is so negative, you can’t even bear
that person and, [to them], such a person
is something great, while somebody who is
so good they cannot make it out.
So what’s the use?
Your computer is so faulty, you’ll do…I
mean, the planes will have to run up and down
if you have such a computer as Sahaja Yogis
are!
Because they just judge the other way round.
A person who is good in Sahaja Yoga, who has
got vibrations, he may be simple, he may be
unassuming, he may not be so rich, he may
not be so educated, may not be from some good
universities or anything, but you must see
the vibrations of that person!
What sort of vibrations that person has, and
then you should judge.
Instead of that if you judge that person only
because he’s very good to talk and he talks
well and very scholarly or something like
that, that’s not the point.
The point is what are his vibrations!
And once you see those vibrations and judge
them on vibrations, then you are a Sahaja
Yogi, otherwise I would not call you at all
a Sahaja Yogi.
But for a Guru it is very important.
I have seen sometimes even the leaders supporting
somebody who is absolutely horrid!
I can’t bear that person even for five minutes!
But here the Guru sends him over to Me, “Oh,
Mother, he’s so good, you know, he donated
so much money."
It doesn’t matter.
You donated money, so what?
Who asked him to donate money?
But he should not donate his bhoots to us
now anymore!
We don’t want his bhoot!
So that’s what it is.
So the judgment should be correct about a
person when you say that this man is not good
or that is not good.
But mostly ‘gurus’ themselves are caught
up and then they are ambitious and if somebody
doesn’t listen to them or somebody wants
to give a lecture at a wrong time and somebody
says, “You shouldn’t talk like this,”
or something, then they get angry.
They are very hot tempered and they provoke
people, they say things sometimes.
And then when people react they say, “You
are a bad Sahaja Yogi."
That’s not the way.
First of all a guru or a leader has to be
himself a very mild, gentle, and a good person.
He has to be in such a way [that] he should
not demand anything, should not ask for anything.
Never demand anything!
Anybody who demands can not be a guru.
Respect is to be commanded and not to be demanded.
And so, everything works out well if you understand
that – once you rise in your ascent, in
your wisdom, in your awareness and in your
Spirit – automatically all these things
happen!
You don’t have to ask for anything, you
don’t have to plead for anything, you don’t
have to complain for anything, everything
works out.
You are looked after by all the ganas, by
all the angels.
They are there.
You are on the stage.
But if you are halfway then they play tricks
with you.
You see, they play tricks, they make you falter,
you have problems, you go here, you go there,
all these things happen and then you say,
“Mother, how is it this happened?”
Because they are also jokers, so they play
jokes with you and they make problems for
you just to make you understand that you are
doing wrong.
So we are on a stage where there’s a beautiful
security, everything is there and we have
to give to the world such a great thing like
Sahaja Yoga, which is for the emancipation
of the whole world, as you realise, and so
also I hope you realise your responsibilities.
There are so many things one has to understand,
how one has to be as a guru, how he has to
act and how he has to work out.
Now I have given so many lectures on Guru
things, but, for today’s lecture, only I
have to say that, first thing, to have a guru
system, you must have complete humility.
Now, with Me, I would say, I am too simple
and I am Mahamaya, so you be very careful.
You cannot take liberties with Me.
You cannot take.
If you try to take too much liberties that
means you are not a disciple.
A disciple has to keep a distance from the
Guru.
You cannot just take liberties, walk into
My room every time, sit there for hours together,
chit-chat with Me – nothing!
You have no right.
Only when I call you, when I ask for you,
you should come.
Then you should not force things on the Guru
that, “Please, come and listen to this,”
or, “Do this!” that should not be said.
For example, yesterday nobody told Me there
are going to be these music programs or everything
arranged.
So we have to report everything to your leader,
or to Me, all those things that you want to
do.
And it should be really transparent.
Like this hand knows everything that this
hand is doing, and this hand knows everything
that this hand is doing.
In the same way everybody should know each
other.
Then the gurus should not have jealousies
for each other.
This I’m just telling you because also I
found out that there are certain jealousies.
And when they talk there is a little bit of,
“Ha, he’s good, but this, this, this."
When they enjoy each other’s company because
they have reached a certain state and they
understand, “This is the state we are in."
When they enjoy each other’s company fully
and appreciate each other much more than anybody
else – the guru’s company.
All the company of the leaders, if they enjoy
each other and there’s no jealousy, there’s
no fight, there’s no problem but just the
enjoyment of the company, then they should
know that they have become a guru.
Now all of them never fought with each other.
They supported.
Actually it is one Principle was born again
and again.
But only the satanic people – they’ll
fight among themselves, not the godly.
And also they will talk against the person
who is a realised soul or who is an Incarnation,
but never against themselves.
It’s very surprising that the satanic people
though they fight among themselves, there
are jealousies, they’ll never talk of each
other.
But here I find that in Sahaja Yoga we have
freedom.
But freedom is not abandonment, is the freedom
with complete rules and regulations of the
Divine, with us, and we have to know them
that this is the Divine Law.
So all of us are now sitting like in a big
vimana, like an aeroplane, and we all have
to land into the beautiful area.
But first of all we have to develop that humility
in your heart; complete humility and surrender,
that’s very important.
Unless and until you have that humility and
surrender in your heart, Guru principle can
not be awakened.
First you have to be the disciple and then
the guru.
So you have to develop that humility.
And that humility comes very easily if you
love Me, respect Me.
It’s not only love, but respect.
That respect has to be there and then people
will respect you.
May God bless you