I talk to you about the right side.
Right side sympathetic nervous system which
is expressed by other subtle energy of Mahasaraswati
which gives us the power to act - by left
side we desire and by using the right side,
the power of pingala nadi, we act.
I was telling you about the right side the
other day.
Let us see how our right side is built up.
I’m sorry for people who have come for the
first time but every time when I start the
introduction to the subject, again it becomes
the same but later on I’ll explain to you
about Sahaja.
Now this right side pingala nadi is a very,
very important energy-giving energy
which makes us act and activate.
Now this one is made of all the five elements.
You know all the five elements that have created
our physical being and our mental being.
That’s how it helps us to work out all our
physical and mental problems, mental activities
and mental and physical growth.
Now this being made by those five elements,
when first time human beings started thinking
of doing some action about anything, say in
India, they first thought why not somehow
or other reach to the principle of these elements,
which is beyond physics, which is beyond chemistry.
And to reach to that point, they thought it
would be better if we try to invoke or to
awaken the Deities which are governing those
five elements.
This was a very big mistake though, I should
say.
Because human beings, whatever they take up,
they do not know where to stop.
If you tell them that you have to clean your
teeth everyday, then they’ll go on cleaning
it 12 times in 12 hours.
You tell them anything, they’ll go so far
that they will destroy the instrument which
is suppose to be looked after.
That’s the nature of human beings, they
cannot have brakes to themselves.
They do not have common sense as far as balance
in their life.
So anything you give them, they become so
mad after it that in Marathi there is a word
is that they ultimately put ashes on their
head, to say to declare that I am dead now,
I’ve become ashes.
Like that, they get so frantic that even while
doing this awakening of these principles,
they forgot, lost their sight that we are
after all spirit and not these elements.
We are beyond that.
You have to reach beyond that.
All these elements are only useful for us
to achieve a state in which we can create
things and we can have more time to devote
to meditation to enjoy our self-realisation.
They got completely blinded by the advances
they made on this side which is in pure and
simple words is materialism.
They became so responsible, so efficient.
First in the Vedas, it’s written, the first
stanza is such that by reading these Vedas,
if you do not know your spirit then it is
absolutely useless.
But this stanza they always close down I think.
Then they started worshipping those Deities,
this, that, exciting them, doing all ritualism,
and all that and they just went into it headlong,
absolutely headlong.
They would not turn back.
So by exciting these elements, they discovered
the principles of these elements.
For example, they discovered that gravity
is the essence of the Mother Earth.
But it is not.
That is not the essence of the Mother Earth.
That is the energy that is asserted by Her
but Her essence is Her fragrance.
They could not cross that limit where they
could see really the subtle thing which was
the subtle principle of this energy of gravity
is the fragrance.
All the fragrances come from Her.
Of course man made there are, that’s different.
But even the man made, are also coming from
Her, if you go trace the source, it’s up
to the point, it is from there.
Like that they went on discovering the subtler,
so called subtler energies or the principles
of these elements from the Vedas style.
Then it became a science.
People started studying physics, chemistry,
this, that, understanding what was there before
them, by going into it and trying to find
out what is it made of.
For example, they went into atoms, they went
into say molecules and things and they tried
to find out and there they find the oscillation
of the protons and they find the oscillation
of these atoms.
And they just can’t understand, from where
does this energy of this oscillation is coming.
They could not capture that energy so they
thought better use the energy, so they started
using the energy.
Now it has gone to such a limit of the whole
thing is, now I read, saw that microchips
or something coming up.
After some time you won’t be using hands
or head or anything, it will be that microchips
will be going on.
But with this kind of a thing, with this extreme
behaviour, you’ll become a machine yourself.
A slave of the machine.
Today the petrol is exhausted, tomorrow electricity
is exhausted, then what are you going to do?
You don’t know even to count two plus two.
So you are left without any counting, you’ll
become the same primitive man and I don’t
know what you will be doing, climbing on the
trees and living like monkeys, I don’t know
what will happen.
So all these advancement that you did has
gone too far.
But as a result of too much efficiency, too
much responsibility and all that, you became
sort of addicted to it and then with that
you started dominating other people.
The machinery came in, that you produced such
a lot of machinery style that you didn’t
know what to do so you had to find out markets
where you sell them so you started capturing
other markets where you started selling them
and that’s how all these economic problems
and all this have started.
There are developing countries, there are
developed countries, all things going on in
this mad world.
But we reach a point now where we realise
that this machine has done something nonsensical
within us.
When we reach that point, we start thinking
now what are we to do.
We have been very responsible, not you people
but your forefathers may be, who went to fight
the whole world and do this and they had to
be at right time at right places and do all
sorts of things.
By that over-responsibility you became sort
of fed up, you just didn’t know what to
do.
For example, morning you wear a grey suit,
in the night you have to wear a tail coat
and then if you have to drink your wine, you
have to take a separate glass and for that
this.
It became too much messy you said “Throw
them in the sea”.
We have collected all this nonsense, we have
collected all these forms and horrible things
that have made us so rigid.
That’s how you try to throw away everything
but even then when you throw away, where do
you go?
I mean you have to exist, you cannot just
hang in the air.
So you said now take another style.
And another style is even worse, much worse.
Because then no responsibility, no respect,
no understanding, so this power goes absolutely
zero.
You are tired very soon.
I’ve seen, I mean in the BBC and all that,
young people, I’m a very old woman compared
to them, after saying two three words, they
say “Ahhh”, they go down.
Again after saying something, “Ahhh”.
This is very big acting these days.
In any play you see a person saying, “Ahhh”.
What does it take to act for this kind of
a thing.
This is what is very common.
Now you notice, the reason is you are tired.
You’re absolutely tired, why?
Because your brain is the same old brain and
you have taken a new life, you cannot adjust
yourself to that.
You say that now I am sitting down, doing
nothing, I am not going to be efficient anymore
and all that, I’m sitting down, the brain
is going, chug-chug-chug-chug-chug, morning
till evening.
How to stop this brain?
This brain is working so hard, using up all
your energy, you have no strength.
So to counteract you will say let’s take
to some sort of a thing by which we go out
of this madness.
Let’s take to something that takes you as
we call it the right or the left side, take
something like say hashish, or something like
another thing, LSD, to go to the right or
to the left.
Now what happens with that you know very well.
Now thank God you have realised also to that
was nonsensical action, that was wrong.
These are two areas within us which are called
as Adi Bhautik and Adi Devik.
Now the Adi Bhautik are the ones which take
you to the left side is the subconscious and
the Adi Devik are the ones where you try to
invoke the devas and all that on the right
hand side, that one is the Adi Devik where
we call it supra-conscious area.
These two are of no use to human beings, actually.
They are not meant for human beings.
They are meant for people who are dead, who
are dead souls, who are good for nothing.
Now they cannot get realisation.
It’s not meant for you.
That’s the area you should not reside.
But you enter into these areas because of
extreme natures.
Some people by going into these drugs, some
taking to some sort of movements like mesmerisms,
spiritualisms and all sorts of isms.
Some people onto the right hand side like
taking to what you call these people who are
racialists and all such organisations which
are racialist and this and that and you know
all that kind of a people, like Hitlerish
type.
All this is nothing but is a kind of intoxicant
which makes you forget the reality, that you
are a human being, that you have to become
the spirit, that you are the spirit is the
reality.
Now the present trend in the Western life
is very much set in this country about which
I am very much concerned.
I’ve talked about to many people in person
and also the vibes (?), that the quality of
the mind, because we are with the English,
let’s talk about the English.
Quality of mind of English is excellent, I’ve
said it always.
And the young people of English have a very
good quality of mind.
But their heart is lacking.
They’re frightened of what God alone knows
but they are frightened.
Why they have taken this course, I don’t
know.
Now to do any work, also they’re frightened.
Supposing we put this colour, then it may
not match, it doesn’t matter, doesn’t
matter.
What does it matter?
Because of those previous ideas they are so
frightened of doing anything, though they
say they have broken all those ideas and they
have taken to new liberated ways and all that.
But this liberation is also another madness
in which they’re fear has now gone.
So the quality of mind of we the English sahaja
yogis and English people is excellent.
If you talk to them, you’ll think you are
talking to a scholar, I mean no less than
Shakespeare.
They could be very well read, they will know
about anything you ask them, what is this
road?
This is the road!
Now, what is the name of this road?
This is the gentleman.
Who was his grandfather, what he did, what
was the gossip about him, scandals, everything.
You can get everything from them, they know
everything about everything.
Sometimes I’m amazed the way people know
about things.
About all the details as to how many women
he had, and how many wives he divorced and
what he did and where he went and what he
wrote.
Take anyone, take a writer, or take an artist,
or take a hooligan, or take a robber or anyone
who has appeared on the newspaper as if they
have drunk all the newspaper into their memory.
The whole thing is so clear cut in their mind
that is sometimes, I mean.
But if you tell them to fix one chair, never
trust that chair (everyone laughing).
Never trust it.
If you ask them to do anything, they’ll
tell you: ‘Alright, tomorrow at 7 sharp,
I’ll be there.’
Even if he comes after 7 days, thank your
stars.
I’ve known people who have been done this
to me.
Now it’s 4 years, I’ve never seen their
faces again.
They’re supposed to be XYZ from Oxford and
ABCD from Cambridge.
They have got first class first and this and
that.
If you go into their rooms, you will find
it’s a pig sty.
You don’t know where you have landed.
I mean, you don’t believe that it belongs
to any educated person, there’s no sense
of responsibility left in their head.
I mean this energy that is working in the
head, if it is not put into a responsible
channel, no wonder, we find every third person
is a paranoid, something wrong with the brain.
What is wrong with the brain is that so much
energy is here and you are not channelizing
it at all.
By what ways are we to channelize it.
Even after realisation, I find people have
no respect for anything.
Sometimes it’s most surprising that with
all this brain activity going on, they get
all the satisfaction from the spirit.
They’re raising the Kundalini and all that
but they have lost that capacity to be responsible
and that’s why in Sahaja Yoga also they
are not responsible.
This goes on not only about their own private
work but about Sahaja Yoga about everything.
So this quality of mind has no heart.
It has no, it has heart in nothing.
Supposing I am telling you something, I don’t
know about sahaja yogis as such, but now…
I’ve seen with people, you give them a lecture
for one year, one hour, it’s lost, finished.
They’re just the same, what has happened.
It’s only the vibrations, it’s only how
you work it out that the life changes and
all that.
But as far as they are concerned, nothing
is recorded in the memory.
Sometimes I feel how do I talk?
Is it too much on their heads or below their
feet?
Where is it flowing?
So the reason is that the heart is lost.
If you register it through your heart, you
will do it.
If you put your heart into things you will
do it.
The heart is as I told you is chicken-hearted,
is absolutely chicken-hearted.
And that’s why, this is what is lacking
in our character.
For that now the stage has reached, we have
to raise our right side, not the left side.
Our right side is absolutely finished and
there the leader of the right side are two
persons.
The Deities are two persons.
Of course Brahmadeva is the one who is the
creator, who has created this universe and
who is the one who is busy still creating
and doing lots of things for you people.
But I would suggest that we have to pay attention
to two ideals we have in the history.
For this to understand what sort of ideals
we should have, because the right side is
a Rajo Guna is the one by which you become
majestic, you become royal, you achieve all
the Rajo Guna as you know that.
Now two persons are really to be followed
on there.
One of them is Shri Ram.
Shri Ram resides on the right heart and is
the father.
He is the father and He is the fatherhood.
He is the one who came on this earth to teach
us how to be a father as a king.
He is a father king.
He is a benevolent king, which was described
before [??] He is the benevolent.
He was the ideal that came on this earth to
teach us how to be responsible to others,
how to respect others, how to understand the
feelings of others.
To such an extent He went that He had to sacrifice
His own wife for the sake of His own state.
He did that and He had to ask His wife who
was pregnant to go and live with a very great
sage.
One may say that what was He doing about His
wife.
She was the Goddess.
She was so remarkable that He was not bothered
about Her.
He was so sure of Her powers that He did it
and there is nothing wrong in leaving things
to the Goddess to do instead of meddling with
Her all the time.
But this gentleman Shri Rama, understood the
responsibility of a king and that responsibility
is lacking in us.
That responsibility towards ourselves and
towards others.
It is very, very surprising.
I mean I came from India.
I’d never met Englishmen at this close quarters
till I came to England I should say.
Because before that we met all missionaries.
All missionaries were terribly responsible
for converting all the people into Christianity.
They will get up early in the morning, take
their Bible, go around to all the places,
cleaning all the dirty lanes and cleaning
all the children like bits of paper see, cleaning
all the dirty people there, kiss them and
do all impressive things to convert the people.
They would go even to the forest to convert.
They were so responsible about it that they
felt they have to do it, this is God’s job,
they’re doing God’s job, they must convert,
and they went on with this and that’s how
some of the people I met.
Then the rulers, the rulers are extremely
responsible.
They were ruthless and they thought this was
the greatest thing they are doing to spread
British Raj and that was their responsibility.
When it comes to spreading God’s Raj you
are not.
First of all in our own life, we should see
are we responsible.
Now in the modern times I find that we have
got rid of that sense of responsibility, it’s
called as a sense of diminishing responsibility.
You’ll just say yes, yes, I know, I should
have, I know, I know.
I can’t understand.
If you have a heart, how can you say that,
that I know I should not have done.
I know, I should have been doing.
The reason is there is no heart and the heart
always catches when your right side over acts.
That means your brain is active too much and
there is no real action the outward of it.
You think too much and do not put it to practice.
I should have gone, I should have done this,
I should have said so, and this is the problem
with our right side.
Now, among our sahaja yogis also, I find people
have the problem of the right side.
To worship the right side, we have to see
to Shri Ram.
How He felt responsible for the whole world.
How He use to look after people.
How He looked after the things of other people.
How He behaved towards other people, that’s
a very important thing which we have to learn.
But I find people coming, if it is somebody
else’s, they’ll throw.
They will just jump into something and say
that alright, this is my house I just settle
down here, the way I like.
There’s no sense of responsibility at all
about it, that you have come to somebody else’s
house.
You have to have some care about it.
In the same way you have to know you have
come in the world of God.
This is the Kingdom of God where you have
entered.
You have been a stranger.
Today you are a guest in His house, what are
you doing about it.
How are you behaving?
Are you responsible?
Are you like Shri Rama who took it up Himself,
all the problems of the world and still He
was so responsible.
He would not do anything even this much to
disturb a person.
As far as possible He would like to try to
console, and have the formalities of good
living.
Formality is meant for good living and good
understanding.
Unless and until you have this sense of responsibility,
your collectivity cannot be alright.
You cannot be collectively alright.
You need not be a machine for that.
There is no need to be a machine, like Japanese,
only one person says another doesn’t come.
But this one kind of a funny individualism
that you have got will never give you that
collectivity that is expected of Sahaja Yoga.
We all have to be one, being responsible for
each other.
Not only for one or two persons, because he
is my friend, he is my husband, she is my
wife but for all of us.
We have to be responsible for their things,
for their children, for their house, for everything.
We have to be responsible.
And if this sense of responsibility is lacking,
how will you have responsibility for your
self-realisation.
Only it can be a self-centred thing, thinking
that I’m very much better, my powers are
better, I must have more powers.
But if you do not have this sense of responsibility
why should God also give you powers.
The main thing is your right side is completely
weak, that is the surya nadi, that is the
nadi which is called as the nadi by which
people hold their prana, so it gives you the
prana shakti.
It’s the prana shakti within you which is
the vital force of energy within you, which
is lacking.
Now this lacking is added up by your heart,
at least for a man like that whose prana shakti
is exhausted.
At least for such a man if the heart is there,
he can really use that power which is accumulating
in the head and exhausting him, like eating
up his brain.
If he has the heart in it.
Now this is what I have told you last time
that the right side of human beings is very
important when it comes to Sahaja Yoga because
when the Kundalini rises, your right side
is also, right side is also awakened.
Now the question is why Sahaja Yoga does not
spread in England so far.
This is a very good question.
Many people have asked it.
While in Australia it’s spread so fast.
The reason is the right side is missing.
The right side to be awakened, first of all
there should be some right side.
If there is no right side, what do you awaken?
If there is no light at all, what are you
going to awaken?
There has to be a lamp to be awakened.
So all these topics and talks that we have
in the society: ,I know, I know’, and then
you ask them this and they say: ‘I don’t’
[?]. How are you, like.
[?] All these accents and all that, one should
give up.
One should know that you have to be responsible.
That’s a very, very important thing of life.
I personally think unless and until you feel
that responsibility, that heart into Sahaja
Yoga you will enjoy just by talk as you would
just enjoy anything else.
Real enjoyment comes when your spirit really
blows out the vibrations.
You are taking my vibrations alright, you
are feeling them.
But what about yours?
Are you blowing your vibrations out or they
are just eating your brain.
Simple questions, are you blowing any vibrations
outside?
We have some sahaja yogis when they just enter
into a house, immediately, everyone feels
it.
Everyone can feel it that somebody has come.
Immediately, the whole thing cools down in
no time, somebody has come.
There are some here also, not that there are
none.
But they’re few.
You have to blow out vibrations, otherwise
you are just a liability to yourself.
Why don’t you blow out vibrations, because
you don’t feel responsible.
In your day to day life, morning till evening,
you have to see that you develop this instrument
of responsibility within you.
Otherwise the vibrations won’t flow because
the main reason is that our nervous system
comes to us through our right side.
Our nervous system is built up by our right
side.
All the elements within us have built up.
If the elements are weakened, if the chakras
which are made by these elements, as you know
all these charkas are made by elements, if
the part is weak, nothing is going to work
out.
You should be able to hold that water of love
or you can say the water of bliss and should
be able to pour it out to others.
Unless and until you are able to do that,
Sahaja Yoga won’t spread.
It will spread very slowly.
This is the difference I feel between English
and Australians.
That the quality of mind is thousands times
better than Australians.
They are not scholars.
I found very few people there who are even
graduates.
Here everybody is a PhD or may be a MAD.
But they are all very well educated.
Despite all that, Sahaja Yoga does not spread
out, why?
The reason is the quality of mind is good,
but the action is extremely poor because they’re
exhausted, tired, you are fighting in the
mind.
You are not doing anything by which you blow
it out.
The right side is what you call the Brahmas,
the Brahmadeva’s creation and the Brahma
Shakti as they call it.
This is the power of Brahma which is flowing
through you.
We call it the power of the spirit, it’s
true.
But the spirit, the power of the spirit flows
on your central nervous system.
If there is the electricity all stored up
here and there are very weak wires, what can
you do with all that stored up energy.
The wires have to be improved and for this
wire your right side has to be improved immensely.
Every minute you have to be responsible and
this is what is lacking.
Then I find when … for [incomrehensible]
responsible, they feel extremely hurt.
They feel that they should really shout and
scream and should do something.
They don’t know that these are really the
saints, they are realised souls.
They are great people, no doubt.
But their right side is weakened.
But that is not a great thing to accept, it
is a very bad thing.
But that does not mean you should feel guilty
again, I am saying.
Because very nice, this is the way you manage
is to feel guilty.
Because feeling guilty is the best way, ‘I’m
sorry, I’m sorry.
I should have done it.
I know, I know’ – finished!
Then how can you improve?
If you are about fear filled up all the time
with responsibility denied, all the junk you
have created out of that, you are pushing
into that pouch and then you say: ‘Yes,
yes, I know, I should not have done that!’
Now what can you do?
As I mother you can’t say ‘you’ll hang
yourself by the nearest tree’.
What do I do?
I’m just look at you flabbergasted.
I said: ‘Really?’
‘Yes, I should have done but I haven’t
done it.’
For example, I should tell somebody you better
cook for 10 people, they are coming and the
person says: ‘No, I’m sorry, I forgot,
I didn’t cook.’
You are doomed.
You cannot hit him with the back can you?
What to do.
That’s how you are at a standstill.
You really don’t know how to deal.
The point is in all this talking of spirit
and God, one has to know the vehicle has to
be better.
The vehicle is so very poor that it cannot
carry, otherwise you will emit vibrations
like that.
I know you can.
Wherever you stand you’ll attract.
People must gather round.
You’ll be amazed, I went to Australia for
how many months, at the most a month or so.
I came back from there, already seven centres
have started and every centre has got at least
300 regular people coming.
It is not to feel guilty.
I’m not saying, but to awaken yourself.
To arise to this point.
To be elated with understanding that you have
to rise up to that point and that you have
to take up that position because you are the
warriors of truth.
You are the people who are seekers who have
been for ages and you have no business to
be irresponsible.
You have to do it.
It is my earnest desire that you understand
what I am saying.
Just sitting, meditating, putting hands towards
me or towards the photograph is not everything.
You are still receiving.
You are still at the receiving end.
You have to be on the giving end.
How will you do it?
You get so many vibrations sometimes that
you cannot feel after some time, it’s so
filled the pitcher is so much filled.
But what about pouring it out?
Why you cannot pour it out?
The reason is that the vehicle within you,
which is the right side, is the pingala nadi,
is out of gear.
And this is what one has to understand.
That can be built up only when you know about
Shri Rama’s life, the way He led His life.
Every minute of His life was dynamic.
Not a single minute He wasted in life.
Every minute, whether He was in the forest
or He went to a place with His wife when He
was in exile, and there He knew His wife was
a very shy lady and She would not take Her
bath in the open.
So there’s a rock which is completely holed
out.
Such a big rock, holed out can you imagine.
Inside there is a water.
Water taps sort of a thing coming out, there’s
a water coming out.
So that there’s stone here, stone here,
stone there, and at the end of it there’s
an opening so that there’s light coming
from this side, light coming from that side
but inside nobody can see.
There are trees.
There are trees like which are called as chikakaye
[??] means that its kind of a soap giving
tree are created by Him for His wife.
Anywhere He lived He created a new dimension,
a new house, a new style of life.
Of course He was an incarnation you can say.
But He’s your ideal and not those people
who sit out for hours together drinking something
and thinking they are great martials.
I see all of them sitting here at a church
here and one of them was asked by someone
who was passing: ‘What are you doing?’
‘We killing ourselves!’
Very proudly to say that.
I mean I just don’t understand, what business
have they got to kill themselves.
How much time it has taken God to create them
and here they are sitting and proudly telling
that we are killing ourselves.
This is the situation in which I suddenly
find myself.
So I ask you what should I do?
How should I do?
You have to feel responsible in every way
of life.
But you do not think that there is anything
wrong if you are a hanky panky person.
If your feathers are falling everywhere, it’s
alright.
To you it really does not matter.
But to the Divine it does.
That means a person cannot convey the message
of God, cannot emit it, the bliss of God,
cannot pour that love.
We have to become very responsible in every
day life.
I’m not saying that in Sahaja Yoga but in
every day life, how you live, what you do.
Are you only worried about yourself or you
are worried about others?
Are you responsible for others?
I mean the modern style is not even to wish
good morning, it’s regarded bad manners.
You see it is bad manners even to open door
to someone, it is bad manners.
They think it’s slavish.
I mean, all manners, all those things, all
responsibility, seems to be slavish.
And this kind of modern ideas that are floating
in the air, you should throw them away.
You have to be human beings of a very great
quality.
You have to be people who have created new
worlds.
You are going to create that, I know.
You have to just rise up to that point and
not to sink into your guilt’s and say: ‘Oh
God, what have we been doing?’
No, awake and arise and get it what you have
to do.
That is what I feel about England.
England is so great and is the heart, is the
heart.
And look at the condition of the heart.
Your heart is so weak.
There’s no heart to anything.
Alright you love Me, I love you, but what
about you loving others, and loving other
things.
Loving doesn’t mean writing love letters.
Doing something about it.
And that’s what, ‘the doing something’
is missing and lacking.
And that’s what we have to build up our
right side properly, into proper shape.
If we have to really do the cooking, we have
to know how to light the fire within us and
not to sit down and worry how to do it.
It is a very great thing to come to England
really.
For one reason that this is the place where
Sahaja Yoga is going to work out.
It is going to circulate in the whole world,
I know through you people.
But if you do not improve the communication
wires of yours is become completely stagnant
and the responsibility of this stagnation
will be on you the Sahaja Yogis of London,
because you did not put your life together,
that’s why it did not work.
It’s a tremendous responsibility.
Of course to be responsible is wrong for wrong
things.
But not to be responsible for Divine work
when God has blessed you with self-realisation,
is absolutely against God, against yourself,
against Sahaja Yoga.
The other personality which I was talking
about is Shri Hanumana.
Shri Hanumana is such a great powerful personality
about whom I did not tell you.
That, I mean, Rama once, you see His brother
was hit by an arrow.
And Rama said to Hanumana, that: ‘Why don’t
you go and get a particular type of a medicine
for him and you get it on a particular hill,
mountain, so you go and get that particular
thing.’
So He had a power, He had nine powers, navadha
shakti He had, nine powers, by which He could
become small, He could become big.
And He could lift anything.
He had lots of powers like that, so nine powers:
anima (remark: reducing one’s physical self
to the size of an atom), lagima (remark: lightness),
garima (remark: increase weight) - like that.
He could become so heavy that nobody could
lift Him.
I mean these are the powers He has got of
the right hand side.
And so He went down to that mountain and He
couldn’t see that anywhere, He just couldn’t
see.
He said: ‘Why not take the whole mountain?’
He took the whole mountain on Himself and
He brought it to Rama and said: ‘Now, select
whichever one you like.’
He could have come back and said: ‘Oh, I
can’t find!
I’m sorry, I know, I’ve been useless.’
If He was an Englishman.
But He said: ‘Alright, if you want!’
He brought the whole mountain, now come along
have it.
In every way of His life, you see His sense
of responsibility and how He carries on.
For example, He was sent to Ravana and He
was asked by Ravana that he told Him that
you cannot stay in this place, why did you
come here.
Actually, first He was, He went to Sita and
told Her that ‘Shri Rama had sent Me’
and He showed the ring and She recognised
that was the ring of Her husband.
And He said: ‘Mother if you want, I can
take you on my back.’
But She said no.
Already you see I am a woman who has come
with another man.
You don’t want to have another bad name
and you’ll have a bad name, so I will not
come.
So it’s alright.
You can go back and tell Rama that I am alright.
‘You as a husband, come and fight this man.
Otherwise I’m not going to come.’
So then He was caught up and taken to Ravana.
Now Ravana said that ‘you are a monkey and
what have you come to do it’.
He said that ‘you better release His wife
of Shri Rama and He is such and such’.
So He said ‘that you monkey, you are telling
me this’.
Alright, he said: ‘Burn His tail.’
He said: ‘If you burn my tail, I know how
to use.’
He knows how the responsibility of the tail
is.
He started burning the whole of Lanka with
His tail and He could have said that: ‘Alright
he burnt my tail I better run away, why to
do such a thing, better avoid, get out, forget
it.
I am not going to go to Rama, he has burnt
my tail.
Tomorrow he will do something else.’
He burnt the whole of Lanka.
The whole of it He burnt till Ravana had to
say, that ‘please forgive and go away.’
He did all kinds of tricks to show that He
was really powerful.
In so many ways of His sense of responsibility
and His dedication and love is expressed.
But they say that even if you take once His
name, whatever work you want to do, it can
be done.
Any work that you want to be finished will
be done and His day is a Tuesday.
On Tuesday, if you request Him for anything,
He will help you to do the work.
But it is not like this that you sit down
and say now come along Hanumana, will you
please do this job?
But if you are doing the job, then He comes
to help you.
Means that He activates, He activates and
He makes your energy flow into that direction
that your work is done.
He’s so helpful in so many ways that you
can’t imagine.
There are so many sahaja yogis have tried
it with that and He has created such miracles
especially the Australians.
Somehow they have such a feeling for him.
I know the reason.
But they have such a feeling for Him that
every time anything happens, better ask Hanumana.
They ask Hanumana.
“Hanumana, now please look after us”.
And they have told Me that such miraculous
things have happened since they have been
using Shri Hanumana.
But you must have the vehicle to carry this
Hanumana.
He’s a very subtle Deity within you.
And if you are irresponsible, He hates such
a person.
He hates, He just can’t bear it.
He, He thinks they are absolutely useless
people.
He doesn’t pay attention to such people.
Those who are not responsible, they may give
any excuses, they may show off, they may do
anything.
He just has no care for such people.
He has no love, no respect, no attention for
the people who are not responsible.
There’s a very nice English saying: ‘God
helps those who help themselves’.
English language has so many beautiful things
in it, all these nursery rhymes and everything.
I wish people would not just utter those sayings
but do it.
They listen to Me but they don’t do it.
Now you have heard Me today you should see
how much responsible you are.
Now we had our first ashram and if there are
others, please excuse Me, because it is an
open thing and we have to talk about it.
And I was surprised that in our first ashram,
when I went there, I was amazed.
I mean, young people living like pigs.
I couldn’t understand.
I mean, they are not hippies, they are not
taking any smokes, drinks, or anything.
They are so irresponsible!
They go to the bathroom, they come out as
if a bull in a china shop has entered.
They really live like that, I was amazed.
How could they?
And we are all graduates, PhDs, MADs, and
everything.
I was amazed, what has happened to these people.
Slowly, slowly they improve.
But this lot went away and a new lot came
in and a new lot came in.
And it’s so surprising that once they become
responsible and good, somehow or other Hanumana
takes them out.
They just get out of it.
Now I have to tell you to determine today
to decide that every moment and movement of
your life you are going to feel responsible
as Hanumana does.
Any work that you are doing, about Him it
is said, [sentence maybe in Hindi ??]. It
means for doing any work, He is just ready,
He is just ready.
You tell him anything, He is just ready to
do it.
It is His quality that you should have and
that quality is so much lacking today in England.
All your strikes, all your problems can be
solved.
First time when I came, I was surprised, I
asked somebody: ‘Are you working?’
He said: ‘No, I am successfully unemployed.’
I said: ‘Really, you are successfully unemployed
so how do you eat?’
‘Oh, we get our doles.’
‘Oh really.’
‘We have securities.’
What are securities, this is nonsense, you
are parasite.
There is no self-respect.
Leave alone the respect … [??], there is
no self-respect.
I was amazed when I told them, all of you
have to take to work.
Anybody you takes the dole is not going to
stay in the ashram.
I wish your government would take some note
of it.
That we have to create responsible citizens.
In England itself, we have to show that by
Sahaja Yoga you have turned the tables, you
have got smart people, now efficient, responsible.
This is what we have to show.
Once we show this to others, people will be
amazed.
With other’s money, it’s the same.
If you can get hold of somebody else’s money
that’s the best thing.
This is a very common feature.
First time the sahaja yogis went to India
they came back here, they never wrote a letter
back thanking them.
And I was amazed.
For six months, I said: ‘What are you doing?’
‘I know we should have written.
I know we should have written.’
But why, why didn’t you write?
No responsibility.
What is this, I could not understand.
Gradually they developed and developed and
developed now they feel but those who have
started feeling are the matured sahaja yogis
I should say.
But others who are coming to it must now that
you have to have a sense of responsibility.
Sometimes people who are realised have a feeling:
‘Oh, now we are realised.
Now, nothing, settle down, have the bliss
of Mother.
Sit down and enjoy it, nothing doing, it will
stop!’
You have to be able to give this to others.
You should emit, if you cannot emit those
vibrations yourself.
If you are enlightened, you should be able
to give light to others.
You can raise the Kundalini, alright but what
about your own personality.
It is so irresponsible which is no where near
Hanumana’s.
This Hanumana style of complete obedience
to your being, the complete emission of that
love that you have received, that divine power
you have received.
Unless and until you achieve that state you
should not be satisfied with your self-realisation.
Self-realisation is only complete when you
yourself become the giver of light.
You the guru, you the great stars.
That’s My ambition.
I know I expect sometimes from My children
and I want them to understand that I want
you to be really honoured in the Kingdom of
God as great sons of your Mother.
May God bless you.
You know that but keep it up.
I do encourage you by saying all these things.
I do awaken Hanumana and Shri Rama within
you.
No doubt, I know, but keep them awake.
Keep them alert and you have to
be alert and active, responsible and respectable.
You have to realise that
you are saints.
Saints of a very special quality.
The saints who can give realisations to others.
There have been not such things like this
before.
Nor even today there are saints who
are realised souls but they don’t know how
to give realisation.
They don’t know so much.
You have so much of knowledge and everything.
Except the vehicle is poor.
It cannot carry the bliss.
The cup has to be alright.
Otherwise it cannot carry the beautiful fountain
of love that is pouring down on this earth.
And that is how you must know that within
you this is awakened, keep it awakened, keep
it … (vague ?).
Please close your eyes.
[continues with guided meditation]