So, this is to thank you all for
helping in building this house
and making it so beautiful.
All the thankfulness
is from
us, both of us, to you.
Today is a very
interesting day when
you are worshipping the Gruhalakshmi here,
means the Gruhalakshmi of this house.
In the same way
in your family also, in your houses, homes you must
do Gruhalakshmis’ puja.
The woman has to be
the Gruhalakshmi herself
and then she should be worshipped.
“Yatya naria pujyante, tatra bhramante Devata.”
Where the women are respected
and worshipped there
reside all the deities.
But they should be respectable also.
If they are not respectable
then the deities won’t reside there.
So, it’s a big responsibility
on a Gruhalakshmi to be respectable
so that all the deities are happy in the family.
And once she is respected,
she will try to be respectable also.
So, the respect
of the Gruhalakshmi is very important.
Today
we are having this little puja
from all the builders
who helped us here,
with the blessings of Vishwakarma
and Brahmadeva;
those who have tried
to make this house so beautiful.
Also, as you know, Blake has described this house.
It has a special significance
and we have to now
hand it over to somebody else,
the one who will appreciate and respect this house;
who will understand the value and worth of this house.
And for that we have to pray
that it will be sold to such a person
who is a person who will be
a connoisseur, a person who will understand
the depth and the
aesthetics
of this place
and the one who will be paying for that,
valuing that.
So, we have to ask
for such a blessing.
Of course, one should not get attached to anything.
Whatever is created,
is created. One should never be attached.
Because we have done this, so
we should be attached to it, is not the way a Sahaja
Yogi should think about it.
But one should think about that,
now we have created something beautiful
we can recreate another thing
and we can produce other better things.
That’s how an artist
can go on producing and producing.
Of course,
there’s one thing: that if there is
within us the joy,
then only you produce joy.
If there is no joy you cannot.
So first of all
before doing any work
creating anything
one must measure up
the amount of
joy one has received,
the blessings one has received from the Divine,
and then recreate.
With that consciousness, with that awareness
you’ll find your creation will be very beautiful.
And we have to bring the world to a new
method of creativity
where there is exuberance,
exuberance,
of joy and
of Divine aesthetics,
because the world is going from bad to worse.
I find nowadays people may just like to have
some sort of a white cloth hanging and calling it a painting.
That’s not a painting because there is nothing inside.
It has become hollow, empty; there’s nothing inside,
so that there is no exuberance.
So, to recreate that,
you people have to
desire and ask for it,
and we’ll have people of that kind.
It is just to be desired,
and you all should desire for such things:
that people of exuberance should come forward
to value such things which are full of joy.
May God bless you.
And so what is this, first the Ganesha puja we’ll do?
May God bless you all.
May God bless this house.
May God bless Mr. Shrivastava.
If you eat all these things. I have done such a good cooking!
I have to say you shouldn’t eat anything anymore
because if you eat it then I’ll just vibrate it,
but you people don’t eat anything
now because such a lot has been cooked,
OK?
Such nice food.
More than that, ahead of that.
Dhanya: Play it forward
Gavin Brown: Yes but tell him.
Yogi: Is it before this or after this? Gavin: No after, further on.
Shri Mataji: There’s a nice song
which says that, in the love of the bhaktas,
how God
does little, little things to please the bhaktas.
And it’s a very good
thing which you’ll like it very much;
which were -
is to be translated and you can…
You see, this is the one but start it from the. And he says:
God thinks that let my,
my respect may be less, doesn’t matter
but I cannot,
I cannot let down my disciples. I may have to come down
but I cannot let down my disciples,
my people who are
my bhaktas.
Just little, just bring it,
I can’t hear it properly.
There’s a switch there.
Begin it again, I’ll tell you meaning.
Bring it here. It’s a very interesting. Come forward!
Till they prepare for your food down below.
You see it will take half an hour at least.
Come forward! Come! Come here! Come here!
Today Mr. Shrivastava has become a Sahaj Yogi!
And he now belongs to our Sahaja Nirmala Dharm so it’s all right.
Sir C.P. Shrivastava: Thank you!
Shri Mataji: We have already
registered ourselves as Vishwa Nirmala Dharm!
Start it, start it from this one.
Start it earlier.
Come forward! Come here!
You can remove this chair!
This is for the devotees of God,
what He does how far that
let His respect
be kept.
What He does is to give the
word of the bhaktas;
not to let down the bhaktas.
So He comes down to every level,
just to support,
just to make them feel happy.
To every level;
for His devotees.
Put a chair also for Mr. Shrivastava there.
He might come.
It’s all right, it’s all right, keep it there.
At the back. Keep it there.
This is a nice one.
This is just the
notes.
The force of great love of His devotees,
palay (पलाय)is a word entrapped by that:
love of the devotees.
God has to change His laws,
in the force of love of God.
This is Mahamaya!
God changes His laws with the force
of the love of His devotees.
Whether people respect or not,
whether His respect is challenged or not,
But the Man of the bhaktas in the respect of the bhaktas
He knows that he should not be let down.
Disciples,
or you can call them the devotees.
Now he describes how Shri Krishna has done it
or the God has done it:
By only a glance of the grace
the whole universe is
sustained: means one glance
of the grace of that God.
And such a God we have seen Him in Gokul,
dancing over,
asking for the butter.
Just imagine! For Him the whole world
He nourishes, but here it is He is just
crying for butter, in Gokul,
just to please His Mother.
The one whom,
Shambu is Mahadeva,
Viranchi is the Brahmadeva.
All the devas,
Sanaka is the one, Sanak is the very great, high,
spiritually evolved personality,
could not get into meditation towards him,
and he is playing here with the little boys
who are ordinary
cowherds.
See what do you calling them? Cowboys?
The ones that look after, the little, little boys.
We saw him playing with him there.
Here the one who cannot
even meditate,
Viranchi is Brahmadeva,
Shambu is Mahadeva:
They cannot even get into meditate:
Suresh, Ganesh, Mahesh and everybody.
They think of God but they cannot go beyond.
But here He is,
He’s being driven mad
by a few gopis who have some
little buttermilk to offer to Him.
Very good poetry!
The feet of,
whose feet are under the,
under the guidance of Kamala, means the Lakshmi:
She is the one who is holding His feet while sitting down.
He can’t get out of it.
He cannot take out His feet out of Her powers.
The one who is even looked after
Shri Lakshmi, you see,
such a Person,
such a God,
have seen His feet walking on the
thorns of the
Gokul. Where he was walking there were thorns; in His bare feet,
He was walking there. Such a God,
who’s feet are pressed even by Shri Lakshmi,
for his bhaktas, because they were all his bhaktas there.
Like me in London!
By only a little
turning of the
eyebrows, you see little one of His,
bending of eyebrows, what do you call this type of a thing?
So seven,
seven seas
start boiling, only one is raised.
Then he describes, Bindu is the poet,
he describes such a great poet.
Such a great power
of God that just lifting one
eyebrows he makes seven seas to boil.
Aap aye, aap aye. (Please come, please come).
There He, with the Mother Yeshoda’s fear,
He drops the little drops
of tears.
Shri Mataji: Bindu's?
Mr CP Shrivastava: Drops.
Shri Mataji: His name is also ‘drop’, so he puts it that way.
From his eyes He drops
the little, little drops of
‘bindu’.
So from where to where? He can make seven
seas to boil and here, there are tear drops,
just like bindus from His eyes,
just to please His Mother.
Just go and ask Danya, she brought a very good article
and something from Kahlil Gibran.
‘Chadariya’ is this body.
Which he has woven, because was a himself, Kabira,
was a weaver.
So he describes weaving;
that, this body was woven.
‘Bini’ means woven.
‘In the name of Rama I have made this body’.
He was a Ram bhakta.
Yogi: Do you want us to massage your feet or something?
Shri Mataji: You can just bring some ice.
Get one little towel and put some ice
and then break it, then you have to also rub it with that.
He says, “This body is a sheath
in the form of this body.”
There are eight
lotuses that is it,
chakras,
and five elements.
Chakka is the one which you spin it,
made out of eight lotuses, means eight chakras
and five elements together.
Then that’s how it was woven
with nine to ten months.
But the stupid have spoiled it.
When my sheet came,
brought in the house
- I mean he is describing his guru
as the person who gives the colour
to the sheet.
After wearing this coloured
sheet, you should not
get into doubts about the guru.
The one who has given you the colour, you should not doubt that.
Don’t think this body is yours.
The guru has coloured it.
He’s given you for two days only.
Should not doubt.
The stupid,
those who do not know the secret.
Every day they go on spoiling this sheet
– that are stupid!
Kabira knew only one or two abuses,
one was ‘stupid’!
This is Raag Desh.
He said,
“Poor Prahlad and Sudama, they also got the same body.”
Kedar hai.
All right?
Are you feeling alright in the hands?
Mark Beaven: Yes, Mother, little warm.
Shri Mataji: Gavin?
This is Malkauns Raag.
You must send prasad to all the ashrams.
All right?
Pay attention here.
No, no. Paul, just see here.
Better.
Eyes also.
Do it a little bit with the eyes, pressure it.
See, it’s better.
Pressure on the eyes.
Take a bandhan
and raise your Kundalinis.
Take a bandhan.
First take a bandhan I think.
First take a bandhan then raise the Kundalini.
Give a bandhan to this house to see people.
Aah, done!
Now see.
See on CP’s head also.
There?
Tie it up!
This is the
song of the Goddess, those who come at the feet
of you Mother.
“The person who gets place in this world
the one who comes at your feet.
This is Saraswati’s bandana.”
Should we come down?
Food is ready?
Accha let’s just finish then.
“I am completely surrendered. My heart is surrendered,
my throat is surrendered,
my voice is surrendered.
Shraddha is devotion,
all emotions, everything surrendered to you.“
Surprising, only to the Mother they ask for blessings.
This is Saraswati bandhana.
In India ‘sang’ means
‘holy’ and ‘geet’ is the ‘music’.
So the, nothing is higher than holy music,
divine music.
“When the ocean of notes starts calling you,
then Sahaj you fill them up
with Godliness.”
“She’s the veena player.
She gives us the blessings.”
“Gives eternal music ‘shaswati’ ”
“And get the new life.
When you get blessings, one gets the new life.”
“Sahaja swayam bhagavan mile” “To them, Sahaja,
God, means sakshat, they see the sakshat of God,
in person.
For such people.”
Chalo, let’s go and have food.
You are the host CP you better call them!