1
00:00:00,967 --> 00:00:05,834


2
00:01:05,334 --> 00:01:15,000
Today is a very important day for all of us Sahaja Yogis,

3
00:01:15,034 --> 00:01:20,634
because today Shri Ganesha was born.

4
00:01:20,667 --> 00:01:26,534
Shri Ganesha is whom we worship

5
00:01:26,567 --> 00:01:35,801
and because of whom we got our awakening (jagruti).

6
00:01:35,834 --> 00:01:39,367
However much you may remember Him,

7
00:01:39,401 --> 00:01:48,434
until you do not know His
 special qualities, you cannot attain Him.

8
00:01:48,467 --> 00:01:59,234
His special quality is that He is the embodiment
of purity (shuddha swaroop)

9
00:01:59,267 --> 00:02:18,301
and complete Master of the Universe.

10
00:02:18,301 --> 00:02:23,601
He is the incarnation of the Supreme, of Brahman.

11
00:02:23,634 --> 00:02:36,734
By coming into this world He has created music (sangeet), 
rhythm (taal) and notes (sur).

12
00:02:36,767 --> 00:02:44,134
By His Grace only people become one with music
(talleen).

13
00:02:44,167 --> 00:02:53,000
A small boy who came into the world
and did such great work!

14
00:02:53,000 --> 00:03:01,601
He has given so many things to everyone
and even today He is active.

15
00:03:01,634 --> 00:03:06,167
Shri Ganesha’s Puja, no matter how much
you do it, it is not enough.

16
00:03:06,201 --> 00:03:24,334
A lot of people say we don’t see Shri Ganesha, even after 
worshiping Him so much, we do not attain Him.

17
00:03:24,367 --> 00:03:32,367
He is omnipotent, omnipresent and in everything,

18
00:03:32,401 --> 00:03:44,534
but you cannot recognize Him until you are Realized.

19
00:03:44,567 --> 00:03:52,000
After your realization you can recognize what Shri Ganesha is.

20
00:03:52,034 --> 00:04:04,634
Shri Ganesha is Purity, the Pure Spirit.

21
00:04:04,667 --> 00:04:16,301
When He is awakened within us,
then we have no questions left.

22
00:04:16,334 --> 00:04:24,167
Then we are successful, in whichever task we undertake.

23
00:04:24,201 --> 00:04:30,467
We find joy in everything we do.

24
00:04:30,501 --> 00:04:37,067
He is the embodiment of joy
and gives joy to everyone.

25
00:04:37,101 --> 00:04:42,934
To serve Him is the ultimate dharma (paramdharma).

26
00:04:42,967 --> 00:04:52,000
To serve Him means to look after small children, to serve
them,

27
00:04:52,034 --> 00:04:58,667
to protect them, to make sure there is no cruelty towards them.

28
00:04:58,701 --> 00:05:04,201
This pleases Him very much.

29
00:05:04,234 --> 00:05:15,467
Such an embodiment of love,
such a simple-hearted Shri Ganesha, was born today.

30
00:05:15,501 --> 00:05:20,867
This is the importance of this day.

31
00:05:20,901 --> 00:05:32,567
Today, if you ask for any wish, then Shri Ganesha will fulfill it.

32
00:05:32,601 --> 00:05:46,067
It is His right to fulfill all your desires,
because you are all realized.

33
00:05:46,101 --> 00:05:57,701
Ask Him from all your heart, and He will help you in every way,
every moment, and every instant.

34
00:05:57,734 --> 00:06:01,501
Today is a very big day,

35
00:06:01,534 --> 00:06:08,367
because verily the pure Spirit itself has taken birth today.

36
00:06:08,401 --> 00:06:17,367
And He already had such a spiritual, eternal state

37
00:06:17,401 --> 00:06:21,201
that many people could not comprehend it or write about it.

38
00:06:21,234 --> 00:06:32,067
Many people didn’t tell anything;
they wrote only what they could understand.

39
00:06:32,101 --> 00:06:42,534
But you can understand that just
by Shri Ganesha’s name you get your realization.

40
00:06:42,567 --> 00:06:50,367
Just by taking His name,
any disease or any pain will disappear.

41
00:06:50,401 --> 00:07:01,501
He is eternal.

42
00:07:01,534 --> 00:07:07,901
He is always present within us.

43
00:07:07,934 --> 00:07:15,901
When you get your realization, you can feel His presence.

44
00:07:15,934 --> 00:07:20,534
And if you are not realized, you cannot understand.

45
00:07:20,567 --> 00:07:26,734
That is why people get misled and do wrong things.

46
00:07:26,767 --> 00:07:33,967
But with Shri Ganesha’s blessings, you can do so many things,

47
00:07:34,000 --> 00:07:41,567
and you won’t feel greedy nor have any problems,

48
00:07:41,601 --> 00:07:49,634
because He does all the work for you. He takes care of you.

49
00:07:49,667 --> 00:07:55,301
Though He is a little boy, He looks after you.

50
00:07:55,334 --> 00:07:58,601
It’s a tremendous power.

51
00:07:58,634 --> 00:08:07,901
By Shri Ganesha’s power, several works are manifested.

52
00:08:07,934 --> 00:08:18,301
For Me, He is the purest ever and My own.

53
00:08:18,334 --> 00:08:23,034
I trouble Him a lot.

54
00:08:23,067 --> 00:08:26,000
When somebody tries to trouble Me,

55
00:08:26,034 --> 00:08:32,201
I ask Him to handle this fellow and to make him alright.

56
00:08:32,234 --> 00:08:37,667
When this fellow is not manageable by Me,
when there is a difficult person

57
00:08:37,701 --> 00:08:40,267
and it is not possible for Me to handle him,
then He does the job.

58
00:08:40,301 --> 00:08:51,934
So today is very auspicious, as He was born this day.

59
00:08:51,967 --> 00:08:57,034
Secondly, today is Panchami (the fifth day).

60
00:08:57,067 --> 00:09:12,934
This Panchami is recognized
because on this day we wear special clothes.

61
00:09:12,967 --> 00:09:24,667
Whatever we wear is so that our body is properly covered.

62
00:09:24,667 --> 00:09:37,501
The sense of chastity that our body has is because of Him;

63
00:09:37,534 --> 00:09:41,601
Lajja Rupena Samsthita
[the one who resides in the form of bashful modesty].

64
00:09:41,634 --> 00:09:50,467
So if you have any sense of chastity, it is because of Him.

65
00:09:50,501 --> 00:09:57,501
That will benefit you immensely.

66
00:09:57,534 --> 00:10:06,234
You cannot feel joyous until you worship Shri Ganesha.

67
00:10:06,267 --> 00:10:11,501
By worshipping Shri Ganesha, your joy increases.

68
00:10:11,534 --> 00:10:19,334
You become joyous,
because He is the personification of joy [anand swaroop].

69
00:10:19,367 --> 00:10:34,367
Because of this, we have both things today:
His birthday and His help.

70
00:10:34,401 --> 00:10:42,534
We seek His help in any work we do. Such is our way.

71
00:10:42,567 --> 00:10:53,401
But we don’t see what we do to establish Him.
Our attention does not go in that direction.

72
00:10:53,401 --> 00:10:58,134
That we should also do something,
that we should also develop our state,

73
00:10:58,134 --> 00:11:05,101
that we should have a state in which
Shri Ganesha is awakened within us,

74
00:11:05,134 --> 00:11:09,734
through which we may never venture on the wrong path.

75
00:11:09,767 --> 00:11:15,367
Those who are rooted in Ganesha are special.

76
00:11:15,401 --> 00:11:25,101
They despise all the wrong things in this world,
and they do not do anything wrong,

77
00:11:25,134 --> 00:11:28,934
because Shri Ganesha stops them.

78
00:11:28,967 --> 00:11:33,067
They cannot enjoy wrong activities.

79
00:11:33,101 --> 00:11:44,267
This is Shri Ganesha’s great blessing,
that you have entered a new, joyous life.

80
00:11:44,267 --> 00:11:52,501
So today in His service, in order to make him joyous,

81
00:11:52,501 --> 00:11:59,767
sing His praise and glory, so that He may be pleased.

82
00:11:59,801 --> 00:12:05,534
My eternal blessings to all of you.

