It is so nice to be here in Brazil, especially in Salvador.
I’ve been to a gentleman a long time back, from my husband’s office,
from Brazil, and his wife was suffering from terrible black magic.
And she really was cured of that trouble.
So, he told Me that, "You have to go to Brazil  because it is full of lots of negative things  specially the black magic,
So you must go there somehow".
And so, it was my great desire to come here and that’s how I came, few years back.
Also, Duilio was here and, I mean, things
were arranged somehow, Sahaj, so I came here.
So, the problem of this country is more,
is this black magic that is brought by the people from Africa.
So, I have thought today, let us have Mahakali Puja.
Mahakali is the left side power in us.
So, actually, she is Adi Shakti.
Only when she enters into the left side of the Virata we call her Mahakali, but she is the power of pure desire of God.
Then she establishes Shri Ganesha herself.
Then she goes to the right-side as Mahasaraswati.
And then she enters into the centre where she is Mahalakshmi.
That is how Adi Shakti takes three forms.
But Mahakali is the pure form, because she’s not yet taken - I mean from Adi Shakti, she is Mahakali Power.
So, first thing she - before creating this universe or anything- she created Shri Ganesha.
And first, to spread, manifest not only holiness but also auspiciousness, and purity.
So, before anything was created, these spiritual Forces were created, to protect the creation that was to follow.
So, this Mahakali force was specially in the purest form to protect people from the negative side.
Now when any thought enters our mind, any reasoning comes up to our mind, it is thrown on the left-side by this Mahakali.
Throw out?
So, goes to the left side. Subconcious.
Every bad thought? No.
You see, whatever thought comes to us.
Ah, whatever.
Today, there’s a thought, now, just now, that goes to the left side,
And then, that is how the present becomes the past, goes to the subconscious.
Now the subconscious also has many layers which are on the left side in a parallel way, not horizontally, but parallel.
So, there are seven of these layers, and the seventh one ends up into the Collective Subconscious.
So, whatever is dead, in the past, and was discarded from the evolutionary process, is thrown into the Collective Subconscious.
Now when - say for example, lives which were thrown out of the evolution, microscopic animals, whatever, viruses,
then also human beings, animals, everything  that was thrown out,
like mammoths and all that, these animals were thrown out of the evolution, are [on the left-side].
So, the people who are living more in the past, if by any accident or by any unhappy incident in life, are thrown towards that,
they catch some of this Collective Subconscious.
So also, this lifetime, whatever conditionings we have, also pass into our, they pass into our subconscious mind.
For example, a person is sitting in the darkness alone, suddenly starts feeling the fear.
Then he is, with that fear, he’s thrown towards the left side
and he can catch something, what we call as ‘bhoots’, you see, what we call bhoots.
It's some sort of a dead spirit and then he becomes a different person.
Also, somebody who is too much right-sided, is always active, thinking too much of the future,
his attention moves to the extreme - say, to the right side.
Then suddenly if some shock or some fear, or whatever it is, this pendulum like thing, can move to the other side also.
So, all the people who are very right-sided can get into problems of possessions.
Of subconscious?
Of possessions.
But, of subconscious?
Subconscious also.
Also, people who are extremely meticulous, extremely futuristic, can catch on the right side also Collective Supraconscious.
Supraconcious. It's a right side. Futuristic.
Now, we have to now understand Mahakali’s powers.
Now Mahakali’s powers are such that she is the Holy Ghost.
So, firstly she can cure any diseases that come from viruses.
Like say from AIDS. You can start from Mooladhara, all Mooladhara diseases, then all Swadisthana diseases, all these diseases.
Left Vishuddhi of course, is a combination, because when a man is too right-sided, to balance his ego, he puts it here in the guilt.
It could be a combination of both right and left.
But all other incurable diseases are left-sided.
Like you have cancer.
Now see this is the left-side centre and this is the right-side centre, they look like this.
So, this is left-side, this is right-side, and in the centre, is the centre.
Now supposing even if you are working in the right side too much, the energy is driven to the right side.
But suddenly something may happen, you see, some accident, some sort of an unhappiness, anything,
and this little bit can break like that, from the left side.
So, the virus can start flowing into the right-side also.
Now, when this virus enters into the right-side, you have no connection with the whole, because it’s broken now. [The triangle is broken.]
So, this right side starts working on its own and that’s how you develop this cancer where the cell itself becomes the ego:
it gets the ego and it starts multiplying, multiplying.
So, this virus can give you any kind of disease
which cannot be cured by medical science because medical science deals with the right side of the physical side.
But the mental side is dealt with by Mahakali Power, mental side.
That is how in Sahaja Yoga we have been able to cure many incurable diseases by using candles.
Because the light when it is shown to these viruses, or to the bhoots, they go away.
So, by three-candle treatment you can cure any one of these incurable diseases, even AIDS.
But when this trouble starts above the Vishuddhi chakra or from the Vishuddhi chakra,
then people become mentally handicapped, like they become mad, they get epilepsy or they get what you call schizophrenia.
Now what do they do when they use black magic? We should understand.
In India, we call it the "preta vidya" or "shmashana vidya". "Preta vidya" means the dead, knowledge of the dead
and "shmashana vidya" is the knowledge of the cemetery.
Preta vidya?
Si, Preta vidya.
Preta also in Brazilian means "black".
Really?
In Brazilian,  black.
But "preta" means dead.
Dead, ah.
And the other is "shmashana vidya" means of the, of the cemetery.
So, the way they do it is that when some evil genius is dead, they know that somebody is dead,
then these people go there and try to wait until everybody disappears.
You know they burn in India, no? They burn the body in India.
Yes.
And when the brain is opened it makes a sound, you see, of the head.
After that people go away. So, they [preta vidya people] are still there.
And then they take the skull of that man, or some part of the body with them, maybe some bones, so that the Spirit, which is hovering there, follows them.
And then they give some names to these bhoots who are following them and then they, somehow or other, tie them up, you see, they imprison them.
And then they use these bhoots to entice someone, to mesmerise someone.
And these bhoots can get more bhoots also with them to entice them more if these people want,
just because they are now been captured and they are evil geniuses.
So, this is what the false gurus do, that they put these bhoots on people, mesmerise them, through their eyes these bhoots come in.
And then these people start giving all their money, all the property, everything to them, even the women give up their chastity.
Anywhere.
Anywhere, yes, anywhere, I'll say.
So, this is how they try to mesmerise.
Also, they can use these bhoots for killing somebody or for beating somebody, putting somebody into trouble, all kinds of things.
So also, they try to sort of put ideas into people, make them violent and make them very bad people, dirty people.
This unnatural sex relationship, like homosexuality and all that, it's also from bhoots.
That is, they do everything that is anti, you can say, Mahakali.
And that is how they may bring inauspiciousness, unholiness, violence, all kinds of problems.
Now supposing, if these bhoots are, say, drunkards, then they make people drink too much.
Or if they are, say, cheats or people who have been making money by wrong methods, they can also enter into the heads of people.
Like here I think the politicians, they have entered into their heads, so they are like mad people now.
And that is how the dharma is not there anymore, there is no dharma, there are no maryadhas, nothing and they do what they like.
So, the hundred and eight names of the Goddess or the one thousand names of the Goddess are mostly for the Mahakali, on the left-hand side.
Because she killed so many rakshasas. All right?
She destroys also viruses and all kinds of things which are inflicted on human beings.
Also, she cures many things like conditionings, say for example, of the Catholic church,
which has given a conditioning into human beings that they cannot ascend, because of this Catholic church conditioning.
So even if you believe in someone, supposing there is a Sahaja Yogi and you believe that this Sahaja Yogi is God, then also you can catch.
If you believe in some Sahaja Yogi that he is God, then they can catch.
Because they- if you beleive in anybody who has no authority, it is unauthorised shraddha [faith], then you get into trouble.
So, in Sahaja Yoga nobody should consider somebody as guru because he has given you Realisation or something, he is not your guru.
And the best way to get rid of it is through the Mother Earth because she sucks in, recedes the left side. The Mother Earth sucks in your problems.
So, if you just put your left hand towards the light and your right hand on the Mother Earth, from the light, you see, the negativity runs and goes into the Mother Earth.
They use the same thing, like lemons they will use, you see.
In the lemon they will put bhoots and they put this lemon to somebody so that, that person gets possessed.
While we remove the lemon that absorbs the bhoots and then put the lemon in the water.
Then another thing, that is the light, you see. Supposing you put the light without Me being there, my photograph not being there,
then the bhoots start, you see, getting more upset with the light.
And it attracts more bhoots to protect itself.
But in the presence of my photograph, the photograph emits vibrations which make all the bhoots run away.
Because the light also, this light, gets awakened in front of my photograph.
So, this is the contrast in which we can achieve results of getting rid of problems.
But I would suggest that Sahaja Yogis should not directly treat these people.
They can put them before my photograph and use the three candles treatment but not to touch them.
Before doing anything, they should take a bandhan also.
So, whenever you take your bandhan, you are taking the bandhan of Mahakali, because she protects you.
After some time, when you have reached a certain stage of ascent, the bhoots run away, if they see you, they run away.
Or they will start shaking before you.
And ask such a person to put his hands towards the light with my photograph. The light will go up and down and black soot will come out.
So, the left side is called as Tamo guna, the right side is Rajo guna and the centre as Satwo guna.
Now, Tamo guna means a left-sided personality.
He is the one who always runs into some darkness and he’s secretive and he’s sly.
And you don’t know how he- what he's up to.
And to look at, he looks very humble and he never answers you back but he does certain things at your back.
You cannot make out his mischiefs till he may hurt you.
Now, the right-sided person is on the contrary extremely aggressive and sort of tries to show off.
But the Satwo guna is in the balance.
But on your vibrations, you can make it out what are the problems of the person.
Last night, for example, my whole Swadisthana was burning.
Even the children will show by putting their thumb in the mouth [unsure].
So, this is what is the Left Swadisthana and for Left Swadisthana, the mantra is Mahakali’s mantra.
And another very important mantra for the Left Swadisthana is that, "Mother, you are the pure knowledge".
But for Christians it is better even to say, "Mother you are the Holy Ghost" like the Christ has said it.
It is really easy to get rid of these things if you just decide that, "I’m not having anything to do with that."
These bhoots are so stupid! That, supposing somebody, they may come to my house, take off their coat, put some other shawl on them,
when they go, the bhoots can’t recognize them. They are so stupid.
The bhoots that are in the shawl.
No, no, no. Somebody comes to meet Me. And I take out the bhoots, you see, he’ll go out somewhere.
The bhoots come inside the house also. Then you make him wear something else. So, the person changes his dress. So, they can’t make you out. They are so stupid.
[To a child] Just come here because there’s kana [food].
Both of you.
So, this is Mahakali’s great work and I have already told you how she works it out. Now today we are going to worship her, I’m sure she will become very powerful here
and she will see to it that all this black magic is finished.
These Mahakali’s powers you will start seeing also when she, once she starts manifesting, your politicians will improve,
everything will improve, because it is under these wrong powers you see that they are doing these things.
Also, all these bad things like violence and all kinds of bad things people do is only under the influence of negativity.
Even if they know this is wrong, it should not be done, they do it compulsively, compulsively.
Now a new disease has come where people have compulsive habits, like washing their hands all the time, or
I mean all these compulsive habits are done like somebody’s brushing their teeth three hundred times, somebody washing their hands, somebody very particular about everything, all the time cleaning, cleaning.
Some women are like that, if anything falls off, they must run, clean and they have no time to sit down for five minutes.
They can’t help it, they can’t help it.
Ultimately, they get out of the society because they are confused.
So, I have now tried to tell you the various things that this absence of Mahakali can manifest.
So, the Mahakali’s manifestation is so important for a country where there are so many negativities.
And I hope next time I come this will be very much reduced [inaudible]. We’ll have a much cleaner place.
Now you people also now know how to cure Left Swadisthana. So, always check up the Left Swadisthana and try to cure it.
May God bless you.