[Music]
or else if you have the puja on Saturday
evening to the facility hey after they
some of us have game is Sunday let us
have it on Saturday dr. Calaway hello
Halloween mother Halloween is an
abbreviation of the term Hallows Eve
because
suspended indefinitely some new zombie
is refuted to be all famous a mother the
day of all the same that's what we
didn't email all things they pursue any
did anything we have it on Sunday all
right Billy 43 it's very important
because that is the day
the goddess as a power as a power
because it was kartikeya he did not pass
whatever and he was one of the worst of
all did not be killed so she WA and
Parvati were married for the special
purpose to produce this fault rule
shucks people trapped in the front of
the shop owners car together and he was
just called to kill this horrible them
fathers not possible and he kicked that
is the day between three it's something
like valuation that way because that is
the day they open the gates of hand and
put all these Devils in to help and
that's why that the one has to rest in
the body tonight because some of them
might be hanging around better
all of it I mean either then that you
are you do not feel much stirring but if
you ran in the realm of subconscious
area of collective subconscious you can
see even some of the spirits and also
can feel their existence we see the
blacks who are Sonora
so that day is very dangerous but
because Nana Karim escaped people
celebrated that celebration it expects
next year next day which that day is the
day of Diwali to say it is America which
needs sahaja yoga much more than any
other country my concern for America is
for the same reason I am NOT saying so
much about South America but more about
the North America but even in South
America what I found is that it is a
kind of a nation where they have no
guidance at all about them no guidance
openly that bring Carnaval these that I
mean how can you do it in a country all
those things they are following the
footsteps of North America like in North
America they have this Halloween
nonsense I mean imagine openly on the
street doing Halloween nonsense so they
are following carnival to them uh what a
thing it is to go to Rio as if there's a
very big achievement and going into that
carnival from all over the places from
Australia people are coming down but the
worst and the worst and the worst is the
Hollywood is the film industry under the
name of industry you can do anything now
this Hollywood is creating such horrible
films but the worst is that they get
awards for these worst films this one
film they sure I have not seen I can't
see it they told me that a man is a
cannibal
he's eating the flesh of human beings
and their soul and they enjoy very very
famous apart from that not only famous
but they got awards for the best film
the best actor the best you must get a
director from there and make him eat the
flesh of human things it's the only way
I think this horn with you
then they are producing other pictures
have seen another one for a short time
where they shows all dead bodies hanging
is it horrible why these people like to
see such horrible things what is their
character where have they gone why do
they enjoy things which no human being
who is a human being with Angela and
then it goes further there hollowing
business I saw a film castle my god this
is a hell in which they thought it was
like the wrath of Shri Krishna so it was
Krishna consciousness I think that was
working there there are thousand and one
things which can shop you in America and
also in England also in Europe
[Music]