“Where is our attention?” we should say.
You are meditating, take it deep down into
yourself.
That’s a meditative mood.
Keep yourself there.
And after meditation you just get up silently,
sit for a while.
I think best thing will be to have your food
first and then meditate,
if that is so, if you think that is proper.
But I think if you have to get now into that
new triggering, as I told you,
into that new jumping that we have to do in
Sahaja Yoga: if you have to catch that train,
then you hurry up.
You have to change all these ideas.
You have had many houses,
you have had many wives and many children
in your previous life.
You never had your realisation – now you
have got it.
So now just every individual, every one of
you should not think of others,
Think of yourself, “I have to do it, I have
to get it, I have to work it out.”
This is what you have to do.
“Why should I miss it?”
This is a chance of many lives, the chance
of many lives.
And that’s how you can jump over, and work
it out.
We had lots of people in Australia,
and if they had worried about themselves as
to “what I have done for Sahaja Yoga.”
So in the morning you just decide,
what I am going to do for Sahaja Yog and myself;
in the evening, what have I done for myself,
and what have I done for Sahaja Yoga?
“Myself” doesn’t mean selfishness, but
“for my ascent.”
Every day.
You start a diary to write it down.
You face yourself.
No excuses, nothing.
If you are left behind, what we can do?
We can’t help it.
And that is how you’ll find all kinds of
blessings will come to you.
You’ll be able to save money, you’ll be
able to save time, you’ll get good jobs.
All your problems can be solved
if you really surrender yourself to that Paramachaitanya.
Everything can be done.
But as long as you have this narrow-mindedness
and these narrow ideas about yourself, till
then it won’t work out.
This drop has to become one with the ocean,
then ocean takes over.