So many questions, you see... Now, most of
the questions are coming from people who doubt.
Can you translate it? In Sahaja Yoga best
thing is to practice what is said and then
see for yourself, but if they're coming I
would like to tell them about it.
Now the first one is about vegetarianism,
somebody's asked. Who has asked about vegetarianism?
Raise your hand. Ah, you, all right. Now,
I said that there should be, there is no question
of vegetarianism; whether you are a vegetarian
or not makes no difference to your meditation.
But for people, you see, the food is only
important because supposing you're Chinese,
you eat too much of fish and all that. So
to give it a balance, if you become a vegetarian
more you'd be better.
It's a question of balancing, but those people
who eat too much of, say, vegetarians, like
in India, they should take more to non-veg,
or to proteins; it's a question of carbohydrates
and proteins, it's not question of vegetarianism.
Now to say that Buddha was vegetarian is not
true; it's false. Because how Buddha died,
you know? Buddha died when he went to a disciple
who had killed a wild boar, and the wild boar
is allowed to leave for some time and then
you should eat the meat. But he was in a hurry,
so they didn't do that and he ate it and he
died.
Now the problem with all of you is one, always,
like whether you're Christians or Buddhists
or anything, you're all conditioned background.
To you Buddha is everything. What did Buddha
do for you? Where is he? What is he doing?
What did he do for the Buddhists? Did he give
you Realization? But you all are like that,
even the Christians are like that. They're
so much conditioned by Christ. You see, they
are either Christ or Mohammad Sahib or someone
like that, but I'm sitting before you. They're
not here. Who has given you Realization? Try
to understand.
So why be so much conditioned by Buddha? Buddha
was never, never was a vegetarian; he died
because of that. He ate that meat and he died;
so it's a wrong idea that Buddha was a vegetarian.
It's all myths they're going about and there
is no need to be vegetarian; if you are suffering
from too much of protein intake you should
take to vegetarianism. It's good for you if
you have that problem, and in China eat so
much of, say, fish. So they should take more
vegetables with it, not only the fish because
with fish you have phosphorous.
Now do you know about your genes, we have
a database of the genes. There are three things,
carbohydrates, there is phosphorous and there
is nitrogen. Nitrogen is good for your health,
for your ascent, for everything. But what
happens? People eat too much of proteins and
fish and all that; then they create more phosphorous,
they become very right-sided, their eyes are
spoilt and the whole balance is lost. Do you
follow the point? The balance is lost; so
what you have to do... So the people who are
eating too much of phosphorous must take to
carbohydrates. So it will suit some people
who are eating too much of proteins or too
much of phosphorous should take to more vegetarian
food, will help; but it's not the way we should
judge it we start by taking vegetarianism
will become a realized soul, you cannot.
Some people it will improve the meditation,
with some people it will not. For example
Me, I can't take vegetarian food for more
than two days, I get diarrhea, <inaudible
> sympathetic. I just get diarrhea, I cannot
eat. I cannot also eat all the time fish,
I have to eat a very much of protein food.
You see for the Goddess they offered a lamb
or sometimes a goat, this is the reason She
has to take proteins. This is what it is that
She has to take proteins, and somebody has
to take, say, more of carbohydrates, they
should take. But it doesn't suit everyone.
"We learn that several gurus in Hong Kong..."
Who is this Sarah Lee? All right. "We learn
that several gurus in Hong Kong promote their
exegeses free of charge and promise the followers
that they can get rid of their karma once
they give their faiths to their guru as they
are also promoting internal peace and transcendence
and they do not charge for anything. What
are they aiming at?" They're just aiming at
controlling you. Just they want to control
some people, that's all; it's a power game,
and that's what they want to do, it's a power
game. And I'm sure at certain point they must
be taking money also. Now the thing is if
they were giving peace and they're talking
about karma.
I'm not talking of karma. I'm saying you've
to go beyond your mind and it has to be connected
with scientific ideas, that you have to go
beyond your mind. They never say like this,
"We'll get rid of your karmas." How can you?
Who does the karma? Ask them. Ask them five
questions, they'll be all right. They don't
know about ego, they don't know about conditioning,
they don't know about chakras, nothing they
know. They might be cheating you just, I mean
it's just anybody can start something like
that but what is the validity. Validity is
that do they talk relevantly, do they talk
about the inner side, do they talk about the
chakras, do they talk about the Kundalini?
Now you have got your Kundalini awakened;
that should give you faith not in Me but in
yourself. You have no faith in yourself, that's
why you start thinking like this. If you have
faith in your achievements, what you have
achieved through Sahaja Yoga, you won't ask
such questions. All right, so this is over...
There's somebody, a new yogini, she said she
cannot believe in her own feelings. Who's
this one, from Japan? Now see, there's nothing
to believe in your own feelings, no question.
You have to believe in your vibrations. You
should see what sort of vibrations you get.
Supposing you are very much inclined for something.
So try to find out of someone, try to find
out on your vibrations, you can find out whether
it is true or not. Because now you have jumped
into an awareness where you know the absolute
but it's not necessary that you have reached
that state. But I'll tell you how to reach
that state, it's different but just now as
it is, you have to go beyond your mind. And
that is what one has to achieve, all right?
So how to go beyond your mind, that I'll tell
you.
Now who's Pamela Ng? All right, well, she
says that when she came first to meditation
she was sleeping very well, it was effective
after, and all that and then later on she
started... Now see, look, if you are just
thinking about yourself, vibrations will go
away. It's not given only for your benefit,
it's given for the benefit of everyone. If
you're just worried about yourself the vibrations
will disappear. Because vibrations are there
to give it to others, to work for others.
If you're not collective enough, you cannot
grow. If you do not dissolve into Sahaja Yoga
you cannot grow. And then when you don't grow
you go on falling down; you go on falling
down, then you'll lose all these things. So
how many people have you given Realization?
That's it. First you start giving Realizations
to others then you will understand that how
joyous it is to give Realization. It's not
meant for you alone, it's meant for everyone,
all right?
"I believe that there are real gurus and false
gurus in this world. If someone follows a
real guru but not Sahaja Yoga does this still
do any good for him?" Who's this Christine?
Now see, I haven't met anybody who's a real
guru and who is giving Realization to others,
who may be real but he cannot give Realization.
That's the point. So what will they do? You
see, they're very hot-tempered people mostly
and they take you to task; they make you work
very hard. I haven't seen anybody giving Realization
so far; if you meet anyone, let Me know .
I'll be very happy, pass on.
Mr. Ling, who's he? Now, this is interesting,
the way you're seeing visions. Have you been
to some other master before? No one? No? Now,
you see, for this, best thing is to know about
Tao which is your speciality, it's Chinese
in which he describes, you see, Tao; Lao Tzu
describes the journey through the river Yangtze.
I've been Myself to see that. So he says on
the side or the banks there are beautiful,
very beautiful mountains and beautiful trees
and it's so beautiful that you feel like jumping
out of the boat and going to the, these gardens
and these mountains. But what your aim is
to go through this, Tao, means the Yangtze
river, towards the river. In the beginning,
maybe there are some currents flowing, maybe
you might lose faith in yourself. But by the
time you reach near the sea, it becomes very
silent and you have to go to the sea, that's
the point is. So, you see, all these are there;
these are just enticing... It's all right
you see but it's nothing important because
all these will keep you on a mental level.
You'll be always thinking, "What is this vision?
What is that?" There's nothing to be on the
mental level, you have to beyond, all right?
If you don't see, you don't bother about it,
they'll disappear.
These questions are nice. The first one is
about confidence, you see and I'm going to
tell you about meditation. If you do that
kind of meditation you'll get back your confidence,
all right? That's one point. And then he says
if there's anything like destiny. In Sahaja
Yoga you decide your destiny, you don't have
to depend on any destiny. Then it's true that
in Hong Kong is highly polluted and lot of
people get allergies and things like that.
But Sahaja Yogis should take bandhans so they
won't suffer with any allergies or anything.
And also you can use something to cover your
nose or something. I know people are smoking
so much I Myself, I absorb so much of this
within Myself, but this will all go away as
far as you are concerned because you're protected,
all right? But the first one I'll tell you
later.
Werner, where's Werner? Now your eyes are
suffering. So very simple is that... All right
now what you have to do... What is your digestion
problem? You get diarrhea? Constipation. What
is your digestion problem? Digestion, what
is it? He's already right-sided. You're very
right-sided person, you see and your eye trouble
also come from the same. For the eye trouble
that you are doing you have to put ice here,
on the left hand side from here to here, and
also on your liver, all right? And your right-sidedness
has to go, that I'll tell you how to do it,
all right?
This is a nice idea, that they come to your
program and then they come to puja and then
they disappear. It's all right, now what can
you do about it? There's no choice, if they
want to disappear let them go away. We cannot
force them, but maybe, maybe some of the people
do not have proper behavior towards them,
maybe. So you have to be careful how you talk
to them and how you approach them. You should
not be aggressive with them and all that.
Maybe some of the reasons could be that. So
that's very common, you see, they come and
they go away. Because this is the time of
Last Judgment. If they want to go to false
guru let them go because this is their choice.
You don't have to worry on that point. But
I think sometimes, sometimes they leave because
they do not do meditation properly, and I'll
tell you what is to be done properly.
All right, now we have to go beyond the mind,
as I said it that mind is a myth and we live
on a mental level all the time. And that's
why so many questions and so many things they
come from your mind. If you reach a state
where you are beyond the mind you won't have
any questions because you will be there. Because
you're not there you're asking these questions.
You are there for a short time and then you
come down. So how to be more on that level,
I'll tell you. I don't have that problem.
I can be all the time beyond the mind but
for you people I've tried to find out why,
how to make it, to keep you beyond the mind.
Now the best way I told people and it has
worked wonders that when you are, wherever
you are free, whether you are meditating or
not, wherever you are freely standing or doing,
try to see what is your mind is thinking.
You separate, now because you're realized
souls, you have to be, first of all, connected;
if you're not connected you can't do this
practice. But if you're connected to the mains
then what you should do is to see that your
mind is thinking. Now watch your mind. Ask
the mind, "Now what are you thinking? Let's
see, what are we to think?" And you will be
surprised you'll go on watching and suddenly
you'll reach a point that you have become
thoughtless.
So always watch the mind. What is it doing?
What is it thinking? What is it working out?
And the mind will just not think because it
cannot answer. It cannot answer a realized
soul, you see. But for that, you have to be
beyond the mind; to begin with you should
separate yourself from your mind. You ask
questions to your mind. "Now let's see what
are you thinking, sir. Where are you?" In
the mirror also you can see, you shouldn't
suffer from narcissism, of course not, but
what you have to do is to ask.
You see, if you try to understand how to become
thoughtless, the best way is to look at something,
now you look at something, say, look at the
flowers. Now immediately it will react, your
mind will react. Now you try to see what is
your mind is saying. "I don't want to hear,
no, I don't want to hear." Just say, "I don't
want to hear anything. I don't want to know
anything." You just want to watch, that's
all. Gradually you'll grow. You see, this
is the system Zen. Try to do it, but it was
such a thing, you know, that time, they were
no such nice people like you, perhaps. So
he had to use other methods to make people
go beyond the thought.
For example, I was telling just now about
the tea ceremony. For tea ceremony, he would
take a bowl of, say, freak, like a freak.
Freak, you understand the freak? Freak is
a thing which comes out by nature naturally
in the cooking. When it is fried it becomes
very funny type; that is the freak. It's not
regular. It's only one piece or something.
Somebody who's Japanese here, who's come from
Japan? You? You people, they like, that's
why freak very much, you see. So, what he
said that it is... , you take the bowl in
your hand for tea ceremony, that's the best.
So first of all, you sit in a garden, with
natural trees and natural fibers of the wood
and all that, sitting down. Now you start
watching that thing, three times sitting like
this and three times like that. And don't
think, that's the point, don't think. And
then you take that tea; the tea is so sour,
so bitter, take quinine raised to the power
of hundred and eight. Once you take that,
you become absolutely thoughtless; that's
one.
Then they give you a sweet; this sweet is
also sweetness, sugar raised to the power
of hundred and eight. You just can't eat it,
so you went from one extreme to another extreme;
again you become like that, you see, it's
like standing. They put this side and that
side and suddenly it works out. But it's meant
for people who already have got Realization,
not for people who have not got. That's why
still they're studying Zen, you know, this
tea ceremony. When we went to Japan, you see,
in one hotel, they had arranged this tea ceremony
and some Americans, they said one couple has
to come, they were fighting, "I'll go, I'll
go." We have had the experience, so we were
keeping quiet, to see what's going to happen.
And one couple came forward and knew they
were very jealous of them. They sat on the
stage and then they brought the tea; they
make it with a very care and all that and
gave it to the wife. She drank it and she
was stunned, and then they gave it to the
husband. Her husband, you know, American after
all, he got so angry he threw the bowl. He
said, "Damn it! You took so much money from
us and what are you giving us?" He gave all
kinds of American abuses to them and they
came away and everybody started beating the
people who had put up the show.
So this is meant for people who really want
to go very deep. In Zen we also made a big
courtyard filled with sand, with some sort
of designs in the sand and they put some stones
in it. You are supposed to sit on the edge
of that and to look at it without thinking.
But normally people start comparing, "It looks
like ships, it looks like this, it looks like..."
No, you have to just look at it without thinking.
There're many such things he did but nothing
worked out with them. There were only twenty-six
people who got Realization in the Zen system
in the Sixth Century. From the Sixth Century
to the Twelfth Century and after that nobody
got Realization. But there were very few and
that's why they don't understand Zen at all.
You see, people write Zen because it's very
deep and they don't understand; so that's
what it is. Now Sahaja Yoga is understood,
can be understood by normally educated person,
by even uneducated people. And this happens
because actualization takes place. Your Kundalini
takes an actual ascent.
Now in Sahaja Yoga when people come in, there're
different categories of people also. Some
of them come because they think they can get
good health; once they get good health they
disappear. Then they again get some trouble,
they come back, just for good health. So you
can't help, they have very limited desires.
Then some people come in Sahaja Yoga for throwing
their weight around, you see, showing off
their ego, that, "I'm this," you see, trying
to make another group, another this thing.
You see, like that also some people come,
it's very common, like a politics, you see.
And they try to do it against the leader,
against this, "This is wrong with him, that
is wrong with him," and all kinds of things.
Thirdly people come but they don't come regularly
to Sahaja Yoga, they do not come regularly
to the center. They just keep aloof and after
some time they're lost. They again get some
diseases or trouble, then they come back.
So it's a religious duty of all of you to
come to the collective, one thing. The second
one is to meditate everyday in the night before
sleeping on your mind. Everywhere you go you
should be in a meditative condition, in the
sense, you should ask your mind what is it
thinking. All should come to collective every
time they have a program wherever it is. In
Delhi you have seen people are really wonderful.
There are so many people, at least about,
I think two hundred people, of course we have
a good center there; two hundred people, every
morning they come for meditation, every morning,
look at these people. So the quality, we call
the pindah, so the quality of a person depends
on how much you want Sahaja Yoga. You just
want to have all the advantages, you want
to do everything.
Like this lady, Sushmita Sen, she got the
first prize, she's a Sahaja Yogini. She's
a Sahaja Yogini and she meditates everyday,
everyday she meditates and everyday she used
to come in the morning to our ashram in Delhi.
She's a great Sahaja Yogini, I must say, but
now she's in Calcutta and there also she does
the same. So the children also, some who are...;
this girl child is very highly developed child,
this one is. I saw her yesterday, she's a
born realized, and she is the one, she must
be meditating, I'm sure. She is a very highly
developed person; she's got it from her last
life so she... This kind of children, there
are many who are meditating or when they go
to school also they become like that. So you
have to first of all worry about correcting
yourself.
Now, you see, also another kind of people
come in Sahaja Yoga they came, they made lots
of money, this thing, that thing, see, the
greed is on. So if you still suffer from too
much greed or hatred or you can call it pride
and aloofness and all that, then you must
know that still you have to work out. Or if
you are very angry type or attached, some
people are very attached to their children.
So in Sahaja Yoga they learn a lesson also
from their children. So one has to be introspective
to see, "Are you just, are you satisfied?"
Then you can certify yourself that you're
all right.
There're so many types of people you'll meet
but what you have to see about your own ascent.
So I've talked about God Realization in My
last speech in this thing, so you better listen
to that lecture of Mine, for this puja, for
the Shiv Puja. So one should not even have
ambitions, when you have become a part and
parcel of the whole, when you have become
the ocean, what is there to be ambitious?
It's all individuality. You have
to be a satisfied soul and I would say about
Myself that I have to buy for My children,
for My husband, this thing, that thing, but
I never buy anything for Myself, very difficult,
very difficult to buy something for Myself.
And somebody says that, "Mother please what
will you have?" I don't know what to say,
what should I have. I asked My daughter, "You
make all kinds of things for your father,
what about Me?" So she said, "You don't like
something in particular, what to make for
you, you tell us."
All these attachments some people have, got
attachments to clothes, you see, "What I'll
wear tomorrow, I'll wear day after tomorrow,"
like that. But so spontaneously whatever
is available you can wear. And some worried
about their past, you see, "I'd a bad childhood,"
this, that, and they write about their parents;
it's all nonsense, forget it, you be in the
present. Now you are no more a seed, you have
to grow. That is something one has to understand
in life; that if you have to grow ourselves
then what we have to see within ourself what
lies, whether that is doing wrong. That is
something missing.
Best is to see the good points of others,
not the bad points. By that you will gradually
develop more good points within yourself.
Competition should be in good points. So on
one side you have to achieve your self-Realization
in a way that you put yourself beyond the
mind, one way, through meditation. And the
second way is to give Realizations to others.
And must attend collective meditation, very
important. You have to be active in it. If
you are not active in Sahaja Yoga then you
lose your vibrations gradually because Divine
thinks, "What's the use of giving to this
hopeless case any vibrations." So you have
to work it out, understanding that now you
are chosen as the instrument of the Divine.
It is not only for your health or for the
health of your family or for anything like
that. But it is for the good of the others.
That's how you'll all go very well.
Now diffidence comes through your mind only;
mind only gives you diffidence. So to overpower
this mind, you must watch and tell him to
shut up. Must tell him to shut up. Then you
will rise. The proof is that you feel the
vibrations. Now, if you ask Me I find the
people in Hong Kong are rather right-sided,
most of them. So you
have to do right-sided treatment for yourself.
Every night, about ten minutes, at the most,
you have to sit with your right hand towards
the photograph and right foot in the water,
with a little salt. Normally use cold water,
ice also is good but cold water normally but
if it is very cold outside, you can use warm
water. In this hand (left hand) you must take
ice and put it on your liver, right hand towards
the photograph. Now, then after that you can
put the ice over here, put your hand there.
If you do it everyday your stress will go
down, everything will be perfect, just sit
like this, just now. Heat is going down; no,
no, no, put right hand towards Me and the
left hand there. You're left sided, you're
not right-sided; you have to use the candle
treatment, all right?
Now some people have both problems. Then you
have to put a candle in front of the photograph,
put both the feet in the water and sit like
this and in
both the cases don't close your eyes. You
should put your attention on My Agnya, it'll
be very good for you, for your ascent into
the realm of thoughtless awareness. As I love
you try to love Me, that's the best thing.
Lastly, you see, in Sahaja Yoga people come
in, they think it's a sort of a contract with
us that we should look after them, their health,
their jobs, their everything. This is absurd.
The contract is between yourself, with yourself.
You have to work it out, all right? This is
what it is. So if the mind is asking questions
ask it to shut up now. Mind is the worst thing,
it is standing between you and reality. (Shri
Mataji speaks in Hindi here.)
Now whatever it is, like yours, you see, you
give a bandhan to your husband; ask everybody
to give a bandhan to him just now, you can
give bandhan to him, her husband, Atul is
his name. Just give him a bandhan. See, it
will work out, you can help, all of you can
help. You can help the whole world but you
have to be strong, you have to have the energy
within yourself. Ha! Good, very good. This
is Sahaja Yog, it's cool. So try to remember
what is your real problem; you're right-sided,
all right so just try to cut it off.
I'll be happy if you could learn some English
because I can't learn so many languages. Deities
only understood so far only Sanskrit but now
they understand English, thank God!
It's a great credit for the English people.
But still English language very limited, very
limited. For example "spirit" word they will
use for the Atma, they will use it for alcohol,
also they will use it for the dead spirits.
Such a language, what can you say, what can
you explain. And the French is the worst,
French is the worst because first of
all if
you speak French you catch on Vishuddhi. And
also
in French there are many words missing, of
course "spirit" is missing though, no doubt,
but
also
the word "awareness" is
not there.
So now I think everybody is happy. Let's have
some music.