سلام برهمه جستجو گران  حقیقت
دیروز برای شما گفتم حقیقت هر چه است هست
شما نمیتوانید انرا تصور یا تخیل نمائید
و نمیتوانید انرا با حافظه و هشیاری انسانی بدانید
ما بایستی یک انسان بخصوص بشویم
ما باید روح بشویم
فقط ما زمانیکه روح بشویم میتوانی تمامی حقیقت را درک کنیم. که
تمامی مخلوقات خدائی  تحت محبت بخصوص
خداییی خلق و نگهداری میشوند
برای این موجود بخصوص شدن در بدنمان مکانیکی است
که راجع بان دیروز صحبت کردم
امروز من میخواهم برای شما در مورد نیروئی بگویم.
که ان در باره روح و دریافت روح بما کمگ میکند.
این نیرو در لگن خاصره یعنی در استخوان سه گوشه
مقدس مستقر شده است.
Diese Kraft ruht im Kreuzbein, in dem Knochen, der Sacrum genannt wird
ان نیروی انعکاس روح القدس در ماست
und ist die Reflexion des Heiligen Geistes,
همجنین روح انعکاس خدای بزرگ در قلبمان است
während der Spirit die Reflexion des Allmächtigen Gottes in unserem Herzen ist.
روح  فقط  ان است مارا  نظارت میکند
ن قسمت از نیروی خدائی که ارزو و خواست  اوست
که ارزو و خواست  اوست
ان روح القدس است
که روح القدس مادر اولیه همه موجودات است
در نوشته ها در باره پدر که خداست و پسر خدا
نوشته شده ولی در باره مادر چیزی گفته نشده است
چگونه ممکن است که پدر و پسر داشته باشیم بدون مادر؟
نمیدانم  انها بچه علتی منگر شده اند در باره مادر اولیه صحبت کنند
در تمامی نوشته ها بخشی است  که  اتینا ( خدای یونانی) نامند
تا درزبان  سانسکریت بمعنی مادر اولیه است
ولی با وجود اینکه انها خیلی در موردمادر حضرت عیسی نگفته اند که او خداست.
مردم بخودی خود احساس کرده اند که در پشت پرده خدائی است
که اورا مادونا نامیده اند
با این که مادونا  در انجیل نام برده نشده است
انعکاس این مادر اولیه  و ابراز  روح القدس در هر انسان را گندالینی نامن
که این گندالینی مادر انفرادی ماست
او هر چیز و همه چیز راجع بما را میداند
خیلی ها گویند بیداری گندالینی ممکن است درناک باشد
چطوری ممکن است که گندالینی درد اور باشد. زمانیکه ان مادرمان است
وقتی که ما متولد شدیم مادرمان همه زحمات زایمان را بر خود هموار کرده
او برایمان ناراحتی ببار نیاورده است
بهمان منوال اگر گندالینی فعال شود بدون هر گونه ناراحتی بشما تولد دوباره میدهد
بایستی بدانیم که که این مادر زمین هچیچ دردی را در دانه ببار نمیاورد در هنگامی که  دانه جوانه میزند
بهمان طریق گندالینی در هنکام فعال شدن ناراحتی ببار نخواهد اورد
گفتم که روح انعکاس خدای متعال در همگی ما میباشد
گفته شده است  که ما فقط یک خدا داریم پس در همهمان  روح از یک منبع است
از ان بابت است که ما بطور دسته جمعی  هوشیار و اگاه میشویم زمانیکه ما روح بشویم
در هر کس روح در قلبش انعکاس یافته است
زمانیکه این باد خنک روح القدس را احساس کردید همانطور یکه دیروزانرا احساس کردید
انکه شما احساس میکنید ان همان قدرت نافذ خواست خدای متعال است
با دریافت روح همزمان ما اگاهی دستجمعی را دریافت کرده که
با ان دانش شما میتوانید شخص دیگر را در نوک انگشتانتان احساس نماید
در قران حضرت محمد فرمود: زمان معاد دست شما صحبت خواهد کرد
این همان روز رستاخیز و دادگاه  عدل الاهی است که بما پیام داده شده است
And you have to judge yourself.
The other day in Holland one person asked Me,
“Mother, how is it that
some people will be saved and some will not be?"
I said, “It is destiny."
Maybe those who are here have done such righteous things
in previous lives and in this life that they are here.
It depends, I don’t know how.
In Russia for example, I have to always book a big stadium.
For example there is a place called Togliatti
and this gentleman Togliatti was actually Italian.
And he revolted against the Christian church and went to Russia.
And there he started a big factory for making motorcars.
Now there are 40.000 Sahaja Yogis.
I’ve not been there as yet.
And on My birthday they had a holiday for the whole city.
I can’t understand why in some places
it works tremendously in a big way,
many people come to Sahaja Yoga
and in some places there are very few people.
As I told you, when this Kundalini rises
then you improve physically.
Now, I must say many diseases have been cured
as a by-product of Kundalini-awakening.
We have three Indian doctors who have got their MD in Sahaja Yoga
for curing incurable diseases.
And there are seven doctors in England
who are recording all those who have been cured.
But in Moscow there are 40 doctors who are practizing Sahaja Yoga.
Because for this you don’t need a hospital, you don't need money,
you don’t need anything.
It is your own power that works.
And once you are properly established,
then you don’t have to worry about your health at all.
It also helps for mentally retarded people, mentally sick people.
Because this Kundalini, when She rises She is also a redeemer.
She nourishes the centers.
By that nourishment the centers get cured
and ultimately She integrates all these centers.
The Spirit, when it shines in your attention,
then your attention becomes enlightened.
Means if you can pay attention to anyone
and try to feel what centers are in problem in that person,
you can immediately feel it.
There are many criminals from India who came to west countries
wearing these orange dresses and became false masters.
Some of them also knew how to mesmerize very well
and they have lynched people because main interest was money.
Of course there are also other so-called masters
in other countries also,
even a person like Freud.
He was anti-Christ, you can see it clearly.
Because Christ had said, “Thou shalt not have adulterous eyes,”
such a subtle description of purity.
Such a subtle description of puritiy.
But on the other hand this Mister Freud
has made everyone into nothing but a sex point.
And the people have lost understanding
that these are the human weaknesses.
To such an extent they have been misled that they say
that you can ascend in your spirituality through sex.
This is absurd!
On the contrary, in the Christian dogmas
people believe that you should abhor sex.
This is both are absolutely absurd.
One has to have a sane attitude.
If you see it clearly, the lowest center which we call as Mooladhara
is placed below the Kundalini.
Now this center looks after our excretion, including sex.
So your ascent has nothing to do with sex.
On the contrary, when your Kundalini starts awakening
you become innocent like a child.
And that is what Christ has said, that
you have to become like children to enter into the Kingdom of God.
So it is Sahaja Yoga which really explains Christ
and practizes Christianity.
Moreover, the breaking of the Sahasrara,
which is what we call is the fontanel bone area,
is actualization of the baptism.
You may follow any religion, Hindu, Christian, Muslim, any religion,
you can do any sin, you can commit any sin, there is no restriction.
There is no restricition from within.
But once you become a sahaja yogi, I don’t have to tell you anything.
You just become righteous.
I don’t have to tell you Ten Commandments,
you just do it yourself.
You become your own master
and you guide yourself.
And you know the absolute truth.
You can get ten children who are realized souls and tie their eyes
and put one person in front of those children
and ask them, “What’s wrong with this gentleman?”
and they will put up the same finger.
And you ask him, “Is something wrong with his throat?”
And he says, “Yes, but how do you know?”
Because this finger indicates the throat.
So, these false gurus who have come here,
the falsehood that they have taught – you can feel it.
You can feel if they are crooks, if they are false,
if they are deceiving you.
First of all you should know that you cannot pay for your ascent,
because it is an evolutionary process,
which is living process,
for which you cannot pay.
And then you enter into the Kingdom of God.
And then you become joy.
Not the wrong type of joy,
but joy that elevates you,
sublimates you.
Joy does not have happiness and unhappiness like two sides of a coin.
That means joy is absolute,
but pleasures are not.
When you indulge into any pleasure it has a reaction,
it has a repercussion,
but joy is absolute.
So, yesterday all of you who were here, most of you felt the Spirit
because you could feel the cool breeze.
So the growth has started
and hardly you’ll take a month to master it.
But you have to work it out
because the connection has to be all right.
Maybe there are some problems within the being
which need to be corrected
So it would be very nice
if you people attend their follow-on and meet them
But the whole thing works in collectivity.
See, at the time of Buddha they had to do all kind of penances,
cleansing, absolute renunciations.
Still they could not achieve their Self-Realization.
Buddha also had to suffer a lot
in His cleansing.
But in Sahaja Yoga it is the collectivity
which cleanses you automatically.
Corrects you, yes.
Now supposing there’s something wrong with this left hand
so the right hand immediately helps it,
automatically,
because they are part and parcel of one body.
In Sahaja Yoga you have become part and parcel of the whole.
The microcosm has become the macrocosm.
So now you can only grow when you are with that body.
Supposing My nail is cut from My body – it won’t grow.
In the beginning you will find little difficult
to adjust to collectivity
you may find that it’s not very congenial for you, maybe.
Not with everyone, but some people do fuss about it.
And the door of Sahaja Yoga is open to everyone,
sometimes we also get mad people in Sahaja Yoga.
Then you start thinking, “How this mad man is here?”
and all that, you start criticizing.
But if you take to introspection, then it will be excellent for you
and not to worry about others,
you will grow much faster.
For you are the seed, you are the Mother Earth
and you are the gardener.
And you are the love that is water.
So as it is, I’ve told you, all you have Divinity,
only thing you have to feel and grow into it.
Yesterday nobody asked Me any questions, it was such a good sign
that you all want your Realization, that’s all.
Then I told you that asking questions is just a mental acrobats.
Now, I can answer all your questions,
but – that is no guarantee for Self-Realization.
Only thing, you must have the pure desire,
pure desire to be the Spirit.
Then it works,
because the Kundalini is the power of pure desire.
As you know all other desires are in general not satiable.
This is the only desire which gives you real satisfaction.
Thank you very much!
So, are you going to ask Me any question today?
What's it?
He wants to know about the appearance of Holy Mary,
for example in Fatima or in other places.
Might have, it’s quite possible, you see one of My photographs,
where people are taking photographs – and She’s there,
She’s appeared before Me also, it’s possible.
You must see some of My photographs,
it’s interesting how these apparitions come in.
All right? It’s possible.
But unfortunately She’s described as just a woman in the Bible,
I mean there’s no respect for Her.
Must be Paul who must have done it, because he was just an organizer
and I think he wanted to use Christianity as a platform for himself.
And he had nothing to do with Christ, you see on the contrary
he killed one of the disciples of Christ, Steven, he killed him.
He must have thought it’s a very good way of getting a platform
so he must have jumped on the platform.
Or might be to make some money.
We, too,  get sometimes such people in Sahaja Yoga.
What to do?
But he was not a realized soul, nothing of that kind.
Sahaja Yoga will explain everything,
the relationship of Christ with others.
Christ has said, “Those who are not against Me are with Me.”
Who are those?
Actually Christ was there till eight years of age,
and then He went to India. For twenty years He was there.
When He came back He lived only for three and a half years.
And they crucified Him.
I mean, whatever He has done is tremendous in three and a half years.
He just used ordinary fishermen and did such a lot of preaching
about truth, very forcingly He talked about truth, courageously.
But three and a half years is nothing!
In England I was struggling with seven hippies for four years,
I had to give them Realization, struggling for four years!
They had no background at all
And they are now, I feel, they were following Freud, not Christ.
It was such a shock to see.
All right,
so it will take us ten, fifteen minutes for us to get to that state.
I have to just request you to take out your shoes,
to take the help of the Mother Earth.
One thing I have to tell you, that Self-Realization cannot be forced.
You have to ask for it in your own glory of freedom,
because ultimately you have to achieve the complete freedom,
complete mastery of yourself,
where no addiction,
no habits,
no false gurus, nobody can dominate you.
So those who do not want to have their Self-Realization should please leave.
Come and sit, there are chairs here, come and sit here.
No use standing, please be seated.
All of you should be seated will be good idea.
You shouldn’t stand and watch others, it is not civil.
Now, please try to understand what you have to do,
and we’ll show you that,
after that you have to close your eyes.
There are two powers within us, left one the power of desire
and the right one the power of action.
So we put our left hand like this on our lap, very comfortably.
You should not sit with a slouch or a stretch on your body,
but just a straight comfortable pose.
Those who are sitting on the ground are perfectly all right,
they should just take out their shoes.
Those who are sitting on the chair
both the feet away from each other.
So we use the left hand
to express that we desire to have Self-Realization.
And we use the right hand to nourish our centers.
So first we put our right hand on our heart
because in the heart resides the Spirit.
Please put it on your heart. You don't understand?
Now, here resides the Spirit.
Now, you take your right hand in the upper portion of your abdomen
where is the center of your mastery.
When you are the Spirit, you are your master.
So now, please take your right hand
in the lower portion of your abdomen -
everything on the left side -
because this is the center of pure knowledge.
Then we raise our right hand again
on the upper portion of our abdomen.
Then we take our right hand on the heart.
Then we take our hand in the corner of our neck and our shoulder
and we turn our head to our right.
This center is spoiled when we feel guilty
and as a result we get horrible diseases like angina.
So please don’t feel guilty!
Then we take our right hand on our forehead across,
forehead across like this, and put down your head,
as far as possible.
Why don’t you do it? Please.
This is the center where you have to forgive everyone.
Now please take back your right hand on the back side of your head
and push back your head.
This is the center where - without feeling guilty,
without counting your mistakes -
you have to ask for forgiveness from the all-pervading divine power.
Now stretch your palm fully
and put the center of your palm on top of your head
and now press it hard.
Push back your fingers and put down your head.
Now move your scalp slowly seven times – scalp!
That’s all we have to do.
But there are three conditions.
The first one is
that you have to be absolutely self-confident about yourself
that you will get your Self-Realization.
Whether you have come late or earlier, makes no difference.
The second one is to forget your past at this point,
you have to be in the present
so that you do not feel guilty.
After all you are a human being, you are not God.
If you have done any mistakes – it’s all right.
This Divine power is the ocean of forgiveness.
And whatever mistakes you commited,
it can be dissolved by the power.
That means you should be pleasantly placed towards yourself
and you should have respect for yourself
because you are a human being,
because you are the epitome of evolution.
Only thing, the last breakthrough has to take place.
So don’t feel guilty at all at this moment.
The third condition is that you have to forgive everyone in general.
As I told you yesterday, wether
you forgive or don’t forgive - you don’t do anything.
That is just mental.
And if you do not forgive others,
you play into wrong hands unnecessarily.
And you torture yourself
while the one who has troubled you is very happy.
Just say, “I forgive everyone in general”
and you’ll feel immediately lighter in you head.
These are the only three conditions.
Now please close your eyes
and please do not open them till I tell you.
So put the right hand on your heart
and left hand towards Me like this
and both the feet apart from each other.
Now, here is the center of your Spirit.
Please close your eyes and ask Me a fundamental question,
you can call Me Mother or Shri Mataji, whatever you like,
Here you ask Me a fundamental question three times in your heart,
"“Mother, am I the Spirit?”
If you are the Spirit you are your guide.
So now please take your hand
on the upper portion of your abdomen on the left-hand side
and press it hard.
Here you have to ask another question to Me,
“Mother, am I my own master?”
Three times.
I’ve already told you that I respect your freedom
And I cannot force pure knowledge on you,
which does all the Divine work.
So please put your right hand
in the lower portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
And here you have to ask six times,
“Mother, please give me pure knowledge.”
Six times.
As soon as you ask for pure knowledge
the Kundalini starts moving upward,
so we have to nourish the upper centers
with our full self-confidence.
So now please raise your right hand
in the upper portion of your abdomen on the left-hand side
and here, with full confidence, say ten times,
“Mother, I am my own master!”
I’ve already told you that you are the pure Spirit.
You are not this body, you are not this mind,
you are not this ego, this conditioning,
but you are the pure Spirit.
So now please raise your right hand on your heart.
Here you have to say
with full confidence in yourself twelve times,
“Mother, I am the Spirit!”
This all-pervading power is the ocean of love and compassion,
it is the ocean of absolute knowledge,
but above all it is the ocean of forgiveness.
So whatever mistake you might have committed,
it can easily dissolve all of it.
So now, here you raise your right hand
in the corner of your neck and your shoulder
and turn your head to your right.
And here you have to say with full confidence sixteen times,
“Mother, I am not guilty at all!”
I’ve already told you whether you forgive or don’t forgive,
you don’t do anything.
This center is so constricted
that, please, you have to forgive everyone in general.
If you don’t forgive you may not get your Realization.
So now please, raise your right hand on your forehead across
and put down your head fully.
Here you have to say with full confidence
you have to just say, don’t say it is difficult,
“Mother, I forgive everyone!”
You have to say it from your heart, not how many times.
Now take back your right hand on the backside of your head
and push back your head as far as possible.
Here you have to say,
without feeling guilty,
without counting mistakes, just for your satisfaction,
“Mother, if I have done any mistakes, or all-pervading power,
if I have done any mistakes, please forgive me.”
“All-pervading power,” you should say.
Now please stretch your hand, stretch your palm,
and put the center of your palm
just on top of the fontanel bone area,
and put down your head and press it hard by pushing out your fingers.
Here again I cannot cross over your freedom,
so you have to ask for your Self-Realization.
Now please put down your head,
push back your fingers nicely,
and move your scalp seven times slowly, saying,
“Mother, please give me my Self-Realization.”
Please put down your head, please put down your head,
If you don’t bend, it won’t work out.
Please move your scalp seven times,
saying, “Mother, please give me Self-Realization.” (Shri Mataji bläst ins Mikro).
Please take down your hands, please open your eyes.
Now please put both your hands like this.
Now bend your head and see for yourself,
if there is a Cool Breeze coming out of your head or hot breeze,
if you have not forgiven it will be hot breeze.
But please don’t put your hand on top of your head,
little away and see for yourself.
Now please put your left hand and see for yourself
with your right hand.
If it is hot air that means you have to forgive.
Now put the right hand again please
and see with the left hand.
Now put both your hands towards the sky
and ask anyone of these questions,
“Mother, is this the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost?
Mother, is this the All-pervading power of God’s Love?
Mother, is this the Paramchaitanya?”
Anyone of these you can ask three times – questions.
Now please take down your hands.
Put your hands like this towards Me.
Watch Me without thinking.
All those who have felt cool or hot breeze
out of their head or on their hands or fingertips,
please raise both your hands.
I bow to all of you, you’re the saints.
I know some people did not feel it,
very few,
doesn’t matter.
Those who want to meet Me are welcome,
but the Sahaja Yogis should not come.
Those who have not felt should come on this side
and sahaja yogis will work on them.