[Music]
so now the other Center which we have
here is very important center call as
the vishuddhi chakra this is the center
we shoot them
one is shoot them in spoon but we should
the means absolutely pure this has got
60 patterns as we have got the cervical
plexus expressed the gross which has
also got sixteen sub-plexuses
it tallies with medical science
completely now let us see how is
vishuddhi chakra maintains all the
baubles that he used governorship
teacher and like in Devanagari language
duties ah
[Music]
aha so as you know that you cannot come
by the word without a moment it's so
important the consonant is weak without
near but without any stay without the
wall so the strength of a person comes
through the vishuddhi chakra in his
speech it's the center what we call here
is the vishuddhi chakra is the center
where human beings raise their head up
this is the center that has made us a
human being and from this Center only
Rises the ego and superego because this
is the center of collectivity because we
speak through the center we talk through
this we have rapport with other people
through this and as a reaction to that
ego and superego is built within us when
that is built within us we become a
personality I am some he is some you are
some at that point
we become a person who has the
consciousness of ilus like then I say I
like this I want this say I will say I
am an Indian you will say I'm an
Englishman all these misidentifications
start because you become an individual
who tries to identify with many things
that's how we become separated from that
power this is the freedom we get where
we have to ourself learn from our errors
and trials what is right and what is
wrong this vishuddhi chakra is has got
sixteen petals and looks after our ear
nose eyes throat everything our face
everything is looked after by descent
now this Center also has left and right
all centers have left and
and when you feel guilty the left Center
gadgets which is a very dangerous thing
because this gives you diseases like
angina or maybe diseases like
spondylitis
and lethargic organs right when a person
is very aggressive talks very
aggressively and tries to dominate
others and use his power of speech to
show off the right side catches the the
reactions of this can be many that the
hand gets frozen and they also get the
cancer of the throat all kinds of things
can happen with this chakra being in
Japan
[Music]
now a person who shouts and screams and
talks loudly and loses is tempered in a
very loud voice or who speaks very
loudly all the time they all suffer from
the right wishes so one should
understand that even when you have to
score somebody you have to just say what
are you doing why are you doing like
this
otherwise why oh it's finished I'd push
it over finished now this is the things
on the right side if you are talking
loudly if you talk too much
if you intimidate people with your
talking then you catch on right
vishuddhi so for that best is to take
some rest and give some rest - you're
right we should be by stopping your talk
go into mana they said just don't talk
for some time if you don't have you'll
see that where we should be will be
improved your problems will be in - so
what is the divine diplomacy you don't
have to shout but you change the subject
if you want to bring somebody to a some
conclusion the best thing is first you
change the subject and gradually if you
are clever enough then you go on
changing changing and you bring it back
to the right thing that's the clever
thing to do
what is the essence of this diplomacy
its benevolence you have to achieve the
benevolence of the whole humanity this
is the essence of it if you are doing it
you are not doing for yourself for your
game you are not doing for the gain of
any particular person but you are doing
it for the benefits of the whole
humanity so once you know this is the
essence so what is the need to shout by
shouting you are not going to achieve
anything so to play around with it and
bring it to that point which is
benevolence so our right we should be we
have to have a temperament a culture a
style a behavior which has got the
quality which is called as midoriya
means melodious melodious you should
talk in such a manner that it should be
melodious the voice of a sahaja yogi
should be sweet like that when you talk
to someone it should be melodies
it should not be aggressive at all but
on the contrary it should be melodious
it should not be sarcastic it should not
hurt another person any word that hurts
others cannot be coming from the proper
type of rightfully so in no way one
should hurt the another quality which we
can express through our right we should
ease diplomacy but there are two types
of diplomacy's one is genuine one is
artificial in the genuine diplomacy you
do not have to take to a certain
standard or you don't have to read some
books
to know how it is diplomacy is it
genuinely it comes to you it the whole
thing works very sweetly in such a
genuine manner I have used it many a
times myself and you all can use it also
many a time that's only possible if you
don't get angry with not possible if you
are
[Music]
relationship between brothers and
sisters have to be established a very
pure brothers and sisters relationship
is without any lust or greed it's pure
relationship where the sister prays for
the protection of the brother and
brother play pray praise for the
self-sufficiency
now the Chima will be of the system so
this time you have to think of your
other sahaja Yogi's and sahaja Yogi's
who are like your brothers and sisters
you have to think like that purify your
hearts something funny in this countries
you know that there's no such
relationship bases purify your mind
today
on that point that everybody else is my
brother or sister if you have married
but look at everyone try to look at
everyone as a brother and a sister when
the sister who is your pure relation is
not treated as a sister when the
attitude of a person towards women is of
indulgence and of lust then he develops
the left with you when he develops her
left we should be very strongly and if
he has a bad Agia or affairs eyes which
are roving eyes then this left vishuddhi
causes a lot of trouble left vishuddhi
cannot be also caused by as you know by
feeling guilty about things for nothing
at all all these problems arise from
issues
the left side Center is what up when a
person feels guilty and obstruct the
scent of the Kundalini that's why I
always request all the Western seekers
first to say in their hearts mother I am
NOT GUILTY these are the conditionings
that have come to us from so-called
religions
from so-called psychologists and other
people who are responsible for our
development in our childhood when
material things very important for the
parents they all the time shout at
children or correct them saying that
don't spoil the carpet don't spoil that
don't spoil that
and that is how we develop a kind of a
guilt within us when we grow up in the
schools and colleges this can be built
up very heavily within us - so how much
important it is to understand the value
of left which all of us catch on left
which is D and we do not think that it
is such an important thing where is your
left Rashida catching means I am feeling
guilty we do not understand that what
have I done I have crossed the limits
that's why he's showing there I have
neglected some kind of a morality I have
gone on a wrong path against mother and
father that's why I left we should be
sketching left switch we should be is
the indication of the mistakes of the
wrongs of the sins we can't afford to
have left to shooting sahaja Yogi's
cannot afford to have left now what I
have seen that when this negativity
starts acting people instead of facing
it facing the mistakes that I am wrong I
should not have done it it's a wrong
thing to do start giving explanations
once you start giving explanation this
left vishudhi starts becoming like a
bloated big lump and then there's no
possibility of curing no possibility of
cleansing so people start giving
explanation why I did it why I do this
once it is said it's wrong is wrong to
be accepted all right next time I'm not
going to do it I'm very sorry
[Music]
[Applause]
you