[Music]
so with the with the permission of Shri
Mataji we are now going to read 51
stanzas in the praise of our divine
madam and you are all invited to say
salutations to you again and again after
each stanza you are the one primordial
being the source of creations salute you
are the mother of the three more teas
and their respective Shakti's you are
the mistress of mani dripper the island
of the adi shakti you are the Bharata
the universal body of God in which all
possible planes of existence are
manifest and interacting you are the
macrocosmic household of creation and
you are the primordial mother who rules
over it with complete control everything
originates from you when you breathe out
and everything returns to you when you
breathe in your divine attention
vibrates as waves through the universes
and carries all information and
knowledge your nirananda fields creation
with marvellous beauty and manifests as
a silent promise your motherly love
pulsates through the rivers of existence
moving gently with the rhythm of Lord
Shiva's damaru you console comfort and
redeem the endless stream of souls
evolving in the cool flame of your
desire from your most worshipful feet
flow endless rivers of Chaitanya
generously penetrating every atom with
divinity with your soft skinned hands
you command the flow of Chaitanya as
well as armies of heavenly beings from
your beautiful deep eyes flows majestic
grace coronating the object of sight
with value and meaning your smile is a
rainbow of assurance and comfort it
splendid colors are expressions of a
love and kindness beyond human
description
the many expressions of your perfect
face are conducting the playful dance of
the five elements your words are always
in tune with the reality of the moment
they are flowing from you as
manifestations of truth and love and
thus composed endless Bhagavad Gita's
each of which is charged with the power
not only of most precious information
but of immediate subtle effect on the
listener calling someone by his name
sends waves of joy through his being and
accommodates his Restless heart with
motherly comfort putting your most
benevolent attention on someone however
far away will bestow bliss on him and
will fill his longing cups with living
waters having dreamt of you during the
night will transform the day into a
sunset walk through the gardens of Eden
hand-in-hand with the image of my
heavenly mother your darshan whether
physical subtle or in a dream is never
without result and blessing it is always
transforming and joyful in a yogi you
are the desire of liberation you are the
instrument of liberation and you are
liberation itself
you are the highest object of meditation
as you represent everything a yogi can
achieve you reside within us as the
ultimate personality of truth being
existence which reveals itself to us
once we release all false concepts and
identifications you reside within us as
the mistress of sahasrara who will make
us into universal beings once you have
granted us permanent citizenship in your
kingdom concentrating on you cleanses
the chakras of the yogi purifies his
desire and enlightens his attention
meditating upon you causes the Kundalini
to rise the cool vibrations to flow and
the awareness to become collective at
the level of sahasrara singing your
praise and offering pooja to your lotus
feet is answered with rivers of
chaitanya in which we get purified and
elated to the state of sat-chit-ananda
when we make the endless silence of
sahasrara resound with your three great
mantras you shower upon us heavenly
nectar from your horn of plenty filling
us with ecstatic well-being
identifying with you will grant
self-realization as you are the Atma as
well as God realization as you are the
param atma dissolving into your being
will grant eternal life in the gardens
of Devi Luca in the company of gods and
goddesses with your presence you can
give self-realization to one person to
fifty thousand or to the whole world
alike
you give self-realization to human
beings by embracing them into your
universal being which is one ocean of
Chaitanya you develop and manifest
self-realization in the sahaja Yogi's by
processing them as cells in your
universal body which is like a Lingam of
cool fire without beginning nor end
ultimately you grant the Yogi's a place
in us sahasrara where you allow them
access to the continuous flow of
heavenly nectar it is because we are
cells in your universal body that we
feel the instant flow of vibrations once
we focus our attention on you it is
because we are cells in your universal
body that we feel vibrations when we are
with other sahaja Yogi's our spiritual
growth is in your hands as we ourselves
in your universal body we can only
evolve collectively within the maryadas
of your divine being we integrate in you
a universal being the parabrahma
through surrender and recognizing your
omnipotent nature taking us into your
universal being is an act of a love and
compassion sacrifice until so total
self-denial as you have opened the doors
to everyone without distinction
of all gods and goddesses it is only the
primordial mother who has the powers to
master this monumental task of
collective Redemption and enlightenment
which has nothing equal in the history
of man being that you are the avatar of
sahasrara chakra
you are the first divine incarnation
addressing the whole world beyond
nationality race and language you are
the Guru of the global village residing
at the top of the Tower of Babel
liberating mankind from the curse of
distinction and creating an integrated
global body of men you are using and
controlling the scientific achievements
of modern days to establish and spread
your worldwide presence
you are the first and only female avatar
and you have established your Universal
living religion single-handed all over
the world in the worst of all UGA's the
story of Nirmala born in chin vara on
March 21st in 1923 is the story of
godmother having incarnated on this
earth for the purpose of completing the
greatest task a single human being has
ever undertaken
you have conquered the whole world with
your power of love and you have
transformed the lives of hundreds of
thousands with your compassion and
kindness no avatar before you has had a
comparable impact on the spiritual
awareness of mankind being that you are
the only incarnation who has delivered
the complete system of knowledge
instrument and technique and the power
to awaken it to a living integrated
process of spiritual transformation it
is your negativity destroying presence
on this planet that ends the Kali Yuga
because you awaken man from his slumber
of sinful ignorance and false knowledge
it is your auspicious presence on this
planet that is the krita yuga because
your most powerful innocence tears up
the collective unconscious and brings
all impurity to the surface
it is your divine presence on this
planet that heralds the Satya Yuga
because you have given birth to a new
man who lives in unity with God nature
and his fellow brothers and sisters it
is your name shri mataji nirmala devi
that will shine like a million suns on
the future of mankind sakshat shri adi
shakti mataji shri nirmala devi
[Music]