[MUSIC - BHAJAN]
- I bow to all the seekers of Truth.
- [INTERPRETER]
At the very outset we have to know
that Truth is what it is.
[INTERPRETER]
- We cannot change it.
- [INTERPRETER]
- It is, it has been and it will be.
- Whatever I'm going to tell you,
- [INTERPRETER]
- you have to have a scientific mind towards it.
- Keep your mind open.
- [INTERPRETER]
and whatever I say to you, if it is proved,
then you have to believe in it as honest people.
[INTERPRETER]
The Truth is, that you are not this body,
this mind, these conditionings and this ego
[INTERPRETER]
- but you are the Pure Spirit.
- [INTERPRETER]
- This is said by all the great prophets,
- by Incarnations,
- [INTERPRETER]
- by Muhammad Sahab as well as our Christ,
- as well as by Moses
- [INTERPRETER]
- also all Indian scriptures say the same.
The second Truth is, that there is a
All-Pervading Divine Power
[INTERPRETER]
and this Divine Power does
all the living work.
[INTERPRETER]
- You see all the beautiful flowers here
- [INTERPRETER]
- it's a miracle.
- They have come out of one seed
- [INTERPRETER]
- Our heart - who runs our heart?
We don't even bother to know
who runs our heart.
[INTERPRETER]
This All-Pervading Power of Divine Love,
runs our heart.
[INTERPRETER]
- It's like the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost
- [INTERPRETER]
- or it is the Paramchaitanya
- or it is the Rooh
- It's what?
- Rooh, in Koran
- [INTERPRETER]
- It is described by many names.
Those who are seekers of Truth, are
actually seeking the connection with this
- All-Pervading Power.
- [INTERPRETER]
This connection is called as Yoga
- the real Spiritual Yoga.
[INTERPRETER]
- It is not standing on your head
- [INTERPRETER]
- or stretching your legs
- that it is a yoga
- [INTERPRETER]
Even the taking the name of God, of
praying to God, is not manifested unless
and until you have the connection with
this All-Pervading Power of Divine Love.
[INTERPRETER]
- As this instrument
- [INTERPRETER]
- when not connected with the mains,
- it has no meaning,
- [INTERPRETER]
- it has no identity.
- In the same way, we the human-beings,
- [INTERPRETER]
- if we are not connected,
- to the All-Pervading Divine Power,
- [INTERPRETER]
- we have no meaning.
- We cannot have Self-Knowledge,
- [INTERPRETER]
- we cannot have the Enlightenment
- and we cannot know the Absolute Truth.
- [INTERPRETER]
- Most of the human problems
- are created problems of the world
- [INTERPRETER]
and most of the human problems come to us
from these centers when they go into jeopardy.
[INTERPRETER]
- All these subtle centers are within us.
- [INTERPRETER]
In the Bible it is mentioned that, "I'll
appear before you like tongues of flames."
[INTERPRETER]
In every scripture it is described
the life, the Tree of Life.
[INTERPRETER]
but nobody has tried to find
out what is this.
[INTERPRETER]
The civilization, in the West,
has grown very much
[INTERPRETER]
- but it has to find out it's roots
- [INTERPRETER]
- roots of Spirituality
otherwise this whole big civilization
will be completely dissolved.
[INTERPRETER]
As it is, you can see what's happening in
the most developed countries like America
[INTERPRETER]
Thousands and thousands of people
are suffering from AIDS,
[INTERPRETER]
- they are suffering from schizophrenia
- [INTERPRETER]
- and the violence is at it's worst.
- You can't even wear a wedding ring
- [INTERPRETER]
- and walk in the streets of New York
- Such greed and such lust!
- [INTERPRETER]
- No morality of any kind
It's not only there but you
see it all over your world.
[INTERPRETER]
At all developing countries, who have
taken to this modern life, like Argentina
- also are in the same [UNCLEAR]
- [INTERPRETER]
- but once we find our roots,
- once we find our identity,
- [INTERPRETER]
- you understand how great you are.
- You understand why you were created,
- [INTERPRETER]
- what is the purpose of your life,
- what is the goal of your life;
- [INTERPRETER]
Is only possible when you have
your second birth.
[INTERPRETER]
- Many people brand them as twice born
- [INTERPRETER]
- Sorry, once more.
- as twice born - born twice
- [INTERPRETER]
- but they are not - but they are not at all.
- Those, who call themselves as Muslims
- and Christians and Hindus, are not
- [INTERPRETER]
If they were real Christians, they would
not have taken to this immoral life
[INTERPRETER]
- How could such immoral life exist then
- [INTERPRETER]
- in the name of Christ!
Who said, "Thou shalt not have
adulterous eyes!"
[INTERPRETER]
- What subtle morality! What deep morality!
- [INTERPRETER]
- That's only possible if you are enlightened
- When the light comes within you,
- [INTERPRETER]
- immediately you give up
- whatever is destructive,
- [INTERPRETER]
- whatever is destructive within you
and also you see what is outside
is destructive
[INTERPRETER]
- Once you get your enlightenment,
- [INTERPRETER]
you can feel this All-Pervading Power, for
the first time, on your finger-tips
[INTERPRETER]
You see also the cool breeze coming out of
your fontanel bone area, which was a soft bone
[INTERPRETER]
- Is the actualization of your baptism
- [INTERPRETER]
Then you start using this power and you
can give realizations to others.
[INTERPRETER]
As a result of this, you get physical,
mental, emotional, spiritual problems solved.
[INTERPRETER]
I don't have to tell you, don't do this,
don't do that, don't do that.
[INTERPRETER]
With the light of the Spirit you yourself
become your own guide, your own master,
- your own guru.
- [INTERPRETER]
You become extremely dynamic but
extremely compassionate.
[INTERPRETER]
You can feel your own centers
on your finger-tips.
[INTERPRETER]
Then you see all religions belong
to the same tree of life.
[INTERPRETER]
- All beautiful flowers
- [INTERPRETER]
- of Divinity
but people have taken out these flowers
and now fighting with the dead flowers.
[INTERPRETER]
And all these religions are one;
They have the same business
[INTERPRETER]
There is no need at all to fight
in the name of God.
[INTERPRETER]
This you can know as a scientific
proof after realization.
[INTERPRETER]
You can feel on your finger-tips
the centers of others.
[INTERPRETER]
Now if you know how to correct them, you can
correct your centers as well as the of others.
[INTERPRETER]
- You develop a peaceful heart
- [INTERPRETER]
- and tremendous compassion.
You realize then how great your are -
all your virtues start manifesting.
[INTERPRETER]
- It is your own power -
- [INTERPRETER]
- it's your own.
- You all have it within you
- [INTERPRETER]
- and you don't have to pay for it
- God doesn't understand banks.
- [INTERPRETER]
- He doesn't understand money.
- It's a human [UNCLEAR]
- [INTERPRETER]
By reading about it, you do not
get to that point
[INTERPRETER]
- You have to seek and you will find.
- [INTERPRETER]
- I call it a blossom time
Time when there are so many
great souls are born.
[INTERPRETER]
- This is the fulfillment of the last judgment
- [INTERPRETER]
The dead bodies are not going
to come to life.
[INTERPRETER]
I mean to say, all the prehistoric people
and the dinosaurs all of them
- are going to come to life?
- [INTERPRETER]
But all those, who were dead,
their souls will take birth
[INTERPRETER]
- as human beings.
- [INTERPRETER]
- That's why we have a population problem
So many great souls, we have
seen, born as children.
[INTERPRETER]
I've seen children at the age of 6 and 10,
can play on violin or on piano like a master.
[INTERPRETER]
In India I've seen children below 10 years,
singing the Indian music, which is very difficult,
- like great masters of old times.
- [INTERPRETER]
[INTERPRETER]
Today only, I saw in the television, in
France there were children - very small children
- playing on the violin
- [INTERPRETER]
- in such a, in such a mastery.
So these are the times, when all these
great people are going to be born.
[INTERPRETER]
There are some people, who are frightening
to say that, this world is going to come
- to an end.
- [INTERPRETER]
- Don't believe that.
- The One, who is our Creator,
- [INTERPRETER]
- is our Father,
- is the Supreme Being of compassion.
- [INTERPRETER]
He has not created this world
to be destroyed
[INTERPRETER]
but He has made places, for all of you,
in the Kingdom of God.
[INTERPRETER]
Don't be eluded by people - some of them
are coming even from India and trying
- to put conditionings in your heads.
- [INTERPRETER]
The other day, I met somebody
from this Hare Rama business.
[INTERPRETER]
- They are absolutely stupid, idiotic people.
- [INTERPRETER]
If you have to call the name of your
Prime Minister here, near his house,
- you'll be arrested
- [INTERPRETER]
and you are calling the name of God
without any protocol, without any
- permission, without any connection.
- [INTERPRETER]
- You might only get cancer of throat.
- I don't know what other punishments.
- [INTERPRETER]
I must say, Russians were very clever.
They said, "We had no food Mother,
so we had nice food from them and now
they have gone away permanently.
- Mother, [UNCLEAR]
- I said that Russians were very clever
and they said that, "These people had
brought food so we ate the food nicely and
now they have gone away completely." They
have completely gone from Russia.
- Did you follow?
- No
The Russians was very clever because
this [UNCLEAR]
Ah! [INTERPRETER]
- I think, the IQ of Russian is very high
- Eh...
- IQ.
- Shri Mataji [INTERPRETER]
They said, "Mother, we could make
out they are idiotic, stupid things
- they were telling us."
- Shri Mataji [INTERPRETER]
In you, Sahaja yoga is not meant
for stupid, idiotic people.
- [INTERPRETER]
- So, one has to understand and think,
- we talk of God
- [INTERPRETER]
and why all these horrible things are
happening in the name of God.
[INTERPRETER]
- What's gone wrong?
- [INTERPRETER]
The mistake is, that we are not
yet connected.
- [INTERPRETER]
- This is what we have to achieve the connection
- which is sahaja - means spontaneous.
- [INTERPRETER]
- Sahaja - 'Saha' means with, 'ja' is born
- What's the matter with this gentleman?
- [INTERPRETER]
- you see, you are little bit disturbing
because they all start watching him.
Please make yourself comfortable.
[INTERPRETER] He's
[UNCLEAR] Mother.
But he's going round, putting up, everybody
looking at him; You see, the [UNCLEAR]
- Alright! I don't know how to tell you
- [INTERPRETER]
How the time has come for you to
specially, to achieve this state
[INTERPRETER]
- through your evolutionary process,
- [INTERPRETER]
through this awakening of this Kundalini,
the power in your triangular bone.
[INTERPRETER]
- This bone is called as Sacrum
- [INTERPRETER]
- that means, the Greeks knew it is a sacred bone.
- Athena, itself, means Primordial Mother
- [INTERPRETER]
- so, Greeks believed in all that.
- and now there's a big upsurge in Greece also
- [INTERPRETER]
- to take to their ancient knowledge
- because they're so restless, so frustrated
- [INTERPRETER]
So, time has come for you all also
to have your Self-realization.
[INTERPRETER]
- Of course, I cannot force it on you
- [INTERPRETER]
- I respect your freedom
- Those, who want to have it, can have it
- [INTERPRETER]
- but you must have a very ardent desire
Those, who do not want to have, please
leave the hall - we'll be very happy.
[INTERPRETER]
- This person, Hare Rama fellow
- but he'll sit down
[INTERPRETER]
- It's very critical to make them understand
- [INTERPRETER]
Such conditioning people have that
it's impossible to break free.
[INTERPRETER]
Only people, who are really introspective,
were Russians.
[INTERPRETER]
We always had programs in a big,
what you call, auditoriums or places
where there were 16,000 people.
[INTERPRETER]
They're so well read and they
know so much about it
[INTERPRETER]
- and they're so introspective
- [INTERPRETER]
- It's very surprising
- and now we have in thousands in Russia
- [INTERPRETER]
- Also in Romania
- and Bulgaria
- [INTERPRETER]
- Czechoslovakia but Poland somehow is not
- I don't know, what is the conditioning
- [INTERPRETER]
- Why?
- So, I know you all have lots of questions
- [INTERPRETER]
I would like you to write it down
and send it over to Me
[INTERPRETER]
- and I'll try to answer them.
- [INTERPRETER]
But just now, I think, you all should
get your realization.
- [INTERPRETER]
You see, it is such an ocean of knowledge
that in this short time I cannot
- tell you everything.
- [INTERPRETER]
You have to understand that these lights that
are here have been brought long time back
[INTERPRETER]
and to explain to you about all these lights
and how electricity came, is such a headache.
[INTERPRETER]
- It's all built-in now
- [INTERPRETER]
- You have to just put one switch and they are on
You don't have to tell them all the
history of electricity
[INTERPRETER]
-So, it's a headache also
- [INTERPRETER]
If you have your light because it is built-in
within you - the system is built-in within you
- [INTERPRETER]
- It's all there
- so better to have your enlightenment
- [INTERPRETER]
- and then talk about the rest of it
- You can come here - there's some room
- [INTERPRETER]
- So, everybody should be seated down
Now ask him to take away the film because
we're going to meditate and it might disturb.
[INTERPRETER]
Some one should go and tell.
Better to go there.
- [INTERPRETER]
- He won't disturb you.
If he's seated, it's alright. [UNCLEAR]
he'll be a point disturbing people.
[INTERPRETER]
Ask him to go out. I think,
he's finished - if you don't mind.
[INTERPRETER]
- Thank you.
- [INTERPRETER]
Very obedient!
- It will hardly take 10 to 15 minutes
- [INTERPRETER]
- just to enter into the Kingdom of God
- which is the ocean of joy.
- [INTERPRETER]
We come out of, like a pond into,
blossoming into a beautiful lotuses
[INTERPRETER]
- because you are that.
- [INTERPRETER]
- So, we have three conditions
- Want to sit down, come along - don't stand
- [INTERPRETER]
- in the door;
There is room for you here, if you want.
- Please be seated.
- [INTERPRETER]
- The first condition
is that you should have full
confidence in yourself.
[INTERPRETER]
You must have full faith that today, tonight
you are going to get your Self-realization.
[INTERPRETER]
- In no way you should feel tempted
- [INTERPRETER]
- The second condition is
- that you are not to feel guilty about anything.
- [INTERPRETER]
Like yesterday, somebody told Me that, "Mother,
I have harmed somebody, so I'm feeling guilty."
[INTERPRETER]
- What is the use?
- [INTERPRETER]
If you have harmed somebody,
then go and tell that person.
[INTERPRETER]
- and tell to yourself,
- [INTERPRETER]
- face your mistakes
but if you feel guilty, then the guilt
goes here in the left side of your center.
[INTERPRETER]
- and you develop horrible diseases like angina,
- [INTERPRETER]
- spondylitis,
- also lethargy problems
- [INTERPRETER]
- So, no use feeling guilty
- It's like avoiding the reality.
- [INTERPRETER]
- At least at this time, please, forget your past.
- Your past doesn't exist
- [INTERPRETER]
- it's finished
- and your future also doesn't exist
- [INTERPRETER]
- The reality is in the present
That's what will happen to you that
you will come into present.
[INTERPRETER]
We are all the time thinking
about the past or the future.
[INTERPRETER]
- Jumping from past to future, future to past
- [INTERPRETER]
- These thoughts come in
but in between these thoughts there's a
little, little space for the present.
[INTERPRETER]
which increases in size and you
become thoughtlessly aware.
[INTERPRETER]
You are absolutely aware but it's no
thought - complete peace
[INTERPRETER]
The second, I told you, that you become
Collectively Conscious because you can feel
- the centers of others.
- [INTERPRETER]
- So, the microcosm becomes the macrocosm.
- Micra is better to tell
- [INTERPRETER]
- Alright.
- We become part and parcel of the Whole
- [INTERPRETER]
- A drop becomes the ocean
Sahaja yoga is working in 55 nations and you will
have brothers and sisters in all these 55 nations.
[INTERPRETER]
- So please, don't feel guilty
- [INTERPRETER]
Those who tell you, you are sinners
and all that - forget them.
[INTERPRETER]
- Those who condemn you, forgive them.
- [INTERPRETER]
- I'll tell you, you are not guilty.
- Absolutely, no question.
- [INTERPRETER]
And the third condition is,
that you have to forgive
[INTERPRETER]
- Forgive everyone.
- [INTERPRETER]
Whether you forgive or don't forgive,
you don't do anything
[INTERPRETER]
- but if you don't forgive
- [INTERPRETER]
- then you play into wrong hands.
- You torture yourself
- [INTERPRETER]
while the person, who has harmed you,
is first class.
[INTERPRETER]
- So, it's a myth not to forgive.
- [INTERPRETER]
But you don't think about the people whom
you have to forgive; Just forgive in general.
[INTERPRETER]
- Some people say it is difficult
- [INTERPRETER]
but it's a myth. What is difficult? Just
to say, "I forgive everyone," finished.
[INTERPRETER]
You don't have to take out
something from your heart
[INTERPRETER]
- You just have to say
- [INTERPRETER]
- These are the three conditions.
- First is of complete confidence in yourself
- [INTERPRETER]
- second one is not to feel guilty
and the third one is to forgive
everyone, in general.
[INTERPRETER]
Now, first we'll tell you how we will
be nourishing our centers.
[INTERPRETER]
As it is, there are, as you know, they
must have told you that the left and right
- are two sides.
- [INTERPRETER]
Left side is for the power of desire,
the right side for the power of action.
[INTERPRETER]
So now please put your left hand towards
Me. You have to take out your shoes first.
- [INTERPRETER]
- because the Mother Earth helps us a lot.
[INTERPRETER]
[UNCLEAR] For those who are sitting on
the ground, it's all right but those
who are sitting on the chair, they have to
put their left leg on one side - right
- with a little distance between the two.
- [INTERPRETER]
Now please, put your left hand towards
Me, on your lap.
[INTERPRETER]
- Be comfortable, first of all.
- [INTERPRETER]
- You shouldn't give a strain
- nor you should not bend also
- [INTERPRETER]
Don't have to go to Himalayas, stand
on your heads - nothing.
[INTERPRETER]
- Now, please put your left hand towards Me
- [INTERPRETER]
This is symbolic that you want to
have your Self-realization - desire.
[INTERPRETER]
Then, you have to use the right hand
for nourishing your centers.
[INTERPRETER]
- So, first you put your right hand on your heart
- [INTERPRETER]
- In the heart resides the Spirit
Now, if you become the spirit, you
become your own guide, your own master.
[INTERPRETER]
So, please take your right hand in the upper
portion of your abdomen on the left hand side
- which is the center of your mastery.
- [INTERPRETER]
This mastery comes to you through
pure, Divine knowledge.
[INTERPRETER]
- But I cannot force it on you
- [INTERPRETER]
The center for that is the lower portion
of your abdomen on the left hand side.
[INTERPRETER]
Now, raise your right hand again on
your abdomen on the left hand side
[INTERPRETER]
- We're working only on the left hand side
- [INTERPRETER]
- Now we raise our right hand on our heart
Then we put our right hand on the corner
of our neck and turn our head to the right
[INTERPRETER]
I've already told you, that by feeling
guilty this center goes out of order.
[INTERPRETER]
Then you take your right hand on your forehead
across and bend your head as far as possible.
[INTERPRETER]
Here you have to ask, you have to
forgive everyone in general.
[INTERPRETER]
Now, for your own satisfaction, without
feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes,
you have to ask forgiveness
from the Divine power.
[INTERPRETER]
So, please put your hand on the back side for
that - the center is here [UNCLEAR]
- [INTERPRETER]
- Just wait
The center is here for asking forgiveness,
so bend your head back
[INTERPRETER]
- Now, stretch your palm -
- [INTERPRETER]
- this is for the last center
Put the center of your palm on top
of the fontanel bone area
[INTERPRETER]
- which was a soft bone in your childhood
- [INTERPRETER]
- Now, please bend your head as far as possible
Now, is important is to press back your fingers,
so there is good pressure on your scalp.
[INTERPRETER]
Bend your heads, bend your heads,
push back your fingers, push back
- [INTERPRETER]
- Push back your fingers, push back.
[INTERPRETER]
- Now, move your scalp slowly
- [INTERPRETER]
Please move your scalp slowly,
seven times, clockwise
- [INTERPRETER]
- Slowly
- pressurize it
- [INTERPRETER]
- That's all you have to do
- These people are standing in the doorway
- [INTERPRETER]
- they can come in, if they want.
- What are they saying?
- [INTERPRETER]
Close the door, They're just close to the
door - I mean, funny people.
Alright. Now, please take out your
spectacles and you have to close your eyes
when I tell you. Please don't
open them till I tell you.
[INTERPRETER]
You don't have to say any mantra,
any prayer - nothing
[INTERPRETER]
Don't put concentrate - nothing, just
leave it alone, your attention.
[INTERPRETER]
- Now, please close your eyes
- [INTERPRETER]
- put both the feet apart
- and the left hand towards Me, on your lap
- [INTERPRETER]
- and put the right hand on the heart.
- Close the eyes. Don't open them.
- [INTERPRETER]
- Not very tight
- ordinary way.
- [INTERPRETER]
Now here, you have to ask Me a very
fundamental question about yourself.
- You can call Me Mother or Shri Mataji.
- [INTERPRETER]
Please ask three times, in your heart,
"Mother, am I the Spirit?"
[INTERPRETER]
Now I've told, you become the Spirit, you
become your own guide, your own guru.
[INTERPRETER]
So now, please take your right hand in the upper
portion of your abdomen on the left hand side
[INTERPRETER]
and ask a fundamental question about
yourself, "Mother, am I my own master?"
- three times.
- [INTERPRETER]
I've already told you that I respect your
freedom and I cannot force your
- Divine Knowledge upon you.
- [INTERPRETER]
- You have to ask for it
So now, take your right hand in the lower
portion of your abdomen
[INTERPRETER]
and here you have to ask, "Mother, please
give me Your Divine Knowledge."
Say it six times because this has,
this center has six petals.
[INTERPRETER]
As soon as you ask for Divine knowledge,
the Kundalini starts moving upward.
[INTERPRETER]
- You may not feel anything
- [INTERPRETER]
- but be happy; Nourish the higher centers
to allow the Kundalini to pass
through these centers.
[INTERPRETER]
So now, please try to raise your right
hand the upper portion of your abdomen
[INTERPRETER]
With full self-confidence you have to say
ten times, "Mother, I am my own master."
[INTERPRETER]
I've already told you the truth about you
is that, you are not this body, this mind,
these emotions, these conditionings and
this ego but you are the Pure Spirit.
[INTERPRETER]
So now, please raise your right hand
on your heart
[INTERPRETER]
and here you have to say, with full confidence,
twelve times, "Mother, I am the Pure Spirit."
[INTERPRETER]
Now, the All-Pervading Power of Divine
Love, is the ocean of knowledge,
[INTERPRETER]
- is the ocean of bliss and joy
- [INTERPRETER]
- but above all it is the ocean of forgiveness
- and whatever you may do
- [INTERPRETER]
whatever mistakes you may commit, can be easily
dissolved by this ocean of forgiveness.
[INTERPRETER]
- So please, forgive yourself
- [INTERPRETER]
Bring your hand like that, in the corner
of your neck and your shoulder
- and put your head to your right
- [INTERPRETER]
Here, you have to say, sixteen times,
"Mother, I am not guilty at all."
[INTERPRETER]
I've already told you, whether you forgive
or don't forgive, you do not do anything
[INTERPRETER]
but if you don't forgive, then
you play into wrong hands.
[INTERPRETER]
So, you have to forgive and forgive not
individually but in general.
[INTERPRETER]
So please, raise your right hand on top of
your forehead across and put down your head
- please put down your head
- [INTERPRETER]
and here you have to say it from your
heart, not how many times,
- "Mother I forgive everyone, in general."
- [INTERPRETER]
- This is very important
Now, please take your right hand on
the back side of your head
- [INTERPRETER]
- and push back your head, as far as possible
Here, without feeling guilty, without
counting your mistakes,
just for your satisfaction you have
to say it from your heart,
"O Divine Power, please forgive me,
if I have done anything wrong."
[INTERPRETER]
- [INTERPRETER]
- Push back, push back your head
- on the back side of your head
not the neck but head.
[INTERPRETER]
- Alright. Now the last center
- [INTERPRETER]
- you stretch your palm fully
- and put it on top of the fontanel bone area
- [INTERPRETER]
- which is a soft bone in your childhood.
- Now, please put down your head
- [INTERPRETER]
- and push back your fingers
- Please put down your heads, please put down
- [INTERPRETER]
- Push back your fingers
- Here again, I cannot force Self-realization on you
- [INTERPRETER]
- You have to ask for it
So, move your scalp, seven times, slowly,
clockwise, saying, "Mother, please give
me Self-realization,"- seven times.
[INTERPRETER]
[SHRI MATAJI BLOWS INTO THE MIC]
- Now please take down your hands
- [INTERPRETER]
Put both the hands towards Me
and open your eyes
[INTERPRETER]
- Both the hands towards Me
- [INTERPRETER]
and now, you put the right hand towards Me,
bend your head and see with your left hand,
if there's a cool or a hot breeze coming
out of your head; Bend your head
[INTERPRETER]
Please don't put the hand on top of
your head - away from it
[INTERPRETER]
- Now please put the left hand towards Me
- [INTERPRETER]
- Bend your head and see if there's a
- and see for your self
- [INTERPRETER]
- with your right hand,
- if there's a cool or a hot breeze coming
- [INTERPRETER]
- Now, again once, please put right hand towards Me
- bend your head as [UNCLEAR]
- [INTERPRETER]
- If you have not forgiven, it's a hot breeze
- Now, raise both your hands towards the sky
- [INTERPRETER]
- push back your head
and ask any one of these questions,
three times, anyone
[INTERPRETER]
"Mother, is this the cool breeze
of the Holy Ghost?"
[INTERPRETER]
or, "Mother, is this the All-Pervading
Divine Power of love?"
[INTERPRETER]
- or, "Is this the Paramchaitanya?"
- [INTERPRETER]
Ask any one of these questions,
three times, on your heart.
[INTERPRETER]
- Now, please take down your hands
- [INTERPRETER]
- Please put your hands towards Me
- Like this and don't think
- [INTERPRETER]
- You can do it
All those, who have felt the cool breeze
or a hot breeze on their finger-tips
or on their palms or through their fontanel
bone area, please raise both your hands.
[INTERPRETER]
- All of you have felt!
- [INTERPRETER]
for the first time; You didn't feel - didn't
feel? Put your hands like this, just now.
You didn't feel? Who didn't feel?
Now, let us see.
- [INTERPRETER]
- Alright, we'll see you later on. Alright?
- Just put it like this - good!
Now? Just see him what's the problem.
You are a sahaja yogi, right, just see
him; Anybody can see. Alright, in any case,
those who have not felt, can come this
side and they'll work it out for you.
[INTERPRETER]
- They would like to meet Me?
- [INTERPRETER]
- Come this side, this side
Take him out. All of you, who did not
get, will get now; Sit down. Let them sit.
Let them sit.
I never sign. Is it Russian? [UNCLEAR]
I don't sign, I never sign. Thank you.
Now the only thing is, it's not an individual
and you should not waste your Self-realization.
- Sit down
- [INTERPRETER]
All of you can sit here till you get
realization. Can I just [UNCLEAR]?
Sit down, in a line. Just sit down.
Just sit down
You are sahaja yogi? Then why are you
sitting here. Just give them realization.
Alright? Just ask [UNCLEAR CONVERSATION]
you are.
Alright?
Shri Mataji [UNCLEAR] in Sahaja yoga but
after the puja or after the meditation
she feels something or a strain in the
back and she's always worried. Show it.
Better now. Alright, you come tomorrow.
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
Over head
Tell her to come in the [UNCLEAR]
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
Sahaja yogini, why are you coming? Annh? What?
What's the matter? Tomorrow you are going to come
[SHRI MATAJI TREATS THE SEEKERS]
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
[UNCLEAR CONVERSATION]
Please, please, please
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
- I can [UNCLEAR] something
- What?
[UNCLEAR] but my left Vishuddhi [UNCLEAR]
- What we have to
- I put my hand [UNCLEAR]
- Did you feel the cool breeze [UNCLEAR]?
- [UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR CONVERSATION]
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
- You must take a bandhan
[SHRI MATAJI TALKS TO DIFFERENT SEEKERS]
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
[SHRI MATAJI TALKS TO DIFFERENT SEEKERS
AND TREATS THEM].
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
[SHRI MATAJI TALKS TO DIFFERENT SEEKERS
AND TREATS THEM].
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
[SHRI MATAJI TREATS VARIOUS SEEKERS]
[SHRI MATAJI TREATS THE SEEKERS]
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
[UNCLEAR CONVERSATION]
[SHRI MATAJI TREATS THE SEEKERS]
Turn around
Hold your breath
[SHRI MATAJI TREATS THE SEEKERS]
[UNCLEAR] times.
Press it hard
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
[SHRI MATAJI TREATS THE SEEKERS]
But he's saying that he's not doing
and he doesn't like [UNCLEAR]
[BHAJAN IN THE BACKGROUND]
[SHRI MATAJI TREATS THE SEEKERS]
[BHAJAN]