today we have assembled here
to a sheep say Ganesha
Shri Ganesha who is the lord of
innocence
he is the ocean of analysis and though
he is such a young little boy he can
fight the whole world he can destroy all
the negatory that's the sign of
innocence
there have been stories that children
who have fallen from very early tide
they are completely saved nothing about
their innocence it's such a powerful
thing that it doesn't harm anyone who is
not to be harmed it has all the wisdom
of the world all the understanding of
the world and anybody who tries to harm
the innocence the world the whole world
which has made me not have cared so much
for innocence might not have worshipped
innocence so much but they all stand
stand up against anybody who tries to
harm the innocence you can see in your
own lies around you anybody tries to
trouble children all of them whatever
they are whatever they are coming from
whatever may be their nationality they
all jump all jump to control and to
safeguard that Charlie what is it what
is it within us that makes us so very
conscious to protect the innocence
it's a really think great shame for us
when we find in this world that
innocence is under attack anything else
can be tolerated innocent people who
have done nothing wrong
those who have no malice who are living
like little children I should say if
they are attacked by you not that the
whole world reacts God but every one of
them cannot bear any innocent person or
innocent being being harmed we don't
realize that within us there is the
ocean of love and ocean of understanding
for children why why should it be why
should we feel like that especially for
children especially for innocence there
are people who are always attacking
innocent people in ascension there are
but
no one wants to support them no one
thinks that's proper to ill-treat
children and those who have done this
have to suffer they all suffer as a
reaction what is it within us that
creates that reaction that tremendous
reaction against innocence for example
if there is a regular war and if there
are people fighting in a regular war
they don't have much sympathy in the
world also they say all right we're of
that understanding they are of that kind
of thing the greatest sympathy comes
when innocent is being cherished that's
what human beings have within themselves
they have the power power of Shri
Ganesha nature gives you that feeling
that capacity that understanding that
you have to protect innocent innocent
children innocent people and the whole
world can rise against all such people
who are trying to kill the innocent
there cannot be any doubt if they cannot
oppose such an attack or criticize such
a thing then they are not yet human
beings I would say
the highest personality can sacrifice
anything and can give up anything but
they cannot give up the feeling they
have her innocence
it is very remarkable we don't realize
how much there is this ocean of
protection and love for the innocent
what attracts the greatest strength is
when we see an innocent person innocent
children are under attack that's the
beauty of human beings of course there
are many human beings who can be cruel
who are I would say I call them devils
maybe maybe but when it comes to
children and to innocent people everyone
feels is a responsibility it's difficult
for normal human beings to be innocent
because they have kind of a
understanding that they are something
great
that they understand everything that
they can analyze everything and they
could be crooks they could be aggressive
they could be troublesome they could be
anything and they can give explanation
for that in math but still on the whole
they can never be respected and they can
never be honored for the thing that for
us the sahaja Yogi's the search culture
is to respect your innocence you might
feel a little bit cheated you might feel
a little bit dominated we might feel it
to be disgraced but sahaja Yogi's I have
to be innocent because with them lies
the power of Shri Ganesha they should
not feel dejected if they are being used
insulted tortured dominated for Allah
they should not try to destroy the
innocence of other people of anyone
automatically it will work will be
amazed that when innocence is charged
all the goodness of the world comes to
the rescue of that example of this is
the recent war so-called war of America
where innocent people they have done
nothing wrong
have been tortured have been killed at
that time all over the world is a big
support worthy every country whether it
believes in those people or not is
anxious to look after those who have
done this crime they may not be
belonging to the same religion they may
not be belonging to the same country
they may not be belonging to the same
crimes but at this moment who does not
take the side of the innocence will be
singled out and will be destroyed no
doubt about once for all they will learn
a lesson that you cannot attack innocent
leader I have told you in sahaja yoga we
should not ever be annoyed with our
children we should not in no way punish
them
our main achievement should be that
loving attention for children all over
the world where he belongs to your
family or to some another family or has
some sort of
detached attention with you still
because he is a child he is innocent
the innocence within itself your own
innocence will try to protect it's very
surprising how people take to
sacrificing their lives when it comes to
the attack of innocence children should
never be attacked they have their own
power to protect no doubt but you
shouldn't waste your energy on something
that is extremely inauspicious extremely
cruel and extremely ugly
if you cannot love children you cannot
love anything else not come across
anyone so far who says that they don't
love to do it luckily but maybe some
might say we love flowers why why you
love flowers because they are innocent
because that beauty of innocence is
within them we love nature why because
it is innocent but the greatest
innocence is seen among human beings who
are sahaja Yogi's