Dr. Warren has already talked to you about
the different centers that we have within
ourselves, and you can see how beautifully
they are placed and how gradually when the
Kundalini rises, how She enlightens the innermost
core of the centers. There are three channels
in the central channel, and the innermost
channel is used by Kundalini to pierce through
for the first time. You can imagine Kundalini
to be made of many strands of energy tied
together just like a rope, and as the chakras
start opening more strands start getting awakened
and they pierce through these six centers;
but if a person after Realization just thinks
that he has got the Realization, then he doesn't
have to bother about it, may lose it for the
time being, for quite some time I should say,
and he'll have to work much harder to re-establish
his Self Realization.
I've seen many-a-times when we give Realization
to people they say, "Yes, we have felt it."
They did feel it, everything happens, and
then they loose it because they have not established
their Realization properly, for which luckily
in every place wherever I go I see to it that
we already have a center established, then
you can go to that center and you can learn
from them how to establish your Realization.
That is a very, very important time which
must be taken into consideration.
There was a lady who had cancer, she was cured
of her cancer, she was perfectly all right
and she went back to her family, she was doing
very well, and after some time - a year or
so - she came back with another disease of
a very serious nature.
So I asked her, "How is it that you are cured
of cancer, now you get another disease? Did
you do anything about it?"
"No, Mother, I went back from here, everybody
says, 'You are looking very fine.' They are
all right, they were all quite surprised how
I was cured, and I never bothered to do anything
about it."
So she got another trouble. You go on like
this, you cure one thing then you again cure
another thing. Like little children, you clean
them, then again they get out and soil their
clothes, again they are back in the bathroom,
then again you clean them, again they do the
same thing. So you have to mature, after Realization
you must in all wisdom and sensible behavior,
you must mature of it, otherwise it is a big
headache to Me and big headache to you, and
you can be quite lost also with it, because
if a seed is half-sprouted it is of no use
at all.
So if you want that you should really have
the complete bliss of Self Realization, you
have to become a little serious person about
it. Shallow temperament is not going to help
you, or looking at it as if like another guru
shopping business it is not going to work
out. You have to work to see that you establish
yourself, till you have established you are
not to work on other people but once you are
established you can start working on other
people, giving them Realization. There is
no need then for you to bother that you will
catch from others, or anything; but before
that you should not try to help others. First
help yourself, selfishness to begin with.
Unless and until you are all right and you
know all the methods of protecting yourself,
you are not to indulge into Sahaja Yoga practices
which helps others. But when you become an
expert, when you have an expertise then you
should do it. Like a mechanic who doesn't
know how to repair a car, they spoil it more.
So better become an expert for which you don't
have to pay anything, you don't have to do
much about it but only to understand how you
have to move the Kundalini within you, how
you have to establish it back, what problems
you have and how you have to cure. You will
be surprised you won't be aware of problems
that you have.
One gentleman came and told Me, "Mother everyone
is coming and asking me, 'what about your
father, what's the problem?'"
I said, "Everybody said the same?"
He said, "Yes."
I said, "I also want to know, what about your
father?"
He said, "My father died very early in life,
and I always had a feeling that I had no father."
That can be cured, and he developed asthma
with it, so everybody knows, those who know
one thing that is the truth about you. All
of them will say the same thing, even if it
is a small child, he will also come and ask
you that "Is your father all right?" Because
if he knows that this center, this center
on the right hand side means the father. So
he will also say the same and then he will
come and ask you, "what about your father?"
It is so remarkable sometimes the way people
see these things that they can't believe it,
but this is nothing, what you get is just
a wee bit of it.
But as Kundalini rises, on every center you
start getting the light of that center. At
the first center you get back your innocence,
your eyes become innocent, your behavior becomes
innocent, you are not filled with lust and
greed, you don't look at things with lust
and greed, but you look at things with innocence,
which is a very big thing that people have
lost and that you get back and such a person
develops many qualities. One of them is that
such a person is full of fragrance, such a
person has a tremendous gravity, tremendous
gravity, and such a person has tremendous
dynamism, and attraction is a bad word so
I don't want to use it, but magnetical.
His magnets is awakened within him, this is
the center of your magnet of the earth. Such
a person develops a tremendous sense of roots
and sense of direction, you place him anywhere
he will know where to go. Like birds, you
place birds anywhere they know which side
is north, south, east, west. In the same way
you also develop your lost innocence and your
magnet within you by which you have proper
direction; but the highest of all you develop
the proper direction to wisdom which is the
wise thing to do. You just don't do stupid
things, you just don't do, even if you ever
try to do it, you will not do it, because
you know it is so stupid, just you don't do
it. I mean it is so simple to be wise than
to be stupid, because if you have to be stupid
you have to go out of the way to be stupid
and idiotic; but if you want to be normal
and wise is the easiest thing to do. But what
people do is to do things that would make
them more and more stupid, nonsensical, because
also some people told Me they do it, the reason
being they think they have a nuisance value.
Like in London now we have one funny stuff
going on, they call it what? "Punk rock."
You see, it's a funny stuff. Now poor kids
they don't know what they are doing it, and
I think the only value of that punk rock system
is this: that they try to sort of make a nuisance
out of them so that people feel attracted
towards them or sort of a significance out
of them. But when you become a realized soul
you realize your significance, because you
understand you are part and parcel of the
whole and that your significance is to give
Realization to others, the highest of highest,
that's what you have to do now you are a saint,
and that's how the whole attitude of cheapiness,
of outward shallowness finishes and you become
a serene, dignified personality. This is not
possible through any sermon, any lecture,
it's only possible when the Kundalini rises
you become like a very dignified child, very
dignified child.
I've seen one beautiful painting done of Mother
Mary being taught first time. You see Her
as a child, She is a very dignified personality,
as a child, She is about ten years of age.
I've seen My own grandchildren who are not
very old but extremely dignified. They walk
like kings, behave like kings. In every behavior
you find there's such a dignity, they'll never
do something shallow, they never ask for anything,
they never weep for anything, they never cry
for anything, they are so dignified and they
understand it so well what is dignity is.
I don't have to tell them, because they are
born realized, in the same way you become,
nobody has to tell you that "do this, or do
that," but you understand that you must have
self-respect. This happens to you automatically,
this is actualization, nobody has to tell
you that "you be dignified," you just become.
I've seen people who were absolutely absurd,
even from this punk rock we got some people
and they were so changed that people could
not recognize them, but one thing bad has
happened with this punk rock that they put
some sort of dye in their head and since then
their eyes became very weak, because these
dyes I think made the optic globe covered
with some sort of a color and you can't see
properly, and the eyes became very weak and
it took some time for us to remove the effect
of those dyes from their head.
We go headlong, "what's wrong?" There is nothing
wrong in this world if it is a stupid fool,
but for a wise man there are very many things
which are absolutely wrong, and there are
very many things which are absolutely correct,
so you develop your wisdom by this first center.
Now as the Kundalini rises She enlightens
your second center which we can call as the
Swadishthan Chakra for the time being, though
it is the third center. But second center,
you become extremely creative, extremely creative.
I know of a gentleman who came to Me, he had
no job.
And he said, "Mother, I have no job and what
should I do?"
I said, "All right, what do you want to do?"
He said, "Whatever you say."
I said, "All right, why don't you become an
interior decorator?"
He said, "Me? I don't know what is a teak
wood, I don't know what is a rose wood, how
am I to become an interior decorator?"
I said, "You just use your vibrations."
And you'll be surprised he earned million
of rupees out of that profession because you
become extremely creative, your sense of creation
becomes so subtle and so beautiful that you
start understanding art at such a high level
that people don't know how, when you are not
educated in art, how you can do it. I went
to Japan once, and they were having an Ikebana
competition or something, so I went to see
the Ikebana class and they requested Me, "Why
don't you do some flower arrangements?"
I said, "All right, I'll do."
I did it and I got the highest marks without
knowing a word about Ikebana, just surprise
Me, I got the highest mark. I can do lots
of things which I've never done before like
architecture. I have built houses without
doing any architecture, I've done decorations
of the houses, I've done all kinds of things
without knowing how to it, because you become
you so creative.
Music you start understanding so much better.
There are people now in America, there's a
girl, she had a horrible hoarse voice, absolutely
hoarse voice, and she always used to go out
of tune.
So I told her, "You shouldn't sing songs before
Me because it's rather funny."
She said, "Mother, why don't You give me a
good voice?"
I said, "You just try your Vishuddhi Chakra,
if your Vishuddhi Chakra is corrected you'll
be all right."
[Shri Mataji speaks aside: Why don't you sit
down.]
So the Vishuddhi Chakra was ... she tried
on Vishuddhi Chakra giving vibrations, and
she sings so melodiously now that I tell you
she can be a great singer. So the creativity,
that also is a blessing of your power of the
Goddess of learning. Boys who could not study
in the schools were absolutely duffers. Some
people brought this boy, recently I've received
a letter from him.
When he came to Me, his father said that "He
is going to be taken out of school because
he's good for nothing, he can not remember
anything, he's absolutely finished."
I said, "All right, doesn't matter, let him
take to Sahaja Yoga."
He got his Realization. Not only that he passed
with first class, but he got a scholarship.
Then he passed another exam, he got a scholarship.
Now he's got a very big job, at a very young
age. He wrote to Me, "Mother no one can believe
that a duffer like me has been so much highly
placed." All the boys who got scholarships
in Maharashtra in schools, in colleges and
universities are Sahaja Yogis.
It is such a tremendous force that starts
working in you, if you try to give vibrations
say to fruits or to trees or to say wheat
and such things which are very important for
life, any food, you will be amazed that the
food also grows so much more and the taste
is so good and it lasts you so longer. Like
one gentleman tried, a university professor
in agricultural college on some wheat, some
vibrations and he was amazed that when they
collected this wheat it was at least six times
more than normal, and when this wheat was
stored in a big hall like this, there were
so many other things, the rats who are always
a menace in India never touched that wheat.
They ate all the rest of it but never touched
the wheat.
Even the animals - the snails, even the tigers,
of course the dogs and the cats - understand
it much more, they understand you, they know
that you are a saint. They'll never touch
you, they will never trouble you. Even a tiger
sees a saint, he never attacks. You can handle
a tiger very easily; this is the power of
a saint. So you develop a tremendous capacity
of creativity. The greatest capacity you have
then is of creating a new human being out
of a ordinary human being. This is the greatest
blessing that you have, that you transform
an egg into a bird and that is the epitome,
that is the spiritual power you have, by which
you can transform the whole human race into
a new race which has this fifth dimension
within yourself.
You can start talking on science now, we have
a scientist here and he's a done his science,
he is a Doctor of Science in this and that,
in chemistry and I explained to him about
this - where is the hydrogen and oxygen and
nitrogen and all that within us and he was
amazed.
He said, "Mother, how do you know all these
things?"
I said, "I don't know how I know, but I know.
That's what it is, you just have a look at
this."
And he was amazed how I was telling him about
spiral movement and linear movement of peptose.
He said that "For this I had to study so much."
I said, "For Sahaja Yog you don't have to
study." A little bit you know and immediately
you click the point. Now this is the second
thing that you know in your learnings, in
your education you are all right, but the
mastery of this center comes, the mastery
of this center comes when you know the pure
knowledge, the pure knowledge of handling
the Kundalini, the pure knowledge of Spirit,
the pure knowledge of the blessings of God,
of Ritambhara Pragya. If you know that, that
is the highest that you achieve gradually
as you grow, because when these centers starts
expanding on the sides, you start expanding
in your personality, in your sensitivity and
in your evolutionary ascent, so that is how
you start growing from one to another to another
to another.
Now the third center that we have actually,
this is the second center because the third
center arises, this Swadishthana arises out
of the Nabhi, is a very, very important center,
is the center of your seeking as he has told
you. Your compete priorities change, complete
priorities change, because the joy that you
get out of Sahaja Yoga, the joy you get out
of this meditation, out of the feeling that
grows in you all the time, like a beautiful
torrential rain of joy that fills you, your
life and everybody's life, you don't care
for cheap type of entertainment. You feel,
you seek other Sahaja Yogi, you want to meet
another Sahaja Yogi, you don't want to meet
anybody else. If there is an actor coming,
or some big man is coming, "All right, let
him come, I'm going to see such and such person."
It is such a different personality that one
day - I will tell you how it happens - there
was a girl, a diplomat, she's a diplomat who
is a realized soul and she happened to go
to Sicily. And she was eating her food, suddenly
she felt there is some vibrations coming down,
she looked around, the other one was also
looking at her, she said, "Are you Mataji's
disciple?"
And she said, "Yes, I am Mataji's child."
They both got up and just hugged and said,
"Such joy Mother in that far-fetched place
of Sicily to find a Sahaja Yogi."
And then they stayed together and they wouldn't
go anywhere else but they said, "Now this
is the enjoyment." Just the company of a Sahaja
Yogi is such an enjoyment.
I've seen these people when they go to India,
the people are not so rich, poor people - they
have little, little huts - but when they go
they go there, you should see the love, the
rapport, and that makes Me so happy, so happy,
the way they love each other, the way they
understand each other, the way they help each
other and the only the company, for the first
time they start enjoying. We were once in
a hotel staying in Calcutta and with two Sahaja
Yogi with Me. They were in the other room,
quite far away, they could not get a room
close to Me, and one gentleman came for his
Realization, he came to My feet, when he got
his Realization it was a tremendous happening
and they came rushing from there.
I said, "What happened?"
They said, "We felt the vibrations, we felt
the vibrations from there, Mother, so we have
come to receive the vibrations."
And they came and they felt the vibrations.
So this man was so great that his vibrations
attracted them and they came down. They were
just enjoying that as if they were enjoying
a big flower with lots of fragrance. What
vibrations, what vibrations! The fellow got
up and said, "Very nice. They are enjoying
my vibrations. Now I'm going to enjoy your
vibrations."
For the first time you start enjoying your
fellow man because everyone is a beautiful
personality, a glorious, fragrant, joyful
personality; but because you cannot feel the
other person, and because the other person
does not emit, you are all the time quarreling.
Even husband-wife quarreling, father-mother
quarreling, this one quarreling, that quarreling.
In Sahaja Yoga there is hardly any time for
people to quarrel. The other day I had a lady
who came to see Me, and she was trying to
put her point and there were about five-six
Sahaja Yogis, and everybody was putting the
same point and she was amazed.
She said, "I've never seen such concord, such
friendship, such understanding, all of them
supporting each other, nobody is cutting anyone."
Such a society has to develop. It's such a
nourishing, soothing, invigorating society,
and you forget about getting bored, boredom
goes out of life, you never get bored, you
enjoy yourself or you enjoy the company of
Sahaja Yogis and it is very different level
that you come of - that is what, that land
you have to reach within yourself.
Now the greatest thing that happens as a result
of this center seeking, that you start seeking
other seekers, you try to find out "where
is the seeker?" If you hear somebody is a
seeker, you go and see. If you hear about
someone that some people are lost there, they
were seekers, but they went there lost, you
all rush there. It is like a person who is
like a, what you call a guard on the seashore
you know, there are guards kept for salvaging
people, and that is how you become. You suddenly
see somebody sinking, you just go. In Bombay
there was a case they announce that "there's
a lady who is going to die, if somebody can
come and help her, it will be a great thing."
They all rushed there; they saved her.
Now the interests changes completely, and
you start really helping people and not feeling
that you are helping them, not at all. But
the surrounding portion of that, which is
the void, is the best, which is affected by
your awakening, that you become the virtue
itself. Nobody has to tell you that you be
virtuous, when you are awakened you become
a virtuous person, you enjoy your virtues,
you enjoy being good, you enjoy being nice,
you really enjoy it. And that enjoyment comes
to you as a blessing because the virtue itself
is so strengthening, so powerful that anyone
who is harmed or troubled or tortured or put
down, you stand up, you are not afraid of
anyone, you are not afraid of any one of them.
Now about these people who have been troubling
you as fake gurus, I told about them in 1970.
I'm just a lady and single-handed I told them
who these people are, how they are going to
loot you, and what they are going to do; but
in this country nobody can think of one genuine
person who could be really genuine. It was
the problem that time, but with this awakening
within you of the virtuous nature, you just
know what is virtue and what is not virtue.
I don't have to tell you; I don't say "don't
do this, don't do that." I never say that,
it just happens, because when the virtue starts
developing, the vibrations improve and you
feel extremely joyous. We have lost our virtues
because there is no joy out of it, no reward.
If somebody is honest, he has to suffer; if
somebody's good, he has to suffer; is somebody's
kind, he thinks he has to suffer; but after
getting Realization you are rewarded for your
virtues.
You are amazed how you are paid for it, it's
so surprising, like once there was a lady
who came to see Me, she was a refugee, and
I had a big house.
So I said, "All right come and stay with Me."
So My husband, My brother they came, they
said, "What's this? You don't know her, who
she is, her husband, whether he is her husband
or not, just given her two rooms. It's not
good!"
I said, "Let it be, doesn't matter. I know
for nothing is going to happen, let her be
here."
So they wouldn't also go against Me. They
said, "All right, if you say so."
This lady stayed for ten days and went away.
Then she become a very well-known actress
in India, I didn't know she was the same lady,
but somebody told Me that she is the same
lady. I said, "Maybe."
Then one day you see, they wanted to make
a film for our Sahaja Yoga, so they said,
"We can ask this lady to act, because she
is a good actress."
I said, "All right, you can go ask but don't
tell her I am here, otherwise she will have
no choice. I will not go and see her. You
just ask her."
They went and ask her, they said, "Will you
be actress?" and all that.
She said, "I'll try." This, that she was saying.
But on the day on when they were going to
open the film I went there, she saw Me, she
was so amazed, she said, "Oh God, You are
the One, You are the One Who is sponsoring
this, Oh, I'll give my life for Her!" She
just came forward, she said, "Have anything
you like, I have nothing to say, I am so sorry
that you never told me that She's there."
Thousand times more she rewarded a little
thing I did for her.
No more cheating, no more troubling, you become
a wonderful person and so many people become
your friends in this world. Your have to just
tell you are coming, there will hundred people
at the airport to receive you. There will
be so many friends all over the world for
you, you will be amazed. It's such a tremendous
thing happens, because now you all are awakened
in that Primordial Being and you have become
one with each other. You can feel it, that
oneness, that unison that we are all not only
human beings but we are yogis, we are super
human beings, and we have to look after the
whole world. That feeling of compassion is
so overwhelming that all little, little stupid
things just fall off, there's no place for
that. This actually happens and has happened
with many.
Dr. Warren, whom you have seen here, can tell
you as I have told you lots of stories, but
there are many, some of them were so hot tempered,
some of them were so quarrelsome, some them
used to fight so much in the beginning that
I thought, "How are they going to be all right?"
But today I find them as great friends and
very great yogis. So this is the center where
your religion is awakened. And what is a religion?
Word comes from "religo," in Sanskrit it means
dharma, "Dhariyatisa Dharma," the sustenance,
your sustenance, your valances is your religion.
As every atom, carbon has four valances, and
in the same way you have ten valances, these
are the ten commandments that were told to
you and you become that, you just become.
I don't have to tell you as commandments but
they become your beautiful ornaments within
yourself. This happens automatically, so spontaneously
you become that.
A bishop came to see Me the other day, he
is a relation of Mine, My brother. He came
to see Me, and he was rather adamant and little
angry when he came to see Me because he thought,
"Why am I trying to do this kind of thing?"
But when he saw the Sahaja Yogis he said,
"I'm amazed, you know, I've been giving lectures
in the church for years together, but I could
not achieve anything. How have You transformed
these people? The drug addicts have suddenly
become such good people that they have given
up drugs, alcoholics have given up alcohol.
How is it without telling them anything?"
I said, "Everything is within them. As soon
as the light comes you can see everything.
You know that this is on your way, this is
against your progress, this is anti-life,
you just give up. Only thing you have to have
the light within you."
So he himself was surprised at this and then
he said, "Really, that should be done, is
to transform them."
But I said, "You do not transform them by
giving them big sermons, you transform them
by giving them the real second birth, real
baptism." And I must say that Calvinist, of
all the persons, Calvinist in Geneva have
accepted Me and they think that this is the
only way they can transform you.
You will be amazed the Calvinist of all the
persons who are such I should say one-sided
people, they have accepted to see the result
of everybody who is open-minded person, who
thinks for the good of others and not for
money-making and for selfish ends. We'll see
one day that this is the way it has to be.
God has given us this power, we have got a
Spirit within us, we should try to awaken
that and we should accept it, not because
I'm doing it, you can do it also. So this
thing happens to you with this chakra.
Now with the another chakra on top, that is
one - as he has told the diseases, I'm telling
you the positive side of it - when this chakra
is caught up he must have told you, you develop
breast cancer and all that. But when it is
awakened, you get all the security of the
world, you are never insecure, you are never
bothered, you have no fear of anyone. You
do not have to suggest yourself that "you
should not have fear or anything," you just
become fearless, there is no nothing like
fear, there's no reaction to any threat or
anything. Like the gentleman who came here,
just to beat Me now, I was just looking at
the drum, and the fellow was getting frightened
of Me, he was going backwards, backwards,
he would not come forward. But you don't develop
any fear of at all about anyone, because you
are standing on truth, like Christ. At the
time when He was challenged, you must know
when Mary Magdalene was beaten up, He stood
up. He had nothing to do with the prostitute,
such a virtuous man, He was virtue personified,
He stood up, He said, "Those who have not
committed any sin, can throw a stone at Me."
He was sure nobody can do it because He was
an authority of virtue.
I, as I told you, I am just a woman and I
spoke openly with the names of these people
and told of what they are going to do, and
how they are going to possess you. And people
came, they were frightened, they said, "What
are You doing?"
So you get rid of all your fear, but you do
not dominate anyone, you love, in your love
you are secured. It is not by domination but
the security that you are love, you are compassion.
And the power of love is the highest of all,
that you stand in complete peace and bliss.
This happens to you when the central thing
comes up. There are many other things happen,
you can become a poet, I mean so many things
happen with this, because you become such
a compassion, such a compassion. And when
this compassion starts working you are given
all the help that is needed.
Then the another chakra - I am going a little
fast because after all you understand that
there isn't much time today, I've been speaking,
and speaking every day, it's a marathon race
for Me, so I'll try to make it short now - it's
the Vishuddhi Chakra as he told you is very
important, this is America. Vishuddhi Chakra
is America in the Universe. America is the
Vishuddhi Chakra and the star is the Saturn.
There are seventeen of them, sixteen is the
planet moving round, there are sixteen centers
there and the seventeenth is the Vishuddhi
itself. Is a very important thing that this
center is America, so America has the responsibility
of transformation. They have to take up the
responsibility of transforming the whole world.
Instead of that they themselves are getting
ruined, they are killing themselves. There
is no fear from outside I tell you, we are
going to be ruined from inside. What a responsibility
you have and what we are doing you should
see to that. That's why so many seekers are
born here, but they do not feel the responsibility
of transformation. They will, one day it will
come, they will have to feel it, once they
are awakened I'm sure they will feel that
responsibility.
This very important center as he must have
told you, by the virtue of this on the gross
we develop a face which is very relaxed and
attractive and good looking. We develop eyes
which are full of compassion; we develop a
face which is innocent, which is very smooth
and which has got a capacity to express its
feeling. The smallest of feelings can be expressed
through this center. It looks after your nose,
yours ears, everything improves with this.
You develop - now I can't hear anything if
a non-Sahaja Yogi speaks to Me. It is a very
funny thing, unless and until that person
is very close I just can't hear what he is
saying, to Me, it is all what you call "blah,
blah, blah." But a Sahaja Yogi, if he speaks
to Me I can hear very well.
The whole thing changes, the whole sensitivity
changes, you start understanding what music
is good for your Spirit; you start understanding
what is good for your eyes to see, because
you don't want like to see that is something
that is horrid, you just don't enjoy it. You
feel like vomiting - you see something horrid,
you just feel like vomiting. You become so
sensitive you can't imagine, to virtue and
to goodness.
Automatically it happens to you, I don't have
to tell you. I've seen people have changed
overnight. The whole idea is that the light
has to be brought in for you to see for yourself,
and when it happens you'll be amazed, you
become such a different, wonderful person.
There's everyone in America has Abraham Lincoln
within them, which has to be just awakened
and you'll find that that great personality
can be shown in you, when it happens to you.
It has to happen to all of you to feel that
greatness that lies hidden within.
I cannot elaborately tell you about Vishuddhi
Chakra what they call the Krishna consciousness,
but not this Krishna consciousness which has
made people actual beggars, they are begging
on the streets. You go in India in the villages,
about they were going to beat these people.
They thought they are Krishna consciousness,
they wouldn't get places in the hotels because
they thought they are Krishna consciousness,
because these people were lost, they had no
money left with them. Now they are begging
in India, imagine. How can we afford to have
these beggars there? They have no money with
them, they can not come back, they don't know
what to do with them, so many you will find
in the villages just begging. So this kind
of thing that - imagine a person who is being
blessed by Shri Krishna Who is the Deity on
this center, should beg!
He's the One Who is the giver of complete
wealth, why should we beg? This is the thing
they don't understand, just the opposite of
what they are suppose to be. There are lots
of stories of Krishna how He blessed people
with wealth. It is to be seen sometimes, if
you have time, I may have time then we might
be able to see all those beautiful things
that He did.
So the other chakra is important, is the Chakra
of Christ. This center is very important because
this is the gate through this you have to
pass to your destination which is the limbic
area. So Christ is the gate, many people are
shouting, "it's only He can save." Where is
He now? Is He here? When He was living, they
talked of Ibrahim, when He came then they
said, "You are not the One. It was Moses.
You are not the One."
They denied Him, defied Him. Now when He's
dead, then we think, "It is Christ." Now I
have come, He's talked about Me, if you read
Bible you'll find He's talked about Me very
clearly there and I have to do My job and
I have come. You are going to say that it
was Christ Who has to do it. If Christ could
do it, why did He say that "I'm going to send
you a comforter"? He talked of future, didn't
He? Why did He say such a thing? We should
find out why did He say that "I will send
you the Holy Ghost and the Comforter and the
Redeemer and a Counselor"? Why did He say
that? Why not look forward to that? Because
we are today after Christ. People don't want
to see this point, they want to depend on
Christ because He's in their pocket, they
can use Him the way they like.
When He has talked, He has said, "Why not
see the point?" If this is what Christ is,
then it is such a bad thing because people
say, "Christ was no good." They say, "What
has Christ given us?" Christians nations,
what have they done, what have they achieved?
It's a bad name to Him if you do not see completion
of His work. I'm here to complete His work
and when you do not complete His work, His
half-work done in a very half-way will bring
bad name to Him.
Why not people who claim about Christ understand
that what others have to say about it? If
you want to know about Christians, go and
ask the Jews; and if you want to know about
the Jews, go and ask the Muslims; and if you
want to know about the Muslims, go and ask
the Hindus. There are all in a doldrum. Nobody
has any understanding that they are worshiping
or they are admiring or advocating a flower
which belongs to one tree of life. They have
all plucked those flowers, "This is mine,
this is mine, in my pocket," and fighting.
If religion means fighting and quarreling,
it is not a religion at all. If it is integration,
then it is a religion.
In Sahaja Yoga you'll find that they are all
together. Christ has said, very clearly, "Those
who are not against Me are with Me." Who are
those people? Try to find out. For that you
have to little bit go out of Bible. In the
Bible how much do you have Christ there, for
three years? Nobody allowed Him to live for
three years, and if they could, they would
also kill Me.
Not easy, He wanted to play the drama, otherwise
He would have finished all of them, in no
time. So He has said that "You are to be resurrected
first, and then that's how you will be judged."
And the Day of Judgment is today, this is
the Day of Judgment, that's why you are confused,
this is the Day of Judgment where you will
be judged and how are you going to be judged?
Through your Kundalini. Your Kundalini is
going to be awakened and you'll be judged
where you are. That's what it is, and those
who will be calling Me, "Christ, Christ" I
will not look at them, that's what it is.
By calling Him "Christ, Christ" you do not
become Christians, you have to get your Realization,
your baptism in the actual sense.
It has to be an actualization. I'm telling
you that if you miss the point, you have missed
it for ever and ever. Be careful on that point.
It's very important. Don't run after things
which have no meaning to your consciousness.
Try to raise yourself up to this point and
understand that the time has come for you
to transform, this is the time of your judgment
and you have to get to it in a very big way.
The shallow things and all this will be finished.
What is America or what is any country in
the eyes of God? Nothing. If they do not take
to His ways, all will be treated like waste,
thoroughly waste, it's a wasteland. But if
you rise, thousands and thousands and millions
and millions can be saved. Try to rise, try
to understand your own responsibilities, that
is very important.
Today is the last day and the last center
which is the Sahasrara, is the integration,
integration of your being, of physical, mental,
emotional being, it takes place. Is integration
of all the Deities, of all the Prophets, all
the great works that they have done, integration
of all the scriptures, everything takes places
when this Sahasrara is opened out, when you
become the Spirit.
This is a much more difficult job, I know,
because if you don't have to transform people
it is very easy to talk about it and get away.
But I have to transform, not only transform
but you have to become, you cannot become
a Sahaji Yogi by paying Me, by saying things,
by arguing, by showing up, you can only become
Sahaji Yogi by going within yourself, face
up to it, see for yourself. I am here to help
you in every way possible. Whatever is possible
we'll try to do it, but you all should also
understand your responsibility.
It is not a joke now, it's no more a joke.
It's not like Sunday morning you get up and
go to church, or Monday morning you go somewhere
else in the temple, and Tuesday morning you
go to see Siddhivinayaka [Temple of Shri Ganesha
- SG] and another day you go to a mosque.
It is not like that. It is a very serious
thing which we must understand. We are at
the brink of destruction, be careful about
it. We must do things so that the blessings
of God comes to upon us and that we are saved.
It is a very serious thing, and the responsibility
is much more on all the people who are getting
Realization, so do not treat it lightly. You
all, I hope, will take it seriously.
Thank God there is a nice seminar we are having
after this for three days, you can come down
there, they have charged you very little,
we don't have to make any profit of out you,
the only profit I can make is that you get
your profits, that's all. So please take it
up seriously, work it out seriously, and I
tell you, out of you will come out those people
who will build that foundations of that construction
which is going to come. Please don't waste
your time in useless things, get to it.
Any one of you can do it. I bless you with
My whole heart and know that I love you very
much. If you have any problems, you can write
to Me, but don't write to Me about your family
problems and this and that, it's a headache
to Me, there is no need to write. Of course
I'm a mother, if you have problems you can
write but some people write ten pages saying,
"my wife is fighting me." It's bit too much.
You should write to Me about the problems
which concern the whole country, concern the
whole world. Widen yourself and that's how,
though you may think that you are very unassuming
simple people, you are the ones who are going
to be, not those who are successful, they
are blinded by their success; not those who
are rich, they are not going to enter into
the Kingdom of God; not those who have a big
name, no. It's you, you are going to enter
into the Kingdom
of God.
May God bless you.
[Self Realization]
Now, all
the angels have
a seat, now, put your hands towards Me like
this, and close your eyes, the vibrations
are so much today, nothing to do. Just so
much vibrations tonight, it's tremendous.
Just close your eyes, you'll feel the cool
breeze, most of you, close your eyes please.
You just put your right hand on the head and
see if there is a cool breeze coming out,
little higher, on top of your head.
Hmm, it's there. Now put your right hand towards
Me and put the left hand and see, little higher,
about six inches higher, six inches higher,
change over, again, now put your hands up
like this absolutely, close the eyes and ask,
"Is this the breeze of the Holy Ghost" or
ask the question "Mother, are You the Holy
Ghost?
You feel the cool breeze? Good, it's tremendous
today. May God bless you all.
Those who have not felt any cool breeze, please
raise your hands. One, two and three. Are
keeping all right? You are not well? All right,
doesn't matter, if you are not well maybe
you may not feel today but you'll get well
and then you'll feel it, so it doesn't matter.
There's one or two persons who have not felt
it, it's so tremendous today, May God bless
you.
You may give your addresses to these people,
let them know where you are, also you can
take address for the seminar, if you want
to come, they are going to arrange a transport
for you to go to Santa Cruz. Thank you very
much.
I say goodbye to you, after a year I'll definitely
will come to Los Angeles again, those who
haven't cool breeze should keep their hands
raised. These boys will come and see you.
All right, those people who haven't got it,
please keep your hands slightly raised so
some people will come and see you, little
higher so that they'll come and see you. Here
just have a look.
Man in the Audience: I didn't hear Your last
question. I didn't understand what You asked
about the Holy Ghost.
Shri Mataji: Just to know that I am the Holy
Ghost.
Man in the Audience: You are Holy Ghost?
Shri Mataji: Yes. Otherwise how will you recognize?
Man in the Audience: The Bible says that God
is the Holy Ghost.
Shri Mataji: Bible never says that. You don't
understand that. You don't teach Me Bible.
[Man keeps interrupting Shri Mataji] It doesn't
say. You don't tell Me. You have no knowledge.
Don't disturb others. If you are such a good
person you ...