Most of you are Sahaj Yogis here.
Now those who have got Realisation, those who have felt the vibrations,
must know that they are now developing into another being.
The germination has started,
and you must allow the germination to work out its own way.
But normally, when we get Realisation also,
we do not realise that it is a tremendous thing that has happened within us.
That this triggering, which is an impossibility, has taken place within us,
and it has to work out slowly.
It has to develop, and evolve us into that, and because we do not feel it,
we do not take it that seriously as we should, our Realisation.
Moreover, they are surrounded by people who have not felt the vibrations,
they do not know this area; they have never seen it.
As Guru Nanak has called it, it is alakshya (???????: unobservable).
They have not seen it, they don’t know about it,
they don’t know there is a power of God that exists,
which understands, coordinates, cooperates with you,
which is working in the collective being, which makes aware,
you aware of that collective being and of others also.
This alakshya, or we can call it paroksha (??????:invisible),
which is not seen by any one, which no one knows about, they talk about it.
They talk about the Kingdom of God, they talk about God’s Powers, Divine Power.
It’s all talk, talk, talk, talk, talk.
But once you are triggered into it, you have to grow into it.
Unless and until you grow into it, you’ll be dropped,
specially for people who have come from fake gurus
and from false things that they have been following.
They don’t know how terrible these things are.
Like you are on a crocodile, and suddenly you discover it’s a crocodile:
how fast you would run from that?
But even the understanding that it is a crocodile and it is going to eat you off
doesn’t come up so easily.
So, this one doesn’t realise also, as you do not realise
that triggering which is the most difficult thing has happened to you,
it is difficult.
But it has happened to you, you know why it has happened.
You take that one for granted and also you take the devils for granted.
At least don’t take the devils for granted.
Run away from them as soon as possible.
Meditate, meditate, and try to establish yourself, in the realm of Divine love.
I say it is Divine love.
You cannot understand what Divine love is.
You cannot understand any human being who loves you only for love’s sake.
Just because that person loves you, he goes on loving because he enjoys that loving.
In Sanskrit it is called avyaja (??????: natural; simple),
that there is no interest, avyaja, it’s just flowing.
Even when it corrects you, it corrects you in love.
And the protection of Divine love is the only way you are germinating.
That love gives you that warmth needed, that strength needed, that confidence needed.
Everything is given to you by that Divine love.
So, one has to realise
that it is love, and love, and love is the basis of all this Creation.
God has created this world, this universe, only because He loved.
And He wants to bestow this blessing on you because He loves you.
But how far you love yourself is the problem.
How far you understand yourself is the problem.
You do not evaluate yourself, and that is the reason why,
though the Kundalini has risen and you have got Realisation,
your vibrations are flowing, the growth is very slow.
Because attention has been outside, and even after Realisation it is outside.
Sometimes it is sucked in [but] again it goes outside.
Then we do not change our old habits at all.
We go on sticking to those old habits.
Our structure of life, our styles of thinking, continue to be the same:
again, we find ourselves lost into the same shambles.
Now SahajYog gives you Realisation, alright,
but also it gives you a long rope to hang yourself,
if you do not pay heed to yourself and to your being,
if you don’t love yourself
and understand that you are the instrument of God
by which for the first time you are going to give Realisation to people,
you are going to save people from getting drowned.
And this is the first time you are made like that.
This capability you never had and no human beings have, which you have got now today.
Very few people had this capability, very, very few people.
But now you have got that capacity and you do not want to evaluate yourself.
How important it is, if you could realise,
then you would work it out [and] allow the blossoming to come up.
On the contrary I find [that]
today, because you are all Sahaj Yogis, I can talk to you like this.
Normally it is about Kundalini and all that, but I find that,
you do not see the movements of your Kundalini.
If you try to understand that She’s the one who loves you the most,
because She is your individual Mother.
And, if you try to follow Her,
you will see that She’s suggesting where is the problem with you,
what you have to correct, what you have to do.
Because She wants to perfect you.
She wants to help you.
So, if you start watching it, carefully, with love, with understanding-
She’s very playful, extremely sweet, full of beautiful plays like a little child.
She will tickle you here and there, call for your attention.
She doesn’t trouble you.
You have to be just alert about Her, and She really matures you.
You have seen people, with time, how they have matured.
But you have to pay attention to Her and to yourself,
otherwise what is your value, without enlightenment?
What is the value of a human being without enlightenment?
What is the use of having human beings if they are not enlightened?
What is the use of this instrument if it is not put to the mains?
The rest is all useless, isn’t it?
And it is you who have to raise the people.
You have to enlighten the people.
As we have some gas lights: a man runs up to the gas lights to lighten them,
he only has the power or capacity to do it.
So, he runs up the street, lightening all the gas lights.
It is he, here, who has to do it.
He is appointed for that.
Sahaj Yogis must realise what is their value.
What have you made out of Sahaj Yoga?
How many people have you saved?
How many people you have helped?
Instead your own problems are so many
and you are creating problems for others by talking, by discussing, by arguing.
You cannot discuss it out.
You must know.
You cannot argue it out.
It has to work by itself.
By arguing, discussing, fussing, judging, confusing yourself,
you create a problem for your Kundalini to work it out.
Are you not seeking your Spirit?
Are you not worried about the salvation of your own Spirit?
If so, what are you doing about it?
That’s the most important thing.
I think everybody realises this, that only achieving Self-realisation is not the end of it,
because it’s just the sprouting that has started.
You have to go further.
You have to have compassion for others who haven’t got it yet.
You have to think about them,
you have to give it to them; work it out, put all your minds to it.
But still I find people are busy with other things.
They go back into the same circle.
You should be busy.
I don’t say that you should not do something for your living.
You have to do it.
This is one thing very important for us to know, that we have to work it out.
We have to allow it to grow within ourselves.
But I mean if you say that, “Mother, we have all faith in you, that’s all.”
That’s not sufficient.
What faith do you have?
What do you mean by faith?
It is such a vague term.
What is faith after all?
Have you ever analysed the word ‘faith’?
Some people think that, “We have all faith in Mother.
If we sing Her praise – finished!”
For that, one has to reach a certain stage, like AdiShankaracharya had reached.
Have you got faith in yourself?– is the point.
Who is having faith in me?
Is the one who has no faith in oneself!
You have to have faith in yourself
and in all your fellow beings, all these other Sahaj Yogis.
Anybody who thinks that, “I am something greater than the others!” is a gone case.
Nobody should work Sahaj Yoga for oneself in that way.
You have to work collectively for every one of them.
Any one of you who thinks that you have something higher than the others have,
you are sadly mistaken.
It’s like one eye saying that, “I am higher than the other!”,
or one nose saying, “I am higher than the eyes!”
Everything has its own place in the body of Virata,
and everybody is so important, as well as dispensable.
You know what happens in Sahaj Yoga – very common in India, not so much here.
I mean Indians do this way: they have certain very good points like,
I mean wherever I go I find them very much matured and very much developed,
because they are not such thinkers as you are.
You are great thinkers, visionaries, intellectuals, you see.
And I was thinking all the intellectuals will be developing a horn here like this after some time.
And when you see them, you’ll know that these intellectuals who are denouncing God
and denouncing all His ways, they are not intellectuals I would say, to that extent.
But they [Indians] fail in certain things, while you fail in certain things.
They always had this kind of thing where somebody came up like one man, who said,
“No, I am something great!”
Then, he says, “I am this, I am that!”
Goes on with this kind of harping, and he shows down other people.
And then suddenly, such a person is brought down, and the people are shocked.
“Mother, how? What happened?” You cannot!
You see if you have to even pull a dead carpet like that,
you cannot pull one side of it, you have to carry the whole.
Only one person cannot shoot off in the whole game.
Now you take my position.
Yes, I know I have all the powers, everything is there, of course;
I am supposed to be much higher and all that – supposed to be, I should say.
But confronting you, I have to come down; I have to fight the way with you, up the hill.
Every step, we have to go together hand in hand.
You know that.
Somebody’s some chakras are catching so I put my Chakra into play.
It works out. It works out that way.
But you know how much I have to struggle, how much I have to work hard.
It’s a task, giving Realisation.
My Kundalini doesn’t need anything, you know that,
but still She has to carry your heavy Kundalini on Herself and raise it.
It’s a very heavy thing.
Only a Person of real love can do that, that’s the only criteria.
The one who does not have love, cannot do it [because] it is too much a thing to do –
the whole body vibrating, every centre vibrating; it’s not easy.
But it’s just the love, the compassion between you and me, which soothes me,
which covers all the tasks and the labour and the thing that I have to put in.
And sometimes it’s such a wasteful thing I feel about some people.
It is such a waste with them.
But still the love that has brought us together gives that soothing feeling
and you feel so cheerful.
Every morning you get up with a new fragrance within yourself, feeling so happy about it.
So be careful in dealing with people, you have to deal with love,
not with criticism or in any way showing them down in any way.
When you are not any way higher than anyone then there is no reason it should be done like that.
If you are getting any way higher, you are helping the Collective Being.
But in that, if you are feeling that you are higher than others you are again coming down
because you are pulling down the Collective Being.
If you put down anyone, or condemn anyone like that, then you are putting down that person.
And, you should not also correct, because I am there to correct.
It’s not easy to correct others, you may hurt them.
You don’t know even the ways of correcting people.
Unless and until you have those powerful vibrations,
which are emitting from your being just love, then you can do it.
Because of an ego-oriented society we are very good at hurting others.
We dominate others.
We don’t even know that we are dominating others.
There are so many ways I have learned in this country we have,
by which we dominate, in a very subtle way.
We talk to people, in such a way that we are dominating them.
Do we ever think, sit down,
how are we going to talk to others, suggesting our love to them?
I’ll tell you again and again that SahajYog is nothing but love, love, love.
How much you love others is the main point.
Despising, criticising, is not good.
Yesterday, you were just the same, today you are better off,
you are going to be better off still.
Of course, some people who are very heavy,
who are very troublesome, you should tell them plainly that:
“Sorry sir, you are very negative, we can’t bear you.”
There are some cunning people also who may come in and try to trouble you.
To a point is all right, then you have to tell them off that: “We are sorry.”
But even to judge whether a person is negative or what sort of a thing he is doing,
you are just thinking about it, you are rationalising –
not through rationality, but through vibrations.
Because rationality, a person may appear to be a very nice person, may be,
or a lady coming in, see, and the lady will be a terrible stuff.
So how much you meditate means how much you love.
When you think of others, think how much you love them,
just try to think how beautiful it is.
If it is not love, it is hatred.
It’s like a scorching heat you see,
which will completely take away all the beauty, the smoothness, of your heart.
Only through love, Sahaj Yoga is going to spread.
All these years you have seen the powers of hatred.
You have seen how people hate, how they talk about each other, how they treat each other.
There’s no tenderness about them, there’s no kindness about them,
how sharp they are with each other.
You have to change all that now.
You have to create a world of people who love each other, for nothing:
not for money, not for positions, not for beauty, not for sex, only for love’s sake,
only because you have been blessed by love.
From next time we’ll be advertising and there will be many more coming
who are new people to Sahaj Yoga.
And I am sure it is going to increase.
But I have told you that all of you must find out
how many people you can bring in yourself and work out.
I must say Jim has done a good job, very good job.
I’m very proud of him.
He has gone and done such a lot of things,
and single-handed he has worked it out,
fighting such a horrible monster there, but he’s done it.
All of you must support him, and also such people who want to do something.
Put your mind to something like that.
All the time we are thinking about jobs, this, that, that.
This is a very precious time which should not be lost.
All our lives we have done jobs, earning money, marrying, having children and dying.
This lifetime, let us do something special, for which this whole universe was created.
Open the gates of heavens for the rest of the people.
You have to be assiduous.
There’s no compulsion in Sahaj Yoga you know that very well.
There’s no timing for it.
There’s no forcing for it, because I say it is love.
If you do not want to do it, nobody is going to force you.
But, as I said, Sahaj Yoga gives a very long rope to hang yourself,
till you go into illusions completely
and you wouldn’t even know that you have lost all your vibrations.
It is to that extent.
If we have entered into something which was unprecedented,
we have to take the ways which are unprecedented.
You cannot go about with the ways that you have had before.
You have to change your methods.
Judge every action of yours through love.
How much sacrifice can you make for others?
What can you sacrifice for others?
What service can you do for others?
Sahaj Yogis I am saying.
There is no sacrifice in it.
If you see it, what is the sacrifice? It is love.
If you love someone, and you want to take, say, a rose for a person,
and you go to the market, with great difficulty you get the rose.
When you get it you feel happy.
But then you get the thorn in the finger, still you don’t mind.
It’s bleeding, doesn’t matter.
Then you are just waiting to see the person there.
And when you see the person, you forget all that is gone in between
and you give that rose just to express yourself, symbolically.
And how happy you feel that you have been able to give that rose to that person.
This we do every day in our life.
But in Sahaj Yoga you do it without even knowing it – it’s happening.
You are transmitters.
Everywhere you are sitting in meditation you are transmitting vibrations.
Do you know that?
At that time if you are thinking of your jobs and your other things
which you have been thinking [about] before, the transmission is poorer.
Think of love, think of the whole country, think of the whole world at that time.
You are transmitters of these waves of love, and love will flow from you.
I told you once that you are made in the form of Ganesha,
and that’s what you have to do.
You know there are vibrations from you coming out,
you are sending vibrations out, you know that.
That means you are like any deity which is thrown out of the Mother’s,
I mean Earth’s womb, and a big temple is raised,
and thousands of people go to worship that.
And they say it is a temple of a JagrutDevata.
‘Jagrut’ means enlightened, awakened.
And that’s just a stone, a stone that comes out and people build a temple on top of that
and go there and worship that.
While there are so many already sitting here, so many jagrut, realised-souls.
These are living, these are moving, these are understanding, they manoeuvre.
The stones only emit vibrations to clear the atmosphere, but you can raise the Kundalini.
They cannot raise the Kundalini; you can.
And what are you doing about it?
Such a precious thing you have got.
What are you doing about it?
Is it because there is no business with it that we are taking it so slowly?
Supposing it’s an enterprise then everybody would be up and doing, is it?
We have to change our ways and methods of understanding.
The reward of God is thousand-fold than any enterprise can bestow upon you.
When He blesses you, you wouldn’t even have words to thank Him, to that extent He goes.
Are we depending on Him or on our own old ways?
We have to change very much;
we have to transform ourselves into new style of thinking.
It is very, very important.
I hope you’ll think about it, what I have talked to you today.
Don’t take to life which has not brought any happiness to you.
You have your friends who are Sahaj Yogis.
Change your friends.
Change your methods of life.
You’ll enjoy much more.
This is for you to understand about yourself and about the importance of Sahaj Yoga.
Unless and until it is an enterprise, nobody takes it up seriously.
This is the style of Western thinking.
It has to be, whether it is hocus-pocus or real enterprise,
doesn’t matter, as long as there are money exchanges, everybody is up and doing.
But when it comes to Sahaj Yoga they have no time even to meditate.
Because we have not yet loved, we have not felt that love within ourselves.
I wish you could all feel that depth of love.
Then you would go all out to work it out for yourself and for others.
I would like to have some questions from you, Sahaj Yogis, if possible.
But somebody should try to give him, he can get it in no time, Realisation.
Is there any question?
Ask me – anything practical.
Because we have very few new people today, we can just have a very nice chat.
Lady: Would you explain to me about sometimes,
when people say if you put your legs out like that it’s just not good
and you should have them underneath– what’s wrong?
I mean if it’s not a sexual tantalisation or something,
what’s wrong with having your legs just stretching out in front of you?
Shri Mataji: In front of me?
Will you do to the Queen?
Lady: No, no, I’m sorry.
Shri Mataji: No, no, what I am saying, will you do to the Queen of England?
Lady: No, no.If you are alone, now what happens?
Shri Mataji: Hum?
Lady: I don’t mean if somebody’s there.
Shri Mataji: Before my photograph? Will you spit at?
Lady: When you sit to meditate.
Shri Mataji: No, no, what I’m saying if your Queen’s photograph is there, will you spit at her?
Lady: Is that a spit?
Shri Mataji: Yes, it is! It is an insult.
Putting your feet towards somebody is an insult.
Is a common thing!
Lady: Is it only a custom in India?
Shri Mataji: No, no, it is a custom everywhere in the whole world.
You have lost all your traditions,
doesn’t mean that there were no such traditions of putting away feet on somebody.
Imagine, somebody coming down to see you,
somebody whom you have to respect, you put your feet up?
I mean, anybody can understand, even a child understands this.
You see the sense of our respect has come to us from inside, not from outside.
It’s not rationality.
It has come to us from our unconscious.
We know how we respect.
Say somebody would say that, “What’s wrong in talking like this to someone?”
You see, supposing somebody says, now you know that, even a child knows,
if he is talking to elders, he’ll put down his head.
But here, you see everybody is so abnormal.
You don’t know how to do everything because everything is rationalised, you see.
Tomorrow, you might say, “What’s wrong if I stand on my head?”
I mean, “Do it”, but that’s not the way.
There are certain normal ways of protocol, of praying.
How do you pray in the church?
Imagine, in the church you go and sit with both your feet towards the priest.
What will he say?
“Put down your feet!”
These things are innate within us.
Human beings know already lots of things.
They are not animals.
They know lots of things already.
You don’t know how many things are built in you.
In a very beautiful way in your understanding, as a human being, you know so many things.
Nowhere in the world you’ll find anybody putting up their feet before anyone whom you respect.
It’s not a sign of respect.
There’s no question of India or anything.
Only thing in India, people have yet preserved all their sense of respect.
In other places, they have so rationalised and so ego-oriented
that they have no respect for anyone whatsoever.
Lady: You take it only as a sign of respect.
Supposing that somebody is sitting alone and they don’t have Your picture
or they don’t have anything, is it all right to stretch their legs?
Shri Mataji: Then it’s all right.I mean, you see it is.
Lady: Somebody said that if you put your legs out it’s creating some bad energy or something.
That’s why I wanted to check.
Shri Mataji: No, no not that way, not losing energy.
I was just thinking about stretching the feet before somebody whom you respect.
Say, my Photograph is there or I am there.
Now, you respect me.Isn’t it?
Then you will not like to sit with the feet.
That’s what I’m trying to say.
But, you see, losing energy and all that is not there at all.
Who told you that? That’s not.You sleep like that.
You don’t sleep with the feet on the ground.How can it be?
If anybody says that, you should not take it for granted.
You see I think all this is not so important also.
Even you sleep, how do you sleep?
I mean, it is so simple and natural.
You know this is what’s happening with rationality.
See, very simple things become so funny that you, I don’t know what to say.
That’s why I said a horn will be growing from here, all of you intellectuals.
You’ll be having a big horn coming out so people will know,
“All right, all right, we know these people.”
Nobody will face them.You see, this so simple.
Because you are so complicated, all simple things look so horrid.
Is a question of respect and is a question of –
if you are sleeping, of course you stretch your feet like that, straight.
It’s all right.
While you sit down, you can sit like that, there’s no harm.
You need not be cross-legged all the time.
It’s not necessary.
If you are doing some sort of a exercise or something, you can be like that.
But everything, now say, for example, you have got hands.
Now this is for many purposes, all right?
It is for taking vibrations, it is for eating, it is for scratching.
Now, if you are eating at that time if you want to scratch, now what to do?
It’s a question like that.
See whatever you have to do, you do at that right time, with the way you want to do.
If you need your feet for something – running, you should run.
When you have to sit down, you should sit down.
When you have to sleep you must sleep.
I mean this is normal.
Sahaj Yogis does not mean that you should cut your noses.
No, it doesn’t mean that.
It means you have to be more beautiful.
It doesn’t matter, you see even if you bend ten times,
but it does matter if you pull back yourself, even once.
Doesn’t matter, to be humble, to be more humble and more humble, is so sweet and good.
You see, makes you more cultured, more harmonious and beautiful.
Man: I have a problem.
Shri Mataji: What’s it?
Man: I’ve been, in my humble way, devoted myself, to the spiritual realisation of myself,
I adopted meditation, I completely lost number of years.
I realised that state in subtle awareness
and I feel myself highly elevated from this material world,
the feeling of bliss, absolute peace, happiness and joy.
And, I see the Spirit which I construct upon in a very glorious, boarded way,
in a boarded, shut boarded way.
That state continues for some time,
but doesn’t stay for a long time, for a long number of days.
After a short time again I find I come down.
And this goes like a curve, and when I find that from the height I have come down,
I feel a little disturbed, why it is happening.
And, I have found that the more I detach myself from my family,
from my work, from my friends, from other things, the lighter I feel
and the greater number of peace I get from meditation.
Now, the trouble is this.
About one year ago, when I would see a beautiful girl, a beautiful lady,
I would remain restless perhaps for two days, three days or something like that.
When I learnt about Patanjali’s yoga –
Shri Mataji: What yoga is this?
Man: Beg Your pardon?
Shri Mataji: What yoga are you doing?
Man: Now, I’m just saying that now, I’m perfectly all right.
Shri Mataji: What was that you did? What yoga did you do?
Man: Well, as a matter of fact, I’m not following any yoga as such
but I have studied Patanjali.
Shri Mataji: Patanjali, all right.
Man: And, then when I met … Now the concern is this: that attraction
which I used to have some time back is eliminated.
But still, I do find a stern will within myself, to maintain that state of mind
which gives me lot of bliss, for that moment it disappears,
and then again I revert to that.
That is my personal problem.
I think I’ve tried to be very open.
Shri Mataji: Yes, yes, that’s correct.All right.
Now, the first thing is what chakras are catching?
Man: Left Swadishthana.
Shri Mataji: That’s it.
Now see, to do Patanjali was a mistake in the very beginning.
As a Mother, I must tell you frankly, all right?
Because Patanjali cannot be done unless and until you have some realised guru behind it.
If you start doing it, it is unauthorised, you see.
It is an unauthorised thing to do.
Like, supposing I am not a policeman,all right?
and I start behaving like a policeman, I’ll be arrested.
In the same way, you did it in an unauthorised way.
By doing in an unauthorised way you have started in the wrong direction altogether.
The direction was wrong.
And the bliss and all that you get it, is not the bliss that we are talking about.
That’s a bliss one gets when you shirk responsibility, you can get it.
You see, if you can get out of your family and children and all that,
one can feel blissful if he thinks that it is having a sort of a pressure on you
or a kind of attachment or something.
But in Sahaj Yoga what happens is that you become a personality when you are in the drama
but you are just seeing it.
You become a sakshi (witness).
That should happen.That’s the reality.
That’s how it should happen.
Once it happens to you, then you will just start seeing the whole thing as a drama.
Man: Yes.
Shri Mataji: You understand?
Shri Mataji: What is he saying?
Sahaja Yogi: He feels a slight cool breeze.
Shri Mataji: He is getting.Yes, he is a realised-soul.
Yes, he got Realisation.He got it.
What about this gentleman here, in front of you Marcus?
Question: (inaudible)
Shri Mataji: So, it should happen in the most natural way, in a spontaneous way.
And, God has given you that ankura which is called as Kundalini, which of course you know.
Kabira and all these people have talked about.
But it is a Sahaj method, it just happens to you, with a realised-soul only.
You cannot do it yourself.
If you try to do it, you will be making a mistake.
And that’s what has happened in you.
So now we have to completely sort of neutralise the effects of that.
And then we’ll raise your Kundalini by which you’ll get your Realisation,
by which, gradually you will get your vibrations, and you’ll start understanding.
All right?
So, you just now forget about what you have done, and it’s going to work out.
Then it’s a permanent thing.
What about his vibration Marcus?
Marcus: Vishuddhi.
Shri Mataji: Left or right?
You’ve got your Realisation is it?
I’m asking him.
Other man: Yes.
Shri Mataji: Is it all right? There’s a catch on the left is it?
Are you feeling something? You get what?
Other man: I have a slight pain on my leg.
Shri Mataji: Hmm.Anybody who has any problems about chakras, anyone of the Sahaj Yogis,
anybody who has any problem about their own chakras, please ask me.
Because next time we’ll be having lots of people here,
then we won’t be able to talk, so better ask me about it.
Dinesh what is your problem?
Dinesh: My problem? Hmm.
Shri Mataji: Agnya.I can see that clearly, from here.
You have to forgive people.
Do you understand that?
Forgive, and forgive.
What about her vibrations? Now just see.