yesterday I was talking about two things,
which we have to do in England, which one
should understand, you see. Because every
country has its own problems and we do absorb
the problems.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside in Hindi sounds
like “Left hamari aur kar. Left hand, ha.]
[In Hindi: Point your left hand towards Me,
point your right hand outwards].
Now the thing is our work is spreading very
fast and people are taking to it. In Europe
I find the land is much more fertile, surprisingly
and once people get realization they become
fantastic, I mean they think it’s something
that they have been expecting and they understand
Sahaj Yoga much better than we understand
here. Though your Kundalinis rise very high,
I’ve seen that, but the progress is not
that all right.
Now Ray has been to India, he’ll tell you
how, what sort of people we have in India
and how they have progressed themselves. Now
as I said the main problem of our country
is lethargy and lethargy is something we have
to overcome somehow and this lethargy is a,
actually a satanic force. It’s not lethargy
only of the matter that comes from material
domination on the Spirit, but it is really
satanic because it stops your progress and
is to be avoided. And to get out of it one
has to be really alert about it, how it crawls
onto you. Krishna has put, the worst vice
in the whole world is “aalasya”, means
lethargy. “Aalasyso Bijayate” – everything
comes out of aalasya. According to Him, first
the lethargy comes in and because of lethargy
we get into vices and then we go to the right
side also because of lethargy. Because just
to avoid the lethargy we go to the right side
too much. So according to Him everything starts
with lethargy and then the person loses the
essence of life through lethargy and this
is our special quality and that is our real
problem – is the lethargy.
Because Sahaj Yoga is a thing where we say
there is “akriya”. We don’t have to
do anything. It is effortless. Everything
works out effortless, spontaneously. So we
think that everything is going to work out
for us spontaneously. Only the Kundalini Jagruti
is spontaneous for the first time, not for
the second time, only for the first time.
That is I have to do it or My photograph has
to do it. But afterwards you have to work,
you have to keep your Kundalini afloat. You
have to understand what are your problems,
what are you getting into. I mean, individually
every one of you is a masterpiece, individually.
Because of lethargy you are clouded.
Secondly because of lethargy you are secluded,
lethargy gives you also ego. Because anything
that challenges lethargy you get on top of
that person, you don’t like such a person.
But the lethargy also those do not have are
the people their attention is not on spiritual
development. Theirs is as I told you yesterday,
on other things, which are not important to
spiritual life. We pay so much attention to
other things than to our spiritual life. Why
is it? Why is it we pay more attention to
material things, to material comforts, to
material achievements, to material obsessions?
Why? You must think about it. And why not
to our spiritual ascent? The reason is we
have been identified with matter. We have
been going through that circle. We thought
that we must have material development, so
we had industrial revolution, we created a
society dominated by industries, machinery
came up. We saw the machinery started dominating
us. We wanted to misidentify from that machinery.
Machinery has also given us lethargy because
we use machine made things our hands do not
work.
We have lost all the deftness of the hands;
we have lost all the walking capacity. We
can only take a bus or a car; we do not want
to walk at all. Now this mechanization and
the use of matter too much, has made us sort
of matters ourself. We have become matter
that we cannot live without it, it, yet we
are so identified with it. After realization
if you are still identified with the matter,
then your realization slows down.
So to, one has to understand, one has to understand
fully that matter is absolutely secondary.
Without of course getting your body you cannot
receive realization, you have to have your
body. But matter which is gross, is of no
meaning. Subtle matter is all right for us,
that’s important. Like this light, which
is burning, is important. Water that is in
the ocean is all right. The sky, open sky
– say here it is not so good but if you
go to a country is even better. The Mother
Earth say example here, I don’t know how
it is, but in India certain places Mother
Earth is very much subtle, your material identifications.
So matter has been identified with us, we
have been using it, living with it and that’s
why it is easy for us to get back into the
same circle of matter. And we get into it,
we pay attention more to it. Now if I say,
“Do not pay attention to it more,” then
you go on to another side, in a subtler way
you jump into vices.
Vices of – I can say uncleanliness, filth,
dirt, mismanagement. So from one extreme to
another extreme you go. Now in the center
what is matter, we should understand, and
we should try to then identify ourselves with
our Spirit. Now what is matter? Let us find
out. What is matter this. And what is created
out of matter?
Matter you know is made out of five elements.
You know the five elements, which have made
this body of ours. And these five elements
are on the right-hand side of the human beings
and these five elements either push you towards
the left side or pull you towards the right
side. I mean to say that when your start using
the matter gradually you become lethargic.
You become slave to it, it forms a habit.
If you use a chair then you cannot sit on
the ground. If you are used to a comfortable
life, you cannot live in an uncomfortable
life. Sort of it slaves you. Secondly, if
you try to overpower the matter, getting overactive
with matter, you make everything properly
and make everything nicely and everything;
you are over efficient with the matter, then
your ego develops and when your ego develops
you go into violence. Because if you produce
more, you have to be violent about it otherwise
you do not know how to sell it. You become,
sort-of an aggressive businessman or a country,
which tries to sell the matter, which tries
to overpower other nations with their material
advancement. With violence you go little further,
then what becomes out of you is nothing but
you become materialistic.
And materialistic people have no heart. A
materialistic person has no heart. He is just
dried up. [10.02] He only understands money,
money and money. He doesn’t go beyond it.
So too much attachment to money is also materialistic,
waste of money is also materialistic; mismanagement
of money is the worst of all. So to be materialistic
is your nature. You have started with it.
That’s human nature to be materialistic
because we have started with matter. But it
is also the human nature to ascend. As it
is natural to be a beast, it is more natural
to be a Sahaj Yogi. So both things are part
of the nature. Now which way you go is the
thing. Now the ladder can take you up or can
bring you down. If you have to go up your
eyes should be upward.
Now these five elements create what within
you? They create the five chakras within you
or you can say the six chakras are created
out of these five elements. And these five
elements, when they create the chakras then
they also give us a support to have the deities’
aasana, a seat for the deities to come in.
So they are important. But if you have to
give a deity a seat, you do not give some
sort of a filthy seat. You give a nice, the
best seat, whatever is available, to the deity.
So you must know that when you are using the
matter, see the auspiciousness of it. You
have to know the auspiciousness of things
that you are using, whether it is auspicious
or not. At random we buy clothes. At random
we buy things. If you could use your vibratory
awareness to buy your things to see what you
should buy, what would look nice because beauty
and auspiciousness goes hand in hand. They
are not two things. Because beauty is a thing
that gives joy to your Spirit, auspiciousness
is the same, which gives joy to your Spirit.
All other beauty is no beauty
So for a Sahaj Yogi it is necessary to use
all the matters, which are auspicious. Now
auspicious matters, whatever are there, which
are important matters must be kept at a higher
level always. For example say My photograph,
is very auspicious. Then you don’t put it
on the ground, then don’t trample over it.
In that also there are gradations of auspiciousness.
But now your clothes because you are saints
now, are very important. You are saints do
you realize? Do you realize your self-esteem?
You are saints now. What clothes you wear,
you are not vagabonds. You are not tramps.
You are not on the street. So you have to
wear dignified dress. I have told everyone
of you that, “Wear something dignified,
not indignified.” It has to be majestic,
because you are a saint now. You are no more
a person running on the street, you are the
selected saints by God. So the dress you wear
need not be absurd or something funny but
should give you dignity. Not any false but
a real dignity. You see the vibrations of
a dress. Wear your country’s dress. You
need not wear somebody else’s dress or something,
but the interest in the dress should be that
it should give you dignity and a sense of
respectability.
It is to preserve your respect that you have
to wear a dress. That is the utility of a
dress.
And now you go to another thing, anything
that you are using, for example your house.
Your house should be a house of cheerfulness,
a house of dignity where people come in, they
have comfort, they sit comfortably.
But too much comfort is against Sahaj Yoga.
But spartan also is not necessary that you
do not have anything to spread on the ground
or something. It should be comfortable. But
it should not be comfort personified, because
comfort creeps on you.
Comfort is one thing is better for English
people to avoid completely, is very good for
them not to allow the body to get into comfortable
positions. Specially bathroom addiction is
too much in English people I have seen it.
It is so much so I was so surprised that if
I go supposing to a reception I can tell you
whether it is owned by an Englishman or by
somebody else. If it is owned by an Englishman,
the bathroom will be done up very well, there
will be towel for everything, soap for everything,
I mean they are extremely particular. And
immediately I know that it is done by some
English gentleman, because they are very bathroom
conscious. Though they do not take baths.
I have seen houses with sixty bedrooms and
no bath in England only. Now of course they
have started. Bathing is not their quality.
But bathroom – they are very particular.
And even if you put an easy chair they wouldn’t
mind sitting in a bathroom. And as far as
bathroom is concerned one should just form
such habits, that within ten minutes you should
be out from the bathroom. Now when I say you
have to take your baths, that doesn’t mean
that early in the morning go and take a shower,
it doesn’t mean that. You should take a
bath at a time when you’ll have one hour
before going out, but that also from auspicious
point of view. Now you are saints, so use
water as much as you can. Wash your hands
ten times is very essential. To get your vibrations
all right, you must wash your hands. But now
in India there are people who wash their hands
countingly sixty four times. And I always
warn about the another side of it, like doctors
go on washing their hands. In the same way,
there are some people who go on washing their
hands. You need not take out the skin out
of your hands. But as many times as you wash
your hands, it is a good thing. I mean you
are saints but you are children. And I have
to talk to you as to the children who are
saints. It’s a big complication. While you
are grown up people and sometimes you might
feel hurt also, the way I have to tell you,
but this is important that you have to understand
that, “We are saints and as saints, what
we have to do as far as the matter is concerned.”
Now in a house there should be no dearth.
Dearth is not the sign of a saintliness. Miserliness:
dearth – you come to somebody’s house
and you find a miserable beggary hole. That
kind of a thing should not be. You must have
proper plates, proper things or a broken plate
somewhere, no. All these things should be
clean, neat, maybe handmade, or even if you
don’t get handmade, but they should be clean,
auspicious. If you can get handmade things,
nothing like it. That’s a very good idea
if you can get hand made things and if you
can use them it’s very good.
I think we went to see Gandhiji’s ashram,
didn’t we? You saw it was a simple place
but very well done, everything. And that way
Japanese are very good at these things; one
has to learn a lot from them. You have to
learn from so many people and because of Zen
influence, the Japanese picked up the aesthetics
of life. Very simple house they will have
but everything very comfortable. And they
know how to make the house look beautiful
and how to make people feel comfortable.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside] Matter is to be
treated with respect because it is created
by God. But whatever is respected is to be
respected – not everything. Everything in
the matter is not to be respected. For example,
if you see some sort of a painting, which
is, which is not auspicious, is not auspicious.
You should refuse to see such a painting.
You should avoid seeing such painting because
it is not going to give you any joy, any happiness,
nothing. It’s not going to work out. < Now
one of the things which people always tell
Me that in … “Sahaj Yogis do not have
a presence.” This is a very important thing.
The presence is done by matter. Now our presence,
if it is not all right people can make it
out. All things that are in us, if they become
auspicious will have a presence. Wherever
we’ll stand people will know there’s a
presence. And this presence is a blessing
of the matter to us. So you must respect matter
in the sense what clothes you wear. Throwing
clothes on the ground, throwing here and there,
living like a donkey, like a pigsty, is not
the way a Sahaj Yogi should live. He has to
be orderly; he has to respect his clothes.
But it should not be that you respect your
clothes so much that you throw away others’
clothes. The others are Sahaj Yogis also.
You have to respect each other because you
are all saints. If you respect yourself you
have to respect others. And once you start
respecting the matter, which is the essence
in you, that is attention. The essence of
matter is attention. Attention gives you the
presence. For example – recently Marie was
with Me. While translating Me, she suddenly
saw some flowers here and there, she started
putting them right. It created a very funny
situation. Everybody started seeing what’s
matter with this woman? But now she’s understood
it. And now I told her that, “When you are
speaking you should say it with full concentration.
Your attention, where is your attention?”
If your attention is on money, even if I am
talking about the highest things you’ll
be thinking about money. If your attention
is on something else, even if I am talking
to something, you will be thinking of something
else. That’s why our presence should be
such that nobody’s attention is diverted
or deluded. You understand My point? If your
presence is funny, like a joker or a clown
or a funny, untidy, everybody’s attention
will be disturbed. If you are overly dressed
also the attention will be disturbed. But
if you are completely a presence then wherever
you stand, people will feel there is somebody
standing, great. The respect flows, actually
respect flows. And it is something so remarkable
that you don’t know how people try to help
you then and how it works out. Your attention
if it is dominated by matter, people can make
it out. And that is one thing has to look
after very clearly because these are countries
who have advanced so much in material advancement.
So what happens, every matter attracts your
attention. You go on the street there’s
this one woman is standing or there is something
selling, this happening. All the time the
attention … You see it is their job to attract
your attention, otherwise how are they going
to exploit you? See, they will have no justification.
So they produce things, advertise things,
to do in such a way to distract your attention.
Now this is a force, which is acting against
our attention. So as far as possible keep
your attention straight, or on the Mother
Earth. If you can control your attention,
you can overcome your material domination.
Now the best thing is to put attention to
your Spirit. If you start putting your attention
to Spirit, the sweetness of the Spirit itself
will make the whole thing very sweet and beautiful.
The attention should be in the Spirit. Even
you are getting ready; keep the attention
on the Spirit. Now it’s not difficult because
Kundalini has reached that stage. Before realization
if I had said it, then you would have said,
“Mother, how to do it?” But now when you
have got realization, try to bring your attention
to Spirit. Means first when the Kundalini
rises you start looking at the Spirit or you
say when you get realization you see the Spirit.
In the sense that the Spirit starts flowing
through you, you start watching its flowing
in this thing. But then after some time, you
must enter into Spirit and [DEL: see,] see
through the window of the Spirit, the whole
thing by developing your witness Spirit. If
you develop your witness state, from attention
you become knowledge, the truth. Then material
things become the knowledge; aesthetics of
matter start giving you joy. You do not want
to possess it, but they start giving you joy
and even if you want to posses it, it would
be just to enjoy it and give it away to somebody
else. It’s like that. It’s for your enjoyment
and you want to give it away to someone else.
When you develop your witness state this will
come to you that you will not keep things
to yourself but you would like to give and
share, sharing. That is the time you should
know you have become a witness, because you
are enjoying. Witness state is the state of
Shri Krishna, of Virat. When you start sharing
your things then it
is a proper thing. Now the essence of puja
is also how to overcome our material grossness.
Puja is nothing but is how to overcome our
material grossness. When we want to have a
matter to ourselves, we must know that it
is given to us by God. Everything belongs
to God. Supposing we give flower to God, after
all it is God’s own creation, what are we
giving? We show light to God or do ‘aarti’
to God. What? It is all God’s light only,
what do we do? But by showing light to God,
what we do is to, we worship light within
us. The light element gets enlightened within
us. The light element is here on the Agnya.
When you do aarti, or when you put light before
God, when you show light to God, the light
element within you gets enlightened. When
you give flowers, Mooladhara gets enlightened.
When you get honey, then your attention gets
enlightened. So, why we give it to God, after
all God doesn’t need anything. But God is
the enjoyer. You are not the enjoyer, you
cannot enjoy. Enjoyer is God. In you, when
God is there that enjoys, that is the Spirit.
So whatever pleases your Spirit is used in
the puja to be given. Now you give rice – all
these things are discovered – that you give
rice to the Devi. Rice should be put in Her
lap. Now what is rice, a little rice to a
Devi? Is, by putting rice, in you the satisfaction
of getting food or food that gives you satisfaction
is enlightened. But that doesn’t mean you
start showering things on Me, that doesn’t
mean that. What I am trying to say, do it
with dignity and understanding. That you give
Me rice. Now, rice giving – these people
don’t understand why rice is to be given
to God? After all, why give Him palm leaves?
What is He going to do? If Christ was the
Son of God. What was the use of putting palm
leaves for Him? Or to give Him oil, oil bath
or to rub His feet with oil? It is for you
to get the advantage. Now in Sahaj yoga it
is proved now. When you rub My feet, you feel
better, not Me. You rub My hands, you feel
better. When you fall at My feet, you feel
better. She, she is a great – what was,
what is, what were you doing? Lady: Reflexology.
Shri Mataji: Reflexology. Big name, ah? Reflexology.
And she is supposed to know about the feet
and things like that.
One day she said, “Mother I want to come
and massage Your feet. I know this and all
that.”
So I said, “All right, come along.” So
she came to rub My feet. Instead of I feeling,
becoming relaxed, she was becoming relaxed.
The more she was rubbing she was getting relaxed.
So you see when you do for God, the blessings
comes to you. You are blessed. Whatever is
the problem with you, you give to God to solve.
Also whatever satisfies you, you give to God.
The satisfaction comes to you.
Now, these flowers when you give it to Me,
Mooladhara. They give you two things, Swadishthana
and Mooladhara. Flowers that’s why are very
important. They give Swadishthana, if the
flowers are beautiful, then they give Swadishthana
and if they are fragrant they cure your Mooladhara.
Now, I mean there is no end to flowers also.
But think about it, that you are doing it
to improve your chakras.
Then other things that are used like say ghee.
Ghee is used. It is for Vishuddhi. Shri Krishna
is very fond of ghee and butter. So when you
rub My feet with say butter, your Vishuddhi
will improve, you know that. Not Mine, I have
no problem. I have only one problem that you
are within Me and when you have problem I
have problems. Because these vibrations have
to go to you. So I prepare vibrations here
as an antidote and they have to flow. It’s
a very subtle thing to understand.
To move from gross to Spirit, this is the
thing by which you move, because first you
enlighten your chakras. By enlightening your
chakras, your deities get happy, prasanna.
By making the deities happy, you keep; get
a passage for the Kundalini to pass through.
By making the passage for the Kundalini, the
Kundalini goes up and then your attention
starts becoming one with the Spirit. It is
step by step, you move from matter to subtler
matter, from subtler matter to your chakras,
from chakras to deities, from deities to the
Spirit. Then Spirit enjoys itself. So there
you do not have to do anything. Just give
your Spirit to Spirit.
That’s why these things were prescribed.
Now people could not see this linkage. They
thought that, “Why should we give anything
to God? After all it is all His own.” The
argument started. “Why should we put lights?
There is no need.” But this is an escape.
Where are you, at what stage? You are at a
stage; you are at a stage where you have to
detach yourself from matter. Same with Sahaj
Yoga, I find it that you must understand the
complete vision of Sahaj Yoga. It’s a very
big thing you are doing. You are not small.
You are doing a very great work, because it
is “the” solution of all the humanity.
This is the solution of all the problems,
whether political, economic or anything, whatever
you call it.
Is not only that but the more people you have,
you will be surprised, I’ll work out much
better. Collectively I can cure cancer if
you are more, if you are clear people. But
your channels are so full of problems that
nothing flows through you. If you get yourself
cleared out, collectively I can stop cancer
spreading, because if you spread more vibrations,
what happens that the left and right side
in Virat becomes clearer and the attack from
the left and right side which creates cancer,
all these horrible diseases, will be less.
Because there will be less.
But you do not understand your responsibility
what you are doing. You are playing into the
hands of satanics. By not paying attention
to your cleaning, by not paying attention
to your spiritual growth, you are not helping
Me at all because these vibrations do not
flow out. They have to flow through you. If
I could manage them there was no need for
Me to run after you. It has to flow through
you, you are the channels and if you do not
keep yourself clean and humble and meek about
it, it doesn’t work out. You are not helping
Me at all by that. So the localized problem
of yours limited problems, should be given
up and see to the bigger problems that you’ll
be solving. I can stop the happening of cancer
completely if I have twenty-one thousand Sahaja
Yogis.
Completely, Cancer will go out of … leprosy
I can control. Cancer already I am controlling,
but it’ll go down, collectively also. I
mean the statistics I’ve not seen but will
go down.
It’s a left side attack and the more you
try to go to left side there will be more
attacks. Right side attacks are also lots
of these wars. All these wars and all these
things take place because we are invaded from
the right side. All these aggressive people
like Hitler and all that are aggressing us.
How much it is necessary for you to rise above
your lower self. One should understand that
and not to indulge into nonsense that you
are doing. You have to really work hard for
that. Even if you have to get up early in
the morning, you have to get up and do it.
You should understand your responsibilities,
that’s the main point is. People are now
busy only doing jobs, working here, how much
money you get, how much do you go, when do
you go to job and all that. That’s not important
for us. Now that doesn’t mean you give up
your jobs and be a liability on the ashram,
it doesn’t mean that! It means you do your
jobs, have money, money is needed for the
work. I need money, you know that how much
money we need for all this work. You have
taken such a big project of going to Europe
having this little money. It’s not possible.
But we are doing it somehow. So, we need money,
you have to earn, you have to give; you have
to give money.
Here people are, they are not even willing
to give ten pounds. Such people. With them
where am I going to do Sahaj Yoga? We are
so attached to money in a subtler way. We
do not understand we have to give money and
we have to do it up. Not only money, money’s
not the only solution; we have to be ourselves
channels. But then some people have money,
then they are exploited in a wrong way and
the money’s all wasted. This is precious
money, this is auspicious money, this money
goes into the right hands into right places.
Problems are created because of that. Now
this money I do not need, you know that very
well. But for your own betterment you have
to give money. Ask Gavin he’ll tell you.
He’s a very generous man and he, he found
it very good. It’s not that I need a single
pai from you. On the contrary I am willing
to spend My own money on things, you know
that definitely. But, you must understand
this work has to be done, so you need money.
I need not tell you that you have to pay money.
I have never said this to Indians, I have
never told them. They have never given Me
a problem you’ll be amazed. How they solve
their problems God alone knows. They are not
the people of money. There’s never a quarrel
about money. Nobody talks about money, nobody
tells Me anything, nothing of the kind. Nobody
oppresses anyone or mishandles anyone or controls
anyone, everybody does so well. Money is not
with one person. Say about two, three people
handle it. Everybody knows how much money
they are taking.
This one part is important. For solving this
problem you give Me rice. It’s called as
“Oti bharne,” that you give Me rice I
beg of you, actually. You put it in My sari.
Rice, you give Me five times, I give you seven
times back. That’s the symbol. You know
how symbols work out. Even when you say, “Mother
are you the Holy Ghost?” it works out, it
gives you realization. If there is somebody
so alert and sensitive sitting before you,
you must know how to do the symbols, how to
do them properly, with full maturity, understanding,
in the proper way. You are very anxious to
do the puja, but do you understand, before
the puja always there’s a quarrel going
on. Somebody who is a very possessed person
will come, to begin with, and everybody will
start fighting. Imagine! You must take your
bath, “What are you doing?”
In the morning don’t talk to anyone. Be
in hush condition. You are in for opening
out to the great power, which is going to
solve the problem of the world. So you cleanse
yourself, you wash yourself; you cleanse yourself,
so that you get your chakras evolved. People
talked against it because they became only
ritualistic, mechanical; matter became very
important. Then only doing these things became
important. But not now, you people are different.
You are realized souls. That doesn’t mean
that you should take to sanyasa or anything.
You should, I’ve told you, you should live
like normal people, but a very dignified people.
Nothing of indignity, childishness, superfluousness
or joker-like, clown-like, outstandingly funny,
all these dresses should not be worn. You
should be properly dressed in a way that you
have a presence. I mean this is to a children
I am telling you. You must have a presence
of grown up Sahaja Yogis, You are all saints.
You know such a lot even many saints do not
know. You can go and ask so many of them.
There’s one thing they know that I am that.
That’s one thing you do not know. They know
that. This is a big difference. Because I
am easily available to you, you do not understand.
For them I am great. As I told you yesterday
that how these saints have recognized and
they have sent people to help Me. In saintliness
only, your recognition of Me is poor. Because
if it was not, you would not be shouting in
My presence, quarrelling in My presence. You
give Me headaches, you tell Me things, which
you should not tell Me. “He knocked at my
door,” somebody tells Me. He says “he
came there, he did this,” another tells
Me. You should not talk like this to Me.
You are materially again bound by talking.
From where does the talk come from? Vishuddhi.
Talk comes from Vishuddhi, but it starts from,
the whole vani, the whole sound starts from
much below. So, to raise it higher there are
stages of this sound coming in. And when it
becomes madhyama, is in the heart, in the
heart region where it just throbs, you do
not feel the throbbing. Then it comes here.
Here it becomes vaikhari. Then it becomes
pashyanti means it sees, it just sees. Then
it becomes Para, where it becomes just silent
in the aweness of the presence. We have to
develop those things. But we do not understand
that all these things are our attributes,
which we have to enlighten and rise. And make
every part, every petal of our being beautiful.
If you start understanding these small, small
things, which are very important because I
am talking of very big things. But even a
small thing can close your eyes completely.
It’s a very big vision I have, very big
vision. And that vision can be done through
you people. You do not think that you are
ordinary. Otherwise I would never have chosen
you. But you have no recognition of yourself
also, as you have no recognition of Me. You
have to recognize yourselves and respect yourself.
Do not respect material things, respect yourself
first of all and the matter within you. If
[side 1 & 2 overlap in this paragraph] you
move that way I think you’ll understand
better what I am saying.
The body of a human being is a temple of God.
But this temple has to be enlightened and
has to be auspicious. You have to clear and
clean your being completely so it’s a beautiful
temple for God to reside there.
But we deceive ourselves, you see? When I
am talking, you listen to Me and you think
that “Oh, Mother talked very sweetly, beautifully,”
finished. But nothing goes inside. Why? Because
of lethargy. Lethargy is a thing, which is
a barrier. It doesn’t allow Me to go inside
you. It’s a barrier. It’s very sweet thing,
which smiles, just you see thinking, “Oh,
Mother is saying something nice, it’s very
great,” it gives you happiness and all that,
but it doesn’t go inside, you do not imbibe.
And that’s why, try to put your attention
to yourself and feel your dignity and honor.
Feel your presence that you have to have a
presence and when I tell to some people, they’ll
say, “I know, Mother, I know I do that.”
Then why do you do it? That means you are
possessed. You are a possessed person that
you know this is wrong, still you are doing
it. Then you are a possessed person. Then
is better you beat yourself with shoes. But
that stage should go now, I don’t like you
to beat yourself with shoes, I mean are you
that, that level? But the level is such still.
And your presence is the one that should give
Prasannata, is the cheerfulness to others.
Others should feel cheerful in your company.
A presence is something, which you can understand.
A presence has prudence. It understand how
to behave in a particular thing. It is not
imprudent like it won’t rush to a thing.
It won’t jump on to a thing. If somebody
is talking you just do not become absolutely
dominating on that. When you talk, you do
not talk in a way that is dramatic or sort
of theatrical; or neither you talk in a way
that is lunatic-like or something like that.
Presence has its own balance in the center
and that presence must be maintained. Presence
is very important and just see yourself: are
you having a presence? Some people are very
good Sahaj Yogis, but they have no “go,”
they have no dash, at all. They receive things,
they see things, they should have a dash.
They have to tell people, but in a way that
is congenial, that is sweet, that is beautiful,
that works is the point. If it does not work,
what’s the use?
Now again I am going for seventeen days. Really
seventeen days I’ll be out. I miss you all
very much and I feel concerned so much, because
you have to still grow quite a lot. I feel
that among you there is no understanding of
collectivity. A very irritable people; you
get irritable with each other, how can you?
You are all saints. You must respect each
other; you must love each other, talk sweetly
to each other. You are all saints! A saint
meets another saint, how does he meet? Have
you seen anytime, a real saint meeting another
real saint? You should see. You do not look
like that. The first proof is this. Are you
really saints or not. He has gone to India,
how they met you?
Yogi: Take really hold of me.
Shri Mataji: See?
Yogi: I couldn’t believe him …
Shri Mataji: How they meet each other! They’ll
hug each other and they enjoy each other’s
company. They laugh at jokes and understand
it is such a congenial thing. Nobody thinks,
“I am right.” Nobody thinks like that.
Once you start thinking, “I am right and
that person is wrong.” “I am doing all
right, he’s wrong,” finished. They enjoy
themselves so much just like one wave it moves,
you see? They are all the time laughing, enjoying
you know, loudly. They help each other such
a lot. It’s absolutely worth seeing that.
While we had only five or six people to begin
with, in [INDIAN PLACE NAME, SOUNDS LIKE:
Nilambar,] from London. One better than the
other. They are all fighting, quarrelling
and they used to come up to beating. Can you
believe it? This was happening. So shameful
I tell you and everybody was coming and telling,
“What sort of Sahaj Yogis you have got,
Mother? Are they Sahaj Yogis, really?” Arguing
and doing this and doing that. All sorts of
things were on and they would not inform Me
the whole of it, but part of it would come
to Me. I was so ashamed. Ask Malcolm. They
used to, I mean they would break each other’s
heads there. This was the condition. Can you
believe it? While you would never find any
Sahaj Yogis doing that, never, in India. I
have not seen anyone. Anybody who tries to
be funny goes out, immediately out of circulation.
There’s no group-forming, nobody fights
with anybody, nothing. And everybody was surprised
how strange these people were, one better
than the other. They were very irritable,
hot-tempered, fighting and all that. They
were so surprised that how can there be.
Give you an example here of Chhaya, see. Despite,
she’s quite shocked; but she doesn’t know
how to really beat things, meet. People are
so criticizing, so this thing, but she’s
trying to keep the balance. She’ll be always
at the back. She’s never in the forward,
when it comes to work she’ll be the first
to do it. She takes up responsibilities. This
is what happened last time. It’s not only
lethargy, it is worse than that. In lethargy,
you see it is a devil’s mind, and when you
come out of lethargy you just come to blows.
But as it is in India, I’ve not seen people
coming to blows, I really tell you. Very seldom
you’ll find people coming to blows. I mean,
people never even talk loudly or in a temper,
never. Now normally people are very quiet
type. Then Sahaj Yogis, Oh! You should see
how they enjoy. Oh! The girls and boys and
every one, the way they enjoy. Love seeing
them. You must try to enjoy each other.
Now the worst thing that can happen to human
beings is ego. Worst thing, possession is
better, at least you feel the pinch of it.
But ego you never feel the pinch. It is you
never feel that there is ego in you and you
think you are the most correct person, you
are the best person and the temper shows here
in the nose. I can see the “haw-haw,”
nose coming up like that.
Such ego, such ego, and this ego Indians have
also picked up from you. Those who have come
in contact with you, you see, as the dog when
he comes in contact with human being learns
many things, in the same way Indians who have
come in contact with you people have picked
up ego and we can see the difference. But
in simple villages people try to be nice,
congenial, good. How – by understanding
auspiciousness. An auspicious presence is
soothing, comforting, absorbing, beautiful.
And this, how do you develop? You should do
little aarti to My photograph is a good idea.
Now when you do the aarti also, somebody is
shouting at the top of his voice. He’s trying
to lead others. Then another trying to lead
others, this should not be. There should be
some, homogeneous, I can make it out, there’s
no rhythm. Sing in the same tone, same style,
try to make it one, one, concord should be
there.
In a humble way, in joyous way that we all
are singing, all our hearts are singing. All
of us are here to do it. So many of us are…
feel that joy, we are so many.
And it has a very bad effect on others when
they see you this way. I mean anybody would
be shocked. Why in India it is spreading,
because they see that love between the people.
Now of our attention if you take it to the
Spirit you’ll feel the collectivity. Attention
should be, as I told you yesterday, find out
how many times you have talked nicely to others
and how many times have you have been quarrelling.
If somebody says even a harsh word just keep
quiet. Do not feel bad, it’s all right,
it comes and goes.
Now some people are negative in the sense
that they are on the left hand side and some
people are negative because they are on the
right hand side. Sometimes these combinations
work very well. When a dominating man tries
to dominate a left handed person, they are
great friends, nothing like it. Because one
dominates and another takes the domination.
As soon as the left hand side person becomes
little on the center or tries to come to the
right, the dominating ones starts clashing.
Then they are the worst enemies of each other.
It happens like that, so be on the alert.
Now a person who is on the negative on the
left side, should try to come in the center
and in the same way a person who is on the
right side should come to the center.
Now how do you do it? Which is the way we
can do it? Let us see it. A person who is
very much on the right hand side should try
to become friendly with the left hand side
and left hand side person should try to be
friendly with the right hand side, supposing.
Let us start like this. So what is the give
and take in this thing? The person who is
on the right hand side will be better organizer,
may be, may not be. At least will be a better
orator or maybe a better sort of a leader,
may be, may not be, you can’t say. He may
be the one who will suggest things and who
will bring out things, who will say “I’ll
do this; I’ll do–” sort of thing, maybe.
The left hand person will be frightened but
will be humble, more loving, more affectionate.
He’ll be much more at the command of others.
This one will be commanding and the other
will be receiving the command. This will be
there. Now how do we solve the problem of
this mixture, you see? The one who is very
much on the ego side should try to obey the
person who is on the left hand side. And on
the left hand side should try to command more
on the right hand side person and should be
accepted. They, it should be mutually understood,
there should be a contract. “All right,
I am an ego oriented person and you are superego
oriented, now let us do one thing. You try
to dominate me and I’ll try to obey you.”
It will work out. It’s a psychological style.
You just work it out. Try somebody who is
a left sided person to dominate you. But rather
difficult to get left sided people here. They
are very few, because I believe some people
were left sided, but when it comes to ego
they are worst than anybody else, you see?
So rather difficult, but you can have a person
who is left sided and let ten/an? ego oriented
ask him to dominate. Till he develops his
ego, he’s all right. If he develops ego
stop it. But with complete understanding,
watching yourself, how you develop, how far
you go – a play should go on. Play with
yourself.
But if you are identified with yourself that
“I am always right, and nobody is right,”
nothing can work out. I can tell you this
much. Because if you are perfect I need not
waste My words here. So the best way is to
do this sort of a thing, “All right you
order and I’ll do. Come along let’s see
what do you think? Let you organize and we’ll
do it. You tell us how to do it.” So he
will use your heart and you will use your
attention, it will work out very well. The
combination will be good.
Let us decide to improve ourselves and not
to feel bad about it. We have to improve a
lot and a lot and a lot, because the relationship
between you seems to be so bad. It’s like
cancer – absolutely cancer. It is malignant.
So try to see your ego and if it’s a…
now even people if you have told them that
somebody says you should say “I’m sorry,”
they’ll not say like that. They’ll say
sarca… “Aha, I am sorry,” or something
like that. They’ll say in a sarcastic way
so that sorry also has no meaning. All right,
all right don’t say anything. This is not
the way. You should say, “See yourself.
So this ego has come. Now please tell me something
else, I’ll do it.”
Christ washed the feet of His disciples. Just
think of that. And that’s what a sensible
Sahaj Yogi does. He washes the feet of another
disciple. If you remember Aradhna, my granddaughter,
when you people came to My house. There were
I think about eight or ten of them. She got
a small bucket; she washed each and everybody’s
feet. Every time she would take it back to
the bathroom throw it away, again fill it
up bring it with great Spirit. She was five
years. She had not completed her five years
and she would wash everybody’s feet, wipe
them, again put back. She did for everybody
and then after that she came on My feet and
then she said “I’m not going to look at
anybody, I’m going to run away now I have
done my job,” and she went away. Aradhna
is of a very high quality Sahaj Yogini she
is, very high quality. But she thought that
this is the best way of washing their feet
is showing the essence of collectivity. “Some
part of me is not all right, let me clear
it.” For example if you think of Me and
you, you will understand how much I work hard
on you. Why? Because I love you very much
and you are My part and parcel. If you are
not all right I’m not going to be all right.
If you consider then, you will never think
somebody is lower than you. Is better to wash
the feet of someone than to wash your own
feet, will be a good idea. Put down your ego
every time.
Mohammad Sahib used this method. But best
was used by Nanaka: He said, “Let all the
Sikhs do some seva.” They have to, as a
punishment they have to do some seva. So,
what is a seva when there is a group? Somebody
has to sit down. Even one guru, very big guru,
had to clean the shoes of all the people who
came for the program. He was given polish,
brush and everything – very recently he
was punished to clean the shoes of the people
who came round. He was supposed to wash their
clothes, wash their things, as a punishment.
Anybody who is arrogant should do it. Anybody
who quarrels or fights should do it. Anybody
who is blunt should do it. And it worked,
it works. They are supposed to wash their
clothes, they are supposed to wash their feet,
rub their feet, give them a massage and feel
better.
In India if you see, all the Sahaj Yogis are
working on each other’s chakras. But here
nobody will accept even that you have these
chakras caught up. Have you seen that? Everyday
they are working, cleaning everybody’s,
they’ll say, “Baba, clean my chakra,”
they’ll say. Then when they do it they say
“Thank you, you’ve cleaned mine.” And
then they helped them, they rub their hands,
feet because you have done so much work for
them. This is not done here. I would like
to see more mutual understanding, mutual love,
mutual attraction for each other, should look
forward to each other. Try to help each other
than to criticize. I hate to hear any criticism
of anyone from any one of you. But when it
gets, goes too much is better to tell Me.
But you must judge yourself, “What are we
doing for others?” Some people think, “As
long as we keep quiet it’s all right.”
It’s not the point. Try to be nice, give
some presents, talk to them and there are
so many ways of expression of your love to
them. Give sometimes flowers, try to find
out what are the likes and dislikes of the
person is, is very good idea. Do not do things
that people do not like, sometimes you see.
It’s better not to do it. What is the use?
If the relationships are spoilt, not to do
those things. Just find out what you don’t
like.
A simple thing: my husband doesn’t like
Me to put flowers in the hair. But in Maharashtra
all the married women are supposed to put
the flowers in the hair, that’s a custom.
But because of I’ve married him, he doesn’t
like because in their community, only bad
women put flowers in the head; I have never
put flowers in My head. Only when it is a
special puja or they tie up – in Maharashtra,
there I agree. But I never make a bun and
put a thing. It’s all right, if he doesn’t
like it why do it? Unnecessary to increase
all the clashes and the problem. Don’t do
anything that people do not like you to do.
Try to avoid, it creates problems. Try to
do something that pleases others.
Let us see if you have devised this method
how to please. If you please others, your
deities will be very happy, because they are
all one, within you, within her, within her,
they are all one. And they feel happy, because
they’re all related to each other, and they
feel unhappy when you try to be unkind to
each other, because they are one.
If this is worked out, properly, understandingly,
all of you are going to be great saints. I
see your image in future also. Of some of
you are going to be very, very great and some
of you are going to take it up. It’s a,
it’s a project launched. Launch a project
against yourself, towards yourself, building
up yourself. How sweet you are going to be
others, let’s have it. Talk to others. Some
people just don’t talk, I have seen they
are all the time …[SILENCE]; they will have
very bad Vishuddhi. You must talk; you must
be nice you must be open-hearted. This Yugoslav
girl is very open–hearted, I like her for
that reason. She has a big heart.
Talk with a big heart, open! No secretiveness
and this cold, what is it called, English
manner?
Yogini: Aloof?
Shri Mataji: Aloof?
Yogini: When you keep yourself above people.
Shri Mataji laughs: Aloof. I think there must
be some English special word for this thing.
The way they are cold you know. When you sit….
Other yogini: Stiff upper lip, Mother.
Shri Mataji: Ha?
Several yogis: Stiff upper lip … Upper lip.
Shri Mataji: Upper lip? Upper lip, not so
much upper lip. There need not be upper lip,
could be pride.
[Yogi’s laugh and one make an indistinct
comment at which Shri Mataji laughs]
Shri Mataji: That kind of a presence is here,
[INDISTINCT: DOUR,] which is specialty of
English also, isn’t it? You go in a train,
they just don’t talk. I mean they don’t
allow you to talk, they freeze you with silence.
They can’t see people laugh, smile or joke,
anything a …[SILENCE] and you don’t know
what to do with them. Newspaper they will
read only all the way, and they will fold
it and read it. But they know each and everything
about you.
Yogini: Could it be called “insular.”
Shri Mataji: Insular. Ah yes! And is a very
dangerous thing for Sahaj Yogis. The one who
becomes insular is in for trouble. Is in for
trouble, insular. You know why, because you
are left alone, you’ll be attacked. Be together.
All these bhoots also know you are insular.
They’ll attack you. By any chance you try
to become unique, they’ll attack you. Even
some people become, by talking too much also
they can become insular, unique; you sit on
top of everybody else. Better be with everyone,
is better. Be one with everybody, congenial.
Take a joke from others. Other are joking
with you, you should not get angry. If somebody
joking with you, “Oh! Shut up.” Like that
one should not do. Take a joke, be a sport.
English language has one very good quality
that they can laugh at themselves, you see.
All the language has found out ways and methods
of how to laugh at yourself, that’s something
beautiful about English language. I don’t
think any language has so many words to express
these odd situations, which are very, very
embarrassing you see. You can only brand them
and by branding them, you know where you are.
You exactly know what medicine is needed for
this. You see it is like that.
It’s just branding, “Oh this is it,”
and it’s very interesting to watch these
things in the society and everywhere. Which
is described, even Charles Dickens, now example,
at that time he found out these things and
he said it. And I mean the description of
all these things is so beautifully done in
the literature that you are amazed how people
had a capacity to see themselves, the society
as it is and to de… Characterization of
people: how characters are built up you see
and how it becomes a social problem. It’s
beautifully done and that’s the wisdom.
That’s the real wisdom of British, I tell
you. I mean you may lose it if you start getting
dominated by nonsensical ideas, but otherwise
that wisdom you have innate. I mean to have
a person like Shakespeare itself shows what?
I mean you are a country of great people.
How can that be? Where some, they are not
“some,” there are quite a lot of them
and you are going to be the wisest because
you have the advantage of their creation.
On top of, you have got advantage of your
creation. Then/that? you belong to a great
country like that. Imagine the whole country
is getting into the mire of lethargy, who
is going to save this country? You people.
So again and again it is against lethargy
and whatever is lethargy is anti Christ, is
anti God, is anti Mataji. Try to become cheerful
and blissful, happy, dignified, sensible,
sweet. It’s not too many things, is very
few, it’s only one. And I know we are going
to enjoy life very much. You are going to
be very happy people. Take out your tempers
from your heads first of all, the angers you
see and to say, “I got very angry.” Means
what? Why did you get angry? To be proud of
your anger and temper and your irritations!
It will be very beautiful I am sure. You are
growing up, but the growth becomes little
dwarfed with these nonsensical things, you
know. So you have to protect your growth from
these things as we protect a small plant from
say frost falling on a plant. It’s like
that. Frost is nothing compared to the plant,
because plant is growing, but the frost can
kill it and that’s how you do not make it
a frost. Be cheerful. People come up and they
go down. I’ve seen people come up and then
they go down. Try to look after yourself.
[27:35 side B] [Extra 19 min on reviewers
tape:] Now after seventeen days I am going
to come and see you very beautifully developed
and all the time My attention is on you, I
work on you all the time. And I’m much more
intimate with you than with anybody else,
because these people see Me only for two days
and then they started crying! They’re lost.
But I see you so much, more than even Indians.
Is Paul there? Paul has come?
Yogi: Yes Mother.
Shri Mataji: Yes. Hm. Paul, what happened?
Paul: I want to get a message to, from the
people of India…
Shri Mataji: Ha?
Paul: …Apart from the – the people of
India send their love. But one of the Sahaj
Yogis in india has become very ill.
Shri Mataji: Who?
Paul: Professor [INDISTINCT: Manneh] in Rahur.
Shri Mataji: I know. But why did you get angry
with Dhumal?
Paul: Dhumal? By that time I’d really, I’d
had enough of seeing in India the way that
there’s two classes of people in India:
those who have a lot of money and those who–
Shri Mataji: And what about in this country?
Paul: Well it’s the same deal in this country,
but the people in this country who don’t
have a lot of money, at least they have bare
necessities of life. You know like a roof
over their heads.
Shri Mataji: You went there to do Sahaj Yoga
or to do these things? You see, what I’m
saying, where was your attention? Now you
knows, Dhumal has given realizations to ten
thousand people. And he’s your elder brother,
you should respect him. He has a servant,
because in India the situation is different.
If he gives up his servant, he’ll have no
food to eat.
It’s not that everybody use brain. You see
this is one thing in this country people do
not realize. If you use, you work much harder
than his servant, do you know that? Because
your brain never stops. His servants works
with his hand he doesn’t think! His energy
goes to his hands, he rests also. You see
here the idea is if somebody’s working with
the hand, it’s cruelty. But what about this
brain? The amount of brain you use all the
time – now tell me, you cannot stop your
thinking, all right?
Now see My servant, though he works hard,
he’s much more relaxed than My husband is.
My husband doesn’t do even lifting a, say
lifting a glass. All right? And what happens,
that one can say that this man is a lazy fellow,
he’s enjoying everything in life, he’s
enjoying all the comfort while the servant
is not. But My servant is, in a way, is doing
his handwork, because that’s all he can
do; his brain is not that developed. And he
has much more rest than My husband has. He’s
much more relaxed. Somebody is the hand, somebody
is the feet and somebody’s the head. But
if you do work with your head, is the same.
Now if you are doing work with your head,
you have to have certain amount of comfort
to your body, otherwise even if you have to
suffer on your body – of course I do not
say that servants should be ill-treated by
any chance, that should not be done – but…
And nobody gives your money to anybody else
like that. You see he’s paid for it and
he does the work with his hands so you can
see it. But what about the brain part, do
you see the brain how it works? I wish you
could have a microscope to see how the brain
works, and all the chakras, “cutcutcutcut-cutcutcutcut”
going on. One thought itself is a dynamite
and you cannot stop it, ask him. Yesterday
his thought going on like a machine! There’s
a machine here working out.
So, this happens and then one should understand
that when you go to any country, you are a
guest there… He was very unhappy and he
wrote a very sad letter to Me and that was
not good. You didn’t want him to be unhappy,
you w–
Paul indistinctly: What if I write?
Shri Mataji: Ha? Dhumal?
Paul: We didn’t have an argument.
Shri Mataji: Ha?
Paul: I didn’t have an argument.
Shri Mataji: You didn’t have what?
Paul: I told him what I felt.
Shri Mataji: Ha?
Paul: I told him what I felt, I just went,
I just… you know the most, quite a lot of
places in India. And–
Shri Mataji: You, what did you feel?
Paul: Well I felt that if somebody’s telling
me how many houses they’ve got and how many
houses they’re buying, when their servant
doesn’t have a roof over his head, when
the roof leaks and the children–
Shri Mataji: Now, supposing, here people have
so many houses which are lying empty, here,
in England. Do they give their houses to you
people? Do they? Is there any way? How many
people you should give also, is there any
system by which you should give?
See that is not Dhumal’s problem, is the
problem of the government. Dhumal has houses,
he has given a huge big fort to us as a present
to Sahaj Yoga. If he gives a house free to
his servant, I think he will make him a parasite
out of him. Do you know in India, beggars
have got big, big buildings? Do you know that
fact? Some of the buildings on Marine Drive
are owned by people who are professionally
beggars. So if you see some problem it has
so many deeper roots, which you do not see.
But, you just write a letter of apology to
him. I was hurt, very much, because he, he
has done such a tremendous job.
He is going to give a huge big place to us
for Sahaj Yoga. Nobody has been able to do
that so far. He has given Me ten thousand
people as Sahaj Yogis. And when you people
say, “I felt,” what is this “I,” what
is this “I”? I know you have a very sympathetic
heart, but sometimes you are swayed by it.
Sympathetic heart, to a point is good. It
should be prudent heart, it should not be
unwise. You must know the sense of proportion.
I mean that’s a system in India, which is
working, but you cannot do without servants.
Here also. What is happening to you, without
servants, you are all intelligent people,
why you live in a mess, in pigsties? Because
you are using your brains, you don’t know
how to use your hands. All these communistic
ideas are of no use. People have to do some
sort of a job, this job or that job. There’s
nothing wrong. Some people who can do brain
job, have to do brain job, those who have
to do handwork has to do handwork. Of course
there should not be much disparity in their
living, I agree, but that’s not his problem,
is the problem of the whole country.
But I tell you even to servants I have seen,
you give them something… There was a lady
nurse, you see? Once I was rather sick so
she used to come and see Me and help Me a
little bit. So I thought just as a favor I
must do something to her. So I sent her by
our ship to sea, I said “Let her have a
holiday, she’ll be all right.” So I sent
her to Africa. I mean the problems are much
deeper than you understand. I sent her to
Africa. You know, she came back and she started
telling the doctor off. She thought she has
become the doctor.
And the doctor told Me, “Why did you do
it?” They get into imbalances. You see,
even to poor persons, if you give them something
like that, they go into imbalances.
I’ll give you another very concrete example.
My husband, who is very socialistic in his
approach, and is a good thing, so what he
did, was to increase the pay of the drivers.
You see the drivers started getting one thousand
Rupee, which was very, very big amount. And
the lowest clerk gets about say twelve hundred.
So there was a very little disparity. Now
the driver’s getting one thousand Rupees,
was too much. Within six months their wives
came to Me. They said, “This was a very
wrong thing he did to our husbands. They have
got keeps now; they have started drinking;
they have started not giving any money to
us.” So to poor people if you give them
more money, they do not know how to use it,
they will be drinking. Poor people drink much
more than the rich people. So they had to
be trained how to use money. You just give
them money is no use. You do not understand
the deeper… thing… People are to be brought
up properly.
Like we have got in India Schedule Caste – I
agree Schedule Caste is a nonsense, it should
not be there, you should not treat somebody
as a lower caste, is all right. But what they
have brought into now, suddenly, that Schedule
Caste must have equal seats, equal rights
in every job and everything, whether they
are qualified or not. So you have got people
who are not qualified, or even in exams, in
the colleges, you must have so many Schedule
Caste.
Now what has happened, by doing this kind
of a top-heavy work, some muck has come up,
and they are absolutely useless people, they
cannot do administration. Instead of that,
what Ghandiji had said, that, “Train them
up, educate them, bring them up.” Suddenly
the educated people are there and some people
suddenly, uneducated, nothing, brought to
that, they cannot bear it.
Now we had a servant with us who came to Me,
who was a – you must be knowing him, Paramshivam
– who came down here. And he used to, he
was getting hardly hundred Rupees there, we
gave him a big pay and everything, when he
came here he started misbehaving. Then his
mother, when I wrote to them that, “He’s
misbehaving, I don’t know what to do. He
has developed all bad habits.” He was buying
pornography pictures here, going to the pub,
then having girlfriends and doing all sorts
of things, he started here. So when I wrote
to his mother, what his mother wrote to Me
is very interesting to read. She said, “Those
people who live in mud, if they have to sleep
on a bed, it hurts them. So suddenly giving
them something materially is not going to
improve him. You have to train them up. You
do not know what problems there are of poverty.
Poverty is just like leprosy. Leprosy: you
know what the leprosy parasites eat? They
eat petrol; they thrive on petrol. So gross
it is.
And then, you being an Englishman should not
have said it, because English are responsible
for the poverty of India, you like it or not.
They have created this problem for us, we
didn’t have this problem before. Our servants
were part and parcel of our house. They treated
us just like slaves, so we have got this idea
from them.
How they treated us! I must say Dhumal was
very decent not to say this to you, but this
is what it is. The way they treated us in
India, you have no idea. Even till yesterday
we had “White Clubs” where Indians were
not allowed on our own soil! When we were
independent, and they’re fighting for it.
They killed thousands of people, raped so
many woman there. “We English” should
not say that, in that country were we have
ruled and made them slaves. You see they did
not allow us to come up. What are you doing
to foreigners here who are coming up? How
you treat them? What racialism you have here
compared to what we have in India, we have
no racialism. They treated you with such great
respect. They should have said, “You are
white, so ‘racialism,’ all right we’ll
ill-treat you.” But if you go to Africa
they will teach you. Africans, West Indies
– they are on top of you. What I’m saying,
to break the vicious circle try to understand
the problem of every country. From where does
this problem come to India, and to most of
the countries who are underdeveloped. The
French, they dominated also many countries.
This is also, one should understand that we
should not dominate any more. We should wash
their feet, that’s what it is.
Now you have killed the culture of all the
Africans and Africans have taken to all French
and English culture. Absolutely, they have
prostitutes the same way you have, they have
the women the same way you have; their ideas
of liberation’s the same, only the Indians
have resisted you. Otherwise everywhere you
have never respected anybody’s culture or
anything. You have to face it. If you go to
South America, you’ll be shocked the way
people have wiped out all the… all the people
who lived there; all of them, one and all.
Except for Columbia, can you imagine? Every
country, every soul has been wiped out. Just
see that.
Of course if he was ill-treating him I can
understand, but he doesn’t ill-treat. These
ideas are Western ideas; they’re applicable
to you people, not to Indians. And this is
the big mistake people are doing is to put
your ideas onto us. For example in field reforms,
you see? My son-in-law is a very enlightened
fellow, he had twenty-five miles, square miles
of area of his own. But he used to get his
labor from all these areas, he used to provide
them everything, he used to pay them very
well; they were living very well. Suddenly
the idea came, “No. They must have their
own land holdings,” all right – without
understanding that they are to be trained,
they are to be brought up, they are not educated,
there must be communication – so everybody
was given a one patch here and a one patch
there and a one patch there and a one patch
there. What happened, that they started getting
strangulated in those areas. There was no
way of communication to them, they could not
get their wheat, they could not get their
seeds, they could not do anything, they started
starving. And they came to My son-in-law that,
“You come forward, you are the one who was
the agency in between and you should have
done it.” But they removed the agency and
without training these people.
Ghandiji suggested these things. He said that,
“You must enlighten the rich people and
you must also try to emancipate these people
by education, by making them understanding,”
and all that. There is a huge, areas in India,
which are called as “Backward Areas,”
where these aboriginals live. They do not
believe in any sedentary habits, they are
like, what you call the gypsies. So what they
do, these people plough their fields and all
that, and they come in the night and plunder
it. And they live like that. And they have
been living like this and they feel very happy
about it. They second is this (?), the so-called
poor of India. You must see how leprosy grows
also. They started in Maharashtra a scheme
by which they said, “We will provide you
jobs and otherwise we’ll give you a dole.”
Now this is the worst thing that can happen
to anyone; that we have realized very soon,
I hope they have withdrawn it. So they what
they did – Indians as it is they are very
cunning and clever – so what they did they
would go and write their names as the people
who are doles, getting doles, you see? And
they would work somewhere and get the dole
as well, double money. Then they would go
and drink. What are these people doing, but
to drink? It’s such a problem, prohibition;
they, they drink iodine, they drink, what
you call this… What do you eat, drink for
this thing, it’s some sort of sulphuric
acid or some sort of an acid they drink? I
don’t know?
Various yogis: Meths… Methylated Spirits.
Shri Mataji: Methylated or whatever… [laughs]
I don’t know! I don’t understand. So,
you see they are so foolish, what I am saying
that taking up anything like that at random
is not good.
And I was sorry because his wife wrote to
Me, “How much they have done for Sahaj Yoga.”
The only solution is Sahaj Yoga. There’s
no other solution, which he has helped Me
a lot.
“You see,” and he was very sorry he said
that, “How am I to do without servants?”
You see the servant system is like that. If
he gives roof to everyone he’ll be left
with no house. There’s not done, this kind
of generosity’s not done anywhere. If there
was such an agency like that, which was doing
such a work, it is possible.
Even the so called communists everywhere,
wherever they are in a democracy, have their
own properties. Once the democracy will go
away they won’t be able to even talk.
But I do not say that Capitalism is the solution;
I say Sahaj Yoga is the solution, all right?
It is the Sahaj Yoga and he’s done so much
for Sahaj Yoga. For that servant we cannot
in any way insult him; servant is not important
for us, who is the servant? Who are these
poor people to us? We are not responsible
for them, the state is responsible. We are
responsible for Sahaj Yogis, because they
are the people who make the difference.