But if your attention is passing through the centre
of the Agnya chakra
you don’t see any light.
But if it is not passing through that,
then what happens, because your attention is outside,
you see the light.
Because it is enlightening also, you see.
And you just see the light but the Kundalini is not passing through,
just it’s stuck up there.
And that’s why, because of that light,
your eyes go on like that, you see.
People have seen even a complete flow of light
moving up like that.
But they have not felt the Realisation.
They saw it coming up to the Agnya
and then the whole thing drops back.
They saw it!
They saw the Kundalini how it was helping,
the Adi Kundalini was helping your Kundalini – they saw it.
Even this light rising is because of that. Because your attention is still outside, you see.
So you go on, the flickering of the eyes starts.
Then I tell you to fix up your eyes onto my finger.
When you fix it up onto my finger and my face,
what happens the chaitanya pushes you, through your eyes, into the centre, you see.
So that you see me as I am.
But the eyes are controlled by the chaitanya
and the attention that is inside is pushed inside that,
what you call the apparition, in the Agnya chakra
So I always say that if you are flickering your eyes,
please pay attention to me, so that the chaitanya works out through your eyes
and fixes your attention to pass through.
Because the light starts spreading on all the sides and you see that light and the eyes go on like that;
you cannot close your eyes.
Which is, that is the reason for that.
Then the second thing you said that
you are facing:
your Sahasrara was on the thing.
Yes, one of the reasons for nirvichara is that.
But also nirvichara is a way to express the blessings of your Mother.
When She wants to bless you. See, you wrote the letter She was happy.
Just to bless you, you became nirvichar.
You see, it’s a blessing.
That’s how you get the grace, you see, that comes to you from your Mother,
that you become nirvichar, that's that one has to recognise.
If you do the things that I tell you,
I feel I bless you very much,
because they are for your good,
for your kalyana
for your mangal (auspiciousness)
and that’s why you are blessed and that blessing you feel as nirvichara.
Because I am Nirvichara myself.
Yes. Come along.
I’m Douglas Fry, one of the early Sahaja yogis from London.
And what I would like to say is,
it’s rather amazing the way that the forces of good
and the forces of bad
have nevertheless, pushed us towards Mataji.
Now the person that introduced us to Mataji,
as you have heard from Gavin,
was a yoga ‘playboy’. Now....
And who was that?
A yoga playboy.
A guru or something.
Yes, he was, he was no doubt, and is still!
The reason he came to England…
…was to make some money out of yoga!
The reason he came to England was because he’d seen this particular fake guru
with the long hair, that looked like a pop star.
He told me, and I think he might have told some of the others of us,
that this particular guru had said to him,
“You should go to England.”
So, obviously he came to England and started yoga classes.
Now, where the yoga classes started
was the last place that you could teach yoga because it was very, very cold
and we started in winter,
and there was no heating on.
But for some reason, the yoga classes still went on.
Now, eventually,
he met Mataji and tried his experiment on us.
And we all felt coolness in the hands, we all got Realisation.
Now, another thing that this yoga playboy had tried
was Transcendental Meditation, I found out.
Now, after us having got Realisation,
he tried to teach us meditation
and the technique that he was trying to do
was a technique used by TM.
The TM people, they give you a mantra, they might make the mantra up themselves.
Or sometimes they give you names that sounds a bit like Sanskrit.
In fact, I heard one fellow who had a mantra that sounded like “key ring”.
"Keyring!"
If you pronounce it strangely it can sort of sound like...
If you pronounce it strangely, it can sound a bit like Indian
but that’s neither here nor there.
So this fellow was trying to teach us
he was trying to use Transcendental Meditation techniques
to make us go into meditation.
And he told us that we should concentrate on a word,
a word that we think is nice.
Now the particular word I used was ‘divine’.
Now we sat down there
for about ten... we sat down
for about ten or fifteen minutes to meditate
and I remember I had my head... I felt an explosion,
that finished in my head.
Now I did not know the time that it was
so I said, “I felt this explosion in my head, what was it?”
So he said, “Oh, I don’t think that was anything, you forget about it!”
Now,
once again, I think perhaps, just for a split of a second, I had achieved thoughtless awareness
and my Kundalini obviously had risen.
And then, at a later date,
once I was asleep, I actually saw my Kundalini rise.
So my head was full of an intense white flame
and then it went down again
and then it came up again.
And then I heard a “ting” from the top of my head.
That is a ting.  That’s not Kundalini, you see, this is the thing
This I assumed to be the breaking of the brahmarandhra
No, no.
This wasn't.
It is not.
This is what happens to so many people, you see,
that is always the ida and pingala nadi.
This is?
This is ida pingala
Oh, I see, pardon me.
The sympathetic.
That works out and it looks like Kundalini.
But you don’t get any vibrations in the hand or head. It looks like.....
You know, some people get a big hole here, down below.
Especially this Muktananda he does like that.
And they get a feeling like that you know.
You should never feel the Kundalini rising like an explosion in a block like that.
Oh, I see
Later on, after Realisation, you may feel the slow movement.
But normally in Realisation you do not
Well, anyway, that’s all I want to say.
Thank you very much.
What about Sahaj Yog?
Well, anyway, after all this experience
initially of course I was in quite a mess, I used to take drugs and drink as many of the Western people seem to do these days.
And gradually I found,
after being exposed to Mataji’s love and Mataji’s influence,
I found that gradually my interest in drugs,
my interest in drinking and smoking, it all dropped out
and I gradually became more and more stable.
And now, I find that life for me is very settled and…
you can give Realisation.
I find that I can give Realisation to people and it's...
I can cure also.
And yes, also I have to say I can cure people
and I find it... the first time I gave Realisation to somebody, I was quite amazed
and just to realise I could do such a thing.
But now, to give Realisation it’s still, you know,
it still makes me feel very nice and clean inside,
and it’s just, just wonderful.
This kind of experience many people get,
like Shri Krishna also had like that and so many people get a feeling like that,
that something goes up, suddenly shoots off,
and you feel exploded and opened out and all that.
But that is not the Kundalini.
It is the sympathetic nervous system
which is very much in strain.
You see her strain.
And in that expression of that strain, what happens
that the whole thing, the energy of the complete sympathetic,
whatever they have in the parasympathetic is sucked in,
into the sympathetic.
Because the sympathetic is too much activated, you see.
Then what happens the parasympathetic system has
your stored up energy, whatever it is.
So it just sucks in all that
and when it is sucked in,
suddenly, the wave from the pelvic plexus, down below starts.
Because, you see, all the energies are released to the sympathetic.
Because the sympathetic is so exhausted
that whatever is the energy left in the chakras is released.
Once it is released, you see,
all that released energy you see, makes you feel
that the energy is rising within you because it is rising through ida and pingala.
Now this is the energy which is just sucked into ida and pingala. It rises up.
And you can feel it going up and coming down and all that.
But the after effects of this one is this,
that such a person – of course in these experiences people feel sometimes a horrible thing also,
that they feel that there’s a heat liberation,
sometimes they feel some sort of a scorpion bites going on
or some snakes coming up and all kind of things can happen in this.
It can be very horrifying also, this one,
and could be very simple also.
But when this happens, the after effect is like that, that you become arbitrary.
It is sort of all this drugs system started after that,
because once you are released from that self-control in between,
you can take to anything like this,
because you are free now to do whatever you please you see.
And that’s how you can take to drugs and things.
And this is what all these gurus are doing,
is to take out this stored energy which is controlling you,
suck them out onto the sympathetic.
There are so many ways by which they can do it:
they can starve you,
they can make you work very hard,
they can make you tired,
they can make you say some mantras, things. I mean they make your sympathetic work so hard
that ultimately a stage is reached where
your chakras release all the energy that is stored in them
and just get out of it, you see.
So all this energy they will suck in and a person feels: “Oh, suddenly something has happened!”
But in these circumstances, you see, you may have a big hollow in the head like that,
as if, like a mad person has, here, a big hollow.
And the whole thing is sucked in and you get a hollow there like that.
So many people get this thing,
that is a very different thing. But because all the energy that was inside is sucked in.
So it has become like a big hollow inside, you see.
Like a mad person has too, the same thing.
So this is the way people confuse between Kundalini awakening and the exhaustion of the sympathetic.
Normally the Kundalini awakening through Sahaj Yoga, you do not feel anything.
It just goes up and works out.
But sometimes, if there is, after Realisation,
if there is an obstruction due to certain combinations,
it may be the obstruction may go out like that.
But there’s a tremendous difference between the two.
That first, you release in the hands, of the vibrations, start with that.
But with the first one you do not get, on the contrary, you get heated up
and you start avoiding yourself, escaping from yourself.
And this starts. And that’s how you get into these drugs
This is very much played by the gurus. You see, that’s what they do to you.
They exhaust you completely, so that you cannot withstand reality and the present moment.
And so you try to get into something.
And once you try to escape it, you see, you just...
the whole release of the stores and parasympathetic takes place
and the Deities are broken
and you are broken, you become arbitrary.
It’s a cancerous sort of a thing.
So that’s not Kundalini awakening but we would say,
it is more a sympathetic system which comes into play
and the movement of peristaltic, what you call that ‘pumping’ up.
Peristaltic movements of the pumping up of the energy starts.
They start putting it into the thing.
And the whole thing is sucked in because of the exhaustion.
So one should not confuse between the two.
Because after Realisation you cannot take to drugs and things easily.
It’s very difficult..
You have to really force yourself to take to drugs.
Mother, you just answered now something that I never questioned because after I met you I did not want to question it.
I had, two years before meeting you, I had an extremely powerful experience of the same kind…