May God bless you all.
And all the blessings of Lakshmi,
all the Ashta Lakshmis upon you.
May God bless you.
I want to see all of them.
In the night I need it,
not in the day time.
Today we have come here to celebrate
a great festival of Deepavali,
meaning the rows of lights,
or the festival of lights.
Somebody has to translate.
It was to celebrate the coronation
of Shri Rama also,
that is to say symbolically to celebrate
the establishment of a kingdom
which has a benevolent
administration.
Today I find all of you here
as the lights sitting before Me.
And with these lights I feel
the Deepawali really celebrated,
I see the twingling of those eyes,
twinkling in the eye
of that light which is within you.
In the lamp of light we have to put
something that is soft, like ghee,
that’s something very mild and soft,
is the love of our heart.
And that burns to give this soothing
light of love to others.
Such a person who has this light
of love, loves himself as well,
and emits love for others.
I’ve been hearing about the way people
used to torture themselves
to become saintly.
There’s no need at all for sahaja yogis
- at all - to torture themselves.
But to be the light of a higher
magnitude,
they have to be full of love.
And this love they get it
from where?
You may say it is from Me,
is true, but the sap of the tree
flows all over,
and all the tree must live
together.
Any leaf that wants to separate itself
will die out.
So is the collectivity which is going
to make you grow.
Any ideas which you have of keeping
yourself out,
or preserving yourself out, or having
your houses separate
from the collectivity, may be
dangerous.
The houses may be separate, but they must
be the houses of all the sahaja yogis.
Anybody who comes to your house,
who is a sahaja yogi,
is owner of that house.
That sort of a feeling should be
developed,
when the light you take out from
one room to another room,
it does not say: “This is my room
so I give light,
if I go to another room I will not
give light.”
Now, light is absolutely detached.
If you do not look after your light,
it will extinguish.
You have to look after it till it takes
its proper stand.
And once it takes a particular
stand,
then you are a strong sahaja
yogi.
Then they see the light
on your face.
And then you manifest light
in their lives.
This light, if you put finger on it,
it will burn.
But the light of love never
burns.
It dissolves all that is bad.
It rejects, it turns away from whatever
that is wrong.
It has patience
and it expels the darkness.
Darkness within and without.
Diwali day is specially meant
to celebrate with the lights,
on a day when Lakshmi
was born.
Now this Lakshmi came out
of the sea,
and even today there’s lot of Lakshmi
lying under the beds of the sea.
But when you do not understand
the real significance of Lakshmi,
then it brings darkness
and Lakshmi disappears.
For example, somebody gets
lots of money:
immediately he will have his first-class
bar in the house.
Then he’ll have his friends to come
and have drinks.
He’ll drink with them
and suddenly find that Lakshmi
has disappeared.
So wherever there is wine,
there is darkness.
And that darkness which comes to you
with the Lakshmi,
makes Lakshmi just disappear.
The whole of the universe, the whole
cosmos is so well-knit
that if you try to do one thing wrong
this side, everything goes off.
It is so well connected, like one bulb
fuses everything fuses off.
In Sahaja Yoga also, it happens
like this,
that a person who is enlightened,
and tries to be nasty,
tries to create problems, can make
others negative.
In the beginning it used to happen
very often,
like one bad apple can spoil
all the good apples.
But one bad apple cannot be corrected
by all the good apples.
One Hitler could make many
Hitlers,
but in Sahaja Yoga when you are
grown up and established,
then one bad man if comes, either he has
to run away or he has to get well.
A person like that himself he tie up
all his luggage and go away.
But the main people, the people
who are grown up
and who are matured, should keep
their maturity and assert it.
It’s in the form of light, again.
Now, if there are many lights
like these are,
and one of them goes out, doesn’t
matter, because it’s,
there are so many others
like that.
But if there is one light which is
matured enough,
even all of them go away,
doesn’t matter.
So the people who are half sahaja
yogis, or quarter sahaja yogis
have to understand that they play
no important role in Sahaja Yoga.
Everybody has to become a full-fledged
sahaja yogi.
Then it matters a lot
if a such sahaja yogi is sick,
or is in problem,
all the angels would run to help
them.
So today is a special day
to celebrate
the kingdom of God on earth.
As we used to pray: “Thy Kingdom
come, on this earth.”
And it has come today on this
mountain.
And we are here to celebrate
the coming
of the kingdom of God, as we have
been praying for ages!
And the blessings of kingdom of God is
that you get drenched in joy.
Joy which has no duality, like
happiness and unhappiness.
Is an experience of absoluteness.
And just that joy is sufficient,
you don’t want any food,
you don’t want to sleep, you don’t mind
where you are,
just in joy drenched completely.
There’s no place for unhappiness,
we have no heart for it.
Italians were known to be
melancholic people,
but now I find all of them are so joyous
that nobody can believe
that they could have been melancholic
once upon a time.
Not only that, but they are giving
so much joy.
The program should open our eyes
of all the Europeans to see
how on the stage they were singing
songs to Me,
and everybody in the audience
was clapping and enjoying it.
Because Italians are very humble
people.
And it is the humble who will be
entering into the kingdom of God,
and not the arrogant.
They’ll have to go to hell to get rid
of their arrogance.
This is something is very great that
we are celebrating Diwali here,
that in the place where people
are humble,
and they have the right to be
joyous.
They have the right on their
Mother,
they have the right to ask for anything
that they want.
This is what is surrendering.
Humble person means the person
who doesn’t have ego.
So to burn off ego, and to burn off
our conditioning,
we had this festival called Holi.
But now we have a new festival,
which is a festival
of singing songs of joy,
and joy alone.
In this Diwali day, let us wish
that so many people fall into
this ocean of joy,
and the ocean of joy has to expand
its borders, shores.
A sea never does that,
but sahaja yogis can do it because
they have ocean of love in their hearts.
So I wish you all a very happy Diwali,
in the sense
that you will enlighten more lights,
every sahaja yogi
should enlighten at least hundred
lights in this year.
Every person you meet, you can talk
to them about Sahaja Yoga.
Not about Me. Later on,
gradually.
So I hope you’ll enjoy your Diwali here,
all of you,
and we’ll create an ocean which
will expand, grow,
and engulf more and more people
into this joyous company.
Today, I don’t want to say that
I’m sorry because I came late,
which won’t be good on a joyous
day like this.
But waiting has so dividends
to play, pay
– waiting gives you another kind
of appreciation of meeting.
May God bless you all.
So we should continue with music…