That, the central one [channel] is the sustaining
power, means is the power by which we evolve
that means we get our sustenance as it is.
This sustenance that we have got as a human
being, when it is to be manifested on the
five elements that we have within ourselves,
the source is there, but we have to reach
it through its different elements. When this
interchange takes place or we can say when
we have to put this force outside, that is
to be done through establishment of dharma
on these.
Like a superimposition or you can say the
connection. Like you can say, say there is
sun. Sun is
the source of light and the source of light
has come to this earth which is created out
of the five elements. So the sun's rays have
to come. But when they come inside, in this
move, what do they do ? They enlighten this
world. But it's only possible if there is
Dharma, means the light is there, the rays
are there. The rays can be obstructed by many
things. If the rays are obstructed, then there
is a-dharma. So the source of dharma, the
spreading of dharma and ultimately the manifestation
onto the five elements is a complete thing
that is Void. This play goes on within us.
Our evolutionary power which has worked from
the very beginning, from matter, when the
matter got itself organized then we had carbon
as tetravalent, then from carbon the life
started, all this is
the work of the sustaining force. Then we
became human beings.
Now we have got ten dharmas within us which
we have to keep alright. These are the main
ten commandments. These ten commandments we
have to look after. And these are looked after
by the people who are the primordial masters,
as you call them 'incarnations' like Raja
Janaka, like Moses, like Socrates, like Nanaka,
the last one was the Shirdi Sai Nath. This
is the principle is there, is the primordial
master. Now, there is another principle that
is in there by which you receive it, this
is called as the disciple principle, the primordial
disciple principle, represented by the moon
and the sun, presided by Buddha and Mahavira.
So, this disciple element if it
is not in you, you cannot receive it. But
when you start getting, receiving it, this
dharma gets into you and then you become the
guru. You become the guru when this is completely
sustained. It starts as a disciple and then
ends up as a Guru. This is the Void part within
us.
First of all, as the human beings are, we
do not observe the first ten basic principles.
In this country for example, or in the West,
we have, we observe the five of them because
of law. In the countries like India they observe
the rest five, because of their society. So
in anyway we are lacking some of them. Five
are missing here or five are missing there.
This is
the situation of the dharma today. The gurus
and the disciples they do this connection
and then the matter, which is created out
of five elements, get vibrated. You can enlighten
the matter. When the dharma is complete you
can enlighten the matter. The rituals that
these people used which was called as siddhu
dharmic rituals they call it dudharmic, these
are the deeds of dharma, is to worship, to
do Puja and to pray to God and to do all these
things, prayer. All these things after some
time became absolutely dead in it, because
there was no Realized soul as a Guru and no
Realized soul as a disciple. So it was just
a joke going on, you see. It has no meaning.
Supposing I tell somebody who is not Realized
to give himself a bandhan, he cannot.
[Apart...]
So this Void is so important because that
is
how you establish your receiving eggs in your
being, the five elements within you, meaning
the five elements that exist. In Sahaja Yoga
we try the other way round stuff [Apart...]
Now, what to do? This dharma is all ruined.
It is. There is another way: all these elements
are represented in your chakras, different
chakras. So why not take the Kundalini through
these chakras and enlighten the elements themselves
? Even there is no Dharma in a person you
can do it. But then the Kundalini goes back
to all the places which you have missed. But
if you have been to some guru and you have
bent your head before him, then the Kundalini
stops at a point. It doesn't move it goes
here, there. It just stops, it doesn't move,
very difficult. You have seen the Void pulsating
so badly. It just doesn't rise it always goes
back into that bottomless pit as you can call
it. It's always sucked into that again and
again if you have not a good... so we try
to remove the guru from your mind by so many
ways. Deny them completely, absolutely so
that they get out of your minds.
And again raise the Kundalini and from the
innermost, the Brahma Nadi as they call it,
the innermost Nadi, the Sushumna Nadi, otherwise
you cannot reach there, from outside you go
on cleansing, cleansing, cleansing until you
reach there, you find you cannot pierce it.
But outside cleaning helps you in one way
that the Brahma Nadi becomes wider, the Nadi
that is in the center of Sushumna. If you-
there's less pressure then it is a wider one
so for Kundalini rising there is a better
chance.
But in Sahaja Yoga, subtlest of subtlest Kundalini
we catch, and thread it microscopically inside
and take it out. And by taking it out what
happens ? These chakras definitely get enlightened,
they expand. That's how we expand the Sushumna.
Expending Brahmanadi. This was- this is the
trick of Sahaja Yoga. Because this cleansing
is going to take too much time as you say.
The whole thing is to be cleansed out and
then it is to be released and then you have
to meet some guru who has to take it. So this
Sadhachar [virtue, correct action], whatever
Buddha has said, the right, the right action,
the right that he has said is the one that
is done. That's what it described. But that
doesn't work out with human beings, it's meant
for people who are realized souls. Most of
these religions are meant for realized souls,
you can find out. Actually realized souls
only took to religion before. Those who where
born again, Dwijah, Brahmins, who took to
religion. But the time has come for people
who are not realized also to take to religion
and to receive his blessings. Sahaja Yoga
is the only way one can do it, is to take
it in the suttle most-inner most Nadi, enlighten
every chakra, increase the size of the chakra,
pierce a little bit here, then again raise
another thread, then again the third thread,
like that, go on expanding.
Apart: This is it, you're alright ..
Better.
This is how it works out. In our case, I did
the same, I mean just talking to you.
Now the main thing about Void one has to remember
: there is no rationality. It's the hunger
inside the stomach and hunger has no rationality
: if it is hungry it will eat. It has to eat,
no rationality can satisfy it : if you are
hungry, you're hungry. And when you have spiritual
hunger, the same hunger becomes subtler and
subtler ultimately it becomes the spiritual.
First the hunger starts of, say, food, of
primitive things. Then hunger for sex life,
hunger for women, hunger for men, then for
power, then for money. Then the hunger for
spirituality starts.
When that hunger is concentrated and starts
rising without any rationality about it : you
don't know why you are seeking. Like Buddha
he had everything, he had a wife and his father
had provided him with everything. Still his
heart was seeking. Why was he seeking ? It's
the hunger that is not rationality, that isn't
explained.
And then this hunger starts and the way we
quench that hunger is Dharma. The way we keep
it intact is the Dharma. Supposing you are
hungry: you go and eat some poison. Then it
is a-dharma. I know you are hungry but you
have to eat proper food. The knowledge about
that is Dharma : what food you must eat, what
book you must read, what people you must meet,
how you should live, what should be your attitude
towards others, others' things, other's wife,
children, daughters. Everything related to
the other, all that knowledge is Dharma. But
it has no rationality. Like, you see, a man
ran away- say- with somebody's daughter, he
would say: « What's wrong ? » I cannot answer.
I cannot answer. If a man has bad relations,
say, with his own mother. He says : « What's
wrong in this ? » You cannot answer, there's
no rationality. It is wrong, it's a fact : « Though
shall not commit adultery. » Christ has said
even to have adulteress eyes is wrong. But
at the time, it was Christ who came. At the
Moses time people did not know this eyes business,
but Christ would see that and He had said
that « Those who have even adulteress eyes
are comiting the sin. »
So, how to deal with others ? Say, materialism
now : you are so attached to matter is also
problem with the Nabhi. Materialism is a false
identification with matter: all false [inaudible
word] with matter, with human beings, with
books, with all that is created is the problem
of Nabhi so you can understand how important
it's now. And the one that prescribes it is
the Dharma, is the Guru. They did not come
like Gurus to convince you and argue out with
you, they said : « Thou shall not... » That's
the commandment. Commandment means there's
not to reason why. It's a commandment. There's
no rationality in Dharma. Now, the one who
is dharmic does not think about sin at all.
Now, I'll tell you about myself, say, I go
to a party and they start a cabaret dance.
I do not think about it wether it is illegal
or wether it is wrong with this adharma, nothing.
I do not think but immediately I vomit. My
grand-children, you see, we one day were watching
the TV and three of them came vomitting. I
went and saw the TV and it was a horrid thing
going on. They just came and started vomitting.
There's no rationality about it : it is again
human sustenance. It is sub-human.
Like animals cannot feel the dirt or filth
we can. We feel horrible smell coming, but
those who work, say, in filth cannot feel
any smell. If you go near a factory where
sugar is produced you feel terrible there
get the smell of this molasses and you can't
bear it, but those who are working there,
are so much used to it that they cannot feel
it. Those who live in sin cannot feel the
sin after some times, they become insensitive.
But sin is a sin. So the insensitivity when
we develop within ourselves we become adharmic.
When we are sensitive about it we are dharmic.
On the left hand side, the intuition about
it, the auspiciousness of it, is the thing
that one has to learn: auspisciouness. Houswife
is to be respected, honoured and comforted
because it is auspiscious. A wife has to be
respectable. A housewife doesn't- hum. It
doesn't look nice for a housewife, you see,
to be dressed in a funny way.
Once the chief cabinet secretary from India,
his wife had come and she used to think she's
very young and smart or something. She was
wearing these tied jeans and things like that,
you see, and the poor husband, you see, looked
this side, that side. He didn't know what
to do, and she's, I mean -very big nonsense-
why ? And she came down in London, she was
thinking how she's great, smart, thin. And
they were invited to a dinner, you see, it's
real thing, you know, real thing that has
happened. And when this man was to go from
somewhere and she had to go from somewhere
else. So, when he went there, he said : « Where
is my wife ? » They said : « She hasn't
come yet. » He said : « No she was to come,
she's not like that, she's much smarter than
me, she must have arrived. » He looked around,
he couldn't find her. And there was a lady
standing, he said : « There your secretary
has come, she's standing there. » And he
didn't know what to say because she really
looked like a secretary and not his wife.
So the housewife has to be dignified and respectable
and she is to be respected. It's the part
of that auspisciousness. And the wife, that
essence of a wife is the governing so you
can imagine those women who stand for lib
and all that those who try to sort of say
that : « Why should we be respectable if
the husband is not, if he is carrying on with
other women I should also carry on with other
men. » You must know that you are being holding
that great position in the stomach, on the
left hand side of every human being. And that's
why the left Nabhi catches in England so much
and America, I think it's missing it already.
So, that is to ask to -- say - to a man, you
see, who is so developped, and so he thinks
no ends of himself, you see, and the civilization
where work is so important and money is even
more important than work is, XX ? to think
that a housewife's respectability is so important
in the play of the universe? Yes it is. Where
the women become dis-repectable the whole,
you see, that's the breaking point of the
society. There the human beings will start
destroying. That's the real atomic bomb you've
got. But it is so, I cannot rationalize it,
it is made like that.
All the Gurus have said : « You should not
drink. » Even Moses. Every one of them have
said it : « You cannot drink. », means take
any kind of a alcohol or any things that will
take away your awareness because that is the
place of your awareness. In the sense that
whatever goes wrong here spoils your attention
and if your attention is spoiled your awareness
is spoiled. The attention is here. The attention
is in the stomach, in the Void. So, how important
is your attention.
Wherever you put your attention, that works
out. When you are Realized, then your attention
is Realized. Wherever you put your attention
it works like a spade, it works like a sword,
it works like a loving hand, it works like
kiss, it works like a comforting heart. It
is an enlightened attention in your stomach.
You see the mother has a child in the stomach,
how it looks after the child, a little baby,
how it protects. All that is there, is given
to us through our Gurus, our own beings which
are our masters, true teachers. The stomach
teaches you, your stomach is your Guru. Amoeba
became a human being through this stomach
only, through the hunger it had. If it did
not have hunger it would not have evolved.
And the hunger teaches you, and when you learn
it properly then you become the Guru yourself
of the whole world and the universe.
Void, that' why, is very important and when
you have had bad gurus, you've read horrible
books, accepted them as facts and thruths,
then your Void gets spoiled, your attention
gets spoiled. It goes to wrong things. Attention,
when it works through your eyes, can also
go to wrong things. Everywhere wherever attention
moves, it can do wrong things if it is adharmic.
But as I said, there is no rationality about
it. Dharma is to be accepted. You cannot rationalize
it. To a point one can, but how far it harms
you, you cannot rationalize. Then the curse
of Divine comes on you.
Any kind of fanaticism or identification with
one ideal- like Muslims thinking they are
Muslims- they're adharmic. They're not dharmic.
dharma is that you have to respect all the
religions. It is a sin not to respect any
incarnation. It is a sin not to respect any
religion. And to identify with one, and denounce
of other.
So, give up all these false dharmas and come
to that one dharma which evolves you, which
gives you light by which you can see the oneness
among all these religions. As I've said before,
that
they are like beautiful flowers on one tree,
nurtured by one sap, adorned by one tree,
but fools take the flowers out, say that these
are our flowers and kill them. And when these
flowers die, uglyness becomes the so-called
religions.
So, in essences, respect all the religions,
all the incarnations. Fanaticism is absolutely
against Nabhi and against the Void, because
the whole balance of your Void has to be kept.
In a very subtle and subtler form you'll be
sticking onto it.
Say, you are born a Christian, so whatever
you may try you can never get out of this
feeling that we are Christians. You'll have
much more respect for Mary in heart than for,
say, Lakshmi. While, you are a Hindu, you
will have much more respect for Radha than
for Mary. That will be lingering on and lingering
on.
When you develop that balance alright then
you are dharmic.
That balancing has to be done.
So one realization is within you like this
and one realization is this way , among you.
and this is Dharma. Among all of you there
has to be another integration, a complete
integration of understanding. Whether you
are white, black or red. Whether a Hindu,
Christian or anything. You must know that
there is only one way that is the living way
of evolution and that there is only one God.
And all of them [Incarnations] are aspects
of the same God, and there is no quarelling
among them.
Why are you quarelling ? This goes against
the Void.
Complete integration works out in the stomach.
And when you are completely integrated, you'll
be surprised, rationality drops out. Automatically
it drops out. Rationality kills this integration,
because if your heart says something rationality
says : « No, it's not right. ». But, if
you take out your rationality there and just
see for yourself, then wisdom comes in and
you just do it whatever is wise and good for
your spirituality.
Apart :
How are you now ?
Better
So, Void we use in Sahaja Yoga in many ways.
First of all, we have to first of all see
the Void of a person, how he has got the Void.
You can see it, very easily because it might
be pulsating. Maybe not be in your presence,
I don't know, but in My presence it does.
But immediately you can feel the Void. The
Void you feel here, on the here or on here.
Now, just see these are the bases of all the
chakras. You feel the Void here, or here.
Bases of all the chakras you can feel, so
you can understand how important is the Void.
Now, if it is catching here anywhere or catching
here, then you have to ask the person about
these various points : whether he's a materialist,
whether he is a fanatic. But these questions
you cannot ask out directly like say : "Are
you a fanatic ? You hit me hard. "
[Laughters]
Not to be very, very clever about it. Now
how to ask a person whether you are a fanatic
or not ? Very easy. Say, he's a Muslim. So,
you just ask him to put your hand, saying
that : « Should I put some Kumkum on your
head ? » His fanaticism will come out immediately
: « I can't do this ! » If he is a Christian,
then you just ask him : « Can you put a Swastika
on your head ? » Cross he'll accept. Swastika
: « No, I'm not Hitler ! » That's how you
can make it out whether he's open minded or
not by suggesting things like this, you see.
So then he comes out with his fanaticism.
Then what do you do ? You do not condemn him
as a fanatic, no. That won't be Sahaja style.
You say : « Alright, alright, I've got it.
The cross, would that be alright ? Alright,
take the cross. So, if I say that cross was
first Swastika then it became cross, will
you be angry ? » Gradually it will work out.
33:03
But if he's a fanatic, you go outside and
tell Muhammad to be him nicely. He will do
the job. Shoebeating is very necessary for
all fanatics. Nice shoebeat. But fanatics
are one of the most difficult persons.
33:25
Then those who have been to other gurus also
will be showing up. These days you don't get
fanatics so many to come to Sahaja Yoga. Mostly
they are guru beaten. You see there are [frocks?]
beaten people, there are guru beaten also.
I mean, mostly they are guru beaten. [Laughters]
Then you ask them : « Have you been to a
guru ? What your guru has done ? This, that.
» If you tell them sometimes they can be
fanatically attached to their gurus. Then
they migh be angry. They'll do it, but what
to do ? It is sometimes-
It 's the food ?
Sahaja Yogi: Yes It is....
It's good they are lookin after the food very
nicely
[Laughters]
Otherwise if you have to cook also then all
your attention is there. So it's much better
that your ashram. [Laughters]
No headache, nothing, your are having a nice
time here and their food is ready, now serve,
come along, have your food. So, the right
time we are talking about Void. [Laughters]
I'll sit here .
Sahaja Yogi: .. the Nabhi satisfied
Shri Mataji: Yes, make the food also dharmic
and every thing.
Good. How are you now? Better?
Sahaja Yogini: Yes
Shri Mataji: How are you now?
[interruption of recording during the meal]
It's such a wide subject that I cannot cover
it in one lecture, you coud write many books,
but the most important thing about Void is
that, that once you are enlightened you become
dharmic yourself. The Dharma starts flowing
through your hands. These vibrations have
a capacity to establish Dharma. So, when you
put your hands now towards the five elements.
Say you put your hands towards the water or
you put your hand in the water. The water
gets enlighted, vibrated, but if somebody
takes that water it will establish Dharma
into that person. Supposing somebody is a
drunkard, now you put this vibrated water
to him, give him to drink. He feels nauseated
after drinks. He'll throw away the drinks,
then he will stop.
Some of you have noticed that when you came
to Me first you felt terrible nausea within
you and you felt like vomiting, sometimes
you felt uneasy, you see. So these vibrations
through the water now pass into your stomach
and they establish dharma there, the proper
relationship. It so happens that if you go
on taking this water the right-side is that
physically you feel alright and the water
can give you such a power, that you can never
get cancer of the stomach, cannot get any
trouble with the stomach. But left-side side,
which has greater power, this water, that
it cleanses you, your sins - and puts your
attention, fixes it up on dharma.
So, your attention doesn't do- you're not
tempted, that's how you've seen people who
come to Sahaja Yoga can give up drinks easily.
Because it turns your attention towards dharma,
then if you want to take drinks, you just
don't feel like after some times. You feel
like vomiting, you feel like headache and
all that. And it happens so easily. Now we
know somebody here he gave up all his drinking
in no time. Otherwise it's not possible to
do that, but because of this happening in
the stomach, now you cannot drink.
Just imagine. This is the great thing about
Void is that once you are enlightened you
can give something to the nature. You have
been drawing everything from nature so far.
First time now you start giving something
to the nature. And what you give to the nature
is so nourrishing to it also. Supposing you
give vibrations to, say, fruits, or to trees,
or to flowers. You will find they will be
ten times more, the growth will be much more,
they will be lustrous. And they will be very
juicy, very tasty and the whole atmosphere
will be different. Maybe after sometimes these
trees if they will be standing there everybody
passing that way if he touches that tree they
will get the vibrations also.
So maybe a tree may become a curer, something
like that. All those waters and all that,
we talk of « curing water » are nothing
but vibrated waters. They are vibrated. So,
if the vibrated water goes inside, you get
cured. So, this is on the left-hand side it
works that it establishes your religion within
you.
All the problems we have had is all completely
cleansed out by them. In the same way if you
enlighten a light now here. You have seen
so many times how you can enlighten a light.
So it starts going, see, both are there but
this one is working a bit. That one also is
going a little bit but this one makes a X?
taking out the blackness. It is because it
is enlightened. That is also enlightened,
now we also ?. But this one actually in the
hand is taking away the- If you see these
lights you can feel they're like pulled out
like this. As if, you see, the realized lights
are pulled out like this, straight.
And, I've been to some of these churches where
they have these lights and as soon as I enter
these like they're all going like 'kakakakakak'.
It is interesting to see how they start suddenly
glowing like that. But people do not notice
it because they do not understand why it has
happened, but you can understand that. So,
if you put the light, enlightened light - Say,
yesterday, the other day, we had that Havana,
is the enlightened light. Havana we had made
it enlightened, Jagrut. Then whatever we put
into it, you see, our badhas, it burns whatever
we wanted to burn away. What is the beauty
of fire is, that, say, if you have some mixed
up gold and you put into fire, you find the
gold will be separated and the filth or dirt
or whatever is inside, it will be separated.
So, this quality which is the right hand side
quality of the fire is becomes in the left
hand side is that when you go near such a
fire or you use such a fire or a light, then
what happens that whatever is unwanted in
you is burned away and you get the pure thing.
So it purifies. Fire is a purifyer and it
is a melter, it melts your heart. This fire
melts your heart and you feel the compassion.
So that's how every element can be enlightened
and this is the work done in that Void by
your Kundalini. Kundalini goes to various
places and She enlightens all these elements
in your stomach.
In the stomach the basic principle is of water.
The Void is covered with water, and in the
water there is salt and the salt is nothing
but is the Dharma. Is the Dharma, the salt.
That's why when we give you salt what happens
the salt that is vibrated goes and helps you
in the stomach. And salt shows it's own nature
there by absorbing all that is in you which
is, we can say, in the mobile there. A person
- supposing is, hum, has got a cancer of throat,
then he should take salt. If he has a right
hand side problem he should take sugar. So
these are the two qualities, you see, the
five of dharmas are done by salt and five
by sugar. And these are the best solvants
in the world as you know. So, all these three
things put together water, then salt, and
the sugar, they solve the problem of the Void.
That's why we use these two things. If you
remember Christ has said that you are the
salt. That means you are the Gurus. Salt is
the Guru. That's why he said : « You are
the salt. » Because you are the Gurus. And
salt disolves into water. Water is the Dharma.
They are the absorber, always have a water
of crytalization. The- it cannot without,
the salt cannot exist without water. So, the
water and salt put together means the ocean.
So Void is the ocean within us. That's why
it is called as Sagar. That means all the
oceans of the world are in our stomach
43 :30
and if you want to hear them sometimes you
can put your thumb in My ears and you can
hear coming [as one sound...?] You can hear
it.
So this is all the times socially churned
and out of it comes out all that is good and
whatever is bad is burnt away or washed away
or made to -- whith the air -- it is made
to be swept off. So the air element is also
there, air element that we see all around.
[recording cut ]
So the vibrated air is a very important thing
and it helps a lot.
[recording cut]
So I've talked to you about all the [?] of
the fifth Akasha, the ether you can say. That
works out when you are a realized soul. Then
you, you also vibrate the Ether. That's how
our, mean, collective work is done, through
the Ether, you see. Now, supposing I want
that you should get a proper seat [or ?] or
something
Apart:
Alright, take a seat up there.
Anything materialistic you can say, [oh, my
chair is going down there, how is it ?] I
have to just worry about it, immediately it'll
go [order some set?] - [Shri Mataji snaps
her fingers] - Alright ? So, Saint Michael
and Saint Catherine, both of them say now
: « What should we do ? We must find out
a proper place. » So, they take down into
consideration. They bring him down here and
find out a nice [place?] Is all done through
Ether.
Ether, is the..., when it is enlightened,
you see, then it communicates the ideas, the
things that shall be done, or the desire,
divine desires are carried out. And then you
are placed in His hands sometimes you are
surprised : « How am I here ? How are you
here ? How do I meet you ? I mean, I was not
to come this side and then now how did I come
? » All these things can be done through
the Ether which -even we get our television
and everything through Ether. But on the television,
if the Ether, if you, say, enlighten then
it will so happen, that a bad [?] program
won't materialize. It won't materialize.
It can work very dynamically. You cannot imagine
how these miracles take place. And real miracles
are felt- of course we do feel the miracles
of all the other elements but it's not so
obvious as that of the Ether because you're
suddenly surprised : « How this... ? Why
? » And it's everybody's surprised at it
: « oh, here in the plane, you get all this.
» So, this is done by Ether and it is so
miraculous. It is so miraculous that it is
hard to believe that it is possible.
Now, this Ehter works day time and night time.
It doesn't take rest anywhere, you see. It's
all the time working for us, means it's all
the time ready to work out the divine work.
All the time it is ready to work out the divine
work. It doesn't wait. It doesn't wait for
anyone to give orders or anything, it's just,
just waiting there. As soon as it sees that
this is desired, alright, nothing is to be
told, just to desire and you'll say that : « Oh,
what will be happening to such and such person
? » Finished, it's done. It is being transmitted.
The same Ether that transmits the - what you
call ? - the air transmissions which you receive
on the radios, radio transmissions. The same
one, when enlightened, does all this job.
He works it out everything. Everything that
you want it works it out. And there's how
the angels show their [ Shri Mataji searches
the word in Marathi] miraculous feats. But
it is worth noticing all that and watching
it, and witnessing it and noting it down : « Oh,
how it helped and how it worked out ! »
It also, ether when enlightened, brings people
closer to divine power. It arranges how [?] But,
now, one would ask what is the necessity for
God to have such complicated methods of 'enlightening
the matter'? Why not it has already the enlightened
matter ? It's the question one should ask,
I mean, I'm asking as you people are there,
so I'm asking you. Let's see the answer.