I bow to all the Seekers of Truth
I'm very thankful to Mr Henry Tsang,
for addressing you and introducing me to you,
that’s very kind of him.
It is the one the very rare occasions, where I have seen people in authority have understood my work
and have tried to help me.
Whatever he said is really very remarkable,
that all these greater people like Lao-Tse, who started Taoism,
Buddha, who was teaching Buddhism,
all of them talked about the oneness of Human Being with the nature.
And if you cannot combine nature with yourself,
then you cannot be called as an evolved soul.
In that thing I was telling him about Yangtze river where he comes from same state Yangtze.
That Yangtze river I travelled through with my husband
and it’s the one Lao-Tse has used
for describing a human ascent.
It’s a river which goes in different angles and makes lots of currents and it's very dangerous
to ply through that,
but they are having an... now a tourist arrangement to go through that
and my husband as he was in the marine time, they invited us to see them.
So in that the message was that, you see, you are passing through a very beautiful land.
You see across the banks, beautiful trees
and very beautiful mountains, which you see in the paintings of Chinese.
They are really like that,
but you should not get lost.
You have to go further, you can watch these.. all these beautiful scenes,
sit down there, enjoy yourself, but still you have to go with the stream.
And then you go further and further, it's described it very well in his Tao.
Tao means 'that it is' and it started showing such beautiful scenes
sometimes that I really felt that I should get out of the boat and sit down there.
But he was meaning that in your meditation when you are moving,
you should not get tempted by this outward fascination of nature also
but you enjoy, be one with it, you just see it, enjoy it
and then he says that the river flows closer to the sea, that is the ultimate aim of the river,
then she becomes absolutely silent
and she spreads out and then gradually she moves towards the sea.
It’s such a beautiful description
and I have seen it myself and I can understand the poet, how he wanted to communicate,
that how the nature should teach us, how to be meditative within ourselves.
Buddha always talked about the Central Path
and also he always said that our character is the mainstay.
If you don’t have good character, then it is very difficult to ascend.
These were the days when really this was the position.
In India there were horrible, cruel kings and then they were killing people just for land or something.
This was so much in India,
that Buddha if he had not come it would have not stopped
and gradually when the awakening came within them,
that this is something wrong they are doing.
They should not kill human beings for just getting some land.
What is the use of this thing?
Ultimately one king, saw the blood flowing through one river
and he got such a repentance about what he had done,
that he went to Buddha and told him that, "Sir please save me,
I am very guilty about what I have been doing and I don’t think I can live any longer with this guilt."
So Buddha pacified him and he became a Buddhist.
Now in Sahaja Yoga we have a way by which we become one with reality,
one with this All-Pervading Power.
So the first point, if is the truth, is this,
that you are not this body, this mind,
or this ego or your conditionings,
but what you are, you are a pure Spirit,
which is said by Christ, said by all these great prophets. Everybody has said that
and then second truth is that there is an All-Pervading Power of Divine Love.
You see the flowers of Sydney, so beautiful, one better than the other.
And see how they have grown.
We never think that there is something miracle about them.
It is a miracle, the way they have grown out of the Mother Earth with such a beauty.
After all we cannot do that.
Mother Earth has done it and we take all those living works for granted.
We don’t even think who runs our heart.
We don’t even think who digests our food.
What is that energy which does all these things,
which controls our heights and everything else that is living?
So there is a power of All-Pervading Love
and that is the one, which really has created us
and that is the one, which is going to give us our Realisation.
This energy that is within us is what we call as the Kundalini.
He must have told you about it,
is the reflection of this All-Pervading Power
which is settled in our sacrum bone.
Sacrum as you know is called ‘Sacred’ by the people who were Greeks.
They were not Indians and they called this ‘Sacred Bone’.
I asked the curator, “Why do you call it as sacrum?”
He said “We were told it's a sacred bone and there is energy of the Mother inside it.”
I was amazed that these Greeks knew about it.
And it's so surprising, that for ancient times we knew about in India, about this energy that is within us,
but somehow or other it was the tradition, not to talk about it or give Self-Realisation to people en masse.
One teacher will have only one student.
One guru will have one disciple, that's all
and he would just select one out of thousands and give Realisation to one
and tell him the secret of Kundalini.
It was going on for ages together till the 12th Century there was a big poet.
We had a very great poet, who at the age of 31 years wrote tremendous secrets about spiritual life.
I mean, it's unbelievable at this young age,
because he died after that
and then he is one who wrote in his book,
after taking permission from his guru, that this Kundalini is one she does all the job.
But people who were in charge of Hindu religion at the time, were just like priest every where.
They said this chapter is no good, this is 'Nishidh.'
We are not to deal with this. It is to be avoided.
So nobody paid attention to that fact,
but in the 16th century we had lots of poets in our country,
who have sang the praise of this Kundalini.
Also in Bible, there is that, “I will appear before you like tongues of flames.”
And these chakras look like that,
Inside, they are very mild tongues of flames.
So all these things though little bit described in the Bible, described in the Koran, everywhere,
but there was no proper, intelligible knowledge about Kundalini I would say,
though in India they had. There was a kind of a
you can call religious experiments which were called as NathPanthis.
These people are the same who had only one disciple,
one guru sort of thing, but later on it just spread out
and we had lots of people in the 16th century who started talking about Kundalini
and saying about it. So that’s how we have this knowledge in that county since long.
But after the British came, it all became nonsense and nobody bothered for 300 hundred years
and all this knowledge has gone into kind of a cupboard from where it came out.
Now, I knew about it myself, but I wanted to find out a method
by which we could give Realisation en masse, not to one person.
If you give to one person, everybody will get after him, or crucify him, or kill him, or give poison or get out.
Now the time also has come, this is the time that we say in the Bible is the judgement,
the Last Judgement,
but in Koran it's very clearly written. See how all the truths are the same everywhere.
The Koran it is written that at this time, which they call Qiyamah, the Resurrection Time,
"Your hands will speak and they will give witness against you."
So actually when you get your Realisation, you start feeling the energy in your hand
and you can verify,
you can verify what centres are catching and it’s tangible.
As you know, that in Delhi there are three doctors who have already got MD
for curing incurable diseases, through Sahaja Yoga.
Now for diagnosis you don’t have to go in to that horrible, gruelling experience of diagnosis.
Just you can feel it on your fingertips.
You can know what's wrong with you
and its absolutely curable. I tell you frankly, that definitely people have been cured of blood cancers.
They have been cured about 9-10 years back.
They are still living and they're quite hale and hearty.
We have seen that people who are suffering from all kinds of incurable diseases are cured,
but they have to enter into a new state of awareness
that is what we call is the Sahaja Yoga state,
where you become one with this Divine Power.
Then this power starts flowing through you.
Most of the world’s problems, if you see come from human beings
not from nature, more from human beings and the nature reacts to it.
Now when you get these problems
you start running about here and there and trying to find out solutions.
The solution is within.
Within our centres, when these centres are in jeopardy,
you get all these physical, mental, emotional problems
for yourself and for the whole society, for the whole world.
So now what should we do?
Is to correct these centres by the awakening of this Kundalini, which passes through six centres.
These centres get enlightened
and that enlightenment cures them, nourishes them and integrates them.
Then you are completely one with this All-Pervading Power
and the correction becomes permanent.
At that time they say that it starts flowing through you, you can feel it on your fingertips
and by that you develop all your potential powers which are so many,
so many that in this small lecture I may not be able to tell you the whole,
but some of them I will be able to tell you,
that the first thing happens to you that you achieve a state of peace.
You are thinking of tomorrow, or of yesterday past and future,
but present we are not there.
Present is not known to us
and reality is in the present.
So when you are thinking of the past and future, you are jumping on the cusp of those thoughts.
In between these thoughts, there is space which we call as Vilamba in Sanskrit,
is 'the pause'.
and that is the time when you are in present, which is very short
and that’s why you can never be in the present.
So, when the Kundalini rises, your attention is driven inside
and these thoughts expand, in the sense that they elongate
and there is the space in between is quite big.
Thus you establish yourself into a new state and a new dimension of your awareness,
which we call as Thoughtless Awareness.
That is the meditation.
You cannot do meditation you have to be in meditation,
it's a state.
Then there is no thought, but you are fully aware.
Whatever you see is recorded like a picture in your mind
and such tremendous changes take place in human beings,
they are surprised.
Like very ordinary person, who was playing once a instrument before me was very boring to begin with
and suddenly I don’t know what happened to him.
His Kundalini was awakened and he was playing such beautiful music and today he is a world famous man.
There are very powerful Sahaja Yogis in the world now
and I am so very happy that this has happened to people, that they have felt their own energy
and they have felt their own peace.
The second state that you achieve,
what we call, this is the Thoughtless Awareness
and the second one is called as the Doubtless Awareness.
Patanjali in his yoga has said, called them, as Nirvichar Samadhi and Nirvikalap Samadhi.
Now these two states if you have achieved,
then all your powers you know what you have.
You know all your inner being.
You know your chakras and you know all the three... What should I say? The Autonomous Nervous System.
like para-sympathetic, sympathetic systems, everything you know
and you know how to control them, how to improve them, how to work them out.
So you become your own master.
Firstly when you are awakened, firstly what you get is all your talents.
For example: I see Australians are great artists.
I have seen people who have come to Sahaja Yoga become such deep artist
and such beautiful artist, aesthetically so rich.
It is because whatever you know is very little
and the whole dynamism of your creativity just explodes
and you start producing things which are very soothing,
which are very beautiful, which makes every one so happy.
It’s not some sort of nonsensical thing you do some queer thing just to please the people
and show off that you are a great designer and this and that.
No.
You do it natural, honest reproduction of what you feel
and that feeling is absolutely divine and thus you produce really classical, beautiful things,
which is very surprising how these modern children have taken to it.
Normally the Modern Art, as you know is mostly understood by the artist himself.
Nobody else can understand it, because they just go mad and do all kinds of things.
In this also you may do Modern Art,
means in the sense that you break all the lines and everything,
but, what you find that whatever you do is extremely soothing
and natural, one with the nature
and anybody who sees that will say, "Who has made this sort of
an expression of the true feeling from within;
nothing artificial, nothing vulgar, nothing nonsensical."
In the same way musicians and other things in every art...
I was, I have been really amazed how Sahaja Yoga has helped.
I have seen this Sydney Sahaja Yogis singing to you this Marathi and Sanskrit songs and Hindi songs,
which not even Indians can sing.
They cannot sing so well,
I mean if you hear them from outside, nobody will know they are people from Australia.
They are Australians, as if some Indians are singing it's very difficult.
Indian singing is extremely difficult, people practice for years together to achieve this.
Not only that they know it, but also so many of them know it by heart
and I don’t know how they have picked it up, this I just don’t understand.
Then they come and sing in India.
Even so many artists have said, "Now we are ashamed, the way these people are doing
At such a young age, how they have picked it so well.
They sing in such beautiful unison."
All these things happen to you.
Secondly it happens, that so-called religions that you have, you follow.
Somebody will say, "I'm a Buddhist." Somebody will say, "I am a Christian, I am Hindu, Muslim," anything.
They can commit any sins, it's outward.
It's just a label.
Like one girl met me and she was saying, "I am born again." I said, "You are not.
You just label yourself as 'Born Again', you are not.
Unless and until you get your realisation, you cannot be born again
and once you are born again, you get the quality of a personality who is a born again
has so many powers, so compassionate, so peaceful.
"You are not." I said, "You are in a delusion."
She asked me, "Are you born again?" I said, "I am, of course I am
and you can be also if you want to,
but if you want to carry on with artificial levels, what can you do?
what good have they done to anyone?"
So the artificiality drops out and your real personality starts expressing itself.
As far as the religion is concerned, you become absolutely righteous.
The other day, I was reading about the genes
and I was amazed to hear that the
Asians have two genes to protect them,
but the Western people have none.
Now, the two genes that are within us,
one is, I would say, comes from the mother,
may be the father, or the society, or whatever it is,
but one we call in Sahaja Yoga, 'sin against the Mother' and 'sin against the Father',
out of which the left side,
when we are there, we are sinning against the Mother,
means we become immoral.
We don’t know what is morality.
We start playing with things, which we should not.
Then we get into trouble, we get diseases, this, that, all sorts of problems,
because there is no protection.
So we are very vulnerable.
All kinds of indulgences and all kinds of habits,
that we form, which are self-destructive, is sin against the Mother.
The another gene, is the one that protects you against, the sin against the Father
and sin against the Father, is to be dishonest,
to be corrupt, not to believe that God is your Father.
Why should we do all this thing?
So this kind of a sin also, we start doing.
Both these genes that are protective,
are created after Sahaja Yoga within you
and you just don’t do wrong things.
I have seen people from West, how they were.
They give up all kinds of nonsense.
We never have the problem of somebody's wife running away with somebody,
somebody's daughter running away with somebody.
Some rape and all that, it's out of question.
We have thousands and thousands of Sahaja Yogis
and they come together many a times.
I have never seen them quarrelling, fighting have any violence or anything.
So this, the sin against the Father and sin against the Mother,
just is sort of established, that they just don’t do it.
They dress up properly. They live properly. They don’t take to drugs.
They don’t take all these things.
Now you know the progeny, how it is facing the effects of this modern life.
Like you see, the children are left to dogs,
they become so horrible.
I have seen in Miami with my own eyes,
children who were only 12 years of age, were carrying revolvers
and were selling drugs,
because the law is such, that they do not punish 12 years old children in the jail,
so people are taking advantage of these children and they are behaving like this.
There are children who are killing their parents.
There are parents who are killing their children.
This kind of a violence is the sin against the Father.
So both ways you see, if there is sort of an attack.
What will happen to such a society?
Is important one has to take to spiritual life
and the spiritual life of not outside,
that you just go to church, sing some hymn numbers, this and that and come home.
This is not that, it has to be innate, within yourself.
You have to be honest.
You have to be integrated with yourself
and then this innate religion will tell you, that you belong to the religion, which is a universal religion,
which encompasses all the religions,
which respects all the great incarnations, all the prophets, every one.
Every religion is a flower on the tree of life,
of spirituality,
but you have taken away that flower
and you are fighting with the dead flower. "This is mine." "This is mine."
You have no claims and is the dead flower which is now petrified
and that’s how you see in every religion what problems are coming.
How people are suffering. How they are fighting. All kinds of things happen.
So people become, they say, "We don’t believe in God."
They become atheist.
When they become atheist also, they are doing the wrong thing
and those who believe in God, in such a way, are also wrong.
It’s a blind faith.
With Sahaja Yoga, I must tell you one thing, you shouldn’t have blind faith.
If you feel the experience of Realisation,
then of course, as honest people, you must accept, respect it and go-ahead with it and grow.
But if you don’t feel the experience, you shouldn’t tell lies.
You should come again and again. See that you get your Realisation.
There are so many things, as I told you, I could tell you,
but only the attention part I have told you, that attention gets enlightened
and wherever you put your attention it works.
It helps.
So in a way you start living collectively.
You start feeling that you are part and parcel of one whole being.
The microcosm becomes the macrocosm,
a drops becomes the ocean
and that’s how the whole world can become one,
one day and all these problems and things will go away,
because through Sahaja Yoga you know Absolute Truth.
Everybody knows the same truth, no quarrel,
as you are watching me, I am sitting down here.
All of you feel the same about everything.
So there are no discussions, no arguments, no fighting, nothing
and you really become a peaceful personality.
You emit peace, as I told you.
So,
the highest thing is that you enter into to the Kingdom of God.
Somebody told me today, “Mother, they... people don’t know what is Kingdom of God.”
So I said, “They have to enter in to see."
Unless and until I enter into this hall, how will I know what this hall is like.
So once they enter into it, they write to me, that Mother we are now in the Kingdom of God,
because you start... drowned into,
you feel you are drowned into the ocean of joy
and joy is not double like happiness and unhappiness.
Supposing you have... your ego is pampered.
You feel very happy, that I am such and such, I have got this
and if any is punctured you feel unhappy,
but joy is singular, it's in that state, from where you witness your life.
In a one lecture, program, I don’t think I will able tell you all about it.
I must have given at least four thousand lectures in only English language.
So I have to tell you one thing, that today whatever is happening in Sahaja Yoga
is the culmination of your evolution,
culmination of all spiritual work,
that people have done, all the saints, prophets and incarnations
and is the last judgement for you, so that you enter into the Kingdom of God.
Sahaja means ‘born with you’.
‘Saha’ is ‘with’. ‘Ja’ is ‘born’
Born with you is the right
to become united, which means yoga, with this All-Pervading Power.
It is your birthright,
because you are born at this time
and this should happen,
but after that please remember, that you might feel very great about it
and you may just enjoy it individually, but it’s not an individual growth.
You have to come to our Centres.
You don’t have to pay for it.
Some people think that this is an introduction lecture so there's no payment.
You can't pay for living thing. How can you pay?
How can pay for the seed which is planted in the Mother Earth?
How can you pay to the Mother Earth or to the seed? It’s all built in.
In the same way it's built in to you.
Of course for formally I use to come Australia with my own money and all that,
but now we have so many Sahaja Yogis, that they want pay for my travel,
may be for this hall they might have paid, but you don’t have to pay for your Self-Realisation
and all the knowledge of your being, inner being,
your powers and everything, for that you don’t have to pay.
All these little expenses, which is very little,
partly I should say, are taken over by so many Sahaja Yogis that you have.
In Sydney itself, you have lots of Sahaja Yogis. They told me there are 22 centres in Sydney.
So you all can take full advantage of it, but you must respect yourself,
you must respect your Self-Realisation.
After all, you must be something special to get it.
So please don’t neglect it.
There is no mesmerism to keep you attached to Sahaja Yoga.
There is no other temptations, but one that you have to be one with this All-Pervading Power
and this Kundalini is the pure desire, the power of pure desire.
You are aware of if it, or you may not be aware of it,
that you have only one pure desire is to be one with all this All-Pervading Power,
because all other desires if you see, once they are fulfilled, they are of no importance to you.
So it is said that, in general wants are not satiable.
You never feel satisfied, but after this complete satisfaction comes in to you
and you start enjoying everything,
enjoying other people, enjoying your own relations,
enjoying the whole world.
This is such a blissful time, that you are born. Take full advantage of it
and pay full attention to yourself
and understand that just by labelling yourself as something, you do not become that.
Do not fight for something that is artificial, but achieve something that is real.
Thank you very much. I hope after one year again I will come back here and meet you.
By that time all of you will grow up like big trees of spirituality,
giving such vibrations and Realisation, that power you will have, that
you can give Realisation, you can cure people, you can help people.
Some people who have never been orators, have become great orators of Sahaja Yoga
and all over the world you have brothers and sisters who are sincerely yours.
May God Bless you.
Thank you very much.
I can't see the people.
Can you ask them to put the light off, so that I can see the people.
There is one thing more that I cannot force Self-Realisation on you.
All of you can get it. Must just have confidence.
All can get it, but if you don’t want to have it, I cannot force on you.
I respect your freedom
and I have to request people, if they don’t want to have it, they should leave the hall.
That’s much better and otherwise I am sure it will work out for all of you.
Can you ask them to reduce the light a little bit?
Put the light, that side.
It’s too much.
Also reduce this one, it’s not too much light on me?
Can’t see anyone.
Till I give Realisation please reduce, this is too much.
I never used to wear these glasses, but for these kind of things
No, no, no these big things.
I want to see them.
We need to douse these overheads.  Thank you.
Ah, that proves one thing,
that if you are blinded by something like that,
you can not see anything else, you see, so one has to…
So again, I would request those who want to go should leave,
will be good idea. It takes 10-15 minutes, not more than that,
but it's…
You go beyond your mind. You just go on thinking about it, this, that, then it won’t work out …
So nice!
Left Nabhi is there.
So, before we start I have to tell you there are three conditions,
which are very simple conditions.
The first one is, that you have to be fully confident,
that you all will get your Self-Realisation.
So it follows the second condition,
that you should in no way feel guilty about anything.
It’s a fashion also, to feel guilty,
all the time, saying “Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.” Even on the phone we use to say, “I beg your pardon,”
but people say, “Sorry, sorry, sorry.”
It’s a fashion. To feel guilty is really a fashion.
If you have done anything wrong, just face it that moment and just leave it.
But you carry on with it and that works on left Vishuddhi here,
which is a very…very, very important thing,
because if your left Vishuddhi is caught up,
then, you can get spondylitis,
which is a very horrible disease,
or another one which is called, angina,
or you may get very lethargic organs.
So this is such an important centre, which you are spoiling,
just with your imaginary… imaginary style of thinking,
that you are guilty,
that you have done this wrong. You should not have done that wrong and you feel guilty.
Of course everybody has right to feel guilty.
I cannot challenge that.
They can feel. Everybody has right, even to cut their throat.
But as a Mother, I am saying, "Better not."
Why to do something which is injurious to us, good for nothing?
And at this moment, when you are about to get your Realisation,
you miss the point
This is the greatest thing that you are going to you have.
All your powers are going to express themselves.
All your glory you are going to know.
At this time what is the use of feel guilty and condemning yourself?
So just, what you have to say in your heart is that, “Mother I am not guilty at all.”
That’s all.
You don’t have to do anything, but in your heart, please say, just now in your heart
that, “Mother I am not guilty at all.”
Second point!
So now two conditions I have told you.
The third condition is very simple.
The third condition is that you have to forgive everyone.
According to some people it’s very difficult.
They cannot forgive, but logically try to understand.
If you forgive or don’t forgive, what do you do?
Nothing.
Both ways you do nothing. You just think, “I cannot forgive, I cannot forgive.”
But if you don’t forgive, then you play in to wrong hands.
If you don’t forgive, then you play in to wrong hands definitely,
because the person who has harmed you, or troubled you,
will always try to deviate the matter. He wouldn't bother to see that I have trouble that person or anything,
but you are the one, who will be troubling yourself
and all the time torturing yourself. All the time saying
that. “I cannot forgive this man. I cannot forgive man.”
That person might have even forgotten you all.
So there is no logic in it,
but more over, when you do not forgive then, the centre, Agnya,
which is on the optic chiasma
is like this, constructed like this, absolutely like this
and to open this you have to forgive, otherwise how will the Kundalini pass.
It has to open,
only by forgiving every one. You don’t have to think about whom
you have to forgive, what they have given, how to forgive,
how to do it, just say that, “I forgive everyone in general.”
You don’t have to think about them.
At this moment, if you say that, you'll feel much lighter.
So these are the three conditions we have
and I think it’s not difficult to do it, if you see the logic behind it.
Now as I told you, it takes about 10-15 minutes that’s all.
All those who want to do it can do it.
Those who don’t want it, I cannot force,
so they should leave.
There are very simple things,
for which people object.
Now I don’t know if it’s too much to do, but if you can take out your shoes,
it helps a lot. This Mother Earth helps us.
She is a living body and she sucks in our problems.
She sucks in our heat.
So I will be thankful, if you could take out your shoes and keep them away.
Even this could be a too much condition for the Western people sometimes, in England.
It’s not so cold also, you can keep your socks on.
Now!
You are quite comfortable and sit comfortably.
You don’t have to stand on your heads.
You don’t have to go to Himalayas,
nothing. No starvation, no fasting, nothing,
it’s something inside. It has nothing to do with your outside behaviour
and surprisingly it’s all there, intact.
If of course if you are suffering from some disease,
may be you have been to some guru, who has harmed you, or something,
then maybe it may not work out, but that’s one percent.
But even those, who do not get Realisation, can get it later on
and there are Sahaja Yogis who can give you Realisation.
There is no problem on that.
You are here means, you have already entered in to the Kingdom of the God,
that you desire to have your Self-Realisation is the biggest thing.
Now,
what we have to do, is to put both the hands like this towards me,
comfortably, again very comfortably, you can
if you have the hand rest, you can put it on the hand rest,
or like this both the hands towards me.
Now, these are two powers,
Alright now, will you go ahead a little bit there and show them, because everybody should see. I think it's better now.
Can you see him all of you?
Alright,
So
ha... now better.
Now you put both the  hands like this,
as these two powers are different, we have put both the feet apart from each other.
Now please put your right hand on your heart.
And we will now show you, what we will have to do.
In the Heart resides the Spirit,
that’s the reflection of God Almighty.
If you become the Spirit you become your own Master.
So you take down your right hand
on the lower portion of the abdomen,
on the left hand side. We are just working on the left hand side
and here is the centre of your Mastery,
which is created by great masters and prophets,
which you have to awaken.
Now please take your right hand, on the lower portion of your abdomen,
on the left side again.
Surprisingly, this is the centre of Pure Divine Knowledge.
You’ll later on know how it works. It’s very interesting.
Now raise your hand again, in the upper portion of your abdomen.
Please.
And then, raise your right hand on your Heart again.
Now put right your hand in the corner of your neck and your shoulder
and turn head to the your right.
This is the centre, I have told you, when you are guilty it is caught and how it is dangerous.
Now, take your right hand on top of your forehead across
and put down your head.
This is the centre for forgiving others.
Now please take your right hand on the back side of your head.
Push back your head. These are all the centres.
Now this centre is very important
without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes,
for your satisfaction, you will have to ask for forgiveness from this All-Pervading Power.
Then, please stretch your palm, fully,
stretch your palm. It's the last centre,
which is on the fontanel bone area.
So put the centre of your palm on top of the fontanel bone area,
which may be hot, which may be cool.
Now push back your fingers. This is important.
Please push back your fingers, so there is good pressure on your scalp.
Please bend your head as far as possible
and now move your right hand fully,
moving the scalp with the pressure seven times.
Please bend your head that’s important.
That’s all we have to do.
Now again please close your eyes
and you will have to open them till I tell you.
But before that, see that your both the legs or feet are apart from each other.
Left hand is on your lap or comfortably put toward me like this.
And now put your right hand on your heart.
You can take out your spectacles. It will help you,
moreover, till I tell you, please don’t open your eyes.
Now close your eyes, slowly, not with pressure, but slowly, delicately.
Now, don’t worry about where your thoughts are,
what you have to do, concentrate, nothing.
Kundalini will do all the job. You just leave it alone.
Now here is the centre of your Spirit,
so here you have to ask a fundamental question about yourself to me.
You can call me Mother or you can call me Shri Mataji.
So please ask a question,
“Mother, am I the Spirit?”
Please ask the question in your heart
“Mother, am I the Spirit?” Three times!
I have told you, that if you become the Spirit, you become your Master,
because in the light of your Spirit, you know what is to be done.
Your Spirit guides you.
So now please take your right hand
on the left-hand side of your abdomen in the upper part and press it.
Here you ask me another question about yourself,
three times in your heart,
“Mother, am I my own Master?”
I have already told you, that I respect your freedom
and this Pure Knowledge cannot be given to you,
with force,
so you have to ask for it.
So please take your right hand in the lower portion of your abdomen on the left hand side
and ask six times,
because this centre has got six petals.
“Mother, please give me Pure Divine Knowledge.”
You have to ask for it. I cannot force on you. Please ask six times.
As soon as you ask for Pure Knowledge,
the Kundalini starts rising
like a plumule in a seed
and is going upward now, so we have to help the higher chakras with our self confidence.
So now please put your right hand
in the upper portion of your abdomen on the left hand side
and here you have to say with full confidence,
because this is the centre of your Mastery.
“Mother, I am my own Master."
Please say it ten times, “Mother, I am my own Master.”
Now,
please raise your right hand on the heart.
I have already told you, that you are the Pure Spirit.
You are not this body, this mind, these conditionings,
this ego, these emotions,
but you are the Pure Spirit.
So now here you ask twelve times.
You have to say with full confidence, twelve times
“Mother, I am the Pure Spirit.”
I have already told you,
that if you feel guilty
and you don’t forgive yourself,
you develop a problem for your left Vishuddhi,
which is very dangerous for your health,
as well as for your Self Realisation.
So at this moment, you have to forgive yourself fully.
So now raise your right hand in the left corner of your neck and shoulder
and put your head to your right.
Here you have to say sixteen times, with full confidence in yourself.
“Mother, I am not guilty at all.” Please say it sixteen times.
Have faith in yourself, just say I tell you are not guilty,
you are human beings and human beings can commit mistakes.
You are not gods, so please say it with full confidence sixteen times.
Most intricate part is that,
you have to forgive every one without thinking about them, in general.
If you don’t forgive,
then this chakra will be completely constricted
and the Kundalini won’t rise.
All your life you have tortured yourself, by not forgiving others
and now at this moment, if you don’t forgive this centre won’t open at all,
so you will miss again your Self Realisation.
You have to ask forgiveness from this All-Pervading Power,
just for your satisfaction.
Don’t count your mistakes please.
Don’t feel guilty in any way.
Now put your right hand on the back side of your head
and push back your head as far as possible
and here you have to say,
“Oh Divine Power, if I have done anything knowingly or unknowingly,
something that is wrong, please forgive me.”
This also you have to say from your heart,
not how many times counting or anything, but from your heart you have to say.
Some people find it difficult to forgive themselves
and some people find it difficult to forgive others.
Now stretch your palm
fully, put the centre of your palm on top of your fontanel bone area
and push back your fingers.
Now, please bend your head.
Again at this centre, I cannot force Self-Realisation on you.
You have ask for it.
So, please move you hands seven times.
Please put down your head. Please put down your head.
Please move your scalp with your hand,
with a pressure, because you have pushed back your fingers,
seven times, slowly, clock wise, saying,
“Mother, please give me Self Realisation.”
You have to say it,
unless or until you ask for it, I cannot force it on you, so please say it.
Now please take down your hands.
Please open your eyes, slowly.
Put both the hands towards me, like this.
Now
put your right hand towards me like this
and with the left hand, you bend your head and see for yourself,
if there is cool or a hot breeze coming out of your head.
Could be hot if you have not forgiven.
Don’t put the hand on top of your head.
So away from it and move your hand.
Sometimes it can be very close, or it can be far away.
So please bend your head and see for yourself if there is a cool, or a hot breeze like sensation
coming from the fontanel bone area and don’t doubt.
May be you might think it’s air conditioning and all that,
but there is no air conditioning in your head.
So, see it if for yourself, nicely.
Now,
please put your left hand towards me and put the right hand... now
you see if there is cool breeze or a hot breeze like sensation,
coming out of your head.
Now,
turn your hand on all the sides.
You can also see if some people get it very far.
Some people get it like a jet out.
Some it is closer to the head. It depends on the personality of a person.
Alright. Now have another one,
right one, right hand last, lastly.
Please put your left hand now, bend your head
and see for yourself, there is a cool or a hot breeze coming out of your head.
It’s little further also you can see clearly, if there is.
Now,
please put both the hands towards the sky
and push back your head and here you have to ask a question.
Any one of these questions, you can ask three times.
The first question is, you can say is, “Is this the All-Pervading Power of Divine Love?”
“Mother, is this is the All-Pervading Power of Divine Love?”
Second question could be,
“Is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?”
Third question could be, “Mother is this the Brahma Chaitanya?”
Ask any one of these questions three times.
Now bring down the hands
and put both the hands towards me and watch me without thinking.
All those who have felt cool or hot breeze on their fingertips,
or on their palms,
or out of their fontanel bone area, which was a soft bone in childhood,
please raise both your hands.
Every one of you!
May God bless you Sydney people. I am so happy.
May God bless you.
Now keep it up.
You have to come to the collective and keep it up, and know the knowledge, all of it.
Can I see this side?
All of you got it?
Oh my God!
It’s remarkable.
This side also?
It’s really remarkable. May God bless you.
It’s tremendous.
Some didn’t get, very, very few.
One here, one there,
so they can also come later on, on the stage and Sahaja Yogis will give them Realisation.
No problem, but we will have one song just before I leave.
I hope you will keep sitting till then
and you can also clap, so your hands become more active.
Some song that will give you nice clapping rhythm, which one?
You put your hand like this.
It will increase with the songs. You'll feel the Cool Breeze increase with the songs.
Now just feel your vibrations
just feel with this clapping, how they have improved or not.
Alright!
It's much better, the flow.
Also you can see on your head, you're much better.
As the lady had seen, the one described by Lord Mayor,
you can see on other's head also,
if it is there or not.
With the neighbours you can see
It's there.
Not on top, here little.
It’s open now.