So one would say that why Shiva, like a birthday
of Shiva you can say or something, how can
it be, because He is eternal, He is all the
time there.
So what demarcates today's celebration, is
the establishment of Shiva on this earth.
In the material self.
Every matter has been created with a deity
and that deity is established in that matter
as you know.
So when it was thought by Adi Shakti that
first you must establish Shiva, without Shiva
you cannot establish anything.
First He is to be established, because He
is the absolute.
So you have to establish Shiva, and now what
should we do?
How to establish Him?
He is the God of Tamo Guna.
He is the cold, he is the God of all that
is not active.
So first of all this earth when it receded
from the sun which was very hot was taken
very near to the moon.
The moon is the brother-in-law of Shiva.
So it was taken so close to moon that the
whole earth got covered with ice.
And it was then gradually moved towards the
sun.
When it was moved towards the sun, gradually
then it started melting.
And the point that did not melt at all was
the point where Shiva was to be established.
That was -- and is still that spot, and that
spot is the Kailash.
The ice never melts there and if you see the
whole mountain is like the face of Shiva -- the
eyes, the nose and everything you can see
clearly getting out -- and all the year round
it keeps its shape as it is.
That is how Shiva was created, and He was
placed in a witness state, as a spectator
of all that happens on this earth.
Facing towards the Kundalini of the universe,
which they were going to place in India, so
He is facing towards the South.
He is looking at the South with both the hands
like this, like a spectator watching the spectacle
of the Adi Kundalini.
That is how Shiva was created.
So, so we'll say that the heart of the universe
is England, still Shiva resides on top of
the Sahasrara: this is the seat.
Like you have got the seat of Shiva on top
of your head, but He resides in your heart,
in the same way Shiva belongs to this place
and He looks at the whole body from that,
this point -- so the Feet are the South, this
(top of head) is the North, this is the East...
the West (right arm), and this is the East
(left arm).
That is how we can see the whole map of the
universe, of the world that is created.
So now...
[You can just sit.
Don't stand up.
Listen to My lecture.
Now don't take photographs.
You must listen to My lecture attentively.
In a meditative way you must listen to Me.
You must make full use of Me, isn't it?
You should be meditative.
Then you can hear Me very clearly, you don't
have to bother.
You have to be meditative.]
So you are facing towards the south as a witness.
Just now somebody told me that in the south
people put their head towards the south and
put their feet towards the north, I mean,
imagine.
The feet are put towards Shiva, who is in
the north.
Kailasha is in the north, isn't it?
It is not in the south.
So why put your feet towards the north?
I mean, one must use logic.
These brahmins have told you all these stories
and you are doing just the opposite that should
not be done.
Sometimes I feel God save this country from
brahmins.
They're everywhere now: they're our rulers,
they're everywhere, and they have no idea
what Brahma is.
If they are real Brahmins, I'm sure one day
the real Brahmins will be in charge of this
country.
So now when we understand that Shiva is the
first thing that is established in the matter,
then in us also first the Shiva is established.
When the fetus takes his form, the throb in
the heart is the establishment of Shiva.
That is the sign that Shiva has been established.
In case of people who are born with bad heart
or with troubles, one has to say that Shiva
is not fully established.
Not that they are bad people, but they are
not supposed to live for long, and have to
have another heart later on maybe.
Or that there might be some sort of a problem
in their previous life, and if they pay attention
to Shiva tattwa, their heart can be cured.
So the most important organ in the body is
the heart.
If the heart fails, you cannot remain in existence.
So the most important thing is to look after
your Shiva principle which is the Atma.
We are worried about every sort of mundane
thing.
Worried about this, worried about that, but
we are not worried about our Spirit.
Which is the biggest problems with us.
If you worry about your Spirit, if you pay
attention to your Spirit, the whole universe
then vibrates with Parabrahma which is nothing
but joy.
So without, without any attention to Spirit,
if we think we can enjoy life you cannot.
You cannot enjoy your life if you pay attention
to other nonsensical things and you do not
pay attention to your Spirit, the complete
silence comes into us only through Spirit.
If the Spirit is awakened within us, this
silence starts working and you feel extremely
relaxed and absolutely one with yourself.
There is no problem, you don't seek other
things that normally people seek -- you seek
your own company and you want to be some time
with yourself.
Only thing that you seek after finding your
Spirit is the company of other sahaja yogis
who also have found the Spirit, so that there
is a rapport established between Spirits,
that is in the heart.
And this Spirit is the universal being within
us about which I have told you that once you
become one with the Spirit, you automatically
become universally conscious.
There are so many qualities of the Shiva,
Shiva tattwa, of the principle of Shiva that
I need not tell you, but today I will tell
you another dimension which I have not touched
so far about Shiva tattwa.
The physical aspect of Shiva tattwa is that
such a person is a more a cold type of a person.
In the sense that such a person is not a person
who gives hot vibrations, but who has too
much of heat sometimes, not in balance, overdoes
it, develops a kind of a temperament which
can be extremely cold.
Could be low blood pressure with it, could
be diarrhea also, diarrhea also one can get
with too much of spiritual strength.
And also could be on the love side because
of the left side.
Because left side is the kapha as you call
it, is kapha is the phlegm that is more.
Because the left side is more, such a person
is always apt to catch colds and has problems
of the colds.
So such a person has to protect oneself from
getting into colds and things like that and
the methods to be employed are to be learnt
through Sahaja Yoga.
But to give it a balance the Spirit itself
is beyond health problems.
But the left sided person who always thinks
of the Spirit also can become one-sided, when
he has to live on this earth he has to be
a balanced person.
So he has to take to another side and that
side is the activity of the spiritual growth
within himself.
A person who is very spiritually developed
cannot exist as a Shiva tattwa on this earth.
He has to exist as a balanced personality.
And when he starts developing that balancing
within himself, the Spirit from his heart
starts rising and goes on top of his head.
So this is the second stage where one has
to reach.
Here is the whole collectivity (touches head)
-- so when you start taking your love and
affection into your central nervous system,
you can say, and put it on top of your head,
that means as soon as you put it in your Virat,
when it starts spreading through your Virata
shakti, through your collective being, then
only you are a complete personality.
Otherwise you are Shiva tattwa -- Shiva tattwa
exists whether this universe exists or not.
It exists even when the whole universe is
existing; even, even it vanishes it all goes
into that magnet, into that Shiva tattwa.
So a person who has spiritual hankerings must
know that to raise your Shiva above the heart
level, he has to raise it gradually onto a
very detached method of existing on top of
the Sahasrara.
Where there is a complete balance, complete
balance.
Many people I have seen in Sahaja Yoga are
extremely loving, nice, very sweet persons.
Like in Delhi, I would say people are not
so harsh as in Bombay.
Bombay people could be harsh, Puna people
are little harsher also.
But Bombay and Puna people are deeper.
The reason is they have balanced themselves
a little, and they have gone above their heart
feelings like sympathies.
"Don't be unkind to somebody, don't say anything
harsh to somebody," can be very, very funny
also sometimes -- like yesterday I was sleeping
in the place where you all were sleeping.
Now if I was in any Bombay or Puna center,
anywhere, you can't hear any voice, anywhere,
nothing -- like a lion, you see, like a tiger
is in a forest, nobody will hear your voice.
If there's a tiger, you can know for miles
together there's tiger somewhere, it's so
silent.
But if I'm in Delhi, then everybody's talking:
somebody was talking about money, this that,
the whole kind of jabbering was [on], even
the sahaja yogis from foreign had become Delhi
sahaja yogis.
They were talking so much I was surprised,
how did they take to this talking so much
there: always talking, jabber, jabber -- On
the contrary if I'm sleeping there you all
should have been in meditation, sitting down
and doing meditation.
Instead of that everyone was busy with all
the possible nonsensical talks, as if they
have no other chance to talk.
And they were all jabbering, jab jab jab,
I didn't know what to say and I just I didn't
know what to do.
(Inaudible)
But this is what one has to know, that unless
and until you raise your sympathetic attitudes
-- like you tell somebody something, "I have
had such a problem in this business", say
example like this.
I mean, what a topic, but doesn't matter.If
you start, "I had a problem with this", another
will: "Yes I too had..." you see, the sympathies.
"I too had such a problem, these people are
so bad, that happened, he had the same problem",
same talk.
They are all, you see, talking about things
which are irrelevant to Sahaja Yoga.
Even relevant to Sahaja Yoga you should not
talk when I'm there.
I have to make a humble request to all of
you -- that the way you people sometimes behave
is not good and is not congenial to sahaja
yogis.
Even to keep your mouth open in My front is
not a good thing.
But I don't want to tell you in such details
but it is so many things are there that you
have to learn before you raise your Shiva
tattwa from your heart.
You are good at pleasing people, at organizing
you are excellent, you organize very well,
there are no quarrels; sahaja yogis in Bombay
quarrel quite a lot and even Puna sahaja yogis
are quarrelsome.
But I must say Puna sahaja yogis are very
deep, and Bombay sahaja yogis are very deep
individually, they have achieved something.
Now they have to go further than that, is
to go little bit in the heart again.
You see, the second essence (?)they have to
have to feel more that way, because that way
they are very, very strict with people.
But you see, certain amount of strictness
is to be accepted.
For example, if somebody is told: "Don't touch
Mother's feet": one feels very bad.
But this is a very mundane sort of an understanding
of the Mother.
If She says: "Don't touch My feet" that's
what you are supposed to do, you have to do
exactly what pleases Me, and not what will
please you.
So you must change your attention from pleasing
all the public -- some people say "Those who
come first time Mother, we must not say this".
You must!
Certain things you must say to them, otherwise
you will make Me a-prasanna: that will cause
problems!
But when you say to others, you need not go
like Puna and Bombay people in their special
Marathi language, but say it in a proper Urdu
style, that people don't feel bad, but you
must say it!
You should not put those people on My head;
instead of that you should tell them in such
a way that people are alright.
So to go deeper into you, you must do also
individual meditation and samori.
I would not say all the sahaj yogis in Delhi
are like that, but... we are very good at
organizing, which our Bombay sahaja yogis
and these Puna sahaja yogis must learn.
They quarrel among themselves and I really
get fed up.
And they treat each other shabbily, that I
don't like.
But individually they are alright, so they
become individualistic.
Some people become individualistic and some
people become publicist, public... they'll
please the public, now they are two extremes.
What should a sahaja yogi do?
They have to become Mother addicts.
They should do what your Mother likes.
Do you understand?
Need not please the public or need not please
the individual, but do what your Mother will
like, that's a very simple thing which Adi
Shankaracharya told you, that just keep the
Mother pleased.
But nobody makes that study.
Try to make the study: "What makes Mother
pleased".
Then you will see, I'm very easily pleased,
you see?
As a Shiva tattwa.
Even if you make mistakes try to pull your
ears alright (laughter).
But don't go too far with it.
You see, the mistakes to commit is alright,
but don't take it for granted that you can
go on committing mistakes.
Because you really get a big rope, but you
will hang yourself ultimately, isn't it?
So be afraid of the rope also which is given
to you, it will hang you much better otherwise.
So one has to understand that you should not
be addicted to public opinion or to the opinion
of your own.
Both things are wrong.
You must behave in such a manner that it should
please all the deities within Me, as far as
I am concerned I don't exist.
I have no existence, really believe Me, I
have no existence at all, I just, is an assemblage
of so many existences.
Otherwise I don't exist, I don't find Myself
anywhere in this body, anywhere I don't find
Myself, anywhere in the universe!
I'm nowhere, I sometimes find, 'What is all
this?
Is not Mine, is all foreign to Me".
But still I permeate into it, enjoy it, live
with it, but I'm not in it, nowhere.
If you just try to understand what pleases
your Mother, you will develop your dignity
because I want you to be dignified; it will
develop your joy because I want you to be
joyous; it will give you more capacity to
achieve more vibrations within yourself because
that is what I'm giving -- whatever is good
for you if you do that, it will please Me.
But what I think is good for you, you may
not think, you may have your own ideas, individualistic
again.
Or maybe public-wise -- like I've told you
that please don't arrange My program before
7 o'clock in the evening.
Then you may say, 'It won't suit our public'.
Doesn't matter: it doesn't suit Me, that's
the main point.
Because I have certain timings when only I
can really be very good.
That time I have to give to somebody else,
is fixed!
So you don't fix My timings according to yours.
Morning time before 11 o'clock no programs
should be fixed.
Early in the morning if you fix, fix at five,
I don't mind.
I have certain timings which I have to use
for some other purpose!
So you have to understand that whatever suits
Me should be done, because that is for your
good also.
Because there are most beneficial.
I'm just telling you My own tricks so that
you take more advantage of Me.
But they insist on that the people who are
going to the office won't be able to come-
that's people should not come at all!
If there is a picture at 7 o'clock they'll
go at that picture or not?
Then why should you make your Mother so cheap
that it should suit their convenience -- if
there are few people it is even better for
us: we'll have better accommodation in the
Kingdom of God.
So don't make Me cheap!
That one should understand, not to cheapen
Me, keeping the dignity of your Mother.
Whatever is to be achieved, I agree, that
all the brothers and sisters must be helped,
all the public must be helped, but we can't
get rid of the kachras otherwise if you see:
there are lots of things which are to be just
thrown away.
So we don't, should not worry about the kachra
part.
Whatever is the best we'll have, but to have
that also one should not speak harshly.
Again I will say not to use harsh words.
The way people: "Get out, get out, get out"
like that one should not talk.
Change your language.
You must educate yourself how to talk to people
in a soft way, in a proper way.
That is very important for Sahaja Yoga, because
if you go on insulting, maybe you might insult
some saint!
So you should not do in that way.
Understand it, and try to make your individual
being so capable that, when you go to the
public, you are able to put the right concept,
the right concept, the right conduct, the
right behavior, and the right knowledge.
Here I do not mean right rationally, right
which is absolute.
The Shiva is the absolute, He is the giver
of absolute knowledge, He knows what pleases
Me.
The moment something will happen that will
really displease Me, He will shut the show.
He is just watching this to please Me.
The moment he'll find that this is not working
out, He'll stop the whole show and will say:
"Shut it, finished".
So though I may say the spectator is Shiva,
but He is just the judge, and He sees those
things.
So try to be all right, a nice spectacle I
try to make, to please Shiva so He continues
to be there, and this let [let this?] universe
be a nice place to stay in, in which you rise
and attain that eternal life which is promised
to you.
But one has to understand what pleases Mother.
Some people have a habit of just looking at
Me straight all the time: not the way to be
done!
Put your eyes down, all the time just you
cannot stare at Me, it's stupid!
Apart from stupidity it will not please Me,
will it please you if I start staring at you
all the time?
I don't stare at you, I try to please you
by doing all kinds of things: why don't you
learn something from Me, how I try to please
you?
You can't do all these things of course, I
know, because somebody says: "Mother, we went
there, the horse was given to us, this, that,"
this help you cannot achieve yourself.
For Me, if I have a difficulty, you can't
solve My difficulty.
Isn't it?
But I can solve your difficulties.
So I can please you very easily because I
have so many methods of pleasing you.
For whatever methods are there, by which one
should not positively displease, that's the
only thing is.
You don't do anything special, but don't do
something extraordinary just to displease.
If you understand this simple thing, that
don't try to do anything that will displease
to please Me.
It is so simple.
Don't have to do anything extra, just try
to be loving, affectionate, dignified, and
I'll be very happy with all that.
As it is I'm overjoyed, I'm very happy with
you.
But I have to tell you what one has to achieve,
and how one has to go above these things.
So it is necessary now for Delhi people to
rise from the heart to the Sahasrara.
And it is necessary for Bombay and Puna people
to go from heart... to go from the Sahasrara
to the heart.
I would say Rahuri people are in between.
Rahuri people are in between.
They are very good organizers, and they don't
create problems for Me as far as individuals
are concerned.
So I think Rahuri is a place, perhaps maybe
it is my Mecca, that it is so good whatever
it is.
But we all can be like that.
We all can change and inform each other and
improve and educate ourselves.
All this education can come to us, if we really
love ourselves, and care for our evolution.
We don't have to bother about it much, if
we really care for.
Gradually all these things will work out and
the balance can be established.
Those people who talk too much should not
talk so much.
What I feel that when you talk too much when
you'll stop you just stop.
In between: when it is necessary you must
talk, when it is not necessary you should
not talk.
So that kind of personality gradually you
can develop with Sahaja Yoga, that you will
develop that wisdom how far to go, how far
not to go.
Not to go is the quality of Shiva.
He doesn't do anything, He is just sitting
down there and watching the whole joke.
He doesn't do anything, but He's the one who
has to watch: if He doesn't watch, then the
whole show is over.
If you understand that in not doing anything,
how much He's doing.
See the contrast: He's doing nothing as such.
But He's making everybody dance, to please
Him.
In the same way in one shot you have both
the natures, as sahaja yogis you can achieve
that kind of a balanced personality.
It is for your good, for your evolution, for
your development.
So today all of you have a great chance of
evolving individually within yourself with
Shiva tattwa, which ultimately permeates into
the whole.
Kabira has said it in a beautiful couplet,
I don't know if you people have understood:
(Hindi) The compassion of my heart I will
vibrate, I will bring it out; the compassion
of my heart I will vibrate, I'll bring it
out; (Hindi) and put it into the five elements.
See Kabira, do you follow him how great he
is?
People talk of Kabirdas, see, he says that
take it out of the heart and put it into all
the five elements.
This
is what is Sahaja Yoga.
If you understand that, then you don't have
to understand anything else.
You have got it in your heart, become the
capitalist in your heart, and become a communist
outside.
If you can achieve this balance properly,
you have done it, and we can do it, we all
of us put together we will do it, we can achieve
it and we can show to
the world that everyone can achieve it.
All ordinary human beings so-called will can
become extraordinary.
So today we have to decide about ourselves
that we are going to do it, we are going to
be educated about it, in a spiritual way,
in a Sahaja way.
And every moment if you watch yourself you
can know.
And
not to explain yourself, and to say "Oh, this
happened to me, that happened to me": that's
not the point.
Many people tell Me like that, that's absurd.
You challenge yourself: how can it happen
to you?
Why don't you do it?
You should do it.
Why can't you do it?
Like that you take yourself to task and
you can work it out, I'm sure, because you've
got
the power to do it.
I bless you all for your spiritual development
and for your collectivity.
Both things must be looked after.
If you have spiritual development and no collectivity,
it is useless.
If you
have collectivity and spiritual development
none, it is useless.
Combine it properly.
So we have to take Shiva
and establish Him into the Virat.
This is
what we have to do, and if you understand
this point, your relationships with others
also will
be good, permanent, of
a
very substantial nature.
And the quality of sahaja yogis' life will
be something very, very great.
May God bless you all.