Today
we have decided to have Krishna Puja because
America is the Krishna bhoomi. It's very surprising
that such a great incarnation of Shri Krishna
came even much later than Rama and has sent
His special people to live in America. Of
course, there are many who are seeking in
this country, no doubt. But there are many
who are also misleading them. That's how you
find, despite all our effort, we have not
been able to expand Sahaja Yoga very much.
What one has to learn from His life is very,
very important. The first and foremost thing
He taught was collectivity. He used to get
hold of small boys and play with them together.
Rama didn't do that. He used to get hold of
ladies who were selling milk and also butter,
those who used to go to fill their water in
the pitcher. He is the one who collected all
such people in the village of Gokul. He played
all kinds of pranks on His friends and His
mother and the mother's friends. Behaved just
like a very naughty child, just to show that
He was just like all of us.
As you know, He was the incarnation of Shri
Vishnu. First Shri Rama was born, took incarnation
as Shri Rama, which was in the Aryan race,
means that time we had an Aryan race which
was sort of superior, superior race than others.
But when He came as Krishna, He took His birth
in Yadav dynasty, you can call it. They were
not superior, they were selling milk, having
cowherds and doing work not of any religious
style. But they were innocent simple people
living in the villages, and they saw the great
miracles of Shri Krishna's childhood. He killed
demons. He killed Pootna. All these people
were sent by His uncle Kamsa to kill him.
It was
to be, because He had to prove that He was
the incarnation of Shri Vishnu and He did
it. As a child, how He killed those people
is remarkable. And how He made them out though
they were all camouflaged.
In these modern times, difficult for people
to believe that there could have been any
incarnation like Shri Krishna. But in Sahaja
Yoga, we have method of absolutely establishing
the truth that Shri Krishna was there ruling
on the Vishuddhi chakra. From His childhood,
you can see He was fond of collectivity. And
He tried to create collectivity of people
who were very simple, uneducated, good hearted
people. And that is His special quality. And
all the people of that village knew Him very
well, all cared for Him. And when He had to
go, they felt very sad and all of them came
running and crying for Him. It was a small
boy who was going. After all, what is there?
A little boy from the village is going. The
whole village had gathered to cry for Him.
That is what we all Sahaja Yogis have to know.
As a child also, He was a very collective
personality. He actually emits collectiveness.
The collective consciousness that you enjoy
is because of His bliss. I find that Americans
are very collective in the sense, they are
more bothered about other countries than about
their own. They want to go all the way to
Vietnam, now to Iraq, now to some other place.
Going all over the world, (Shri Mataji laughing)
they try to correct. But their own country
they do not see what's wrong. It's so divided.
Mainly divided on race, racial discrimination,
is divided by religions and all of these are
just concepts which they have accepted and
are fighting among themselves.
Now after all these, there are people who
believe they are born criminals and they should
be criminals. And their criminality is going
very far. They are gangsters. Even small children
have become gangsters. But the worst part
is that these little boys also, including
others, all these criminals are regarded as
big heroes.
I
have seen once, a young boy wearing a shirt
with another young boy's photograph on it.
So he told Me. I said, "Who's this?" "You
don't know? Very famous gangster", he said.
At the age of thirteen years he is a very
famous gangster and this boy is very proudly
putting up that - like a big hero, or you
can call it like a God there. So see the perversion
to what limit Shri Krishna's blessings have
been used. That's why this country is very
difficult. One after another there has been
attack of negativity.
For example, first thing started by Christians,
who said that Jews killed Christ. It's not
true, it's not true. He was never killed by
Jews. "Christ was killed by Jews", is a false
statement, absolutely. Christ was not killed
by Jews. How can a multitude kill a man? It's
the law there. The Romans, or we can call
the Roman law crucified Him. So the Christians
started nicely torturing the Jews, because
Christ was killed. I don't know how to explain
this. Such absurd idea. Now somebody was killed
so many years back, and now what's the use
of killing some grandchildren of those people
or great grandchildren of those people? But
they did not, the Jews did not. Still this
concept was there that the Jews killed. And
the Christians felt they have a right to torture
the Jews. So when the Jews came here, they
were never given a good position, they were
tortured very much and troubled very much.
It happened everywhere but very much more
here. So among Jews now came out some devils,
like Freud. And he said, "All right. We must
shatter these Christians absolutely. Their
moral roots must be finished." So he started
his own psychology to destroy the Christians.
And Christians stupidly accepted it. They
did whatever he said, experimented whatever
he did.
When I was once in Switzerland, two girls
came and they were shaking in the program.
I couldn't understand. I called them. I said,
"Why are you shaking?" So they said that,
"Actually we are very much degree holders
in Freudian (Shri Mataji laughing) knowledge
and we have done all experiments of Freud."
"And then why are you shaking?" "Because we
have power to shake!" [inaudible] (Laughter)
So they followed this Freud and this vindictiveness
that was there was not seen by anyone, even
by Jews. As a result we had people who were
deadly against each other and ruining each
other, destroying each other.
Then this Black and White business started.
All kinds of theories people are putting up
to show that the Blacks are bad or the Whites
are bad. The difference is only skin deep.
If you want you can cut the skin and see for
yourself. Inside body is the same. But it
was so. This divisive method started and it's
still going on. I always say, without Blacks,
Americans will be left high and dry. Look
at the talent they have. Not only music. Atlanta,
I saw, all the Blacks were winning and Whites
were not anywhere. (Shri Mataji laughing)
Very nicely they used to run, very swiftly
at the end of it, you see. And all the Whites
were saying, "Ha, ha, ha." They were nicely
enjoying their [BEAUTY / position ?]. (Laughter)
You don't have the stamina of the Blacks also.
So in games also, same thing. With all this
what is going to happen to America? It's a
country which has to be collective because
of Shri Krishna. All of them are immigrants
here. Who is not an immigrant? Whether they
came earlier or later doesn't matter. Thank
God, I have told you many a times that Columbus
lost his way and came here and not to India.
Otherwise, there would have been no Indians
left and no Sahaja Yoga. (Laughter) I think
it was the trick of Hanumana. (Shri Mataji
laughing) He misled him and Columbus came
here. Thank God. (Laughter)
Now you are in a country where you have to
be collective. Krishna won't spare you unless
and until you are collective or you give up
this nonsense of skin-deep differences. Then
religious differences. He had a friend who
was lame by one leg. He had some friends who
were very black. He had some friends who were
quite Indian white, I should say. I shouldn't
say white like you people, but Indian white.
He had all kinds of colors. And He took His
own birth in the Yadav vansh. They were milk
sellers, milkmen who used to sell milk to
people. He didn't take His birth in a very
royal family like Shri Rama. Though He was,
because later on He became the king of Dwarika.
But in His style, in His behavior, in His
life, nobody could see that He was a royal
personality. He could sleep under a tree.
He could eat anything that He could get. All
kinds of sweet, sweet stories you can read
in His life, showing how He was enjoying His
collectivity, never showing off. And His collectivity
has to be worked out in this country. Unless
and until it is done from your heart, it's
not going to work out.
We had problems like this always with our
collectivity here. For example, a lady, you
know, she is a big lady, I think. She started
correcting people. "Why do you put here? This
thing is getting dirty. That thing is this
and that." Such a woman should be sometimes
sent to some stable to clean it. Then she
will give up these nonsensical ideas that
she has. If you are a Sahaja Yogi you cannot
behave like this. And this kind of a behavior
can destroy Sahaja Yoga. Have you ever heard
Me saying that, "This is dirty, this is not
good, I don't like this?" Did I say, ever?
First of all, we have to understand, if we
have to be collective, we should give up these
stupid ideas about ourselves. Some people
get some position, may be some money, maybe,
I would say, have a background. If you are
sticking on to it then you are not a Sahaja
Yogi. You are saints. You cannot be demanding.
You have to give, and give, and give. Whatever
may be your position in life, if that can
overpower you then you are not a Sahaja Yogi
at all.
Shri Krishna, who is the Virat, who is the
great primordial personality, didn't show
any such signs of His greatness. But Americans
have a specialty to show that they are something
outstandingly great. But Sahaja Yogis, please
don't learn those things. You have to make
others unlearn. If that cannot happen, it's
better to leave Sahaja Yoga for ever. Such
people will make everyone miserable and destroy
Sahaja Yoga in America.
Even about protocol, you should become timeless.
Absolutely timeless. Now, if you are particular
about time, Shri Krishna will play His tricks
and your timing will be finished. Happened
yesterday. (Laughter & applause)
So one has to know that time is your slave
and you don't have to be the slave of time
- if you are a Sahaja Yogi. Otherwise, you
are not. That means you are guided not by
the Divine. The Divine works out everything
very well. But for whom? For Sahaja Yogis.
But if you are not Sahaja Yogis, you'll topple
down.
In every way you should find out what things
we have accumulated among ourselves, which
is not Shri Krishna's quality. Now, Shri Krishna
used to steal as a child, the butter from
the ladies. Why? Why did He steal the butter?
Because they were selling it to the military
of Kamsa, His uncle, who was a devil. They
used to go all the way to sell him in Mathura.
So He used to steal it, because children needed
it, and giving it to children. He didn't like
this idea - why should it go to these horrible
rakshasas of Mathura?
Just the opposite in is America. All the false
gurus, all the rakshasas come here and they
get all the butter. As if people have no brains
to understand, while Shri Krishna is the brain
of the Virat. But here you find that people
have no brains. Anybody comes, says something,
"Ah, ha, ha, great." Somebody talks big - all
right. They will give away their money. They
will give away their houses. Their children
they'll remove from the school - for something
extremely stupid. While He is the brain in
the body of Virata. So this kind of brainlessness
comes and we really start, even Sahaja Yogis
start behaving in a manner that shows they
are really brainless.
Apart from that, He is Kubera. He is the God
of wealth. That's why there is wealth in this
country. But this wealth is all becoming debts,
you see, because of the special brains of
Americans. They are so stupid that whatever
is selling in the market, whether they need
it or not, they'll buy. Take loan, again take
loan, take loan till they are absolutely indebted.
Now here in the country of Kubera you should
be really rich. Rich doesn't mean just to
have bank balance, but means by temperament.
Now it's much better but once upon a time,
Americans were the most miserly Sahaja Yogis.
They used to send Me candles as present and
I used to hide that. I said, "Baba why do
you send candles, even? Don't send anything,
because everybody is going to see those candles
and what are they going to say about it, that
candles have been sent." Now, this I am talking
for introspection.
Are we collective? Are we willing to share
everything that we have? Do we look down upon
people who come from other countries? Do we
have racialism in us? Thirty five Sahaja Yogis
came from Australia, to America as if this
is some Haj. They went back with very bad
vibrations. Out of them half were thrown out
of Sahaja Yoga. Imagine Australia is a country
where they used to send all the criminals.
So first and foremost, to judge yourself is
to see your vibrations. That you should meditate
and judge your vibrations if you are really
collective or not. Because you are not like
that, Sahaja Yoga does not spread.
I have seen people from Hare Rama Hare Krishna.
Poor things have found nothing. They get up
at four o'clock, start their Hare Rama Hare
Krishna bhajan - four o'clock. Then the whole
day they wear a very thin dhoti in which they
are shivering. They shave their heads and
put a pig's tail here which is bought in the
market. If you see their dedication you'll
be surprised. How they are so much dedicated,
when they haven't found anything whatsoever?
What about the nuns? You see them, you will
be amazed. One fellow came from the Catholic
Church to us. He was trying to be a priest.
He said, "Mother, Sahaja Yog - you don't do
anything." I said, "What do you want to do?"
"No, there we could not eat any meat on Fridays.
On Saturdays, we could not drink anything.
Then on Sundays, the whole day we had to fast
and pray to God." "Then - what about the rest
of the time?" "The rest of the time, we had
to remember Bible by heart and then recite
it. And if we made even one mistake, the Father
would give us a nice beating."
That's another problem with Sahaja Yoga because
it is Shri Krishna's play. It's so simple.
You don't have to do anything of the kind.
No disciplining, nothing. Left to you, you
are your own master. You are your own guru.
But these things which are lingering in your
mind, which was just the opposite of Shri
Krishna's life, which you have acquired in
this country, are still there, here and there,
here and there left. Some of the people are
really still so much busy with themselves.
They look so pale, thin - I tell you, I can't
believe they are Sahaja Yogis.
So when we see Shri Krishna's life, the way
He lived. And then He went to help the Pandavas.
He told Arjuna that, "I can be your charioteer.
I can drive your chariot. But I will not fight."
Arjuna knew that He was all powerful, if He
is there everything will work out. "And all
My army, I'll give to Kauravas, to see the
balance." He said, "All right." He didn't
fight to show off, I am this, I am that. Like
here, "Mother, I am the leader. (Laughter)
I am the leader." "Can't hear, I can't hear."
(Laughter) "Mother, I am this."
You are a Sahaja Yogi. It's a very great name
that you have achieved. The highest position
you have achieved. There's nothing more to
be achieved. Like somebody asked Me, "Mother,
the Indians in India never catch. Why do we
go on catching all the time?" I said, "Because
Indians in India know they have achieved it
now. Nothing to be achieved. You want to have
God's Realization - I don't know what other
Realization." They don't think like that.
They say, "We have achieved now. We are in
the sea. It's for us to swim over."
All these things some of you have crossed
over, some of you have absolutely lost them.
But some of you are still there. They are
the most dangerous thing as Christ has said,
"Be careful of the murmuring souls."
I don't know how to stop this little rat-like
people, who are cutting the nest of Sahaja
Yoga. I've been reported about many and I
am really shocked. After so many years of
My visit how can people talk ill of each other
and can create these problems?
Shri Krishna's friendship is well known, you
know with Sudama how He behaved. All His beautiful
manifestations must show in your character.
Then only this country can be saved. I must
say it's nowhere, we have Canada, we have
people also I am told from Austria. From all
over, from England. But still, we are not
so many people as we should have been. If
you just take Austrians, they must be double
of this. If they could do it, why can't we
do it? Because we do not introspect and we
do not grow out of our egos. They will say
that, "Why didn't Krishna meditate?" (Shri
Mataji laughing) You have to meditate on Shri
Krishna. If He meditates what will happen
to you all?
On the whole, I was very happy with the other
day's program, somehow. Despite, as usual,
in New York, our inability to really do good
advertising, unsystematic everything. Despite
that we had so many people and I put the responsibility
on them. Because that's the thing - it is
Shri Krishna's responsibility. And that is
what is your responsibility now. You are responsible
for America and Canada, South America. You
all are responsible and you people should
be such that people who see you listen to
you, are with you, should know that these
are the Gopa and Gopis of Shri Krishna. Unless
and until that happens, this America is the
most difficult place. Sometimes I feel it's
not Gokul but Mathura.
So it is for you, and otherwise you cannot
enjoy. If you live with your all old clothes,
you can't enjoy. I must say this time there
were so many people and I have asked them
to promise, and put a bandhan on them, and
I'm sure they will try to keep My promise.
I am sure. But it is you people who disappoint
them. When they see you, they are disappointed.
Actually, here is the first time, Vishwa Nirmala
Dharma has been established as a religion.
It is. But the rest of it is zero. So all
this differences and divisiveness has to finish
and we should be one in the collective nature
of Shri Krishna.
First, meditation is very important. Introspection
is very important. And also, meeting each
other, talking to each other, knowing each
other is very important. It has worked all
over. It has worked out in India tremendously,
Russia tremendously, Bulgaria tremendously,
so why not here? It's no fashion for brainless
people. It is a living process which has to
take place where you must mature. And what
I find that Americans are not matured. But
you are now mature. You are now mature people.
And I hope you will all behave like mature
people henceforth.
So may God bless you!
There are
Shri Krishna's names they have written down
and I would request leaders to come on the
stage. Now try to understand every word, every
name of Shri Krishna.
[Hindi ?]
Also, you
say
the name first and then they
will repeat it. Name and
the meaning and they will repeat it.
What about the children? They
can also come.
Firstly let us do little bit of Ganesha Puja.
If
there
are children.
[Hindi ?]
Very few children there are.
Just a minute ??? - Ganesha Mantra.