Today we are going to celebrate the Diwali,
which means the rows of lights or, you can
say, group of lights.
Need somebody to translate in Turkish also;
it's all right.
This Diwali has been a festival of very ancient
times in India. I already told in My previous
lectures what are these five days are. After
killing Narakasura, Diwali was celebrated
when it was the darkest night of the year.
So now, it is very symbolic of these modern
times, because the worst time, as far as morality’s
concerned has been in these modern times.
We call it the Ghor Kali Yuga. And as you
see around you’ll find out that there is
complete darkness as far as morality’s concerned,
but that's why there are all kinds of crisies.
Because of that, also, there are many who
are seeking the light, the truth.
In the darkness of ignorance - people have
no knowledge as to what they should do, why
or they are on this Earth. As you know very
well, that thousands and thousands of real
seekers who are born at this time. That is
why this job was given to Me is to create
Diwali in this dark ages of ignorance. It's
not an easy job because, on one side, we have
all the dark forces acting against the truth.
Also, on the other side, we have to fight
the false people who are taking advantage
of your seeking. Firstly, people don't know
what to seek, so all these false people have
been money-oriented and they tried to work
out marketing of their falsehood, and they
have the expertise to do it.
Somebody asked Me in Bogotá, a television
lady: “What about the cults that are killing
people and doing all sorts of things that
they did in Switzerland?”
So I said, “It's true, they are crooks,
they are horrible, they are criminals who
call themselves as spiritual, but the mistake
lies with the people who follow them.”
So a person who is absolutely immoral, absolutely
dishonest, who launders money to Swiss banks,
cannot be a guru. He used to buy these drugs
and sell them. He used to buy weapons and
sell them. He was worse than his disciple,
much worse. They have used a kind of a suggestion
from the books of so-called Guruvita or something
where it is said you should surrender everything
to your guru. That means it was to suggest
that a disciple should be willing to surrender
everything to the guru.
So, it was for the disciple; but for the guru,
he should not grab anything, he shouldn't
ask for anything, he should not be greedy.
All these things are already written down.
But nobody reads what is required of a guru
and only they see that you have to surrender
everything to the guru.
Why I'm telling you all this? Because how
the darkness is so deep and so dangerous.
Moreover, the other day I read an article
which said that in Milan there is a very,
very organization, a global organization of
satanicism. Many politicians and many people
in the government, very highly placed ministers
- prime ministers - are involved in it. Many
people who are bank managers or bank owners,
and also the people who call themselves social
workers, and also those who have got peace
award and this award, that award. So this
is what is the worst times of Kali Yuga, modern
times.
Now, the second day of Diwali, last day, is
where a brother and sisters celebrate together
for relationship, which is so pure and so
protective. That is to show that, after putting
the lights, morality must be the first priority
for the society. I need not tell you this
today immoral side of modern times. It's horrible.
Immorality is the greatest darkness of modern
times where people don’t know how they relate
to each other for which, as I told you before,
Christ has suggested that you take out the
eyes of a man who looks at a woman twice,
because He found, at that time, people were
horrid. Who can follow Christ in these modern
times? Both the eyes, both the hands will
be cut off. On the whole, if you see, I haven't
seen any Christian like that, so far.
Mohammed Sahib was even more strict. He thought
nothing has been done for the women, so he
passed through some regulations about women
also. So he said that any woman who looks
at a man with bad eyes should be buried halfway
and should be killed by stoning. I don't know
what would have happened to the American ladies,
if they had followed this.
So when I came to this earth I discovered
that these two are very difficult, especially
in Kali Yuga. These laws are actually meant
for not normal human beings, but for angels.
So, modern man is even worse than a normal
human being, because they want something destructive
all the time, like the Spanish ask the bull
to hit them.
Now the description of modern times is there
to show you in what times we are living. And
I realized it's not an easy thing to talk
to them about anything that is good without
giving them realization. Unless and until
you give them realization, nothing can penetrate
into their minds on just mental level. And
also giving only lectures and sermons, the
whole thing will be at a mental level only.
And also the religions, that are so-called,
are really very harmful for the spiritual
growth of human beings. I felt that enlightenment
is the only way one can save this world. In
this darkness of ignorance, the darkest night
of the whole history of this world, we needed
light and lights, many lights.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside to the interpreter/translator:
“Agni? Did you say in Sanskrit? Yes, Agni
means fire in Sanskrit language.]
All right. So the world divided into so many
countries, so many races, so many languages
and also their own thinking - to think of
a global religion was only possible when people
got their realization.
So, I had to study human beings, what are
their problems. So, in a light, in India,
we have the pot or the container, which is
made of clay, then the oil, and then the wick.
Now, this body, this mind, we can call all
that is visible and is within, is all the
pot, and the oil is the compassion, the love.
And the wick is the Kundalini, the pure desire,
and the spark is the Spirit. So, the - first
of all the container has to be all right.
It should be able to contain the oil properly
and should not allow it to ooze out.
Now there are two holes that cause problem.
One is your ego, another your conditionings.
So, if a Sahaja Yogi thinks of his conditionings,
that "I am a Christian,” or, he can say,
that, “I come from this race, I'm this community."
So all these limitations with which we have
built ourselves are so flimsy that they break
out, because there’s no reality in them.
There's no substance, so they fizzle out.
They all act like possessions and a person
becomes absolutely blind.
After coming to Sahaja Yoga, I've seen Christians
will adhere to Christ, Muslims will adhere
to Mohammed Sahib or to Ali, and others will
adhere to the conditionings from which they
have come. But they don't adhere to Me, so
they cannot see the integration of all these
personalities in One Person. Now, one has
to know, on this point, that you have got
the light. You are enlightened. You are not
an egg. You have become a bird. So, you have
to give up all that is falsehood.
If you are fully enlightened, you will give
up automatically, you don’t have to be told.
When the light is enlightened, it automatically
feels responsible that it has to give light.
Nobody has to tell that, "You please give
light" because it is light now. Because it
is eternal light, nothing can kill it. I will
say a Sanskrit shloka , [Shri Mataji speaks
in Sanskrit] - means it cannot be killed by
anyone, not air can blow it away, nothing
can destroy it. The - even if you want to
suck it, you cannot. It's such a powerful
light you have got within yourself. You can
verify whether it is eternal or not. You should
introspect and see for yourself. You've got
such a unique light within you. Not in the
history of this world of spirituality so many
have got realization, such light within them.
So how could these stupid, flimsy, useless
conditionings dominate you now when you are
the carrier of eternal light? But if you don't
respect this eternal life, then the conditionings
will put it off. This is the only problem,
that you have the freedom. You want to have
the eternal life, you'll have it, otherwise
this light can be damaged completely.
So, the another hole is that of ego. One side,
conditioning can be resolved by the sense
of responsibility. The same sense of responsibility,
when asserted through ego, could be very dangerous.
This light can become fire and it can burn
the house of Sahaja Yoga. In normal life,
we know that light is for giving us light,
not for burning houses; but when you get to
ego in Sahaja Yoga, you can think that you
are responsible for Sahaja Yoga, but this
responsibility should not give you an idea
that you are in charge of Sahaja Yoga. So,
then gradually you become so right-sided and
people are surprised that how this man who
was normal has become like a bull in the china
shop.
So you are not in charge of Sahaja Yoga. It's
like government servants. They are supposed
to be servants, but they are the bosses. They
become bosses. So the whole understanding
should be of complete wisdom in Sahaja Yoga.
The second part is the oil, which is compassion,
which is natural, innate and joy-giving. This
oil has to be pure. The compassion has to
be pure. I have seen many Sahaja Yogis try
to trouble the leaders. They oppose the leader
and try to hinder the work of Sahaja Yoga.
Now, these are supposed to be Sahaja Yogis
and they don't understand that if their compassion
is pure they will appreciate their leader
because the leader is doing such a compassionate
work. Of course, pure compassion, one must
understand, has nothing to do with greed,
with temptations, is nothing to do. One has
to feel such nearness with the leader and
appreciativeness of the work he or she is
putting in. So, compassion cannot be impure.
There cannot be lust in it. Moreover, this
compassion should be expressed in such a decent
manner that nobody should doubt your compassion.
Thank God to AIDS, one good thing has happened,
don’t - people don't kiss you. First time
when I went to Western countries, I was just
bombarded with kisses. I didn't know what
to say – I mean, it’s horrible. There
may not be anything wrong in the mind, but
it's so indecent and stupid. Long time back
I was told it was written on Indian airports,
"Please don't kiss the custom officers." [laughter]
In modern times a man can kiss a woman, but
he can't kiss a man. I mean, it's absurd.
Even if they make a goal in the match of football,
now they don't even hug, poor things, they
just touch with hands.... So, and now I've
seen many people who make a goal and are excited,
so they run out of the field. They don't know
what to do.... [laughter]
So, for Sahaja Yogis, we should know men can
kiss men and can hug them - there's nothing
wrong - and same with the ladies. Otherwise,
in excitement, they might run out of the field
of Sahaja Yoga. Men need not touch women,
women need not touch men. It's all right.
What is this nonsense? You can't express your
love? Say for India we have a rule that a
lady can touch the younger man and a man can
touch a much older woman, who could be a mother,
sister-in-law, anyone, which I think is a
good rule because it has worked out.
So, for compassion, it has to have decency
as fragrance in the oil. So how do we express
our compassion? We have rakhi sisters, rakhi
brothers, but I know of a lady who became
friendly with rich boys as rakhi brothers.
Or the other way round also, that many boys
became rakhi sisters of rich women - Racki
brothers
So, one has to understand that it is not for
money that you should become rakhi brothers
and sisters and to exploit, but for compassion.
You have to express your rakhi relationship
just for the protection of each other. The
compassion is so joy giving that you should
have not such conditions of money or any other
such stupid conditions which will kill your
joy. But another thing also is that to express
your love, you use some things as presents
that gives you joy. That doesn't mean, by
any chance, that you just give it to your
rakhi sister and not even to your wife, some
present.
So, the sap, as I always say, of compassion
has to rise in the plant, giving love to different
parts, in different ways, whatever is required,
and that it then evaporates or goes back to
its source. Attachment is the killer of pure
love and compassion. So try to always find
out, introspect. Are you attached to your
children, to your wife or to your rakhi sister
or to anything, attached? Then there's a danger
that you may get into a kind of a stagnation.
You’ll be amazed, when you are absolutely
detached and nourishing the different relationships
that you have in a proper way, your joy is
perfect. Ambition is another killer of joy.
So, if you have to be ambitious, you have
to be only ambitious about Sahaja Yoga, so
that you humble down. One promise in Sahaja
Yoga, is that your life will be full of joy.
There is no need to take out your eyes, cut
your hands, no punishments. If you have too
many holes, you need not come to Sahaj Yoga.
You have to become a real holy person, not
full of holes. I must say that you are all
"your holinesses." I’m not. I’m not, because
I've not become. You have become. Supposing,
somebody has to call you as a man, will they
say, "Oh, man, such and such"? No, because
you are a man. What you - whatever you achieve
is attached to you, whatever you have achieved.
[Shri Mataji commenting on translators: “This
Russian seems to be long translation, and
sometimes very small, and sometimes Romanian
very short, sometimes very long.”] [Laughter]
All right, so now the another thing that is
promised is bliss. What is bliss is the experience
of joy. It can come from anything. Maybe you
find you were in an accident, and you were
suddenly saved, protected. You are amazed,
and everybody feels the bliss. You also feel
the bliss.
[Laughter. Shri Mataji commenting on translation:
“To be very frank, I cannot translate. I
know languages, but from one language to another,
I cannot translate. That’s something wrong
with Me.”]
[Yogi: "But you understand very well, Shri
Mataji, what we say."]
[Shri Mataji: Well, it is very easy. See the
thought first is in an abstract form …(translation)…It’s
an abstract form, that's all I said. [laughs]
]
[The Russian yogi gives a very long translation.
"This is the reverse, Shri Mataji."] [Laughter]
All right, but thank you very much.
So, it is - you see, the - at that point anybody
can know what is the thought is because later
on it becomes a language, takes words. So,
if you can jump at that abstract, then you’ll
know that, but you have to put attention quite
a lot. Now, you have to pay attention to that
abstract form, you see, continuously
So now, to solve this problem, I would request
you all, to learn, at least, English language.
[applause] I'm not saying Sanskrit, but English.
Now, it’s the Kundalini, which is a pure
desire, is already existing; you don't have
to do anything. Maybe the cotton is not clean.
It has some problems, because it has passed
through dirty hands, but it can be cleaned.
Kabir has said something very beautiful about
it. He says that when the intestines of a
goat are inside the stomach, they say, "Mai,
mai, mai," means "I, I, I." But when they
are pulled out and are made into strings,
and put on a instrument for cleaning the cotton
wool - put on the instrument that cleans the
cotton wool. You know, in India we call it
"Duna." And when it is being strung, it says,
"Tu hi, tu hi, tu hi," means "You, you are,
you are, you are."
[Shri Mataji and the translators discuss these
words.]
All right, whatever it is. So, it means that
when your Kundalini is not working out well
because there are problems in your chakras,
what you have to say, "You are, you are."
You say that. "You are sakshat this. You are
sakshat that." Sakshat means "in reality."
In reality. You don't say, "You are Her Holiness
something." You said, "You are Ganesha. You
are this." That is how you cleanse all the
dirt or all the problems of your chakras.
By this, you also correct your conditionings
and your ego. Then you do not take the credit
for anything. You do not feel you are doing
something, and the whole personality changes
into a complete instrument like the flute
in the hands of Shri Krishna. Then you see
your work, everything as the work of the Divine.
That is how you become enlightened. That is
how you become the light of joy, of peace.
A lot has been said about what you are. That
is how, you see, is whatever is described
about, you become that. If there is a light,
you don’t have to say that it is a light.
It is. It is not a stamp that you have to
use.
So, today we are celebrating a Diwali of the
lights of Sahaja Yoga. I don't know what to
say, in what state of bliss I am. All the
ripples you have created of joy are overwhelming
for Me. No words can describe. I cannot compose
poetry. Keep this light burning beautifully
through meditation, and you can become very
strong beacons of light.
May God bless you, it’s Happy Diwali to
all of you.
I must say Diwali Puja is a very short one,
and My lecture has been three times said,
so you can imagine the time has been more
spent than normal.
Lastly, there are many who are invited in
India free. Most of them may not also pay.
Those who cannot pay for travel should let
us know… No, no - we have invited many people
to India. They should give their names, and
those who are free, I mean free for Ganapatipule,
but they are paying for their traveling. And
those who
are not paying for traveling also should give
their names. Also some of
the leaders who cannot pay are invited.
May God bless you all.