now of course it is also true the second
point is that in sahaja yoga you have to
become you cannot just say that all
right I am become a sahaja yogi no you
cannot nor can you say I'm following
Shri Mataji that also cannot be said nor
you can say that all right we have an
organization or something like that or
I'm wearing this just because she's my
guru you can't say that I have to become
you have to become a sahaja yogi if you
have to become a sahaja yogi then it has
to be worked out and that takes time to
rise from near each other to miracle
might take style for some people it
takes more time for some people it takes
less time depends on the preparation of
a person also I would say previous lives
good deeds and this lives understanding
so many things are there so it takes
time but at least one can talk about it
so that mas fear is created you can talk
to people tell them that we have found
the truth and it's very simple you can't
pay for it it just works it's
spontaneous it's a living process it's
an evolutionary process you can talk
like that not about me but about sahaja
yoga in an abstract manner it's such a
wonderful thing one should do it all
such talks are going to help us a lot
though I would say those who listen to
you may not get realization but at least
in that posture it will be and that is
going to help us a lot if it is in the
atmosphere people know that there is
something like this coming up for you
people of course you have to work hard
and you have to become sahaja Yogi's
becoming is a little bit difficult to us
sometimes because there's this great
mystery ego
or maybe certain conditionings you see
that people can't give up and that they
find it difficult
get out but if you know how to raise
your Kundalini she will manage it she
knows how to do it and she will give you
that status but first and foremost thing
is to meditate and to raise your body
meditation is the only way you can grow
there's no other way out
because when you meditate you are in
silence you are in thoughtless awareness
then the growth of awareness takes place
then it opens up but if you are thinking
supposing there's a lake and the lake is
completely in a turmoil nothing can grow
but supposing it is silent then notices
can grow anything can grow in it in the
same way if your mind is agitated and
your growth is not yet fully expressing
itself then it's such a vicious circle
that you are agitated
and your growth is hindered again you
are agitated your growth isn't there so
the best way is to take to meditation
when you take to meditation this turmoil
will settle down and ready to settle
down
your growth will take place after
meditation will feel definitely that you
have come out very well you know grow
very well but for that one has to be
very honest you cannot force people to
be honest that's one thing you can't do
you have to be honest yourself you are
not to be hypocrite you have to see for
yourself that whatever you are doing is
for your benevolence it's for your good
and that you have to do it because it is
good for you to begin with and then for
the good of the humanity you are doing
for the good of the humanity
now some people who come for the first
time we will have lots of doubts because
of ego they have lots of doubts because
of ego how can that be how can this be
how I mean all kinds of things they ask
now you have to say that first of all
you develop your inside you develop your
enlightenment your light is not
sufficient in the light only there are
no doubt
supposing in darkness you think that
this table has no cover it's alright you
can think whatever you like but when
there's light you see for yourself there
is a beautiful cover on top of this
table in the same way it happens to us
that we have to achieve a state and as
we achieve that state then there's no
question there's no doubt there's
nothing and you become so empowered it
is such a simultaneous thing it works as
soon as you achieve something it works
when it works then you are convinced
it's so I'd say it was a very beautiful
new chain starts within yourself
and then you really starts enjoying your
joy of yourself now it is for your gain
you have come to sahaja yoga not for
anybody else's gain first of all your
gain and once you gain something then
you can only help others to do something
about it so it is important to
understand the first rule of sahaja Yoga
is that you look at yourself how are you
really progressing or you are worried
about other thing like your business
thing is that all you are worried about
your asset what are you worried about
are you worried about your ascent if you
are worried about your ascent what are
you doing about it that has to be the
main object of life the rest of the
things followed once you are saying the
whole cosmos can look after your
problems but you must ascend into the
kingdom of God that's the main point is
so first of all you have to ascertain
about yourself am i ascending am i
transforming am i giving up all my bad
habits
am i getting rid of my temper
am I getting peaceful
am I now sweet or am I now still the
same horrible criticized er of others
just put your attention to yourself and
see for yourself it's like a mirror you
start seeing yourself in the mirror
what's wrong with you and then you try
to correct it now second point is that
you must see your vibrations what
centers you're catching yourself for
that you have to give yourself up on
that you give yourself abandon and see
for yourself what's wrong with you
when you give yourself up and then you
will know about your chakras and you'll
be amazed so that is how first pay
attention to yourself you find out
what's wrong with you
some of you might be having terrible -
ego then maybe you might be having a
very bad I'll getcha then you should
find out how we got wrong ketchup
this is equal then there's a very good
remedy in sahaja yoga which may look
ridiculous but it's very good remedy is
to beat yourself you choose as they know
it's the meeting with the shoes is
called as a shoe treatment now then you
have to go further see you find yourself
that your right side is hot what you do
is to put your right side towards the
photograph and left side up towards the
ether the ether takes away the heat but
what actually happens is that your right
side gets the vibration and the heat is
pushed towards your left and passes out
into theta now this heat comes from too
much futuristic living those people who
are too much futuristic they have too
much heat and too much heat has to go
away and when this heat starts going
away then you are amazed how it works
for that there are various things we
have to use but mainly for right-sided
people they should not use any light at
all they should not sit in the Sun they
should sit in the moon right they should
read some poetry they should not die
what
they should not look at time they should
allow the time to pass and they should
just become very sort of emotional
people they should sing songs of bhakti
they should not do hot yoga there's so
many things they should not do if their
right side you'd be surprised how people
have been helped through this kind of a
treatment which treats one side of your
being the left-hand side people are the
people as you know are the ones who are
those I who bear up lots of things from
others cry and weep and all the time on
the loser send such people have problems
also because all their organs are
lethargy and they have problems of a
guitar cheek heart the target liver
lethargic intestines everything becomes
very lethargic all these left-side
things can be cured plus they might have
some sort of a bother in them in the
sense they are possessed by someone of
course some of them are possessed by
right side also not that only the left
side is possessed but from the right
side also they're possessed and left
sided positions are of a peculiar type
because they give you pain in the body
you get pains in the body right-sided
person doesn't get any pain himself he
gives pain to others he's very sarcastic
he's very aggressive he troubles others
but the left-sided people have pains
themselves they get being here and a
pain there and pain here
so left side is to be cleared as you
know very well through the light light
is put before the photograph left hand
towards the photograph right hand on the
mother earth so the left hand gets the
light and the light passes through and
the negativity of the left side passes
through the right hand and the right
hand is on the mother earth the mother
earth is the one who sucks in all the
negative forces of the left-hand side so
these are the two sides which we clear
but once you have cleared these two
sides then you can use the photograph
sit with your both the hands towards the
photograph and put both the feet in the
water a little bit of salt in it and
about five ten minutes you must allow
vibrations to clear you out then wipe
your feet put the water properly into
some disposal and then sit down for
meditation if you can do that every day
even ten minutes is more than sufficient
don't have to do anything in an extreme
manner in the morning time you have to
give yourself abundant when you are
going out don't go out without giving a
button and attention should be all the
time
inside in the sense that walking on the
road people have habit of seeing these
in that sing like that the attention
gets returned away what you should do is
to see about three feet or 4 feet at the
most on the ground and not about because
you can see are the beautiful children
flowers everything there's nothing very
beautiful about that so better is to see
only up three four feet if possible to
fix your attention so the attention
becomes concentrated and you feel very
relaxed and relieved of too much of
wobbling of your eyes eyes are very
important very important and as you will
notice because you are all realized
souls that your eyes now have got a
gaint a kind of a light in the eye and
that light shows that you are a light
source so best thing is that you should
try to
you should try to put your attention
within yourself to see for yourself how
far you have grown through your
vibrations know yourself what is
required in you first and foremost thing
the light has to be clean then see how
far you can reach your mind how far you
can increase your dimension how far you
can go with others I hope this little
small little explanation about your
meditation and your method of rising and
ascending will help you to grow further
but I don't mind if you have any
questions I would like to answer them
may God bless you
may God bless you may God bless
see you must raise your Kundalini try to
raise it put your attention to your
sister say mother come in my head as
soon as kundalini crosses da guia you
cannot have those thoughts you should
allow this simple method also that if
you see any thought coming in you should
say I forgive I forgive is a very big
mantra see that taught me strong
what happens what happens it has an
effect all right it has anything but
after that I think you all should go
into meditation for a while after
listening to my lecture you just going
to my meditation actually my lectures
are not to be understood by your brains
but through your Kundalini and through
your heart so it's doesn't matter if you
don't remember something sorry I did so
many lectures have given how can you
remember I also don't remember much of
it but it will come handy whenever you
want to use some words so sentence it
will come handy you not know from where
it is coming it's all recorded is all
recorded
you