I bow to
all the seekers of truth. I’ve been many
a times in Birmingham before and today I find
there are so many people whom I know very
well, and gradually we are all increasing
in size, understanding our Spirit.
Now, the seeking of the Spirit is not a new
thing. It’s a very ancient pursuit of human
beings. They have been seeking the Spirit
and many a times many prophets, many great
incarnations came on this Earth to help the
people in their pursuit. The seeking of the
Spirit is a inner urge, a very compelling
urge within ourselves. But we don’t know
what we have to seek; we don’t know what
it means to be twice born.
I come from India and suddenly I feel I belong
to Britain. I’ve become British and I feel
the shock that we are all facing. Where are
we going? The other day I saw some program
about cocaine smuggling in England and I was
shocked. All self-destructive things sometimes
can be misunderstood as Spirit seeking. One
can misunderstand. But they lead us nowhere
- is a fact. Then why do we do it? We do it
- I know that we do it only because we are
seeking the Spirit. It’s very misleading,
though. We seek the Spirit in wrong things.
This urge we think will be fulfilled by wrong
things, by doing wrong to ourselves, by harming
ourselves, by torturing ourselves.
We get bored. Why? Why do we get bored of
life? Life should be bubbling with joy. Because
we think life is worth nothing, we have to
seek. And what do we seek there? It’s a
amazing thing how many seekers are born in
the West – so many seekers! Even I talk
to little children and I am surprised that
there is seeking within them. They are seeking
something and they don’t understand the
mystery of seeking. They don’t even understand
what they are seeking, but they think there’s
something wrong. They feel frustrated, angered,
and they feel that life has not given them
what they wanted. They’re bored stiff; they
don’t know what to do so they take to vandalism,
some sort of a sensation. They try to destroy
others or themselves.
So the human mind today is at a different
level, we must understand, especially in the
West. Of course East has its own problems,
but it has traditional understanding about
seeking and it understands what to seek. But
in the West such intense seekers are there
and they don’t know what to seek, what to
achieve, what is Spirit. It’s a big problem.
But today one has to realize that the category
of people that are born in these modern times
are very different from the people who were
born about say, I would say fifty years back.
They had political ambitions, economic ambitions;
they wanted to achieve political freedom,
power. That generation is practically over
now. They have realized that in this power
game they’re not going to gain anything.
It’s a subject finished now for them; it’s
something absurd. They find the whole thing
is a joke - same with the economic problem.
Like there was once upon a time a gold rush.
So everybody rushed to find the gold. Today
if anybody wants to do that, people will think,
“Are you mad? Must be joking.”
So the category of people today are of a different
level, we must be aware of that. We must understand
that the category is very different which
perhaps media people don’t understand so
much. I don’t think they have any idea as
to what is the level of awareness of human
beings today in the West. They are still of
that old school which was busy fighting elections
or strikes and this and that - all nonsensical
things. But the people who are aware are many,
many more than yet what we know of, that they
are seeking something very different that
their fathers and forefathers did not seek,
because the times are such. Today, it’s
a special time – special time where many
people have to get their Spirit. But then
again we are misled because people who are
trying to exploit this have found a good market,
and they come down to find out how they can
market their goods in this new awareness of
people.
We get enamored because we are still not fully
conscious or knowledgeable about what to expect
in your spiritual pursuit. And that’s how
they come and befool us. We have cults and
we have sects, but one must understand that
as you have grown through amoeba in your evolutionary
process, gradually, from that to this level,
the awareness has to also grow the same way,
in a traditional way. It cannot be somebody
like Freud coming up and saying something
new, that we accept. Suddenly, how can we
deviate from all those who talked of something
very different from what Freud has been talking?
Because it’s a mind which is of course very
aware, but also it is what we call very right-sided
mind, as is described in the Gita they are
called as the people who are rajasikas, the
people who are in action. They live with the
power of action.
So the people who live with the power of their
action live with their egos, and ego likes
something new, some sort of a new stuff comes
in they think, “Oh, why not do that? Try
this, try that.” It’s like a horse which
wants to go into every new direction and fails.
It’s a very venturesome horse, I think,
and that’s how something new somebody says,
everybody jumps to it. We are not new ourselves,
we are ancient. And when we take to some new
idea suddenly we find after some time that
we have to recoil back, because these are
all mental projections and that’s how in
every religion there have been sects formed.
Because, say Catholicism - Martin Luther who
was himself a realized soul saw that Pope
was doing all kinds of wrong things, so he
started a new sect. But it’s a mental projection
still, I would say, though he was a realized
soul. Then out of that came out I don’t
know how many churches. So now we have one
Unification Church which turned out to be
another horrible stuff, then we have Unity
Church where they unite all these sects – is
all projections, all branches of that mental
movement. But the essence is lost. In the
first case it was lost, and it was completely
forgotten in the last case.
So that’s how the sects were born. Now we
find Pentecostals. The other day I was reading
the harm it has done to people. We have all
kinds of faiths - Seventh Day Adventists.
What does it matter what was the seventh day,
the Sabbath? Supposing you have your Sabbath
day, say, on the seventh day, will you become
righteous? Will you become virtuous? Will
you become your Spirit? By changing a particular
type of ideology or thought, will you be transformed,
will you become great, will you become a super
human being? No. Then what? You think that
by going from one sect to another sect you’ll
achieve something great, you will just form
different social orders, that’s all.
Then you have anti-culture, another sect formed
as a reaction. That also is another problem.
All these venturesome ideas of this horse
takes you from places to places, and you think,
“Why whenever we try to do something why
we are committing the mistake?” Because
we have forgotten the fundamental, and the
fundamental is very simple, that you have
to seek your Spirit, and when you seek your
Spirit it is a spontaneous happening, it’s
a living process in your evolutionary process
by which you become the Spirit. By mental
projection you cannot.
Then the people who took advantage of the
situation that there are so many seekers on
this Earth, they started all kinds of cults,
also. I’ve been talking against them since
1970 that “Don’t go to these cults. These
are another ego-pampering stuffs.” Suddenly
they start a new idea – it appeals to you.
Suddenly someone says that “No, by leading
this kind of a life you’ll achieve God.”
You accept it. Why not find out? Since ages
people have been writing about the spiritual
life. What does that mean? How to achieve
it? Why do you take to anyone who just says
that “This is so, this is so”? Because
perhaps they have a nice circus or a publicity.
There must be something that is so attractive
that people take to it. Or maybe it is some
sort of a ego-pampering that you want to join
these cults and get destroyed.
There cannot be a cult for your assent. What
cults did you follow to become human beings?
The nature itself works it out. It is a spontaneous
happening. But for a person who lives only
with mental projections, morning till evening
you see television or listen to radio, it’s
nothing but mental projection all the time,
you see, hovering on your head. You cannot
think that there is something beyond that
mental projection which is the reality.
So you find reality horrifying, absolutely
horrifying. You have to pay the tax; you have
to pay the rates; you have to pay this. You
have to be like this; you have to be dressed
up like this; you have to have clothes like
this. All kinds of pressures on your head.
So now what to do? How to get out of this?
This is reality for people.
So then we accept the drugs and the alcohols
and things because we want to get out of it.
That gives definitely a sensation, hallucination;
but reality in itself is so beautiful, is
so surmounting all this, that we have to honestly
understand that if it is reality, it cannot
be hallucination. It cannot. You cannot pay
for it. You cannot follow somebody who says
something against the tradition of evolution.
It has to be fundamental, what it has been
and will be. It has to be something that is
integrating everything, integrating all the
religions, integrating all the religious leaders,
all the great prophets and all the great incarnations,
otherwise it cannot be reality because reality
has to be one. It should unite everything.
It cannot create a separate identity on mental
level. It may create on a spiritual level,
maybe, that people who get Realization, who
have got Self Realization, maybe the people
form a more coordinated concord among themselves,
but they’re all the time worried about the
other people who are not yet in there – not
for money, not for lust, not for greed, but
only because they want to share the joy of
reality.
This has to be first of all understood by
all those who are seeking that reality cannot
be a mental projection, neither can it be
a emotional projection which we can manage
ourselves. One moment we are in love, another
moment we are walking to the divorce cases.
Why? If there was some truth in that kind
of a love, why? It is something beyond, which
is eternal, which doesn’t change, which
overflows, is promised. What about that? Why
not seek that?
Then you turn your eyes to find out where
it is described. Vedas were written thousand
of years back and every Veda, whichever you
read, the Upanishads as they are called as
the people where they have described about
human beings have talked that you have to
worry about your Spirit, it’s the Spirit
that is important. Then you have other people,
in India we had fourteen thousand years back
some great poets. All of them have said the
same. Then we have people in other countries
like Abraham, like Moses, we have Confucius,
Lao Tse. We have Krishna, Rama. All of them
have said one thing, and one thing that “You
seek your Spirit.”
If so, then how? We should again look back.
It is described how to seek it. It is described
in Gita, but much before that it is described
in the Vedas very clearly about the Kundalini
and the seven Chakras. Nobody says in any
book that when the Kundalini awakens you become
mad or you start jumping like a frog.
Recently I went to Pune, and there I was surprised
that the Brahmins of Pune, who are supposed
to be very learned people, were all suffering
from high blood pressure, from kidney troubles,
from insanity. I mean name any disease, they
had it. I said, “Why are they suffering
like this?” So there was one fellow called
[Gumani, Gurumani, or Gulumani ???] Maharaj
who really came as the killer of all these
Brahmins, I think, that they followed him.
And their main person came to discuss with
Me about his religion, so-called.
And he started asking Me, “Do you know about
“terno pai, erno pai”
I said, “What is that? I’ve never heard.
Where is it described?”
‘Oh, You have never heard about it?”
I said, “No.”
“Do You know about shaktipath?”
I said, “I’ve never heard about this.
From where does it come? Which book?”
“Oh, it’s from one book.”
I said, “Which book?”
“About sixty years back there was one Vishnutirth,
Swami Vishnutirth who wrote this book.”
I said, “Really?”
He’s the only one. Only sixty years back
this fellow comes up from somewhere, writes
down something new, “erno pai, terno pai.”
All the Vedas, all the Shastras are all finished.
Bible is finished. Everything is finished.
Only this fellow sixty years back comes up
from somewhere and talks about shaktipath
and you believe it. All of you, the Brahmins,
the educated, the learned.
I said, “Where do you see these words in
the Vedas? Show Me. Where do you see them
in the Patanjali Yoga Shastra? Show Me. Is
it written anywhere? “
He said, “We haven’t read them.”
I said, “What did you read?”
“This Vishnutirtha’s book.”
I said, “You are supposed to be learned
people in Sanskit. You read only this Vishnutirth
who came only sixty years back?”
How can it be? And all of them are so sick
you won’t believe it, and in My presence
when they came they were in a very bad shape,
absolutely in a very bad shape as if they
had taken cocaine or something worse than
that. Eyes were going up, their hands were
moving like this, all kinds of things.
And I told them, “Please forgive Me. Go
to Vishnutirth or to his disciple, this [Gumani,
Gurumani, or Gulumani ???] Maharaj.”
And the only thing they did was not to eat
this, not to eat that, not to have relationship
with your wife, become like a dry bean, live
on a shoe string and then you become godly,
is it? It’s very simple. In India so many
are like that already.
Use your brains! They are very brainy people.
I said, “How could this man dominate you?”
So they came out with very intelligent answer
that “In the Vedas, you see, when we followed
the Vedas and what did we get?”
“All right.” I said, “You didn’t get
anything. But there’s something promised
in the Vedas, in the ancient books, that in
Kali Yuga, at these modern times, you will
get your Realization. Why didn’t you go
for that?”
But this fellow says that through erno pai,
karuno pai - God knows all kinds of nonsensical
words, it has no meaning at all in Sanskrit
language - that you will get your Realization.
All right, anybody says so, must you join
him? You should have asked, “How do you
get these words? From where did you find them?”
You should have asked Mr. Freud, “From where
do you get your knowledge?” He, himself,
was a drug addict. He, himself, was a horrible
man. He had bad relations with his mother.
He had a cancer, and he becomes your guru
instead of Christ? Suddenly, and you accept
him.
Those people who deal on mental level cannot
talk of God. They cannot understand God. God
can be only understood through your Spirit.
Like your theologians here – theologians
– what do they understand about Christ?
They haven’t got power to talk about Christ.
Just because they are elected, they are just
paid servants of the people to look after
the churches, that’s all. They don’t deserve
to be saints. Why are they so important? At
least in India nobody treats them as something
great. They are just priests, finished.
You have to be a saint to understand God.
You have to be a realized soul to understand
His miracles. You cannot just become a theologian
in a theology school or somewhere and start
talking about God. It’s blasphemous the
way these people talk about God and Christ.
I don’t know how you tolerate it. In India
they would have been stoned and finished long
time back. They don’t know what God is,
how can they know about Christ? It has been
on and on from this Augustine time and this
Paul also another horrid fellow. I don’t
know how they call him as Christian, from
where he becomes Christian. And that now they
are not following Christ, they are following
Paul.
Theologians, intellectuals cannot understand
God. He’s beyond your limited intellect;
He’s an unlimited personality. You have
to jump into that. With your limited knowledge
you can play your horses of your politics,
not of God. Such arrogance, such ego! You
are challenging the wrath of God on your countries
when you go about like this.
Please humble down yourself and understand
that God is beyond your petty intellect. First
become your Spirit. You have to become your
Spirit. By reading if you understand God,
then he’s not God. It’s clearly said “Atmanave
Atmana Tattwa”. You see, through the Spirit
you will know God. Christ has said it so clearly
to Nicodemas that “You are to be born of
the Holy Ghost.” And Who is the Holy Ghost?
These people who go to theological colleges,
are they Holy Ghosts or what are they? They
are nothing but ghosts of intellect.
Beware of them. This is another very subtle
attack on reality. And they all will have
to suffer for it, they must understand. You,
those who are seeking, should seek your Spirit
and should understand that you are invited
in the Kingdom of God. The time has come;
this is the judgment time. This is the judgment
and you can see it so clearly.
So there is attack on the seekers. One, from
ignorance because they don’t know what to
seek, how to seek, what to expect; and there
is attack also from outside because they think
you are ignorant, because they think they
know more than what you know. They don’t
know anything about Christ, believe Me - Who
He was, why He came on this Earth, and how
He plays His role so perfectly within ourselves.
I would request you all to receive your Realization
first. There’s no argument about it; there’s
no discussion about it. Even if you try to
argue it out – I may be able to answer you,
but that won’t give you your Realization,
your Kundalini has to rise. Humble down in
your heart.
I went to a village where about three thousand
people came from all hills of Himalayas, very
simple people. And they were waiting for this.
I asked them, “How is it you were waiting?”
“Oh, it is said. It’s said it, that Devi
Jagaran will be there in modern times. We
were waiting for You to come, Mother. Devi
Jagaran is the awakening of the Goddess, of
the Kundalini.
The villages know about it. On the foothill
of Himalayas they are waiting. In one day
I got three thousand people realized. In this
Birmingham, how many people there are today
who are new, who have come to receive their
Realization? Very few. But theologians get
all these lectures. They like to play with
their mental projections.
But beware, time is very short. Better get
your Realization. Become the Spirit and then
you will know that God is not intellect, It
is love. And love which is not limited – unlimited
love which is the most powerful thing in this
universe which you can become aware of and
you can become empowered with that great,
unlimited love which just flows, acts, coordinates,
thinks, plans, works out everything. This
All-Pervading Power about which you have heard,
you have to know That and get It. You can’t
pay for It. You can’t organize It. It has
to work out like a living process within you.
May God bless you.
I would like to know if you have any questions.
[Shri Mataji says aside, “Ice, I don’t
take ice. It is very cold water.]
Come along, come forward. There are lots of
seats here. Who are sitting at the back, come
along. Sit at here.
Can you hear Me? Is it all right? Have you
any questions? Come along, this side. There’s
room this side. Don’t sit on the ground.
There’s room here this side. Any questions?
Question: A man asks if it helps to be a vegetarian.
Shri Mataji: No, no. It has nothing to do
with vegetarianism or not. Christ was not
a vegetarian. It’s all absurdity. Of course
you have to eat whatever suits you. I would
say that – whatever suits you. This vegetarianism
is a fad. It’s just a fad. To believe that
by eating some food you’ll go to God is
a wrong idea. But, of course, alcohol goes
against your awareness, you know that. But
I don’t say, “Don’t take alcohol.”
You will just not take it, that’s all, because
you get the alcohol of God within you and
then you don’t want to take it. That’s
a different point. But I won’t say just
now that “Don’t take it.”
But food has to be seen whatever’s suitable
for your body. I would say that Indians should
take to meat. It would be better. And the
Western people should take to vegetables,
it would be better for them, just to balance.
Question: How do you become your Spirit?
Shri Mataji: That’s a very good question.
That’s the question is - I’m saying it
is a spontaneous happening and that within
us is placed, if you see here in the triangular
bone, is the power of Holy Ghost within us,
which we call in Sanskit language as Kundalini.
In Koran it is called as Assas. In every scripture
it is described. And this Kundalini has to
rise, this power which is the desire power,
which is the pure desire power, because all
other desires are not pure. If they were pure,
then you would have been satisfied. But you’re
not satisfied.
So this pure desire is the desire to become
one with the Spirit. And this is within you,
this force is within you dormantly placed
in the triangular bone called as sacrum. That
means the Greeks also knew the word sacrum
means “sacred.” And this power has to
rise within you, and there are subtle centers
above it, six centers above and one center
below through which it pierces and you feel
the Holy Ghost, which is described by Christ
and you feel the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost
coming out of your fontanel bone area which
is the real baptism. And as a result of that
you start feeling your Spirit in your consciousness,
means in your central nervous system. You,
yourself, feel it.
That’s how you become the Spirit. That’s
the only way it is sprouted. It’s a living
process like if you want to sprout a seed,
you have to embed it into this Mother Earth
and spontaneously with the power what Mother
Earth has, it sprouts. In the same way it
happens, and that’s how I have to work it
out. But later on when you get it and you
become established, you can do it yourself
to others. Like one enlightened light can
enlighten another light. But the first light
has to be enlightened.
For that you can get some books from here,
but once you start reading books also I find
you become more bookish, so it’s better
to postpone the reading for some time. Better
get your Realization first. Like I would say
that when you want to put lights on you say,
“All right, switch on.” It’s all built
in there; it’s all done. Only thing you
have to switch on. And the whole thing becomes
enlightened. But I could first of all tell
you all the details about the history of electricity,
then all the organization that has worked
it out - would be a headache. Better have
your light first.
And then you’ll know all about it. And this
is not I’m saying that is today. Has been
said for thousands of years. That is how we
become the Spirit. Christ didn’t tell us
lies when He said that “You are to be born
of the Holy Ghost.”
He never said that any priest can put his
hand on your head and say, “Now you are
a Christian.” Did He say so? He did not.
That’s all artificial. That’s why children
cry such a lot when they’re baptized, I
think. Like William Blake has said that “A
priest cursed me on my head.”
Any other question, please?
Now we have to work it out. It’s very simple
and it will work out in no time. It works
out. It will happen to you in no time but
the problem is, it’s a new experience and
people actually think that when you get an
experience you must jump or you should become
like a mad person. I don’t know what things
are expected.
You become empowered, and unless and until
you use this power how will you know you’re
empowered or not? So to establish that power
you take some time. Once you have established
that power then you can see yourself how you
are blessed, that how this power is flowing
through you of God’s compassion, that how
you are blessed in every way and how you,
yourself, become the source of joy – to
yourself and to others. How you jump into
a new awareness of collective consciousness
by which you can feel the problems of others
and your own problems, how you can cure your
problems and cure the problems of others.
For this you have to have patience with yourself
for a little while and once you’re established
you will see that you, yourself, become your
own master, your own guru.
So to achieve it, we have to do few things
is to understand that we have to have, first
of all, desire. You and your freedom cannot
be challenged. So you have to have intense
desire to be the Spirit. If you have that
desire in your heart, it works much faster.
To express that symbolically we put the left
hand like this which represents the power
of desire and the right hand is the power
of action. We have to take out our shoes because
the Mother Earth helps us a lot. We have to
take out our shoes to take some help from
Mother Earth. Thank God here it’s not concrete,
slightly better than that.
To put both the feet on the Mother Earth in
a parallel manner, and be comfortable - you
have to be comfortable. Now supposing somebody
is feeling uncomfortable because of something
that’s tight on the neck or on the waist,
please loosen it a little bit if you find
that. But if you’re comfortable, it’s
all right. Or somebody has got a coat which
is making one uncomfortable, you can take
it out.
Attention should not be distracted towards
some discomfort to the body. That is important.
Secondly, if you can take out your spectacles
will be better because here you don’t have
to see anything, you have to keep your eyes
shut.
So please put both your feet on the Mother
Earth, your left hand towards Me like this,
with the desire in the mind that we have to
be the Spirit. We are not yet complete till
we become the Spirit; we are not complete
to understand God Who is absolutely complete.
Now the right hand is to be used for the action.
That is on the different centers we have certain
problems. In a village I don’t have to do
all this. You’ll be surprised, it’s just
like this, (Shri Mataji clicks Her fingers)
just like that. I don’t have to do anything
whatsoever. But we are little complicated
so doesn’t’ matter. We have to remove
our own hurdles by putting our hands into
different things. [Shri Mataji speaks aside
in Hindi] Please put your shoes at the back.
Now, you have to keep your eyes shut, but
before that I’ll tell you the different
centers we’ll try to clear out. One is on
the heart because heart reflects the Spirit.
So that’s why one.
Then secondly we’ll have to put our hand
on the upper part of the abdomen on the left
hand side. The whole thing we are working
out on the left hand side because here resides
the center that governs the mastery. Then
below that is the center that governs the
true knowledge, the pure knowledge.
Then here is the center on the left hand side
which is very important, because this is the
center where when we feel guilty, condemn
ourselves, try to show that we are sinners,
we are good for nothing, a blocket is built
up. And that blocket is very common in the
Western people, surprisingly. Whatever you
may say there is ego, this blocket of feeling
guilty is too much. They all the time feel
guilty for everything that is nonsensical,
or maybe little sensible also, but mostly
nonsensical. So a blocket is built. That’s
how you develop this angina troubles and you
develop other troubles like spondylitis and
all that. So this is a very important point.
At the very outset you must know that you
are not guilty of anything, and God’s power
of forgiveness is so great that He can wash
up whatever wrong you have done. He’s quite
capable. So don’t try to condemn yourself.
Know that you are the temple of God and the
Light has to come within you. That’s all.
So the hand has to be here, push back when
I tell you. Then the hand goes here - is the
center here is very important of Christ which
is in the center of optic chiasma. The center
of Christ is there where you have to forgive
others. At the back is the center where you
have to ask for forgiveness, just to get over
your guilt. And then you have to put your
hand on top of the fontanel bone area which
is the soft bone in your childhood. Put your
palm, just please put it just on top of that.
Stick out your fingers, press it hard and
move it seven times clockwise when I tell
you.
So this is what we have to do ultimately and
then you will see that the Cool Breeze will
be coming out of this fontanel bone area.
You have to certify yourself and then you
start feeling the All Pervading Power of God’s
Love as Cool Breeze around you, on your fingertips.
You have to know on your fingertips. Nobody
else has to certify. You have to certify yourself.
So now first of all we close our eyes. At
the very outset we have to tell ourselves
that we are not guilty.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside in Hindi] These
are uprooted people from India so you shouldn’t
worry about them.
Please have your right hand on your heart.
Keep your eyes shut. Please have your right
hand on your heart. On the heart is on the
left hand side above the stomach. Heart. Higher,
it’s higher. Now, at this point you have
to say, or you have to ask Me a question,
in your heart.
“Mother am I the Spirit?” Ask this question
three times. If you want you can call Me “Shri
Mataji” or you can call Me “Mother”,
whatever suits you.
“Mother am I the Spirit? Mother am I the
Spirit?” Ask the question three times.
Now, put this right hand on the left hand
side in the upper part of your abdomen. Please
put this right hand, your fingers, press them
in, on the left hand side, in the upper part
of your abdomen, that is stomach. Now , this
is the center of the mastery. Keep your eyes
shut. Now as you are the Spirit, you are your
own guide.
So now ask the second question, “Mother,
am I my own master?” Three times. “Mother,
am I my own guide?” “Mother, am I my own
guru?” Ask a question within yourselves.
Three times.
After asking this question please don’t
open your eyes, and put your right hand – left
hand to be all the time towards Me and the
right hand in the lower part of your abdomen
on the left hand side. Please put your right
hand in the lower part of your abdomen, your
stomach, on the left side, on the left side.
Press it hard.
Now this is the center of our true knowledge.
As I told you, you are free, I cannot force
things upon you. So please, you have to ask
for it. The true knowledge of Divine Power,
how it works, here you have to ask six times,
“Mother, please may I have the true knowledge,
the true technique? May I have the pure knowledge?”
Ask the question six times, please.
Keep your eyes shut, please. Don’t open
your eyes. Ask this question with full confidence,
please. Keep your eyes shut, please, all of
you.
Now, with your asking the Kundalini starts
getting alert. The Power of Desire wants to
ascend. So you have to make proper seats or
arrangements for the Kundalini’s rise. So
what do you do is to put your hand now on
the upper center that is placed on the left
hand side of your abdomen, in the upper part.
Now, in the upper part of your stomach, on
the left hand side you place your fingers.
Now press them.
Now here you have to say with full confidence,
that the Kundalini wants to rise but you show
your full confidence by saying ten times,
because this center has got ten petals, ten
times. “Mother, I am my master. Mother,
I am my guide. Mother, I am my own guru.”
Please say it with full confidence.
This is the place is created by all the great
masters, satgurus as they are called, within
us. They have to be awakened by this confidence
that you say. Ah. Ten times, please.
[Shri Mataji rubs Her hands together and blows
on Her palms]
Now raise your right hand on to your heart.
On the left hand side it is. Please raise
your right hand on to your heart. Now here,
with full confidence again in yourself, you
have to say, “Mother, I am the Spirit.”
Twelve times. “Mother, I am the Spirit.”
Twelve times. Because you are, but have confidence.
Don’t feel guilty.
As I told you, God is the Ocean of Love. He’s
the Ocean of Compassion, but above all He’s
the Ocean of Forgiveness. With full confidence,
please say, “Mother I am the Spirit” twelve
times.
Now, with full confidence again, put your
hand on your neck on the left hand side from
the front, from the front. Don’t take it
backwards because is easier from the front.
And push it towards the back. Hold it tight,
hold it tight. Here is the problem where you
have to know that you are not guilty at all.
Here with full confidence please say sixteen
times, “Mother, I am not guilty.” Please
say it sixteen times with full confidence
in Me, yourself. You’re not guilty at all.
Believe Me, you’re not guilty of anything
– is all conditionings and all kinds of
things, the norms that people have created,
is all their mental projections. You’re
not guilty at all. Believe Me. But if you
still think you are guilty, you better have
punishment of saying it hundred and eight
times.
You have to be pleasantly placed because you
have to enter into the Kingdom of God. You
have to be pleasant about it. Not to be disgusted.
Now, sixteen times please say, “Mother,
I am not guilty at all.” Believe Me you
are not guilty.
From your heart please say, “I am not guilty.”
Believe Me. Believe Me.
Now, now raise your hand to your forehead
across and press it on both the sides as we
do when we have headaches. Now here you have
to say from your heart, from your heart, “Mother,
I forgive everyone.” But this is from your
heart. How many times is not the point.
Now some people say that’s difficult to
forgive. But it is again a mental idea that
we forgive someone, or we don’t forgive
someone. Actually, we don’t do anything.
But when we don’t forgive, then we play
into the hands of people who want to do us
harm.
So put your hand on top of your forehead across,
forehead across and say, “Mother, I forgive
everyone” from your heart. Please say it.
You wanted to have your Realization, isn’t
it? Please, go ahead with it. Otherwise then
you’ll say “We didn’t feel it.” Come
along. As you asked the question, please go
ahead. Everybody’s doing it. What’s so
special about you? Just do it. Otherwise you’ll
say, “We didn’t get Realization.” Then
I’m not responsible. You are here to get
your Realization. Be sensible. What are you
going to lose?
If you are seekers, please do it. [Shri Mataji
rubs Her hands together] It’s not proper
that you should watch others. It’s not civil.
Now put your hand on top of your head. Here
– we have missed one center because I don’t
think you need to do that one where you have
to ask for forgiveness – but just put your
hand on top of your head and press it hard
on the fontanel bone area and move it in a
clockwise manner. Here now, again, I cannot
cross your freedom, so you have to say, “Mother,
please give me my Realization.” Seven times.
“Please give me my Realization, I want it.”
I cannot force it.
Place your hand on top of your head, top of
your head, on the top, and press it hard,
and move it. Now, seven times. Now, bring
down your hand, please. Slowly open your eyes.
Slowly open your eyes. Now see, there are
no thoughts in the mind. Just see for yourself.
Watch Me without any thought. Just watch Me.
Put your left hand on top of your head. Left
hand. And right hand towards Me, and see if
there’s a Cool Breeze coming in. Just move
it up and down. It’s very subtle. Here,
here. Here, the fontanel bone is here. All
right? It’s very subtle.
Now, change your hand. Put your left hand
towards Me. See with the right hand. [Shri
Mataji blows into the microphone]
Now change, see it with the other hand. Carefully.
Without thinking. [Shri Mataji blows into
the microphone] Feeling it? There’s a little
breeze coming out. Are you? Little bit here
in front.
Now, those who are feeling the Cool Breeze,
raise both the hands. Let Me see. Those who
have not felt, should not. You should be honest
about it. All right.
Now, all of you raise your hands and ask a
question, “Is this the Breeze of the Holy
Ghost?’’ Ask a question three times. “Is
this the Breeze of the Holy Ghost?” Now,
put your hands like this. See if It is coming
in your hands also. It’s a very subtle thing.
It’s very subtle. Now, put down your hands
and see are you feeling It in your hands,
some sort of a cool breeze. If you are not
feeling, doesn’t matter. We’ll work it
out. Doesn’t matter. Don’t get upset.
All right?
Now those who have come for the first time,
please raise your hands because people will
come and see you if you are feeling the cool.
First time. Please raise your hands. Are you
feeling the Cool Breeze. No? You are? All
right. Now those who have come for the first
time, please raise your hands because people
would like to see you. All right. Just see.
Now, we have here people who have got Realization,
who are established people and they would
like to see if your chakras are all right
because they’ll just feel your Cool Breeze.
Now the thing is, this is what, exactly what
happened to Christ’s disciples. When they
felt the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost, they
started using their hands because the chakras
and all that, they could feel raising of the
Kundalini and they started talking in the
terms of the centers. So people thought they
were mad. Because this is a new language,
a new subject for them. So people thought
they were mad. Exactly the same way you will
also feel everything on your fingertips.
Now, don’t think about it. Again, I would
request you to raise your both the hands those
who have come for the first time so others
could come and feel it, if there is a Cool
Breeze coming out of your head or not. If
it is not coming, doesn’t matter. All of
you who have come for the first time, who
have come for the first time, please raise
your hands. Is important because they will
all take over.
Come along. Forward. You have? You have come
for the first time? All right. You’ve come
before? All right. Doesn’t matter. You raise
your hand. Raise your hand. Also, those who
have not felt the Cool Breeze, raise your
hands. All right.
Can you have a look now? Some of you should
go and see. Now the lady who asked Me a question,
Adita can you see her? She didn’t do anything
and she had neighbors who didn’t do anything
at all. So just see if she’s felt the Cool
Breeze. She has felt it. This lady has come
for the second time, she said. Just see her,
Danny. Liver. Liver. Let her put her right
hand, left hand on the liver.
Now don’t think about it. You cannot think
about it. You try to remain in thoughtless
awareness. [Shri Mataji says aside “ May
God bless you.”] Just see this gentleman
who came for the first time, this gentleman.
Yes. See him, if he’s felt the Cool Breeze
on his head. Now I have to request you one
thing – that, though you have felt it, you
have to establish it. Now don’t waste your
Realization. See these people, all of them,
they have got their Realization, they’re
helping people, that’s how we have to save
this world. And now you will know that what’s
the meaning of your life, why are you here,
what’s the purpose.
Did this gentleman come? You felt it? Still
see him. They have got? He’s got it, you
can see so clearly. Eyes start sparkling.
Hah. Is it better? It’s better now. You
think too much. Don’t you? All right. For
that what is to be done she’ll tell you.
It’s very simple to get rid of it. [Shri
Mataji speaks in Marathi and Hindi]
Just see. Kalab [not sure how to spell this
name], just see him.
There are some new people here? Are there?
Some Sahaj Yogis should come and see this
side. Have you come for the first time? No.
No. You are Sahaj Yogis. Just see here. Some
Sahaj Yogis should come and see there. Come
along. Um. Better? Better. Don’t think.
Just don’t think for awhile. Ah. Is he all
right? Ask him to keep his eyes open. More
on the left. More on the left. Right to the
left you should put it. Right to the left.
Yah. Better. These two ladies here. All right?
Good. How many beautiful people there are
in this world, just see. You have to just
find them. Hah. It’s better with that, very
beautiful, isn’t it? That’s the fact.
That’s the fact. They are beautiful. Ah.
Better. Flowing better. [Shri Mataji talks
in Marathi and Hindi] All right? It’s good.
[more Hindi]
Down below, little. Pat, there’s a gentleman
in front of you here. Just see what about
him. One ahead. Here. No, in there all right.
Yes, this gentleman. Just find out about him.
Yes, please find out. Next to that one.
Did you feel the Cool Breeze? Beg pardon?
What did he say? He didn’t feel it? Should
feel it. What do you say? It’s all right.
Next to that one also. He’s got it. He’s
got it. Keep your eyes open, please. Just
watch Me without thinking. Just watch Me without
thinking. Hah. Better. [Shri Mataji laughs]
Don’t think. Don’t think. With thinking
you cannot be there. This is the first mantra,
first chanting, “Don’t think, don’t
think.” By thinking we reach nowhere. [Shri
Mataji laughs again] It’s maddening, I tell
you.
The lady who asked the question, how is she?
She’s what? Hah. Good? That’s very good,
Ian.
Those who have come today and are not yet
attended to, please raise your hands. Anyone.
Hah. Great. You’ll knock down ten years
at least. Ten years younger, minimum. I am
sixty-three years of age, Myself. I might
be the oldest among all of you. Good? It has
nothing to do with age or anything. Good,
he’s got it, you can see.
These ladies also, they have got it. All right?
Good. Thank you very much, all of you. May
God bless you.