now
this left hand side of the heart
is concerned with your mother
and with shiva
the existence you get your existence
through your mind
and shiva and power they are your
parents both are your parents
as far as your existence
and it is such a beautiful
center is your heart center
you want somebody to do something for
you twice
they want that somebody should need
or something you find somebody very
obsessed like i have
told you that you can beat them with you
do all those things but there's a very
simple way if you know how to do it
you see you just think of their
their heart and put a bandhan to that
and you can do it so beautifully
you can melt a person without any
difficulties if you know how to handle
their heart you have to appeal
to their heart and that's the best
attraction
at all and the best
secret method by which you can bring
good india when you are talking to
somebody
supposing i now intellectually if i
start
quarreling with you you'll give me up in
no time but
i have to use your power and i have to
enter into your
heart and that is how it works so always
when
you want to do something like that just
humble down yourself
in your heart that is first first of all
you must tumble down yourself in your
heart
and from there work on the heart of
others just put
a bundle and you will see a person will
melt away
we melt our intelligence our ego
everything even your superego in your
heart
so it's a very thing if you know how to
approach people
through their heart and
that is only possible if you are genuine
because genuineness is something that a
heart recognizes
you can be fool a person with your
cunning methods
but the heart will recognize it later
and the person will
hate you even if you talk to someone oh
very much very good thank you very much
and the heart knows so he's trying to
before me and he is very funny
the heart is going to hate such a person
and
heart has the utterance and feel the
person
so if you could appeal to somebody's
heart and put a bundle
on the heart you can melt that person
and if you love someone and if you want
that person should be corrected
supposing such a person is a drunkard or
a person who beats you
and is torturing you because he's under
the spell of
some drugs or some sort of a foreign
thing
then you just put bandhan to his heart
and you see
they'll be changing they'll be changing
very fast
and that's why you say change of heart
everywhere you find
in every scripture it is written change
of heart is needed not the change of
clothes
so it's not intellectual but a rational
change
but it is the change of heart and that
is brought about
by moving
the heart chakra on the right hand side
in the clockwise moment
that is the heart itself in the
clockwise mind if you can do that
you can really do marvels and that's how
on a collective basis the heart
is sort of the innermost innermost
string of the collective
one string that is passing through
alliance so
if you put strike at the innermost
because in
a three and a half circle that's the
innermost point
if you touch there it passes over this
supposing you touch somewhere else then
it might break
but at the beginning if you start
striking it it goes
very nicely and passes into complete
circumference
now the center one i have told you is
the
heart nexus which we call as cardiac
plexus
and it has got tens of plexuses and the
english names for that i will
again i'm going to give you the complete
list i don't know when will i have time
to go to the
medical journal but i'll find out all of
them and i'm going to tell you what they
call it
in the medical terminology but they know
that very there are tens of plexuses
which are supplying to the muscles of
the heart
to the lungs iron to the right side
lungs and
that's how we divide it but they do not
know that it is already
three parts and then there are 10 petals
which are working
down i'm sorry 12 30 saturn what moved
up so 3 divided into 12 is
4 each side but actually it is not true
it is uh
the ten petals are together in the
center
and the center one is known as the
sacred heart in the bible it is called
as sakura
and this the sacredness of that heart
in the abstract form is the
motherly love of god
that's why the the mother of the
universe decides
that and these those
12 petals act according to the mother of
the heart
and that's why we cannot allow them to
this side or that side
because it is he who actually makes them
pulsate
so here she becomes the dominant person
and not the heart they are the
spirituals so spirit has
rules by itself and it is ruled
with the help of the
reflection of god almighty himself
it is on its own it is arbit it sees
it watches it is the witness it watches
the play of these ten pet
twelve petals here but if it finds that
there's too much of stain on the
center one it just
switches off and when it's switched off
the whole thing
you see so you must understand the
difference between
the other other chakras and this one
is that there is a
pivot and the on the other side
third is a human
perfect personality
three things together now if you reduce
into our three powers
you'll understand on one side is
the instrument or you can say the
nucleus for the left hand side working
in the center it is or you can say left
hand side working you can say the
mahakali is working
in the center you can say it is for the
mahalakshmi working
and the nucleus for the working of the
right hand side is in the heart
on the right hand side where rama
recites because we can call it a
nucleophilicist he was active
he was active without feeling without
feeling
they witnessed it now they combine here
where krishna came and he felt the
witness state
and he called it as diya is the whole
prayer brahma never called it as plain
but he called it as play so that's why
krishna here
is completed and that's why we call him
he's a complete incarnation
but now this coming back to the heart
again on the right hand side we have got
rama's place now rama was known for
his obedience to his father if you know
his story
his father was in
ahirtha he was there and he had three
wives
the third wife had no
i mean he she had two sons but she could
not
see rama getting the throne
she was a very nice mother but somebody
you see some lady went and told
something to her and she listened to her
and she told
her husband that if you want
to give me my boon the promised boom you
have to
make rama go into the jungle for 14
years
and give the throne to my son birth
and when the heard this he
he fainted he fainted with this request
but rama was there
he heard it and he immediately told her
that i'm going to
the forest and i've accepted it and your
point your son
has the bharat for me it's all right and
that's how he went you see
just to obey the order of his father
because father had not even
ordered but because he was compelled he
had given his wife
two goons that once you see an award she
saved his life so she
he said that whenever you want you can
ask for these two goals
and they were she she never knew that
she would use them in such a funny way
later on she repented because bharata
came and he refused to accept the throne
and he put only rama's
slippers there and ruled there and
everything was different but
died in because when rama went away he
just died
so you see
rama's life shows how he was obedient
to his parents he suffered so much
anyone who has not been respectful to
his parents
you see if your parents have been
unkind
you have every right to tell them that
they should not be unkind to you
and that you feel hurt but
you have no business to answer them back
and you have to be respectful you have
to be respectful because they represent
your primordial parents you are not to
shout at them and misbehave
you have to be really respectful to them
they may be bad people
but you have to respect them because you
have chosen them
when you were born you chose them you
could not have been born to them
you have really chosen them and you said
these are going to be my parents
so if they are your parents they are
there because of certain reasons
because you have been seeking them in
their previous lives and that's how you
are there
you are not to boss over them it's real
i'm telling you the secret
it's not for anything for you see to
make you change your ways or anything
but i'm just telling you the secret
because you have lost the idea of the
secretive methods
of winning over people and understanding
them and managing them and
really you will have your way only thing
is