I would like to have some questions from you
about it.
And then we’ll see how it works out.
All right?
And not to be afraid, there’s nothing to
have any fear about kundalini.
Because you must have read such big, big books
saying that kundalini burns you, kundalini
does this.
No she is your own mother.
She doesn’t do anything of the kind.
These are the people who have never known
what kundalini is.
It’s like somebody putting the fingers into
the plug and saying electricity burns you.
They are unauthorized people who have done
all this, and that’s how they have suffered.
So any questions please?
Can’t think; if the kundalini rises above
this you become thoughtless just can’t think.
And when she gets out from here you start
feeling the cool breeze from your head.
Really a cool breeze you feel it and from
your fingers.
As simple as that
You are still doubting something.
Ask a question.
Can’t hear.
Loudly.
Come, come, come here.
Come
(Lady inaudible)
All right All right May God bless you sit.
She is saying that have you to pray to kundalini?
No nothing you don’t have to.
You see prayer before realization has no meaning
it’s like telephoning without connection.
There’s nothing to pray nothing to pray
nothing to pray.
(Lady inaudible) Can you come here?
(Man: I think everybody has got a question
to ask but they don’t know how to ask you)
They don’t want to?
What, What Questions?
Ask now What is there?
What is you don’t know?
I know English at least so ask me any question
in English.
Now what did you say?
(Lady)
Oh very good question.
That’s a good question.
That’s a good one.
Yes sit down sit down sit down.
She asked me a question if it is awakened
can it die out?
It doesn’t.
Once it is awakened it goes up it opens out.
But, but is there.
At the first shot you see it goes really in
a big way you get it in a really big way.
You remember.
But then it goes back and looks after other
parts where there’s a problem so the force
is reduced.
But then you have to learn how to keep the
force there and how to raise it and this is
called as vidya, called as the knowledge.
How to raise the kundalini….
Side B: ….What is all this about?
So that part you have to know.
I am here to decode it.
Somebody come and told me, Mother I feel here
tickling, all the time tickling, I said this
centre is not all right you have to open this
centre.
Now how to open this centre then I had to
tell that person you have to do this very
simple method.
You see certain movements, because it is flowing
from your hands, certain movements how to
do it, which are the deities on different
centers if you come to know about it.
For example this centre is the centre of Christ.
Between the optic chiasm is placed a very
subtle centre of Christ.
In the Indian scriptures He is called as Maha
Vishnu.
Now He was born on this earth to suck the
ego and superego.
His crucifixion was there to suck our sins
means the ego and the superego.
But He is to be awakened.
Unless and until He’s awakened it cannot
happen you go to church or you pray to Him
nothing will happen.
But if kundalini goes and stops there, and
if you say Lord’s Prayer, it will rise.
Is the proof that it is Christ’s centre.
Now this very important point that He should
be awakened that Christ was for this was never
known to Christians.
It’s a living process.
He said I’m a living God.
And when they went to India the way they talked
about Christianity was something absurd.
So Hindus still believe that this one who
has to redeem us has to come.
They don’t know that He’s already born
and crucified and He’s the one.
He is Maha Vishnu who is described in Devi
Mahatmyam very, very clearly.
He was specially made.
Who was His father; who was His mother all
described.
But the people who know English have no repor
with our ancient scriptures and those who
went from here have no repor with Christ.
That He’s to be awakened within us.
He said I am to be born.
And how to awaken it nobody knew only through
kundalini you can do it.
He said, it’s said in the bible I’ll appear
before you like tongues of flames.
Now what are these tongues of flames?
Go and ask these people.
These Jews do they know?
Mohammed has very clearly said that you are
to become a peer; you have to be born again.
I mean namas is one of the very good ways
of raising the kundalini, if you are using
the Sahaja Yoga method.
Means you get your realization and then you
do namas.
You’ll be amazed.
Everything has a meaning only when it is a
living thing.
Otherwise it’s dummy.
Everything is a dummy stuff you see like this
is a dummy thing.
I shout at it or do whatever you like its
not going to work.
That’s why everything is a dummy and that’s
why people say oh Christianity is wrong.
If you go to the Muslims they will say the
Jews are wrong.
The Jews will say the Muslims are wrong, the
Hindus are wrong.
I mean they are all blaming each other.
If you have to learn about yourself better
go to the other party.
But they are all dummies.
Once you get realized you will know they are
all connected with each other absolutely one
there’s complete harmony and concord.
Christ Himself has said those who are not
against Me are with Me.
Now go and ask these priests who are those
who are not against Him; who are with Him.
I mean, He was not even given sufficient time
only for four years He could talk and He was
killed.
Everywhere they have done a nice pickling
up of all these great people.
But Sahaja Yoga completely exposes their advents,
their purpose, their places within us and
also establishes all the fundamental things
that are described in all the scriptures and
their core relationships.
It’s such a fantastic thing.
How it establishes?
By proving it.
I’ll tell you one example, a simple example.
There was a gentleman from Iran he was a doctor
he came to see me.
I mean it is now we cannot contact him because
he’s in Iran.
But he came to see me he was a Muslim.
And I told him that Mohammed Sahib was born
as Nanak Sahib in India.
He could not believe it.
He said how can it be?
Though Nanak Sahib had said it in a way, because
Nanak Sahib was sleeping and somebody told
Him that you are placing your feet towards
Mecca he said all right I’ll turn my feet
to other side and the Mecca came that side.
He said I can’t believe it’ I can’t
believe it.
I said but Mohammed Sahib Has said that He
is the last.
I said I’m not sure of that but maybe He
must have decided to come back the way people
are.
He could not believe it.
And he had stomach cancer, which is caused
by one of the reasons is fanaticism.
I told him you have to believe in Him.
He was one of the incarnations of the Primordial
Master and He was the same Abraham was the
same Moses was the same Socrates was the same.
And you have to believe it.
He said I can’t believe it.
I said I can’t cure you.
Then he went back and he was very sick.
His wife said now what is there after all,
you see, we became Muslims because our parents
were Muslims and they told us Mohammed Sahib
was the last.
After all you are to be saved.
Then he came and said all right Mother whatever
you say I’m going to say.
I said now you pray to Nanak Sahib instead
of Mohammed Sahib because it is Mohammed Sahib
who’s angry with you.
He got cured; he’s still living.
He got cured.
It’s so simple.
We can’t believe it; it is so fantastic.
It is worth seeing yourself with your own
eyes.
The other day only, in Scotland, there was
a Gentleman was suffering from terrible, terrible
arthritis.
He got completely cured and he came to see
me in Edinburgh.
Arthritis absolutely curable; Diabetes is
absolutely curable; paralysis is absolutely
curable.
These all come out of your imbalances.
If you want to treat a tree and if you just
treat a flower or a leaf you cannot treat
the tree.
You have to go through the sap.
Sahaja Yoga is a system by which you go through
the sap of a personality and treat the whole
body as a whole.
Because the whole is the one, which is to
be looked after and not a part of it, because
you are a part of the whole.
And once you get connected with the whole
that whole that primordial being looks after
you.
And this is what has exactly happened to us
that we are all separated from the whole and
we have to become one with that with all our
awareness and understanding; so that that
whole looks after us.
So coming back to your question about kundalini
that it falls off is a true thing with some
people it does go down.
But all the forces that are divine are looking
after you.
You have to little bit cooperate with your
kundalini and she comes up she makes you beautiful,
absolutely beautiful.
Now any more questions?
Man: Could you explain what exactly you have
to do?
That’s the exact point.
You don’t have to do anything.
You see I have to do something about it not
you.
In the beginning then you can do it.
Like this light is here all right?
This is enlightened.
Now there’s another candle, which is not
enlightened that candle has to sit straight
just keep the wick out that’s all.
And this candle has to just go near that and
that gets enlightened.
I mean, I’m not doing anything about it
that also I must say because sometimes the
ego gets challenged; you know somebody says,
why Mother you?
I said you better do it.
I’ll be very happy to be replaced.
If you can come and do it, nothing like it.
You see it’ll be such a change.
But what can I do?
I have to do it.
Otherwise I’m a happily married woman; I
have my children, grandchildren, everyone
there, I have no problems.
But I see your problems, and I see that spirit
in you, and I just feel in all my love and
compassion that you must know it; that’s
all.
And once you know it you can do it yourself.
Like one light can enlighten many.
Isn’t it?
It’s as simple.
You become that.
You don’t have to do anything about it;
you have to just put your fingers like this
and the power flows into you.
It’s that simple.
You won’t believe but it is so because you
are ready.
You are just ready to be enlightened.
Now this instrument is made, if it is not
put to the mains what’s the use?
But how do you put to the mains?
Just put to the mains, that’s all.
The mains are there and this is ready you
just put to the mains.
You are just there.
Like a television set to a villager if you
tell, he won’t believe that it is so fantastic.
That there are all things around you; he will
say I can’t see anything.
How can he believe it?
When you put to the mains and you start seeing
the television manifesting, which is so fantastic.
In the same way, you are a special instrument
created by God.
You are just put to the mains.
You don’t have to do anything.
What did you do for your evolution?
When we became human beings from a monkey
what did we do?
Nothing, we did not cut our tail or anything
it just dropped off.
In the same way, we don’t do anything for
this also; it’s just there; you are just
ready; you just get it like that.
You don’t know how fantastic you are.
You don’t know that, na?
I know that.
But you will also know very soon.
When you know you will be amazed how fantastic
you are within.
It’s said all ways, all the scriptures,
all the great people have described you as
very great.
All of them have described.
But you must have faith in yourself that you
are great, no doubt.
And that instrument is ready, just ready.
It is to be applied to the mains and once
you start manifesting you can give it to others.
It’s that simple.
You can’t believe it I know, but it is so,
you will see that very soon.
Do not doubt it too much all right?
Otherwise this brain will be working khat
khat khat.
That’s why I’ve said for a while you should
stop thinking about it then it will work out.
Because I’ve seen people who go on doubting
very much they take time.
Just open, open out yourself, you must open
yourself fully and it will work out.
After all you want to have your realization
isn’t it?
What else you want?
You don’t want to doubt for doubting sake.
What’s the use of doubting also?
I mean if there is supposing I say there’s
a diamond here.
You will all run not only you but people from
Australia will come if I say it is free available.
Don’t you think so?
They will say worth going by plane, if there’s
such a big diamond available.
So no use doubting.
Just have it.
You have a diamond in your heart.
No doubt it will spark.
Do not doubt.
This mind has been doubting all the time,
what has it given you?
Nothing it will give you problems and headaches.
Don’t be doubting Thomas’s; be trusting.
Come here; come.
Lady: do you find people’s problems stop
them getting realization?
Problems it stops a little sometimes little
bit.
But I know all the permutations, combinations
now.
So I can get over all the problems; I think
so.
All right?
I know many permutations and combinations
now of problems.
In the beginning you’ll be amazed in this
England I came here when my husband got elected
to this job.
For four years I worked on six people, for
four years, can you imagine?
And now they just get it like that.
Now I know all the permutations, combinations
of English people and England and western
people.
Now I’m going to America and I’ve been
there before also; so keep your fingers crossed;
I’m sure I’ll work it out there also.
Everybody’s an interesting sample of some
combination.
But I know all the keys somehow; I’ve studied
it and I’ve put all attention to it.
It has worked out and all these problems I
know what you all have.
Somehow it works out so don’t you worry
about that.
If there were no problems, there was no need
to do this.
I mean you would be just there.
There has to be problems.
Any other problem?
Man: We’ve got seven chakras over there;
can you please tell us what part each one
plays?
That’s good.
Now all that is so elaborate I may not be
able to tell you today; but can you come and
show?
But I will be able to say in short, all right?
Now he is coming; he will show you.
Now the first chakra which is below the kundalini
the first one is the very important centre,
which is bestowed by a deity, which is the
embodiment of innocence.
Is the centre of innocence, the first chakra.
To explain it more we can say when we were
at the carbon stage, carbon stage.
Now Carbon is a very important element, you
know that.
In the periodical laws it is placed in the
centre; it is tetravalent means it has four
hands either it can give four hands or take
four hands.
And at that stage only the nature started
producing life.
So that is the stage where we were at carbon
level.
And nature is innocent a chair doesn’t get
angry with you.
Its only we can get angry.
So the nature that we are, is innocent our
basis is innocence.
We are surrounded first by innocence.
We are basically innocent people.
So this is the first centre, is of innocence.
Then the second centre that you see.
Actually the Nabhi we can take it.
Is the second centre and the third centre
are connected.
From the second centre arises the third centre.
The second centre is the centre of our seeking.
This one manifests our solar plexus.
And this caters to our seeking.
As amoeba we were seeking our food through
our stomach; it is in the stomach we can say.
Actually they are all placed in the medulla
oblongata; they are placed in the spinal chord.
But they manifest outside the plexuses.
For example, the first one manifests the plexus
called as pelvic plexus, which is responsible
for our excretory functions.
All right?
Now the second one, which is the one I told
you just now, manifests the solar plexus,
is for our seeking.
And now you are at a stage where you are seeking
the ultimate the beyond.
But there are people who are still seeking
money, there are people who are still seeking
other things.
But I take if for granted that you are seeking
divine.
So the seeking reaches that state at that
centre.
The other centre that comes out of it is the
centre of action.
The seeking has to put into action.
Otherwise supposing you are hungry you have
to go into action to get it.
So this is the centre of action within us,
which works within us all the activities for
the future.
It thinks and all the activities that we require
for our mental or our physical needs.
So this is a center of the creator.
The above centre to that is the centre which
is the centre of Heart as we call it.
Is the centre which represents your sense
of security.
When the child is about twelve years of age
this centre creates anti bodies in your sternum
bone and these antibodies by the time the
child is about twelve years of age go into
the whole body and they are the ones who react
to any invasion on the body.
And these antibodies react; say for example,
all our injection system works on that.
We put a little virus, which is an outsider
invader inside the body and when you put that
they get energetic to fight.
And because of their energies they fight the
disease and we get cured.
This is the principle of that is.
This is the center of our sense of security.
When we are insecure then this centre starts
pulsating and emitting more antibodies and
looking after us.
And this is a very important centre within
us.
But there are other two other centers on sides
of it; one is of the mother, one of the father;
on both sides.
I mean they have sub centers also.
Now this one can be called as the one which
manifests cardiac plexus.
Then above that is the centre which is behind
here, is the centre of our collectivity.
Is the centre where we become one with the
whole.
Is the centre which gives us the idea that
we are one.
By this centre we become also the witness
of the play of the divine later on when it
is enlightened.
It is a very important centre by which we
talk to others, we communicate to others on
the right hand side.
On the left hand side emotionally we become
attached to people.
Then above that is the centre as I told you
of Christ or we can say the centre of ascent.
There is the door, which goes into this area
of limbic area, which is grossly known as
limbic area, which is the kingdom of God.
And above is the last one here where this
point.
The whole thing is one centre the limbic area
and this point.
When the ego and superego are sucked in, the
kundalini rushes through, and this fontanel
bone area becomes very soft and you start
getting the cool breeze from that part.
Now in short I’ve told you but in details
you can go through the book it’s all written
down about these centers.
Which are the basic seven centers but there
are many other centers, which are sub plexuses
of this.
Amazingly there’s one thing that all these
centers are manifesting the plexuses outside
and all these plexuses.
For example here, the plexus is the one that
looks after the pituitary and the pineal,
these two things.
So it is related absolutely with the gross
as well but we go from inside outward while
the doctors go from outward inside.
Which you cannot go you cannot enter into
a tree through a leaf you can enter only through
the sap into it.
These are in short I have told you.
But there are all these things are clearly
written down in a book that they will give
you.
They have got it.
Have you got that book?
You can get.
It’s a very small booklet.
Do you charge any money for that?
No?
It’s free?
You charge a little.
How much?
Man: Ten pie or something.
Ten pie or something they charge.
You see because maybe, so far all these boys
have been printing it and paying for it for
the whole also.
I mean this thing requires money no doubt,
but these boys have been doing it.
And it’s all right not much you see.
Birmingham is a cheep place that way I must
say compared to some places I went to.
Also everybody is trying to fund it so that,
I mean there is no sort of any profit basis
or anything.
But like ashram we have got we have got say
ten people they take a house they live there,
look after it and that’s an ashram.
There’s no sort of a profit making or any
fees or anything.
Because they live there, they have a house,
they live there that’s all.
It’s as simple as that.
We do not have any such organization; there
is nobody who is organized in it.
You cannot organize God.
So there’s no organization they are there
because of their free will, because of their
freedom and because of their love and because
they feel responsible that they should do
it.
There’s no force on you; there’s no compulsion;
there’s no money taking; there’s no membership.
Man: Is it also possible please for any of
those centers to awaken without the knowledge
of the individual?
You see, sometimes it happens, that a person
can be attacked from the sides and then that
centre can go on emitting too much.
Like in cancer it happens.
That one of the centers you see, say for instance
the stomach.
If you are eating say something which is irritating
the stomach centre, then what happens that
this centre receives all the energies from
everywhere, all the stored up energy and starts
working very hard.
When it starts working very hard, it gets
dislocated.
When it gets dislocated, what happens that
there is no relationship left with the whole
and the cells starts growing more than in
relation to the whole.
And we say malignancy has been set in.
And like that can happen they can get over
excited.
But the energy from other centers is brought
in one and they get over excited with out
any relationship to the whole.
And that’s a very dangerous situation.
Such a thing can happen and sometimes it can
happen on certain centers where people just
get possessed.
And they think they have got some sort of
a great experience.
Is not so.
Like there was a lady who always felt she’s
getting out of her body.
Ultimately she got her cancer.
Now, of course, she is cured; she’s all
right.
But these all such experiences come from the
left and the right side.
Not from the superior.
The one experience on the left hand side is
of the collective subconscious because on
the left hand side of this channel that you
see is the collective subconscious.
Now we do not know because these are unknown
areas for us; the collective subconscious
on this area and the collective supraconscious
on this area.
Now, for example, spiritualists they work
from the collective subconscious; very dangerous
thing to do.
We have nothing to do with spirits, nothing
to do with them.
We are in the centre and the present.
If you indulge into spiritualism, you’ll
find you develop a very funny situation and
I don’t know how they end it up.
Apart from mental trouble, you’ll be amazed,
I’m amazed at it myself, that all the cancer
patients I’ve seen so far are all attacked
from the left side not from the right side.
Those who are attacked from the right side
is the supraconscious the collective supraconscious
are the people like Hitler.
Who get possessed by very, you can say very,
very dominating personalities who are dead
or those who lived in the future great planners
this that they get attacked.
And once they get attacked there’s an outlet.
For example you can say Hitler was like a
medium and he transformed other people into
that kind of a frantic temperament.
I mean it took him eleven years to build up
that kind of a domain of Satans you see but
it took eleven years.
And I would blame then the people who allowed
this to grow and once this grew up and suddenly
it blew up them then they realized; oh God
where are we?
So these attacks can come from these two areas
they are called as Adiboutic and Adidevic
in Sanskrit language.
But this is, is the spirit; is the Atma; is
the superior; is the super most experience
where you become the spirit itself, your spirit
not somebody else’s.
So all these experiences are not healthy;
they should be avoided for all those who are
seeking reality.
I mean if you want to have some jugglery,
then it’s a different thing but it is a
very dangerous thing to play with it.
All these gurus are using only this either
left or the right side.
They use the spirits and that’s how they
mesmerize.
That’s a very dangerous state.
The other day Sahaja Yoga has become so powerful
now that they these people gave realization
to an archbishop of black magic.
Can you imagine?
I was amazed.
And this fellow was quite all right then he
went home and he found everything was moving
around.
This all the things that were there were moving
Now the spirits were tempting him back they
thought if we show some sort of this jugglery
he will be back again.
And they telephoned to me Mother now what
to do.
I said why did you give him realization?
There was no need to give him realization.
He said just he came and he got it.
I said leave him alone I’ll look after him
you don’t worry.
It happens now.
This Sahaja yoga is so great imagine giving
realization to the archbishop of black magic.
I mean this is too much.
It’s doing.
It’s happening.
Man: May I say by the way that um I can see
a white aura around your head for the last
hour.
Yes it’s true, but I would say don’t see
that.
You’ll see many things because I’m something
more; there’s no doubt.
Quite a lot I am.
That you have to discover later.
You can see many things.
But I would say don’t say anything because
this also seeing is not the thing experiencing
is the thing and that’s why you must experience
your being.
And People have seen me in many forms many
things.
That’s not important.
Important is that you must get your realization.
I must be something isn’t it to do it?
No doubt there must be something about me.
But I don’t want to talk about it just now.
I’m very tactful; you better find out.
Lady: Why is peace and tranquility adjusted
on your face?
On my face?
You are also going to get it.
That’s all I can say.
It is there inside.
It is all whatever is inside comes out isn’t
it?
You are all peace, tranquility everything
inside you are also the same not only me.
You have to just feel it.
You will, you will no doubt, you will no doubt.
I assure you.
That’s why I’m here; I want you to enjoy
that what I am enjoying.
That’s all.
You see it’s like a drunkard who cannot
enjoy his drink.
That’s why I say that I am a capitalist
because I have all these powers and I am the
greatest communist because I must share.
I can’t help it without sharing.
So this such a combination, all right?