…that has to be first realised – what
is your category.
And if you are that category, of the category
which is seeking beyond what you have and
that you are not satisfied with what you have
already, then you are the category of seekers
who have been seeking something that is very
subtle, that is not gross, not intelligible
through your sensory organs.
How it happens within us – it is very interesting
to see.
Within us, as I have told you, there are these
subtle centres which have developed through
the process of our evolution.
Through the process of our evolution we have
become human beings.
While we were becoming human beings, all these
centres have been also evolving within us.
These centres are placed in the spinal cord,
in the centre of the spinal cord, and they
manifest outside grossly on [the] physical
level, as plexuses.
As they are evolving inside, also the outside,
the gross plexuses are also evolving.
For example, animals do not insure their lives,
do they?
They have fear.
They know how to react to a fear but they
do not know how to insure.
After some time the animals forget their children.
Animals can pass through any filth, any dirt,
any untidiness.
They don’t understand tidiness, neatness.
Animals do not organise.
Animals don’t plan.
They do sometimes when they have to catch
hold of a prey, but that too, not too far.
Like we have five-year plans, ten-year plans,
twenty-year plans as the human being have.
They do not put any energy into that.
The reason for all this is that man has evolved
much more than all the animals put together.
He is an evolved soul.
Now these evolved souls have also got a category
of greater evolved people who are not satisfied
with the general norms of life.
For example, there are people who are interested
say, in having power.
And they want to have power.
Till they die they want to have power.
Till they die they won’t give a resignation.
I mean, sometimes they put one foot in the
grave and still the resignation in the another
hand, in case they do not die and they have
to pull out the leg, so it’s better to keep
it handy!
There are people who stick on to other games
of life, like money.
They are money-oriented people.
They find their securities in money.
They run after money.
They plan out everything according to money.
All their lives they are doing that.
There are [a] third type of people who indulge
into so-called love affairs and things like
that; into emotional movements of their mind.
But there are some others who think that these
things are not so interesting for them.
So the fourth category takes to religion – to
know about beyond.
They read about the prophets, the great scriptures,
all the great religions of the world.
But as the pioneer of the religion dies, the
followers, somehow or other, built in fanaticism
around them and fanaticism is the death of
religion, is absolutely the death of religion.
I have seen people who get cancer are sometimes
fanatics.
If you could cure their fanaticism, you can
cure their cancer because all such false identification
requires extra energy in a man.
He has to stick on to some sort of obstinacy!
Now supposing I am holding on to it (the microphone)
and I do not want to leave my hand from here
– for nothing at all!
I say, “No, I am not going to leave."
“No!
This is the thing I believe into.
I am going to stick on to it!”
Then I require a lot of energy to hold on
to it.
But if I could be free and see, it is better.
Like I remember a gentleman fell down from
the sixteenth story and he was asking for
help and help.
And he saw people passing from the back.
He was holding onto one of the rails, and
he could not understand how the people are
passing around.
He said, “Help for what?”
He said, “I’m falling."
They said, “Where?
Here is the road!”
He had, just near the road, had caught hold
of the rod!
And he was asking for help, and he was just
shouting.
When they said, “This is the road.
You better put your foot down."
he fainted!
Because he had put all his energy into a nonsensical
thing, believing into a myth.
And myth always takes away your energy, while
the Truth enriches your energy.
Because you don’t have to hold on to the
Truth, the Truth carries you along.
Any kind of fanaticism is not your way, as
I told you yesterday.
And if anybody is a fanatic, then he is not
seeker.
Because he’s found whatever it is.
He has to deal with his fanaticism and his
faiths.
So the another category of people are there
which are anti everything: everything that
is established.
Anything.
Christ – they are against Christ.
They are reactionaries.
They are against Nanak Saheb, they are against
Mohammed Saheb.
They are against everything that has been
established because whatever is established
is not true.
Those who have established have taken a mythical
attitude.
When they take up a mythical attitude and
they try to stick onto it, those who think
about it are shocked and they think, “These
are drunk people.
These are possessed people!”
So they say, “Alright, that we are not!”
So we become atheist.
We don’t believe in God.
We don’t believe in any spiritual power.
We do not believe in any divine power.
We do not believe in anything that is said
before.
According to them, all prophets were wrong.
All religions are wrong.
There is no God – [they think they are]
the wisest people every born!
So there is another category of extra-wise.
You can call them intellectuals.
These days I don’t know what you call them.
This is another category.
Now there is another very subtle category,
which tries to exploit all these things that
are existing.
Some of them do it because they do believe
that they have found out something new, like
psychologist, like Freud.
They are ignorant, absolutely half-baked people.
They do not know the whole thing.
They just know a part of it and to them that’s
the truth.
Like you find a needle somewhere and say the
needle is the whole world.
They know very little and they don’t know
what to do with the needle, and so they come
out with the needle, saying, “Needle is
the world!”
And such people are very anxious to write
books and convey their messages to the world
and communicate to the whole world what they
have found out, while whatever they have found
out is nothing but just a few drops of truth.
And they are trying their level best to spoil
[it].
Now there is a category of another people
which are sinister.
In that you know so many types which I do
not want to discuss here.
From Hitler you can start, all kinds of brutal
people and all that.
They go parallel with all these categories.
But I would say the worst of all are those
who try to make money in the name of God,
and worse than that, the worst of all, are
the people who try to play games with God.
Those who take money are openly bad but those
who try to play with your Kundalini, with
your Realisation, are really to be called
as demonic categories.
And all such people should know, as Blake
has said, that they will go to the hell from
where they can never rise.
Now whether you believe it or not, there is
God.
Sahaja Yoga is a thing today which has reached
that stage where the category of people who
are men of God, they do not proclaim on the
streets that, “I am a man of God."
No.
They do not stand up with banners in their
hands that, “I am the man of God."
They are very normal people.
They are householders.
They have children.
They have grandchildren.
They are very simple people.
They lead a very ordinary life.
They are not very successful people.
But they are people, men of God.
And these human beings of God are the ones
I am talking about, is the category you people
are.
If you are not that category, Sahaja Yoga
is not going to work on you to begin with.
Later on, when we have a particular number
of people, the evolution will take such a
dynamic form, that thousands of people will
receive their Self-realisation.
Now the Self-realisation is the thing in which
an ordinary man who looks an ordinary common
person but who is actually a seeker, a true
seeker, not a false seeker but a true seeker,
receives the grace of the Divine and becomes
a prophet.
He becomes a prophet.
This is what Sahaja Yoga is, that it makes
you a prophet and a prophet of a very unique
style, because the job of today’s modern
prophets is very different from the prophets
which came before, as I told you yesterday.
The prophets who came before, as we celebrated
yesterday, Guru Nanaka’s birthday and Mohammed
Saheb and all others, like Moses, Abraham
and all these, was to maintain your sustenance
through giving you Ten Commandments.
And these Ten Commandments exist in that centre
there, where you see the green centre.
You can see it very clearly in your stomach.
The religion is in your stomach.
It’s a thing built within you.
It is not that I can give you a lecture about
religion.
But it is built within you.
It is inside you.
And this religion is to be maintained, was
to be maintained that time; very important
was that people should know what helps them
to be a human being.
And that was the job of all these prophets
and they did it very well.
But their disciples and maybe their followers
made them into fanatic religions.
You can’t help it.
I mean, I have always said that they were
like living flowers on this Earth, who came
one after another on the Tree of Life.
And people just plucked those flowers and
said, “This is mine.
This is mine."
The flowers became dead, ugly and useless.
That is how fanaticism has prospered.
And all the fanaticism in these modern times
is [now] challenged.
Everywhere people can see it that it is not
logical to be fanatic.
But as a result of ego activity in thinking
they go to another extreme by which they condemn
even the real flowers, even the originators,
the ones who came on this Earth.
This is going too far from the right point.
From one extreme to another extreme they are
moving.
Now the specialty of the modern prophets is
that you can make other people prophets.
That means you can give them Realisation yourself.
This is the difference between the Sahaja
Yoga that worked out at the time of other
people.
That’s why there was hardly one or two Realised-souls.
At the time of Janaka – say about eight
thousand years back when Shri Rama was ruling,
his father-in-law, who was a great prophet
– he had one disciple whom he gave Realisation.
And with very great tests and all that he
took under his own guidance.
He gave him Realisation.
But today the time has changed because the
Life’s Tree has increased, has reach to
that state of maturity, where thousands of
you have to be transformed.
It has to be done.
It’s the God’s plan.
And those who fit into it are the people who
are of the category who are seeking.
Now, such category can be understood by many
ways and there are some tests to understand
what these people are.
It may be that such people could be extremely
nervous people, could be, because they cannot
bear the unrighteous, sinful, deceitful world.
The whole atmosphere may be jarring them.
That’s why they are very shaky.
Could be they might be very nervous because
of that.
They could be a people who might be a recluses.
They might be people who might be hot-tempered.
They might be people who are escapists.
They could be the people who could be druggist.
Could be alcoholic.
They could be anything, because they are running
away from the so-called horrible ‘reality’.
Sahaja Yoga is a thing which establishes your
reality within yourself, by which you feel
secure, because your reality is beauty, it
is joy.
And then you don’t want to run away from
that.
This is what we have to understand, that we
are here to receive our reality, to know ourselves.
By knowing ourselves, how many things can
happen to us, you have no idea.
The whole property that you are, the whole
wealth that you are, the whole beauty that
you are, becomes your own.
You become the master of your own being.
This is the first thing that should happen:
means your ill health must get alright.
You know that there are people here who had
very serious diseases, who got completely
cured.
You know there are people who have mental
problems, who had epilepsies and things – they
are cured.
And how it happens?
Just by knowing yourself, how powerful you
are.
Just think of that!
Think of your own powers that, just by knowing
yourself, how you have become so powerful.
But this knowledge is not through your rationality,
that, “I am such.
I am Napoleon.
I am this."
This kind of a knowledge is really stupid,
it’s egoistical.
But this knowledge is a dynamism in your own
awareness.
It’s a new perception within you by which
you become something.
You become a different person.
You become a higher, evolved soul.
And then you realise that you have suddenly
become a being who is collectively conscious.
Some progress very fast but some do not.
Some progress tremendously fast.
I know of a gentlemen who was supposed to
be a drunkard and used to waste all his money
in races and he did all kinds of things.
He used to smoke like a chimney.
And when he got his Realisation, the whole
room was filled with fragrance.
And everybody said, “This man?
How can we believe, Mother?
He is this and this and this."
I said, “But this is what it is!
This was all the clouds upon him.
And all the clouds have gone away and you
see the sun coming in him.
He’s a different man."
I don’t believe in the clouds, I believe
in the sun.
If I see the sun, the sun is there.
I don’t see the clouds at all.
I see the sun.
Perhaps I have more penetrating eyes than
you have.
And I see the sun in the man.
He has risen out of that.
And now he is shining like a sun.
So accept him and bow to him.
He’s the one who was seeking, really, within.
He thought that by playing races he’ll find
joy.
He thought by eating food like that he will
have joy, or by smoking like that he will
have joy.
But he never was satisfied within himself.
He never got involved into it to that extent
that he lost his own being and his seeking
and that’s how he is the one who is a true
seeker.
Sometimes it is some shocking to see in Sahaja
Yoga how people get transformed just like
that.
Just the change starts coming, as if some
magic has happened in the person’s life
and he changes.
But actually it is very simple to understand.
When it rains and the whole place is so foggy,
you don’t feel like going out anywhere:
it’s so grey, you feel so horrible.
But when the sun comes out, everyone, children,
old people, young people, the housewives,
all of them come out to greet the sun.
When your sun comes out and you see your brilliance
yourself and then, “Oh, it’s me!
Is it me?
Oh, God!”
And that starts transforming.
And you are amazed to see yourself the way
you are transformed.
That has to happen for you.
But for this, already God has planned within
you all these things very beautifully.
As beautifully as He has made your exterior,
He has made your interior equally beautifully,
very delicately and with very great, very
great care.
Within you lies the Kundalini, in the triangular
bone, the sacred bone called as sacrum, which
gives you Realisation.
This is one about which Christ has said, “I
will appear before you like tongues of flames."
What is that?
Every person has talked about him, but the
trouble is, how will you explain tongues of
flames?
Kabira has talked so clearly.
He has said, “Ida, Pingala, Sushumna."
Everything he has talked about, he talked
about Kundalini!
Shankaracharya has talked about.
I would say Blake, William Blake.
You read him.
You will be amazed!
He’s talking of today in his book, “Milton”.
He is talking of Jerusalem of today.
This place, this England, is going to be the
Jerusalem, is the pilgrimage, where the people
of God are going to be the prophets.
He has talked of today!
Can you imagine?
He was not very old; he was not very ancient,
very modern.
He has prophesised about these days and it
is happening.
You don’t have to worry about these things.
It is God’s plan that He has done it so
well, and individually all of you have got
this Kundalini in your triangular bone, called
‘sacrum’.
See, the word ‘sacrum’ means ‘sacred’.
How did they know, the word ‘sacrum’ to
be put for this, is a sacred bone?
This was discovered in ancient times, long,
long time back.
Even they say that Indra was given Realisation
by Dattatreya.
To that extent!
I mean, how many years back it was done!
But it was a guarded secret.
It was done for very few people.
Only it was Shankaracharya who started first.
Adi Shankaracharya I would say, not these
[modern ones].
But the Adi Shankaracharya started talking
about it so clearly.
Everywhere you find, even in Koran or in the
Bible, everywhere it is said, any scripture
which has lasted the time, it’s said that,
“You are to be born again."
Now people have taken a note from that and
they certify, “I am a twice-born."
Now what is the proof that you are twice-born?
Everybody says, “I am a twice-born."
It is absurd.
What do you mean by twice-born?
As I have told you before that a bird is called
as twice-born in Sanskrit language, and a
Realised-soul is also called a twice-born.
As the bird is an egg and, when the egg breaks,
we do not see the egg but we see the chick
coming out of it.
In the same way it has to happen to you that,
when your egg, which is made by the formation
of ego and superego, the yellow and the blue
on your head, has to break and then you become
a new personality, a personality which is
very different from what it was before.
Egg doesn’t grow, does it?
But the chick grows.
Now the growth starts in the spiritual arena,
in the spiritual understanding, into spiritual
education.
Now it starts!
Not before that.
You start feeling the Divine Power around
and you understand that you are a universal
being.
All these nonsensical ideas, of race, of different
religions, of different communities, are products
of human endeavour, or we should say the human
thinking; which is so stupid sometimes that
it is impossible for a person like me to understand
why we have to carry a passport from places
to places.
The God Almighty also must be failing to understand
how this has been worked out by the great
wise human beings.
That He made only one world.
He didn’t make many worlds.
He just put some rivers and some nice mountains
and some hills and dales, to make it a beautiful,
interesting place for you.
And you have divided into nations and into
cities and villages and then into smaller
places and then into a road and then into
your houses and then into your kitchen.
That’s what we have become!
But the category of the people about whom
I am saying, they can’t remain in their
kitchens, they can’t remain in their houses,
they cannot remain in their nations.
They transcend the whole Universe.
They cover the whole Universe.
Because they become universal beings.
They cannot think in this terminology.
It hurts them.
You see, it would be like a great person being
put in a sack.
You just force him to get into a sack or into
a cup – how he’ll be hurt?
Either the cup will break or the fellow will
throw it away.
It’s the ocean you are trying to put it
into a cup, which you cannot do it.
And such a stupidity has been done so far.
But the time has come for all the oceans to
be awakened to their greatness.
And once they are awakened they will throw
away all these minor boundaries and all these
nonsensical barriers that has created such
a mountain from one seed to another seed where
two beautiful human beings are sitting and
are fragrant with the fragrance of universal
joy.
After Realisation only you can also enjoy
another personality.
Normally you cannot.
What you enjoy is his car, or his house or
his dress or his looks or his behaviour towards
you.
At the most his intellect, his success, his
horses.
I don’t know what else.
But after Realisation you just enjoy his vibrations!
You just enjoy him in his innate thing.
You do not see his age, you do not see his
caste, you do not see his race but you see
all this chaitanya, these vibrations, coming
from the person and you just enjoy for hours
together just feeling that.
It’s so enjoyable.
One person like that walks in, and all of
you, “Ah!”
This should happen to everyone.
It has to happen.
The time has come for this happening.
That’s why we have so many seekers.
They have been ill-treated, they have been
deceived, they have been used, people have
made money out of them.
I accept [that].
But then I have to accept also that in seeking
you had to be tested also, to see where do
you stick on.
If you want to go to the Truth, you will discard
everything [else].
And once you come before the Truth you will
have it.
And that’s why this testing has to be done,
because there is ego, human beings have their
egos; they think, “Oh I will do this.
I can do it.
I can sort it out."
Alright.
God says, “Alright, have it.
Have it your way."
Then they will go and break their heads, break
their legs, break their hands and then come
saying that, “Mother, see, I have broken
everything.
Now what will you do?”
So alright!
The Sahaja Yoga has to work it out.
But why do all that?
Come straight to the Truth.
Now, one has to understand that before Realisation
you don’t have to do anything, but after
Realisation those who do not understand their
own esteem, they do not value their potentialities
or their powers, can lose their vibrations
in the early months.
It has happened with many people: they have
lost their vibrations completely because they
have not paid any attention to themselves.
They have not tried to improve themselves.
They have not tried to keep up the vibrations.
It’s like enlightening any light.
We have to look after it for a while till
it takes its own form.
And that is how in Sahaja Yoga so many come
and get Realisation, but those who grow are
the real Sahaja yogis.
The rest of them are wasted, are just wasted.
They’ll come back again but they take too
much time and the Divine does not have interest
in such people, it does not help such people.
So I have to request to you, request you that
if you are seekers, you have to have your
Realisation.
Without that you will not be happy.
But you must have full idea and responsibility
about yourself that you are now an enlightened
light.
You are a beacon and you cannot afford to
hide yourself.
You have to give light to others.
You have to work it out that way.
It’s not now a question of only one Christ
bearing the cross or one Mohammed talking
about the message or one Nanaka fighting the
whole world.
It’s all of you put together have to fight
it out and work it out.
That’s what it is today.
That’s why Sahaja Yoga, one can say, has
reached the state of Mahayoga.
“Sahaja”, Sahaja means born with you.
It’s spontaneous.
It is within you.
The whole thing is within you.
Just like a seed sprouts, the Kundalini sprouts
spontaneously.
You do not have to do anything about it.
But when it becomes Mahayoga, means it becomes
en masse, thousands of people can be given
Realisation.
In India we have someone who has given Realisation
to ten thousand people in a village!
He is just a farmer and he has done it.
So you can imagine how much you can do.
But in the West, as I have always warned you,
it’s a very ego-oriented society, and people
are very exclusive.
Everybody wants to sort out.
Immediately after Realisation everybody becomes
an Archbishop of Canterbury!
And they think no end of themselves.
You have to have spiritual knowledge after
this.
You have to know everything about it.
You have to master it.
You have to master your body, you have to
master your mind and you have to master the
whole art of Kundalini.
Then only you can say that it works.
Otherwise, it’s just a waste.
You are the people who are in the foundation,
and you have to be the strongest people.
You have to be the masters of Kundalini, absolutely
the masters of Kundalini.
It’s not individual.
This is Mahayoga.
Anybody who tries to be individualistic will
be lost, will be no more in the circulation.
This I have told you hundred, and hundred
and one times.
And the Spirit can only grow in collectivity
because the nature of Spirit is universal.
You cannot achieve anything exclusively.
Those who try it will fail.
You all have to join together and should know
that you all awakened people.
In the Primordial Being you are like the awakened
cells who know the Primordial Being and who
have the powers by which they can communicate
the powers of God to other people.
You all have to be absolutely one with each
other, not to find faults but to love and
enjoy each other.
That’s the best way you can move.
As you know that this subject is so varied,
and it requires so much of explanation, for
which now we have lots of tapes, and if you
people want you can get tapes from Douglas
(Fry), who has really put in lot of effort
for it.
You can play them and can understand and can
improve all your knowledge about Sahaja Yoga.
And now I’ll be going to India and perhaps
there may be only one lecture more where it
will be just a farewell function we’ll have.
I would like some of the Sahaja Yogis to ask
some questions today, because it’s a nice
opportunity for you to ask some questions.
But not the people who haven’t got Realisation,
because those who haven’t got Realisation
are not entitled because they do not know.
They have no news about it.
They don’t understand.
They should not ask any questions.
Those who are Sahaja Yogis should ask.
I mean, it would be something like those who
have never visited India, are asking questions
about India.
Better go to India, find out about [it] yourself,
see it in deeply, how it is, what it is, and
then you can ask questions.
Not just visit Delhi talk to some Westernised
Indians and come back and tell me stories
about them!
In the same way, those who have not been to
England, meet some of the politicians or something
like that, go back and tell something about
England which I will not believe and you should
not believe.
You have to understand the country on a philosophical
level, on philosophy – where are they.
And unless and until you understand that subtle
thing, you cannot say anything about it.
For example, for England, I have always said
that the young generation of England are the
best in the whole world.
Take it from me, whether they are English,
or whatever it is, whatever nationality, but
the young generation that are English are
the best.
No doubt about it.
Because they have developed, no doubt, but
they have kept their wisdom intact.
India, the young people are developing and
they have to go through all your discotheques
and all those rumble-tumbles, till they come
to the stage where they’ll take alcohols
and then they will take to your drugs and
then they might take to [seeking].
Americans are too shifty.
They have not kept their wisdom intact.
(laughter) But thanks to the tradition of
British, that you have kept your traditions
still intact and you know about your country
because it’s a small country.
So I depend very much on the English youth.
But if you ask anyone else, they will say,
“Oh, these English youth [are] extremely
rude, arrogant.
Good for nothing!
Drugged, lethargic.
Useless!”
But I have seen now young people and young
people all over the world and this is what
I have to say about them.
Now I would like you to ask me questions.
First the Sahaja yogis, then we can ask the
non-Sahaja yogis.
Difficult.
You have become thoughtless, actually, you
cannot ask!
This is the trick of Sahaja Yoga!
When it crosses this point, you cannot think.
Even if you want to think, you cannot.
No questions?
Now non-sahaja yogis, please.
Seeker: How about times when you should do
the meditation?
What sort of times?
Shri Mataji: Oh, there’s nothing.
No rules.
You go beyond time.
Every time you are in meditation only.
You see, what is meditation?
You cannot do meditation, you have to be in
meditation.
You become meditative.
You are all the time in meditation.
I mean, there is no time when you are not,
because you become a different person.
Those people who do meditation, I don’t
know how they do it.
Really, I can’t understand.
Because which is the way you enter into the
realm of meditation?
Unless and until the Kundalini takes your
attention to that state,you cannot meditate.
So how can you do?
You cannot lift the Kundalini with your hand
and put Her there.
No lift can work it out.
It’s only through spontaneous awakening
that the Kundalini rises.
So you cannot do meditation.
And once you are there, you are there.
So there is no timing.
Nothing fixed.
But it depends on the kind of a person they
are.
For example, say somebody who gets up [at]
eleven o’clock in the morning, doesn’t
brush his teeth, rushes to the office, comes
back home, sleeps at two o’clock in the
night, can’t sleep before two o’clock,
then such a person has to develop certain
habits.
Because we have to neutralise the habits that
we have had.
So maybe that time we will have to just turn
the tables, and we can manage.
We can change all our habits.
And we can have such habits by which we neutralise
our old habits.
It depends on what sort of a person it is.
For example, we Indians have a bad habit of
getting up very early in the morning and having
a bath in the morning.
Whether it is England, America or even if
we are with Eskimos, we’ll do that!
That’s typical.
Otherwise, we don’t feel happy.
Just before going to the office, we’ll take
our baths and walk out in the cold.
I mean, it is the greatest punishment for
an Indian to say, “You don’t take your
bath."
I mean, after coming to England some of them
have reconciled.
And to take bath in the night and sleep, they
can’t believe it, they just don’t know
what it is.
So they get lung troubles.
Some of them have got lung cancer.
One of the common diseases I’ve seen amongst
Indians is what you call the, we call it the
heart chakras, the, the cardiac plexus catching;
common.
The reason is this, that, they have no consideration
about the temperature outside.
Now if you tell them, they can’t believe
me.
They think a religious person must take his
bath every day.
That’s the idea they have.
Not in England.
I mean, you can take your bath every day,
but not the bath and just walk out [of the
house].
Then I have to tell, “Can you have you bath,
say, thrice a week or four times a week, if
possible?”
But to an Englishmen, you better get up at
four o’clock and have your bath!
It depends on who you are.
So there is nothing like having a fixed thing
in Sahaja Yoga.
It depends on what sort of a person you have,
what habits are there, what are your loopholes,
what are your weaknesses.
So we have to look after that.
Like, it’s very common practice, you know.
Supposing we have to go to my house from here.
Now you don’t know how to go, so you see
the map and whichever way you have to go,
you just go.
It’s a new life.
It’s a new map.
So you have to see which way you have to go.
You change accordingly and you go accordingly.
You cannot have fixed idea now, anymore.
You have to see.
If your car has got a trouble with its brake,
better is to repair the brake, isn’t it?
Or will you say that, “Doesn’t matter.
Even [if] my brake is bad, I’ll go ahead.
As long as my tyres are alright, I don’t
care for the brake."
Sahaja Yoga is just opposite.
If the brake is not alright, don’t worry
about the tyres, but think about the brake.
It’s very discretionary.
You become very discrete about yourself and
you start repairing your car; that’s yourself.
Because you get out of your car and you see
the problems.
You are not identified anymore with you.
For example, Don would come and tell Me, “Mother,
I am catching on my Agnya here."
Now what does that mean?
It means actually Ego.
But he will have no objection in telling me
or he will in no way feel ashamed to tell
me that, “My ego is like a balloon here
coming up Mother.
Better solve the problem."
You see your ego so clearly and you want to
get rid of it.
Anybody would do that.
But if you tell somebody before Realisation,
“You have got ego,” you’ve had it.
I have never done that and none of you should
do.
Let them feel the Agnya after Realisation.
They come and tell you and you move it.
In the same way, any other trouble, even for
diseases, if you tell somebody that, “You
have such disease,” he may jump down from
here with fear.
In Sahaja Yoga you come to know about the
diseases much, much before any doctors know,
because on your fingers you can feel it.
But you don’t have to tell the person at
all.
You just talk in your code language.
What is catching?
You tell, “This is catching.
Ekadasha Rudra is catching."
Alright, what does that mean?
That is the beginning of the cancer.
There’s already for it.
So Ekadasha.
Clear out the Ekadasha Rudra, is all here
(pointing to forehead).
Now nobody knows what Ekadasha Rudra is, except
for the Sahaja yogis.
And they know there is no danger because it
is curable.
So they clear it out.
That’s the beginning of a personality, where
he starts getting into this trouble or that
trouble.
And say left Agnya is catching, is a sign
that he is going lunatic asylum and little
combinations.
You don’t have to tell the person but you
can save him from going to lunatic asylum.
He need never go.
People have come down to our program to lunatic
asylum and when they went back, they were
told, “You better not come up here."
It can happen like that.
It’s very simple.
It is so simple, you can’t imagine.
The whole thing is so simple but you have
to learn what it is.
You can cure people.
You can help your atmosphere.
You can do lots of things.
The greatest of all that you become the collective
being.
So it changes.
There’s no time, nothing.
You are a free bird.
It’s all freedom.
There’s no bondage.
You yourself want to sit down meditating.
Now I came here, I was supposed to talk and
start my speech but I was enjoying my meditation
so much so I went into that.
All the time you are in meditation mood and
you can enjoy it anytime you want to
Seeker: Do you hope to come back to England
in the near future?
Shri Mataji: No, no, I am stationed here.
Absolutely, I am glued to this place for five
years more!
And I am going to come back very soon.
I am there only for two months, or one month
I will be going to Australia.
So [after] three months altogether, I’m
back.
I’m sure even when I go back after five
years, your government won’t object [to]
my coming here.
I hope so by that time.
So, it’s just I had to come here.
I have been now here seven years and five
years more.
Twelve years!
Can you imagine?
Alright?
That should set you alright.
That was one of the fears is it?
No.
Now is it alright for all of you?
Anyone else?
Sahaja Yogi: You can tell us something about
dharma Mother.
Shri Mataji: Dharma?
Sahaja Yogi: Yes.
Shri Mataji: There’s a, there’s a tape
on dharma and on Guru which you can see.
Dharma is the sustenance which is established
by an aspect of God in our stomach.
Our stomach teaches us our dharma.
“Dharayati sa dharmaha”, means the one
you sustain is your dharma.
For example, the dharma of gold is that it
is untarnishable.
The dharma of carbon is [that] it has got
four valencies.
If you have seen the periodic laws of chemistry,
you will know that all the elements have got
their own dharmas.
And they are given these dharmas by the law
of God.
It’s the Divine Law which has given them
these dharmas.
Up to the stage of human beings the dharma
of a person or of any animal, or of any element,
is determined absolutely by divine laws and
they do not cross it.
For example, a lion will behave like a lion.
He cannot behave like a cat.
A scorpion will behave like itself.
It cannot behave like a lion.
A tiger will behave like a tiger.
Tiger is the king and he won’t eat anything
killed by another animal.
Only when he is hungry, he kills the animal
and he eats whatever he likes in one gulp
and then he rests and others come and eat
that.
He won’t eat anything that is eaten by others
and he won’t kill anything that he need
not kill.
He’s the king.
That’s why if one tiger is killed in a forest
the whole forest seems so gloomy.
Because their king has been killed.
Though he’s a terror for them.
But he lives with his own dharma, with his
own boundaries.
He doesn’t cross his boundaries.
Any one of these, up to the human level, have
their own dharmas.
Only the human beings have been given the
freedom to cross the dharma, they can.
I mean, in a human being, you can find a lion,
you can find a serpent and you can find also
a worm.
You can find the combination of all that in
one person or in the whole group you’ll
find all kinds.
But if they want they can transcend.
And the greatest thing is [that] they can
transcend the dharma itself.
Means they become so great that they can be
sinless.
Just they can’t do any sins.
These dharmas are established within you.
These Ten Commandments are there within us.
If you try to transgress them you are losing
your dharma, your sustenance, beyond which
you have to rise.
For Realisation, you have to rise beyond dharma,
dharmateet – beyond.
But first your dharma must be established.
If it is not established, you cannot rise.
But in Sahaja Yoga, even [if] your dharma
is disturbed it’s forgiven.
Still you can get your Realisation.
Then you establish your dharma.
It’s better.
Because it has been seen [that] those people
who tried to establish their dharmas can become
extremely, extremely dry.
They can be fanatics.
The compassion part of it is lost.
So the compassion itself works in such a way
that all adharmas you have done, whatever
you have done is forgiven.
And you better have your Realisation and with
that power you establish your dharma.
And you have to establish it.
For example, you know that alcohol goes against
your awareness.
Awareness is the main thing, which is enlivened,
enriched by dharma.
The human awareness goes down through alcohol,
you know [this] for definite.
All the great saints who have looked after
the dharma, the prophets, have said against
alcohol and against smoking.
Mohammed Saheb did not say about smoking because
they did not have smoking.
But the same person came as Nanaka.
As Guru Nanaka he has prohibited, absolutely
prohibited anything that intoxicates you,
your awareness.
Because they knew that it will harm you very
much.
It does harm you.
You lose the chances of your Realisation very
much.
It is true that it is injurious.
One thing as alcoholism, I am saying.
There can be something else people do, like
thieving or anything like that, is against
your sustenance.
But Sahaja Yoga is a method by which you first
get your Realisation and then your dharma
is to be established so that you are empowered
by itself.
For example, I never tell people, “Don’t
drink,” because half of the people would
walk out, even Indians.
They just drink like – I don’t know – fishes.
I don’t know if fishes drink, but human
beings do!
And then if I tell them, they will be very
angry.
We had a doctor here who used to drink who
came to me.
He got his Realisation and he went to Germany.
And he was fond of a kind of a wine, a special
wine they make in Germany.
He said, “Let me try some of this."
He had given up because you don’t remember
that you have to drink.
You never get bored enough to drink!
You see, you feel, “What’s the use of
getting up and getting a glass and all that?
I am enjoying myself.
Why to do?”
You are never bored of your company.
You enjoy yourself so much that you don’t
want any drink.
Like when you get the nectar of life, why
should you get after these horrible things?
You just don’t do it.
But this doctor thought, “Oh, how can that
be?
I may have forgotten but today I’ll have
it."
So he walked into a pub and asked for the
thing.
He drank.
After that he had such a pain, he vomited
all that.
And he told me, “The same wine which I used
to enjoy, started smelling like cork to me.
As if cork has been pushed into my tongue.
I just couldn’t bear it and I vomited and
I had pain in the stomach.
Mother what is this?”
I said, “Alright, it’s good!”
You cannot do then adharma.
You just cannot do it.
You just become dharma.
You just cannot do it even if you try.
It just works.
I mean, there are people here, at least fifty
percent people, who have been druggists and
chemists!
Absolutely!
They have given [up] drugs just like that.
Just like that they have given [up] drugs.
Of course, they had to get over the after-effects
of drugs.
That’s different.
But as far as giving up is concerned, no problem
at all, no problem of any kind.
I didn’t have to tell them even, it just
happened.
Dharma is established within you, because
when the light is there you see what it is.
But this seeing is not what you understand
before Realisation – is through your rational
being or through your sense organs – but
is a happening within you where you become
that, you just feel it.
You just can’t help it.
That should happen; is the best, because human
beings otherwise are difficult.
They find it difficult to maintain it.
Now, I mean, everything they surpassed.
First they use to say, “What about our social
relationships?”
Their social relationships have improved,
their jobs have improved, their all material
things have improved.
If you don’t drink, I mean you save fifty
percent of your money as it is!
[It’s] practical apart from anything else!
But, according to Sahaja Yoga it’s much
subtler because the power of maintaining our
material well-being is called as Lakshmi.
And this Lakshmi is a very powerful deity
or a very powerful thing.
But, alcoholism, alcohol is one thing or any
such things like drugs and all that, as soon
as she sees entering into the being, she just
disappears.
She just can’t bear it.
So a person may think that by drinking he
doesn’t lose his money [but] he is sadly
mistaken.
If he does not drink he will have ten times
more money than he has.
And you can see the result today that, when
Englishmen were known in India, Englishmen’s
whisky meant this much, every night; that’s
all.
Today if you see the same thing in third generation,
you’ll be shocked.
I mean, first time I came to England I was
surprised because to us Englishmen means one
peck, so little, before sleeping, very decent.
That’s what we thought they were gentlemen
of that calibre.
But when I saw here, I was surprised.
“Oh, God, what is this?
What Englishmen are these?”
So this happens in [the] third generation.
If alcoholism somehow or other reduces in
England you can surpass all the economic problems;
take it from me.
Absolutely!
You’ll solve all your economics.
Just stop alcohols.
All your strikes will stop because they want
money for what?
For alcohols only.
If you get money – have an alcohol.
Somebody dies – have champagne.
Somebody passes – champagne.
Somebody married – champagne.
For everything there is a champagne!
Even in the church you see barrels and barrels
of whisky flowing in.
Barrels and barrels of this thing is flowing
in.
In mean, even in the church!
Now today somebody told me that he’s got
a special wine from a Catholic church, which
is called as Benedicts and is a special one.
I said, “Where did you buy that?”
He said, “In Rome, in the Vatican.
You can only get it there, the best!”
I was surprised that you can only get it in
Vatican and he was so proud of it and he was
showing me that!
And now it is called as ‘Benedict’.
Just imagine!
‘Benediction’.
‘Benediction’ is that which gives you
Realisation.
What Realisation does the drinking give you?
I don’t know.
Only thing I have seen [is] that people fall
on the streets, they talk like stupid people.
You don’t know what to do with them.
It’s most embarrassing.
So this is what is dharma is, that is just
enlightens you and you enjoy your virtues.
Not your weaknesses but your virtues.
And you enjoy the virtues of others.
That’s what is dharma that has to be enlightened.
May God Bless you!
You have to just put your hands just like
this, just like this.
Put both the feet on the ground.
Please close your eyes.
According to the way the Kundalini is moving,
which I know on my own Kundalini, I will ask
you a few things.
Please try to do them with earnestness and
alertness.
Now, I have to request you to forgive everyone.
Forgive everyone: those who have troubled
you, tortured you, have made you unhappy,
anyone.
You just say, “I forgive."
Is very important.
Just try to forgive.
Say, “I forgive.
Mother, I forgive.
I forgive all of them, all the people who
have tortured me."
Just say that from your heart.
Please say that, “I forgive."
Please close your eyes.
You have to be honest to yourself.
Just say that, “I forgive."
Only saying is sufficient.
Only saying.
But say with the heart.
It will help you a lot if you can say that.
Forgive everyone.
Everyone you forgive.
When you forgive everyone, actually you leave
it into the hands of God to punish them or
do whatever they like.
And that’s the best [way] to manage the
thing.
Just say, “I forgive."
Best thing is to leave it to God to do the
job whatever it is.
You don’t take the load.
They may be nasty.
They may be horrid.
They might have tortured you.
Doesn’t matter.
Just say.
Even Christ said that.
Just again, please say it.
Close your eyes and say it, because if you
do not forgive also, what do you do?
You are playing into their hands.
Nothing is harmed, they are not harmed by
your not forgiving them.
It’s you [who] are harmed.
Because you are remembering all that, you
are harming yourself.
You are tortured by that.
You are torturing yourself not they.
Now the second thing you have to ask [for]
is the forgiveness, yourself.
Because might be some mistakes must have been
committed.
By mistake you might have done something wrong,
something unrighteous.
In seeking, you might have done something
wrong.
So just ask for God to forgive you, that’s
all.
You put your right hand on your heart and
ask for forgiveness.
It will be better.
Left hand towards me and right hand on the
heart.
Now, [while] asking this, you must know that
He is the ocean of compassion.
He is the ocean of forgiveness and He is the
ocean of love and He is anxious for you to
enter into His Kingdom.
He is the One who wants the culmination of
His Creation into a beautiful happening by
which He gives you the complete joy of your
being.
So you just ask for His forgiveness but do
not feel guilty about anything.
Whatever has happened, has happened, is forgiven.
So you just say that, “If there is anything,
please forgive."
But do not feel guilty.
I think best thing is to say, “I’m not
guilty."
Again and again to say that, “I am not guilty."
Because that’s a very common practice here,
to feel guilty.
Let Him judge you.
Not to feel guilty at all is very important.
Please tell yourself thrice that, “I am
not guilty."
Now the Kundalini will rise and you will feel
absolutely thoughtless.
There’s no thought in your mind.
You’ll see that.
Just see it: is there any thought in your
mind.