I am sorry, I was dealing with some newspaper people, journalists,
and they came very late,
whatever it is.
I found them to be very sensible
and very understanding.
All of us have come to Aurangabad now,
and it seems this place is full of vibrations.
Maybe here Shalivahana has ruled in this area,
but also there have been many saints
who were born on this side of Maharashtra,
and they perpetuated Dharma.
They always talked about self-realization.
Dharma gives you the balance.
It gives you the establishment
into proper behaviour,
proper understanding,
proper living,
but it doesn't give you the completion of your journey.
It doesn't give you the satisfaction of reaching the destination.
And your personality is still incomplete.
So, one has to have the experience of the spirit.
As I was discussing with them today,
I told them that those who do not have ...
the experience of the spirit ...
are not only incomplete, but are limited people.
So whatever they see, or whatever they know,
or whatever they criticize, is limited.
As in English we say that "hate the sin and not the sinner".
Like many people who find something wrong with Christianity
start blaming Christ.
Christ did not created Christianity, first of all.
He did not create Christianity.
He did not create Christians.
So there is no relationship between the two.
As you know, recently, they have found out
the books written by Thomas,
the disciple of Christ who was coming to India.
On his way he went to Egypt,
and there he wrote these treatise
and had put them in a big earthen vessel,
or perhaps it was a metallic thing,
and it was discovered fourty-two years back.
The people ...
whom he considers to be ...
authorized Christians, he calls them as Gnostic.
"Gne", "gne" in Sanskrit language means, "to know".
"Gne" means "to know".
And he has written that to know,
and to have the personal experience
is the only way to follow Christ.
Clearly.
Not only that,
it's said that God Allmighty who is so kind,
why will He ask you to suffer?
So it challenges all the Christian principles of suffering.
In the same way, in all religions,
people have diverted from the right path,
and have come to the wrong path,
and are indulging
into self-created religions,
which has no relationship with reality,
or with the incarnations,
those who started those religions
or who gave the ideas of the religion.
I hope you won't do that to Me,
because you are gnostic people.
You are the ones who know,
who have had self-realization.
Without self-realization you cannot have a complete personality.
But as you see in Sahaja Yoga,
you don't have to go to Himalayas,
to give up your families;
you don't have to be away from the society
to get your realization.
You get your realization in the circumstances where you are born.
In the same society, in the same family-life.
But, you rise higher then them,
and try to pull them out of the mire in which they are existing.
This mire of ignorance has to be crossed,
and some of you have to do it.
And when you realize that,
then you should know that you all have to be very strong people.
You all have to be extremely strong.
If you are not strong enough,
how can you pull out the rest of them?
People who are mediocre
think that gradually they'll be allright,
and that they'll come up.
But I would suggest that you should make all-out-effort
to become strong Sahaja Yogis.
To become strong Sahaja Yogis is not difficult.
Because you have all the powers within yourselves.
You have the Kundalini within yourselves.
And you know the way, how to become a realized soul.
The problems are of you being dragged into your ego
or into your conditioning.
Only two problems,
not more.
Like somebody asked, "How many turns there are in London?"
Only two, left or right.
So either you go to the left or to the right.
All the permutations and combinations of this left and right
starts working and then you get into trouble.
And then you get into problems.
But actually it is a very simple thing.
To get out of your ego should be the simplest
and that is where you try to understand yourself.
You see yourself. How you are reacting.
Where is your attention?
What are you doing?
What is your attitude towards Sahaja Yoga?
So many people think that "this is my house,
this is my family, this is my car,
this is my horse, this is my dog.
I don't know how far it goes - "my, my, my, my, my".
But nothing is yours.
Yesterday, as Kabira has said it,
that "some cheat", that is the death, "will come
and take away everything that is not yours".
Then "my family" ...
then "my children" ...
All this is a nonsense,
and so, when you start getting attached to this word "my",
there where you fail completely
into your own understanding of your ego,
you're completely blinded by this ego.
First of all you should say that "nothing is mine".
Kabira has said that when the goat is living
she goes on saying "Mei, mei, mei ..."
means "I, I, I ..." in Hindi language.
Made a pun on the word "my".
And when she dies, and her intestines are taken out,
and are made into something that spins the ... cotton,
they go on the street, these people,
telling people that they are around,
they go on playing on that string
which is made from the intestines
of these goats,
it says, "Tuhi, tuhi, tuhi ..."
meaning "You are, you are, you are ..."
So one need not be like a goat,
that till you leave you go on saying "I, I, my, my ..."
When you die then your intestines have to be taken out
and put on that thing
just to make the sound "Tuhi, tuhi, tuhi ..."
So this sound of "I, I, I ..."
is made only by egoistical human beings,
but this ego is so much identified with you,
that you think that "I am this ego
and ego is me".
And in that ego you start doing all kinds of nonsensical things.
This ego takes you nowhere,
it takes you nowhere
but into a complete mire of ignorance about yourself.
Ultimately you become stupid,
others can tell you that you are stupid,
or you become idiotic,
or you get a bad name,
and everybody knows that you are doing all wrong things,
but nobody there tell you,
because you are to be reached with a barge pole.
Such a hot-tempered personality you become,
nobody dare come you and say that this is wrong,
it should not be done, it's stupid, idiotic,
and you, yourself, in that idiocity and stupidity
think no end of yourself.
This is the extreme of your ego.
But it's nice, we have people like Hitler to see.
So if you put Hitler as the ideal egoist
then you will not go on that road.
Because it's a very slippery road
and maybe  one day you land up there.
The second side of ours,
which is a very, looks very morbid
and very mild, is the left side.
The movement on the left side is the emotional side.
You develope habits with the left side.
Now, some people have very dangerous habits,
some have simple habits.
Like I have a bad habit, or a good habit, you may say,
that i must put my right hand under my foot,
because it's all the time working, so I want to controll it.
So, I put it under my head like this, while sleeping
and sometimes under my foot,
just to make it little bit stop working, it works too hard.
Just to give it rest.
So under my pillow I put it and sleep.
But I discovered once, I hurt myself,
that I now cannot put it under my head.
I said, "It's a very funny habbit I have got."
But it's not such a dangerous one. It's quite good.
So I am continuing with it.
But I can get rid of it. It's very simple.
But when I get rid of it
I think the people become overactive
so I put it again, under my pillow.
So as Sahaja Yogis all your habbits should be under your control.
Now the ...
habits we have formed through drugs,
from drinking, from anything, are very dangerous habbits.
Also, people have their attention being all the time around.
All the time is attention here, there and there,
attracting people, looking after them,
not looking after yourself.
This attention has to be brought under control. Is very important.
That's very simple, that whenever it happens,
you just put down your eyes.
Keep your eyes down.
That's one of the ways we ...
allow our attentiion to fritter away,
and also our growth becomes stunted.
This is a very very dangerous thing
which in the West specially we have developed.
Here, also, people must read every shop's name.
Indians have a bad habit,
because they have just now started reading,
so they want to read everything that they find, anything.
So on the road if there is a road of shops,
they read every name of every shop,
turn round again and see if they have missed anything.
It sounds stupid. But they all do it.
And all the time they are doing it.
So the attention, wherevever it goes,
has to be under our control.
We have to keep it, all the time under our control.
As Namadeva has said very clearly,
in Guru Grant Sahib has written,
that when a little child is flying the kite,
he's talking  to everyone,
he's playing in a way,
but his attention is on the kite.
And when a housewife is carring her duties,
putting her child on her waiste and working,
then she's doing all kinds of work,
but her attention is on the child.
The Ladies who are carrying
three-four earthen pots on their heads,
water filled up to the brim,
are walking, talking to each other,
having mirth and enjoyment,
but the attention is on the earthen pot, on their heads.
In the same way, whatever adventure you are into,
whatever you are doing, your attention should be on your spirit.
Then everything is under control,
and you can never get enveloped
into anything where attention should not be lost.
So, these two problems we have,
and those problems even after realization people have it.
So please try, when you are not meditating,
to keep your attention on your spirit.
Now, the person who is left-sided or right-sided,
he has developed a mechanism within himself to justify himself.
Through his intellect,
or maybe if they are ladies they have water power,
they'll start crying.
And you just don't know what to say to them.
If you tell them anything, first thing they'll do is to cry,
means sometimes I feel there are thousand arrows on My head
when they start crying.
It is impossible to say anything to them.
And if you talk to some men
the'lll give so many explanations
that you would feel like, just, going off to sleep.
It's so boring.
It''s easy to read some book like "War and Peace"
than to listen to the arguments of such people.
But they don't want to see
that this is all ego, which is talking,
It is not, they are talking,
it is not their spirit.
And if the spirit has to evolve
we have to be extremely wittnessing, in a full way,
very alert, extremely alert
and wittnessing ourselves, what are we doing.
Then only we reach the completion of our realization.
Unless and until you reach the completion of your realization,
you can never be masters of your attention,
and you can never be the enjoyer of your joy,
and you can never know the truth fully.
Achieve this Sat-Chit-Ananda swarupa
you have to be extremely careful
about the instrument that God has given you,
this body, mind and emotions.
You have to keep them in check,
because wherever your habits are
they can never be joy giving, it's a joyless pursuit.
and wherever your ego is, it's a destructive effort.
So both things are detrimental to your growth,
apart from that, they are extremely dangerous thing for yogis.
So, as you are, in whatever conditions you are,
in whatever situations you are,
whatever may be the surroundings,
like a dirty mire full of creatures and filth,
you can become like lotuses.
When you become like lotuses
all that is filth, all that is horrible, can become fragrant.
And this is what we have to achieve.
When people will see the lotuses they'll come to you,
not to see the worms and to see the filth,
but to see the lotuses.
So please, this time, correct yourself,
you don't need anybody to correct you,
you just correct yourself,
watch out for yourself, and see for yourself.
If something doesn't work out just give up.
Don't go to extrems for anything.
Must learn to give up at a point
and be happy about it.
If you are contained within yourself,
if your hand is attached to your body,
then you reach up to a point and then leave it,
but if it is not attached, if it is disintegrated
then it goes all round and round and round
and comes back without anything.
That understanding has to be there in you people
because you're standing in the central part,
and you're attached to the central part, not only,
but you are identified with it.
So you cannot go too far to the left,
cannot go too far to the right,
if you do that you get lost.
Then you are no more a Sahaja Yogi,
and then no use having you here artificially or superficially
because it will be hypocrisy.
Whatever is needed to put you back into right frame you must accept.
And whatever is needed to understand Sahaja Yoga you have to do.
As I have said, please try to learn English language.
I cannot learn fourteen languages.
Very difficult.
It's surprising how I have learned this English language also.
So now to learn fourteen languages
I've to take fourteen Avataras again.
I don't ask you to learn Marathi.
Because that's the best language for Me to speak.
But at least try to learn Engllish.
and then we can see if you can learn Marathi or Hindi.
What is to say now?
that you are born in auspicious place.
this auspicious place
Aurangabad,
I feel that ,s very auspicious place.
Great Saints are born here.
Since thousand of years people worked
and gave you these Punyas.
Because of those Punyas you are here today
You behaved well,
respected Dharmas
but not yet reached the Completeness.
Therefore you took Self Realisation.
After getting Self Realisation
we should be able to see our defects.
Otherwise you have not got that light yet.
Now with the Foreigners
they have other defects.
and Indian people have another defects.
And now I see those defects so prominantly
that I feel sometimes better I tell them very clearly.
Actually
for Indians my house
my daughter, my grandson these things very much
and they are so much involved
in the family matters that
they can not come out of it.
I made 4-5 boys marriages and
sent them to Austria.
They had no jobs.
They got nice jobs there.
Immediately they made their own houses
or rather an Indian man can not live without home.
Even having all the facilities in the Ashram
they want their separate houses.
Their wives get bored
because to have separate house means to work on your own.
There are no servants, no nothing.
After having Delivery also they work on their own.
Though they are pregnant they have to work on their own.
Husbands will be enjoying outside.
They will have Cars,
have Television
and then go everywhere.
After coming home
shout at wives,
‘You did not cook well,
did not do that’.
Wives got bored. What kind of husbands are this?
They can not work everything,
can not clean outside.
Only my house should be neat and clean
and go out for scrolling.
Everyone is the same here.
Here Indian men
can not work anything.
They do not use their hands for Work.
All are sophisticated.
We have appointed a Gardner.
Well, he is Gardner.
From Austria.
He is also
an agriculture adviser of U.N.
He came here.
He takes Spade and Scraper
in hands  and works so hard.
Indian men with hands on Waist
and wearing Gumboots.
I asked,“ why did you wear Gumboots?“
I have Problems with mud. Is it so?
Then you can go now and be royal.
These things are very much in us.
And speciality of Wives is that
they know well that our husbands
are in our control if the house
is clean and if they get delicious food.
So today this delicious Dish,
tommorrow another delicious Dish
for husband.
Then for the meal they
give you what you like.
So if you like bitter Gourds
then bring the bitter Gourd
at any cost from the Market.
Then cook them for husband.
All the time serve husband.
Whole time after husband.
First thing, due to this husbands get spoiled.
And.
Home is something special.
is our thinking
Our attention does not go beyond that.
That is my, mine.
It becomes so
narrow minded that
we get destroyed in this.
This should go away from us
If you are Sahajyogis,
became Yogis
wherever they sit, it is your home,
wherever you go it is your home.
Do not ask,
the family is small.
How that smallness will become gross?
You are born in Yogabhumi of India
because of whatever Punyas
you earned
in past Births.
But everything gets destroyed.
That greatness should come.
That greatness does not come and
Some people even say
it is very less in Men.
Now,
Now all have written that
we like Indian women but not Indian Men.
Because all are lazy Lumps,
we can see it.
If there is dirt outside the house
they will still walk on it.
But women will keep the house clean.
But women are clever.
If the house is in order then
husband stays at home.
It is very difficult to keep him at home
because he always remains out.
Therefore we have the defect that
we do not have collectiveness in us.
How to become collective,
how to be nice with one another,
how to become compassionate
we do not think this.
Now with the great difficulties
we opened
an Ashram in Delhi.
Nobody wants to stay there.
Somehow we sent one couple from Mumbai.
Within 2 days returned back.
The feeling like
my home should be given up.
The day when you will say that
the whole world is my home
then can be said that
you have become great.
The mind is so restricted.
How Sahajayogis will do progress.
Though they become Sahajayogis,
even they meditate,
do Pujas, everything is OK.
It is past earnings.
But as it is.
No progress  beyond that.
I have found reason for that
is wasting time at home very much.
If you move only in Circle
how will you go further?
We can not get in Collectivity.
So much Selfcentreness.
Increase only Self Esteem.
My home,
my wife, my children
this and that.
Until you
do not come
out of this
it is only load of work.
It is just a Donkey-work.
If God is doing everything
then why do you become Donkey?
If you say you do everything
then you became donkey
Like Jesus
was sitting on a Donkey
and Donkey was carrying him.
That Donkey thought,
it became Jesus because
everyone was garlanding donkey.
Then Donkey started troubling Jesus.
So Jesus got down of donkey and went somewhere else.
From other side came the Washerman, the master of donkey.
He beated (slapped) donkey nicely.
Then it realised that it itself is donkey
and Jesus is Jesus.
Likewise Yogi is Yogi.
He is not donkey.
Unnecessary donkey-work.
To please wife,
please this person, please that person. There is no need.
In collectivity
One should get in collectivity.
To get in collectivity first of all
one should give up all these small small petty things.
Small person sees everything small.
Does not see anything gross.
Whatever is small,
which is false
is always easily accepted.
Therefore we have to make our mind great.
First of all my house these Words should be given up.
Mine, this word is false.
What is there in mine?
Like yesterday it was said
about Kabira
that one theif came
and robbed me.
Means who? Death.
The time when Death comes
everything remains behind.
Then my, mine everything is left behind.
But this Death has come in us
because we have become Sahajayogis now.
Formerly we were Eggs
and now
we have become Birds.
So everything from the past
has been left behind.
Now we
have to spread our Wings and take flights.
But we are
still entangled
in our Wings.
What to say now?
We are still stuck up in mud.
Which is not correct.
But after this everyone should
make his mind great.
Greatness should be adopted.
And this acceptance of greatness
should be enjoyed by everyone.
So many people come here.
You do not speak with them, meet them.
Do not do any introduction with anyone. That is wrong.
When these people come many of you
help them, serve them, agreed.
But you should introduce yourself with them.
Make freindship with them
because they are your brothers
and you do not have any brothers
or any sisters.
These are your relatives.
It is said that they are
your own near and dear ones.
Gyaneshwara has said clearly that
these are your own Kith and Kin.
All others are
not your relatives.
There is no comparison between
you and them.
They say something and do something else.
I can say about my family that
some are in Sahajayoga, they are there.
Those who are not Yogis I do not know them.
They are Strangers.
So those people
who are not in Sahajayoga
are not relatives, accept this.
You
will be surprised.
Many things will be given up.
Now there is Maratha.
Then Maratha should
marry Maratha.
Then it is OK if he is beating his Wife.
It is OK even if he is not Sahajayogi.
It is OK however way he is treating her.
But Maratha should marry Maratha.
Why?
Tommorrow
if that girl is in trouble then
will your Maratha stand by her?
But Sahajayogi will stand by her.
Sahajayogi should marry Sahajayogi
and there if something goes wrong then
Mother we married in Sahajayoga
therfore we got in trouble.
This Cast system
or internal hatred
about religion
or
about another Caste
or for another Country
that
will be disappeared only after marrying.
I do not see any other solution.
We can understand by seeing it.
Just few days ago I made
one Maratha girl’s marriage in Australia.
Her family members
made a big issue
and said that they will go to the Police. I said,“ Go.
Do as you like."
She is an adult now.
She has all the rights.
They did (tried) a lot
but nothing could work out.
Now that girl is very wise and got married
so nicely.
Her husband has a good Salary, etc.
They see this. Now
all of them want to go to Australia
with packings.
At the time of marriage they did stupidity.
Likewise we are Bramhins and marry only with Bramhins
and if tommorrow that Bramhin
threw out of the house, what will you do?
Then you will come to me.
Mataji, please do something
about our Son-in-law.
What should I do? You yourself found
such a Bramhin Son-in-law.
Then have it !
Why should I do for that?
Like this many
big big things we are
wasting blindly
and all these problems
stood
in front of us
because we did not raise our Aim. We are Yogis.
From inside we have become Ascetics
Though from outside we are free from worldly matters,
we have become Ascetics.
You should be proud that
you have become Ascetics
and you should be happy about it.
Otherwise you will not progress,
will never progress.
Whatever you do you will not progress
until you make your mind great.
And we have many
misunderstandings in us those should
go away.
No one will be called
as real Yogi
unless all these false ideas go away.
So no one should keep
these all kinds of strange,
peculiar things in them.
You will be surprised about what I say.
Before this
in this
Maharashtra whichever many great Saints,
Sages took birth.
Very great Saints.
Those Saints and Sages have told the same thing
that Cast system,
Religion-fanticism are very bad things.
Take any Stone and
Take any Stone and put Shendur or Kumkum on it.
It is said that
Nrusimha Saraswati (Freedom fighter) used to spit on it.
If he saw something like that used to spit on it.
He raised his Weapons against them many a times.
But he was alone
and so people troubled him.
Dnyaneswara also
suffered a lot. He was tortured
because he was Sanyasi’s son.
Though he was son of Sanyasi,
he was higher than
all the Bramhins.
In such a way
many things has happened
happened in our Country. So we should
learn from that history
and now we have become Yogis.
Therefore in such situations
we should behave ourselves so that
we are standing on our Basic Principles.
We have achieved everything.
So we do not belong to
those things. We are
only Yogis
and these things do not suit to Yogis.
In such way all the false ideas
or whatever way you had
them till today should be
given up and we should place
God in our hearts.
Without being obstinate
all those things should be given up.
Give up completely.
Chokha Mela was also a Saint.
And likewise
Ramdas Swami was also a Saint.
But followers of Ramdas Swami and followers of Chokha Mela
are fighting with each other.
It is a amazing.
If both are Saints
why should there be any fight between them.
But it will be.
Because there is no vision
so these things happen.
Therefore
I want to tell you that
We have to come out of this Cast system and stupidity.
In Muslims,
in Christianity
it is same thing everywhere.
Though following these Religions
tell me one thing that
have you anywhere seen that man
can not do any Sin because of any Religion?
Ready for all kinds of Sins.
Though he is Muslim,
Hindu or Christian.
I have not seen
any one who will not
commit any Sin.
But Yogis can not do any Sin.
If they do then Vibrations will go from hands.
Saints never did Sins.
No one had to tell them.
Automatically they became like that.
We should become like that
and achieve
that Stability forever.
Sahajayoga is
a gate of Salvage (Moksha).
So you should
feel great that
you came to Sahajayoga.
You should respect yourself
and you should
grow
in that respect.
Actually we do not
have to sacrifice anything in Sahajayoga.
Yes, but if you give up your Wisdom
then we can not do anything.
But we do not need people who are great Sacrificers.
On the contrary there are only benefits.
Everyone gets benefited
but there is also
an illusion. One should not get lost in that
There are many benefits. You will get Laxmi’s blessing,
shall get good health.
May get various benefits.
But it is an illusion.
Beyond that is Spirit.
That we should achieve
and should be dwelling in it.
This I am telling you very clearly
and everyone should
give up all the things
of Religions and Religions fanaticism.
Likewise Atheists also
should open their Eyes and
see if there God exists or not.
They do not have any authority
to deny God, existence of God.
Who are they to say such things?
And if they say so
then they are wrong
because they have not yet
seen if God exists or not.
So there should be Purity.
One should make oneself absolute pure.
And in that Purity
we should understand
know God.
Otherwise
it won’t be understood.
There won’t be oneness, unity
and any benefits ever.
Unnecessarily
we should not come here as we travel
to do pilgrimage to Pandhari.
I request you all that
you should achieve something.
A very sincere request.
I see that here
in Maharashtra apart from lot of hardwork
why Sahajayoga has not deeply established.
Because only by doing my Puja nothing will happen.
What is the use?
You are anyway doing my puja in all Temples.
To do only Puja is useless here.
Today it should be decided and determined
that we are
doing Shri Mataji’s puja
keeping all this fanaticism away.
We are doing Shri Mataji’s puja keeping ourself clean.
Then only there will be benefit.
Otherwise I am suffering from Puja.
This is
a big authority.
And though I have given you,
you should acquire
that deservence.
And I bless you all !
Many blessings !
Please attention to yourself.
Know your importance !
Know your greatness !
Today which Task you have taken.
I have started this great Work
of Evolution of Universe.
You are standing there
and you should be prepared for that.
Everyone should be strong and ready.
Today is the first Day.
Therefore I say explicitly that
you are
organising whatever
to be done.
But I am not doing it
Mother is doing if you think this way
and then
then whatever we are doing
in that
let only Divine Work be manifested
if you desire this
then everything will be fine.
Everything will be fine.
Anyway, I bless you all.
May God bless you all!