Today is a sad day because such a great man
like Sadat is dead. He is not great to Me
because he was a great politician or he was
president, but he was a saint, he was a realized
soul, I knew all about him. The attack of
the negativity is on but no more they will
crucify a saint this way and will not face
the punishment. They will be punished now.
All those who tried to do such things will
be punished because the new age has started.
Today I wanted to tell you about the Agya
chakra, about Jesus Christ who adorns this
center of Agya chakra, where you see the red
mark. Behind that, inside, in the brain on
the crossing of the optic chiasm is this subtle
center where this great Deity is placed through
His crucifixion and through His Resurrection.
He has created this space for us to enter
into the Kingdom of God, which is placed within
us. Is not in without, is the limbic area
that surrounds your ego and superego. In the
Puranas, in the ancient scriptures of India,
Christ is described so very clearly. Actually
in the Bible what they saw of Him when He
was on this Earth was written down. But nothing
what created Him, how He came on this Earth
what is the spirit of Christ, what is the
seat of Christ and how He came and what is
His purpose and where does He stand within
us. All these things are not described in
the Bible as I told you the people at that
time were not at all aware of His greatness,
of His special Incarnation. But if you read
some of these ancient books you’ll find
that He was called as Mahavishnu in the Devi
Purana, in the Goddess Purana, is the ancient
scripture of the Goddess. Mahavishnu was created
immaculately. Now when we say that Christ
always pointed out this pick is very significant.
Actually this, this means Vishuddhi chakra
and means also America. But this also means
Vishuddhi chakra stands for Shri Krishna as
I told you and He is the Primordial Being,
and He is the epitome of our evolution in
the sense that He is the Primordial Being
who is the Father, who is the preserver.
Now in the Puranas He is described that His
power was Radha, Radha. Sanskrit language
is absolutely very scientific as far as the
Divine Laws are concerned. Ra means the energy,
dha means the one that sustains. [SANSKRIT
TALK] She is the one who sustains the energy
and She was His power. But in India Krishna
is never taken as Krishna Radha but Radha
Krishna. The energy is before the deity. The
lady is before the gentleman, we can say.
Radha Krishna.
Now this special happening took place long
time back. This is at the stage of Vaikunta
as we call it, at the stage where nothing
existed as far as this world was concerned.
At different stages it came up. We see the
world in such a way that it was created in
seven days, but actually these are seven stages
in when this whole Universe was created and
we are at the seventh stage, we can say. Now
at the first Vaikunta stage where it was all
decided, how to work it out the creation of
this great personality, of the Son of God,
the greatest of all, the Adhara, the support
of the universe, this Mahavishnu. So Radha,
She’s Mahalakshmi, She is the central path.
First She created Him in the Vaikunta stage.
And at that stage She decided that She’ll
create It by Herself this great Incarnation
and She created this Mahavishnu. I would like
you to get the translation of the description
of Mahavishnu and also the description of
Ganesha who is the Spirit of Christ and who
incarnated in this, on this earth as our Lord
Jesus Christ.
So we have here an Incarnation, a very special
one, which was conceived thousands and thousands
of years back at this level where it’s only
the activity of the God’s mind was there,
Vaikunta stage, where it was decided that
this power called Radha will conceive Him
in Her heart. And She conceived Him in Her
heart. And then He was made like an egg. See
the symbolism of Easter, like an egg. Can
you recognize it? People knew about it somehow.
Why do we have Easter, eggs? We never think
about it. He was created like an egg out of
which the half of it was kept as the seed,
as Shri Ganesha, as the Spirit, and a half
of it was created as Jesus Christ. The whole
egg was nothing but the egg of this Divine
power, which has to manifest this Divine power
on this Earth.
This story is very beautiful, how She created
and then He asked: “Who is my Father?”
Radha is nobody else but Mother Mary Herself.
She is Mahalakshmi. People may say that they
can’t believe in immaculate birth of Christ.
They cannot believe in the conception of Christ.
I mean you it’s easy for people to say:”
We don’t believe.” What do they know about
God? What do they know about His mysterious
ways of doing it? Can you say how you convert
or you transform a flower into a fruit? You
don’t know anything about living miracles
and you start doubting the Immaculate Conception.
Here, when you got your Realization I conceived
you in My heart and gave you Realization through
My Sahasrara. How did you get your Realization?
You never thought of it. Is an impossibility.
Thousands of people are getting Realization.
How is it possible? There must be something
special about Me and about the way it is done.
In the same way She conceived and gave Him
the birth through Her uterus.
You can move it anywhere on your central system.
And this great Incarnation came on this Earth
with such a special purpose that He was nothing
but Pranava, is the, this integrated power,
this great power which has all the powers
in it: the Iccha Shakti, the Prana Shakti
and the Dharma Shakti is the central path,
all of these put together. He was nothing
but energy, energy put into an egg because
He had to do a very great job. So this Radha
Herself, this Mahalakshmi, this Mother Mary
conceived this child and to name Him after
Krishna who was the Father. She called Him
Christ. Christ come from the word ... In Indian
language is, we call Him Krist, Krishna. Krishna
means the one who has sown the seed. He is
the Father. He points out always to the Father.
But in the Puranas it is described that Krishna
said: “You are higher than Me. I placed
You higher than Me”. He placed Him, you
can imagine that Christ is at this point and
Krishna is at this point. He placed higher
Him than Him and He said: “In anywhere people
worship Me – Shri Krishna said – automatically
You are worshipped. You will be the support,
Adhara, of the whole world.”
Is wonderful to say that about I think 14000
years or 12000 years back, Markandeya, such
a great saint was born in India. And he has
written the complete Ganesha Stotram, means
the complete praise of Ganesha. You can see
the translation is so beautiful and that he
said: ”You’ll be so humble”. He is the
one who is the ninth Incarnation called as
[BAUTHA] among the ten Incarnations. That
He will be so humble that He will wash the
feet of His disciples. All the miracles of
Christ are described in these books. But these
books are not translated.
And that He will be the one, when enlightened
within you with the Kundalini, He will take
away all your karmas and all your conditionings
because He will die for your sins, for your
karmas. The world will not have to suffer
anymore, if He is awaken within you. These
are all the things already written, thousands
of years back. Can you imagine? I wish the
Christians who went from here to take, explain
Christianity to Indians told them that Mahavishnu
is already born and we are preaching about
Him, the One who is going to suck your conditioning,
the One who is going to suck all your problems
of karmas. They never told. On the contrary,
they were so stupid, I must tell you, that
they would put a loaf in a well and say that:
“You all have become Christians because
we have put the meat of the beef, the beef
inside the well”. Indians don’t eat beef,
you see. “So you all have become Christians”.
Villages after villages they converted into
Christianity. They started branding them as
Christians. This was absurd. And that’s
why the people were waiting and waiting for
the Advent of Christ.
His name Christ comes from the word Krishna,
Krist, and the second one is Jesus. Krishna
had a foster mother whom Radha loved very
much. Her name was Yeshoda, we also call her
as [Jesoda, Jeshoda]. Christ is called also
as [Yesu, Yeshu] in India. The short form
of [Jesoda, Jeshoda] is [Yesu, Yeshu] or [Jeshu,
Jesu] we have both the things. From there
the name Jesus has come. She wanted to name
Her after the foster mother because she was
a lady so she was called as [Jeshoda, Jesoda]
but for a man She selected the name [Yesu,
Yeshu] and [Jeshu, Jesu]. Moreover the word
[Jeshu, Jesu] or [Yeshu, Yesu] is very important.
“J” in Sanskrit language means, every
word has a meaning in Sanskrit language, means
to know, is to know, the knowledge, Gyana.
[SANSKRIT TALK]. The one who knows. But [Jeshu,
Jesu] [“shu”, “su”] means auspicious.
[“Shu”, “Su”] means “that brings
auspiciousness, that brings blessings”.
Jeshu is the one who knows how to bring auspiciousness
on this Earth. People never told this, they
never knew who went from here with the message
that Christ was born.
At the time when Christ came on this Earth
with this big message that somebody has to
pass through this special problem. Now let’s
see why the problem was there. We have to
understand the problem that faced human beings
at that subtle level where they had to work
out this special, a very extraordinary Incarnation.
The problem was that human beings had raised
their heads. By raising their heads their
ego and superego grew up around their limbic
area, making it a very hard shell, just like
an egg. A man developed his I-ness and only
way to transform him into a bird, like an
egg breaks up into a bird, was to make the
Kundalini rise. But how to make that compact
stuff where it is crossing, crossable, which
can be crossed over, which can be passed through.
So they had to create this special Incarnation,
which is nothing but Pranava, the Aum, the
Logos as you call it, the sound of the All
Pervading Power. To be put at a place where
nothing but the power itself can remain, because
anybody else, all other Incarnations who came
on this Earth had all the five elements within
them. But He was just the power, the energy,
the complete energy. He didn’t have, for
example we all human beings are made of five
elements on the right hand side as I told
you, and when we die the part that is our
body, means one of the five koshas, as they
call the cocoons of the body which is the
matter, falls off. Then the water cocoon also
falls off and the soul remains with the Spirit
on your head and the Kundalini also there.
But He was the only One who had no earth element
in it. And so it was a very special type of
an energy engulfed, engulfed into a human
being was placed.
Krishna has said about the eternal life and
about the Spirit. In Sanskrit language is
very beautiful because it’s a mantra: [SANSKRIT].
Means it cannot be killed by anyone, the Spirit
cannot be killed. It is eternal. You cannot
press it. It cannot be flown out by any wind.
And He had to prove it and to prove that they
had to have somebody here, on this Earth,
with that energy to come in, with a body,
to act like a human being, live like a human
being and go through that drama of death to
show that He overcomes the death. The Resurrection
is our message, that He resurrects Himself.
He had to die and He had to be resurrected
because He says that it is beyond death. Krishna
has said that the Spirit is beyond death.
And the Spirit had to come on this Earth.
So you understand when we talk of Christ how
little we know as to how this worked out.
Is the most difficult thing that he did. And
His Mother was the Mahalakshmi, is the power,
which is the central power of sustenance,
pure sustenance, pure holiness, pure innocence.
Such a powerful woman She was, very powerful.
And Himself is endowed with, you won’t believe,
with eleven powers of Rudra, means of destruction,
eleven powers of Rudra. He’s Ekadesha Rudra.
Is described, all that is described, I’m
not telling it as My own. You can see for
yourself. He was endowed with eleven powers
of destruction. But He was to go through all
this, with all the humility. When you have
all these powers with you and when egoistical
people behave like this, these donkeys, you
see, who could not understand Him, these brainless
people in those days, who could not believe
Him, He could have destroyed all of them in
one [SHOT, SHUT]. Absolutely He has got eleven
Rudras. You can imagine His destructive powers,
with which He is going to come back. And He
had to keep them in control.
But He didn’t say about His Mother much,
because She was the power and if He had said
so, then they would have directed, these negative
forces would have directed all their attention
towards Her and then He would have used all
these eleven powers and the whole drama would
have been failed. So He kept quiet on that.
My father, as I told you, was a learned man
and a very great soul and [WE] used to discuss
about these things and I said: “Martin Luther,
who was a Realized soul, when he started his
new movement of Protestants, why did he not
enhance the glory of the Mother?” As the
Catholics knew, because Catholics just followed
after Christ so it linked about with them.
My father told Me that at that time Martin
Luther faced three forces against him. First
one was the Christians themselves, the Catholics,
who believed in nunneries and all kinds of
ritualism and all kinds of nonsense, which
he wanted to flout, then he had another force,
which was facing and that one was the one
that came from the Jews because they would
not accept Him. Even today they don’t accept
Him. They are very adamant. And the third
force that he had to face was the Islam, Islamic.
And the Islam pleaded down the role of a woman
though Fatima Herself was the Holy Ghost,
is the Mahakali power, the daughter of Mohammad.
But he pleaded down just because the Islam
had pleaded down he thought gradually as Protestants
will grow up, he will start introducing the
greatness of His Mother. As it is Jews even
today are after the Immaculate Conception.
In London, very recently, I think about two
years back, as they have money they paid some
of the newspapers and published something
nonsensical about Christ. They said that it
was predicted in the Bible that a child will
be born to a girl, but it was not a virgin,
the Hebrew word, as it is, is for the girl
and not a virgin. I said: “In those days,
we didn’t have girls of 18 years as we have
today”. Even in India today if you say a
girl, a [KANYA,] means a virgin, [KANYA] and
virgin is the same, means the Virgo.
Modern times are funny. We can’t judge Christ
style according to modern times. Even you
find a woman who is married ten times they’ll
call her a girl here. But one should logically
understand this point. Is very logical. But
if it was to be said that a prophecy means
something special, that a child would be born
to a girl, of course it is going to be born
to a girl and not to a boy. And why was the
girl word? It is going to be born to a boy.
If it is to a woman it is nothing special.
What is there to prophesize and say about
it? Is so logical that when the word girl
came in it meant the virgin. All kind of things
they are talking, doesn’t matter.
First of all they say that our, we have to
suffer till our Savior comes because Christ
didn’t suffer for them. So they are suffering.
Now, we have to know that Christ has suffered
for us absolutely to the brim. We don’t
have to suffer anymore. Is a nonsensical idea
coming from people who are sadistic, who have
no joy in themselves. They cannot see you
happy. And that’s why also they make Christ
look like a TB patient, I should say. I went
to the Sistine Chapel and Michelangelo was
a realized soul, a great person. He has done
complete justice to the image of Christ. Huge
big thing like a, we can say, a Texas fellow
standing with a lambodara, with a big stomach
of this kind. Ganesha is lambodara. Standing
there throwing people right and left. Just
see the words, how He has spoken. He was not
a cabbage like person, He was extremely dynamic,
He was full of vigor, He was absolutely fearless.
He had nothing to fear. And He’s standing
there and throwing people to the left and
the right and the right ones is accepting
them and putting them in the Kingdom of Heaven.
Just imagine! It is Michelangelo is the only
person who has really done justice to Him
and I would say Rubens because of his habits
of painting the muscles, he’s done a very
beautiful painting, I saw, is in the place
where he lives, of the ascent and descent
of Christ. Beautiful, one of the best one
could think.
Nowhere miseries written on His face. Such
people do not feel the misery. They just watch
the drama. They don’t suffer because of
taking up your sufferings it took it upon
Himself and He showed to the world that: “Now
I ask forgiveness from My Father”. He stood
as a representative of all the seekers of
the world before His Father who is a wrathful
Father. I told you Shri Krishna has a Samara
Shakti and worse than that is the witness
God whom we call as Sadashiva. He is only
there when He has to destroy. And He asks
as your representative: “O Father, please,
forgive them”. He asks for forgiveness,
facing His own Father as your representative
that: “Please, forgive them”. This is
the greatest weapon He has given us, to forgive.
That’s one thing none of the Christian nations
are doing, is to forgive. Perhaps people have
not known the power of love. They do not.
They talk. God is love. Just talk, talk, talk,
talk. If God is love then love must be the
most powerful thing.
When I first started My work I flouted all
these fake gurus by names in India and I told
them what devils they had been and I‘ve
known them for ages. And people told Me that:
“They will shoot You this time”. I said:
“Let them start shooting. I’ll se who
can shoot Me.” [AND ALL THOSE I HAVE] flouted
them anywhere I get the chance. I’ve told
that: “These are horrible people“. As
Christ has said: “Hot or cold.” He doesn’t
mind, because if it is cold they are realized,
if they are hot then we’ll fight them. We
can tell them how. But if they are one lukewarm,
you see, there are people: “O, we are in
different awareness, they are in different
awareness, we must accept this awareness also,
we must accept...” Such people are the ones
He said: “I’ll spout them out of My mouth”.
So clearly. He’s the One who whipped people
who were selling things in the temple. He
is the One who said: “Don’t throw pearls
before the swine.” So far I’ve never used
this word but He has. He was dynamic. He was
not afraid of anyone. And He couldn’t bear
the mediocrity and this kind of balance: “Oh,
we have them also, we can have the devils
and also the Gods”. People argue: “Why
do You criticize them? They don’t criticize
You”. He said: “The devil, the Satan is
not going to speak against his own house”.
This is exactly what is happening today. I’ve
seen when I say that: “This man is a devil”,
people say: “Mother, why do you call him
a devil?” “Because he’s a devil, I have
to call him a devil. I’m your Mother.”
When I see a person suffering, he cannot get
his Realization because he went to this devil,
I have to say he’s a devil whether you like
it or not. If you are a true seeker you stand
up to that and see for yourself you are a
true seeker. And if you are a true seeker
you must find your Spirit and you must get
to your Realization.
I’m not here for any elections or pampering.
I’m here to give you your own, to have your
own Spirit, to enjoy your being. Even if the
whole world gets against Me, I’m not bothered
about it. I’m here of course to look after
you, to tell you in a proper way. But if it
comes to the devils I will be the One who
will stand against them, every minute. Whatever
may they come in, whatever guard, it’s very
easy to make them out once you get your Realization.
It’s very easy to find out. He Himself has
said it all these things. He said: “Don’t
judge anyone”. Before Realization you can’t
judge anyone, from the appearances. They look
very sweet, you know, or they talk very sweetly.
They come to you in a band, you see, and they
walk with such beautiful gait. They are great
dramatist, some of them play tricks, jump
like Krishna. Some say: “We are Incarnation
of Christ.”
There was a gentleman who said: “I’m the
Incarnation of Krishna”. I told him: “Why
do you make the ladies nude and naked? What
religion has taught you this, to make the
ladies nude and naked, take out their clothes
and make them dance? What is this?” “O,
he said, I’m Shri Krishna!” I said: “Really?
I never knew Shri Krishna did that.” He
said: “No, He did.” Once Krishna was a
small child of four years, you can imagine,
a naughty little thing. What did He understand
of nudity or that? Innocent. And the gopis,
you see, were having their bath in the river
Yamuna where Radha was putting Her feet, so
the water was all vibrated. And He climbed
up onto a tree and they had put their clothes
on a tree and He hid them. So they were asking
for His clothes: “Now what are you doing?
Why have you hidden?” It’s a mischief.
It’s the fun. But in that fun what He was
doing? Was to give them Realization because
He could see their Kundalini at the back.
[AS, AND] a child of four years... What does
a child of four years know about nudity, or
dress or anything? Innocent. Modern children
may be very precautious, but not in those
days. But when He was the king in Dwarika
– I asked this nonsensical fellow who says
he is the Bhagavanan, and the Shri Krishna
– I said when He was a grown up man and
a king in Dwarika, which is at least two thousand
miles away from Hastinapur Delhi, and a lady
called Draupadi, who called Him as a brother,
was troubled because she was pound and all
that, a big story of Mahabharata, you might
be knowing Draupadi, and a devil of a man
called Dhuriodhana said that: ” I’ll make
you nude”, tried to pull Her sari. It’s
a beautiful description of the whole thing.
He, He was worried that she will lose her
chastity by removing her..., this is called
as [SANSKRIT WORD]. So she put it in her mouth
like this and she was to call Krishna. She
says: “Kri”, and she was holding because
Krishna means “falls down”. And as soon
as she found that the sari is going, she said:
”shna”, and the description is so great:
“[SANSKRIT TALK]”. When she did that “shna”
it echoed in Dwarika where He was ruling.
He was the king there. And with shanka, chakra,
gada, padma, these are four weapons, one better
that the other. One is sufficient, the chakra,
I told you, all up on to on the Garuda, on
the condor He arrived there to save the chastity
of His sister. If He was fond of removing
the clothes of women, why did He all the way
come and save that? And this fellow didn’t
know how to answer Me. I told him: “One
day your clothes will be taken out like this”.
Within eight days it happened. Somebody took
out all his clothes and he was dancing on
the street and nowadays he’s backing America
with a paralysis. He couldn’t smell flowers.
One better that the other. But his disciples,
if you tell them: “O, don’t say, Mother.
We love him.”
This kind of a funny mesmerism it’s stupidity.
Awake yourself! This kind of emotional nonsensical
attachment to one person is not going to give
you Realization. You have to become your Spirit.
You have to be actually reborn. There is no
place for devilish people. If they are from
hell they will go back to that, but many of
their disciples are also walking through.
[WHILE, WHY] they are My children, I would
say? They are the children of God, they are
the men of God, as described as William Blake.
They have been born on this earth for seeking
because they know this is the time they are
going to achieve their Realization and these
horrible people have mesmerized them. At this
time should I go and garland them and say:
“You are very nice people”? If you expect
Me to do that, then you have not understood
Me at all. No use telling Me: “O, their
awareness is different.” I see that your
Kundalini is ruined, you are up to get a blood
cancer or some sort of a cancer or you are
going to get into the lunatic asylum. Something
horrible is going to happen to you and when
I see that am I to say “Yes” the one who
has done, go and fall at his feet? But if
there’s a real guru I would go and meet
him Myself. There are many, but they are hiding.
I sent one fellow to New York, he ran away
within two days, within two days. He said:
“O, these New York people are different”.
He said: “I have to take a circus with me.
They like a circus.” But Houston people
are different.
Now, so this was the great Incarnation of
Christ who came on this Earth, a very dynamic.
Those who say that: “I’m the Christ”,
there’s many, you see, self certified people:
“I’m the Christ”. Now the kind of a
Christ they do, He was never like that, He
was a healthy man and He was not one of these
people who’s these cheeks have gone inside,
who looks like a miserable, hungry, pitiable
man.
[MISSING RECORDING]
[THIS IS] of Holy Ghost, the Kundalini rises.
Is written down. There are thousand things
written and every word has to be tallied with
that person otherwise you just don’t believe.
Let them go and walk on the water, is not
far away from you, seventeen miles only, and
see how far they go. Is the best way to judge
these people. We have got a method to judge
these people. Thank God, we are born in modern
times when we are not [ILLITERATE], we have
had Christ, we have had so many people, we
can read and we can understand, we should
logically reach the position to understand
what do we have to expect from a Realized
Soul. If he talks like a politician who wants
to have votes, how can you believe that such
a person could be an Incarnation? An Incarnation
has not only to be a fearless person, but
has to be a holy person. Not the one who is
like a parasite living on other people. Like
these lamas [ARE]. They live like parasites
in Nepal and also in Lhasa [UNCLEAR] were
suffering. They had no food but these lamas
were living and taking their special Ambrose,
they call it, in golden cups. Today they are
driven out so they are on our head in India.
We have to support these nonsensical people
sitting down there as lamas, these parasites
of the worst type. And those who could not
get a place there are now moving about and
now they want to live on a marble flooring.
They can’t live on a carpet flooring. They
must have a marble flooring. And people have
to starve themselves to create a marble flooring
for these horrible parasites.
Why should a saint ask for anything? A saint
is a king. He’s above all these comforts
of life. He’s not bothered. I mean, if you
ask, I can sleep on the street, I’ve no
problem, no problem, because I’m above the
want, I’m above greed. I don’t know what
sort of a thing is temptation. If they call
themselves as Godly people, look at their
faces, worn out, biscuity, serious, nonsensical
people. They have no sense of humor of any
kind. Not only but I’ve seen some disciple
who came to Me, all their bone was broken,
all their back bone was broken, every bone
was broken by these people. They use to beat
them [THESE SADISTS]. They take money from
you and finish your Kundalini.
Their days have come now. Because they talk
well don’t believe them. What have they
given you? Somebody says: “They have given
us the knowledge”. All right, what knowledge?
What knowledge have they given you? Knowledge,
is all mental. What have you got it in your
awareness, where you have to evolve, when
you rise. Christ has described it so clearly,
I did not say what a Realized soul should
be. You become a witness, you become a witness
of the whole drama, of the whole show. And
this should happen to you. Not only, but you
are empowered with the powers of your Spirit.
At least your health should be all right.
People are suffering from stresses and strain,
having a headache all the time, jumping on
their sits and they say: “We get very positive
results”. What are positive results? These
make believes if you carry on with them you
will have no way of judging as to where you
are.
First of all get your Realization. Get to
your discretion power and realize that it
is you can judge them after Realization, not
before. Christ has said “right discretion”.
He has used the word: “right discretion”.
How do you get “right discretion” unless
and until you are realized? And this is not
to be self-certified. As Christ has said:
“You’ll be calling Me Christ, Christ.
I will not recognize you”. Meaning what?
Those who say: “We are Christians”, you
see, going about with the label: “We are
Christians, we go to church, sing our hymns
and come back home and quarrel, going to wars,
fight. We are the people who drink on a Christmas
day. On a Christmas day, we drink!”
Now, when Christ said that, they said at the
time of Christ, He went to a wedding and He
blessed the wine. Is not true. That wine,
at that time never meant, even in India today,
wine never means an alcohol. But Moses has
talked about it very clearly and Abraham has
talked about it because they had to deal with
this wine which I told you, the Primordial
Masters, they had to deal with the liver,
so they talked about it, they called it the
“strong drink” and “fermented drink”,
so clearly. But everything happens if somebody
dies, you must have champagne to celebrate
his death perhaps. If Christ is born we must
have champagne. If Christ is born that is
the day we should dedicate ourselves to our
Spirit, not to get out of your awareness.
Anyone of these fermented things take you
away from your attention. Your attention is
in a way empathized. I don’t say: “You
don’t drink!” at this stage but after
Realization you will not. You will not, even
if you want to. You will not drink, because
you get drunk. Like Me, if I go to a party,
you see, they will always say: “Please,
have something. O, You must have, please.
You have not tested this. You better have”.
I said: “No, sir, I’m sorry, I’m over
drunk already. If I drink more, I don’t
know what will happen to Me”. I mean you
can’t tell them: “You don’t drink”.
You see, that would be absolutely [UNLIARLY]
to tell them: “Please, don’t drink today”.
But they’ll go on forcing you and if you
say anything against it then absolutely you
are no eliteness about you. You are absolutely
unsophisticated.
This is the thing in this world. Virtue has
no meaning. If you are virtuous, you better
hide yourself. Not in Sahaja Yoga. You enjoy
your virtues in Sahaja Yoga. You really enjoy
yours and others virtues. Is a very different
thing as in the unity church you call it,
a New Age is coming, is absolutely true. I
find, as I told you the principles of this
church are very, very close to that which
is the stage on to which you have to jump.
And that’s why the right conclusion that
is reached is absolutely the way to understand
where you have to reach logically. But you
must know, you have to take a stand. You cannot
be a person who’s apologetic. There is no
place for apologies. If you are a realized
soul, you are a realized soul. You are not
dominating it by that to anyone. You are not
dominating. By that you accept your situation
with glory and with pride. But I’ve seen
many Sahaja Yogis also feel shy to accept
that they are realized. They understand what’s
happening. They are giggling, they are laughing
at the way people are, but they find it impossible
to talk to them about their Realization, that
other should get their Realization. You have
to take a stand in your family, in your surroundings,
with your friends and you have to tell them
that: “You better all get realized”. The
reason for that is that the Christ who crucified
Himself, He is going to come back, with his
eleven forces of destruction. And then He’s
not going to tell you anything, not going
to ask you to take any Realization, nor He
is bothered whether you go to hell. He will
just sort out.
But those who have got Realization will enter
into the Kingdom of God. You have to enter
into the Kingdom of God. Here, as I say, is
the seventh chakra. I told you about the sixth
chakra, which is adorned by Jesus Christ and
the mantra of the (seventh chakra), sixth
chakra is our Lord’s Prayer. That’s the
way you can solve both the things. But the
bija mantra is Ham Ksham. Ham Ksham. It means
that when you are infested with negativity,
with depression, with the attack of the superego,
as shown here, then you have to say: “I
am, I’m going to fight you”. If you go
to a guru who makes you a negative person,
who makes you feel very shy, who says: “You
are all the ego and you are good for nothing,
you must pay me more and pay me more”. And
you all the time say that: “Oh, must be
something wrong with me, nothing wrong with
this man”. If there is self-pity and also
there is guilt, then you have to say: “I
am not guilty”. Then you have to say that:
“I’m my own guru”, if you have left
side problems. But if you have right side
problems, then you have to say: “I forgive,
Ham Ksham”. These are the bija mantras of
this two, which you have got, your symbol
is of these two wings, is actually the Agya
chakra.
It is just like that. Agya chakra is just
like that. But they call it the, what Egyptian,
what... no, is not that. You see, this symbol
has come to you from unconscious, is the Agya
chakra, is this center. Egyptians didn’t
know much about God, I must tell you. Of course
pyramid is, pyramid is, pyramid is all vibrated.
But the way they were so much worried about
their dead is horrifying. Imagine these bones
buried in the one box of gold, then one box
of silver, then one box of this and all the
ornaments kept with the dead. The dead is
finished into bones, the ornaments are there.
I’ve seen that in Egypt. Mad people, I must
say. It’s Sadat who would have brought it
round. But lets see something new will happen
there, in that country.
Traditional countries have wisdom, inbuilt
wisdom and they go on improving because they
have tried all these methods and they know
[WHERE TO GO]. He didn’t talk of death.
They know it from the people, pharaohs and
all that who had all these kinds of a funny
mummies going round and keeping the dead in
a silver box and as if the dead knows where
is the silver. Christ has said many things,
which we do not pay attention to. [NONE, ONE]
of them is about the dead. In every church,
I was happy to know that in this church there
is no cemetery. You walk into a cemetery if
you want to go to a church. A lady who came
from India, she said: “Everything seems
to be upside down in England”. I said: “What?”
She said: “I went to see a church. And all
the dead were laid there under my feet. And
I was holding my sari walking like this. I
was thinking I was going to step. And the
lady with me said: ‘What, you should walk
straight‘. She said: ‘How can I, you see?
These are dead here. It’s like a cemetery.”
And she was walking carefully because they
must be respected.
You take your children to those churches.
I mean I don’t know, you don’t understand
that God has talked about spirits in so clear
ways. Of course, maybe it’s not so much
in the Bible, maybe, but He showed that He
took out the spirits, He talked of spirits
of so many people, and put them in the pigs
and put them in the sea. All this is so clearly
given, still, just see the Christian nations.
Today’s newspaper, was there one free newspaper,
witchcraft, devils [TEN], devils angels, this
guru, that guru, psychic, ESP, all kinds of
spirits. Imagine! I mean in Indian picture
you won’t even find one advertisement like
that. Maybe some of the gurus might try, but
in India people know who is real and who is
not. Most of them know.
While here I find all kinds of things, which
are negative, which have something to do with
the spirits we are doing. It is against Christ.
Why should we bother ourselves about the spirits?
Let them alone. Like somebody’s father is
haunting, somebody’s mother is haunting.
Now, there’ve been so much for you! Now
forget them. Let them be born again to get
their Realization. Then you call somebody’s
spirit here, somebody’s spirit from dead.
Some spiritualist goes into a funny gesture
and you start believing that and asking about
your future and this and that. Is all very
superfluous and absolutely silly against your
Spirit. I’ve told you yesterday, those people
who indulge into these, for seven generations
they suffer, seven generations. I’m telling
you from My experience. And those who go to
them also suffer. Even the countries where
this is practiced too much. If a child is
born there, I know of a lady whose child was
born in a country like that, and he had this
Agya protruding just like this. And when he
saw Me, he started screaming and shouting,
he couldn’t bear Me. And today he’s a
different child, I saw. He’s a French child,
he’s a very different child. Absolutely.
But he was so much and so many spirits in
him, you can’t imagine. And she told Me
that she, she had a nurse who was form that
country and perhaps she has done something
to him.
So the source of this is already unlimited.
You don’t have to pay for it. You stand
outside and you can get anyone of them. It’s
very easy to catch on them, very easy. For
example, somebody asked Me: “How do you
catch a spirit?” I said: “Very simple.
You put a light before you, of course you
don’t try on that stick, and make a whole
in a black paper, little hole. And through
that hole you see the spirit. You see that
light and you’ll get a spirit into you.
You get any name, which is commonly used and
go on and chanting that name, you’ll get
into a spirit. You start saying any absurd
thing in the presence of God, in the presence
of the picture of God or of Christ, you insult
or do anything you get into it. It is the
easiest thing to get a spirit in you. You
start jumping too much, you get it, you start
saying: “Hooo”. You get it. You do any
funny thing, you get them. They are all around.
They are busy bodies. They want to use you
for their purpose. They are very easy available.
Why do you pay for them? Will you pay such
a lot of amount just to get one of them on
top of you? You
have to be your master, I told you. You have
to be in the way Christ was. It’s only He
has the power to raise the Kundalini of people
like that, as you do now.
He was created in that immaculate way in which
you have been given Realization, in the same
immaculate manner. So have your self-esteem.
You are not going to become slave of these
horrible useless sly aggressive people, who
are hanging around just to trouble you because
their ambitions are not fulfilled or they
are sly or they are sadists, or they are masochists
and all that kind of thing. You are seekers,
of high quality. Rise up to your Self. This
is the message of Christ to you, because He
resurrected Himself. Did you dance or did
you say Hu hu, haa? Even He was tempted by
Satan. And invited the Satan arrive there,
and invited. Nobody asked him to be there.
He has fasted for you, so you don’t fast.
If you fast, you’ll get a fasting spirit
in you. If you overdo your Hatha yoga you’ll
get a spirit, which will do much more Hatha
yoga till your ribs break out. Yeah. They
take you to extremes, you see. You see those
mad people running, jogging on the road. They
will get it very soon. I am worried about
them. You see, all these extra things, there
is no need to do. Today we saw one of the
circus or some sort of thing that was there,
they were three people from somewhere, I think
from Spain and [ALL THAT]. And the Vishuddhi
was so badly catching in them. Poor things
were putting all the pressure, going like
this, going like that. And they said they
are statues, whatever it is. I said, I had
simple pity for them. I said: “What are
they up to?” I mean, you can have real statues
like that. But why make human beings behave
so funny, so extra energy consumers? Why?
Why? You are human beings, you are delicate
things. Why do you want to stand on your heads?
Why do you want to do something that you are
not supposed to do? You have to stay in the
central path, in a sensible way, in a very
normal way, to get your Realization. We’ll
not do anything that is extreme. Always avoid
extremes.
But you tell something to someone. Is impossible.
Human beings must start doing it. You give
him a cycle, till he breaks his head, he will
not give up his cycle. You give them the skates,
till he completely is in an accident, he won’t
give up his skates. It’s impossible to deal
with them. To be in the centre is the easiest
thing. Just to be in the center, in the balance.
Before going to the Sahasrara, I want to tell
you about the balancing, because tomorrow
I’m going to tell you how the diseases are
caused. So the balance is... Because if you
use anyone of these powers, for the first
power is of superego, through which we run
away from places, we avoid, we are frightened,
we have fears. The another is of aggression,
right hand side, is the ego.
Anyone of them if you use too much, the other
one gets frozen. For example, a person who
thinks too much and plans too much and thinks
that he is responsible for the whole world
of affairs, you see, and he is doing all the
work, while he doesn’t do anything, God
does everything. In the myth that he is, develops
his ego to a great extent by which his left
side suffers too much. And then, first thing
he develops is all the problems of the left
side in the organ. First of all, the poor
Swadhishthana cannot look after the liver
so he develops a liver, then on the left hand
side it is absolutely useless, so he develops
diabetes. Diabetes is not caused by sugar
by any chance, I can tell you. Of course,
you should not take too much sugar, also.
I mean, too much of everything is wrong. But
you must take sugar. Is important for your
liver to have your sugar diet. But it’s
the idea in the head that if you take sugar
you get diabetes. Not at all. It is caused
by over thinking. Absolutely. Not by sugar.
In an Indian village, a farmer takes at least
every day half a kilo of sugar, for your information.
And they do not know what diabetes is because
he doesn’t think. He just does.
If you want to solve your problem of diabetes,
you have to develop your thoughtless awareness,
which you get when Christ is awakened within
you. He thinks for you. You don’t have to
think. You just be in that silence, that bliss.
And then Swadhishthana can look after the
other side. Diabetes is absolutely curable
through Sahaja Yoga. Then people who suffer
from the troubles of the spleen, like anemia
and all those things. But the worst of all
is the blood cancer. Blood cancer is the worst
thing you suffer from spleen. Now, how it
is caused? A person who’s very busy, you
see, is big man, he has no time. So he gets
out of his bed, puts on his trousers and he
is there for the breakfast, standing he’s
eating something. All right. Poor this spleen
is trying to cooperate that emergency, is
trying to give some blood. Suddenly he jumps
into his car, he’s driving, he goes and
meets other who are on the way, have jammed
this way, so he’s cursing them, doing all
kind of things. He is very speedy, you see.
He must go and he can’t bear that jam. This
speediness comes to you because this spleen
becomes mad. It becomes crazy. It doesn’t
know how to cope with the man like that. He
has no time to sit down and eat.
Formerly, in India, the husband, of course
our system is rather different, which the
American women won’t like, but we have been
very successful with our methods, you see.
It’s a trick I will tell you. The women
must know cooking in India. They might be
the richest of rich. They must know cooking.
They know very good cooking, excellent. You
know, you approach your man through his stomach,
always is true. Hundred percent. And then
they make the husband sit down comfortably.
In India, we sit on, I mean we have a kind
of a – what you call a [HINDI WORD], we
can say a stool which is very low and the
husband sits there and another stool in front
of him. And she sits there with a fan, you
see, she’s fanning him. The rhythm of the
food is with the fan. And she serves him and
she looks after him, and she talks to him
very sweetly at that time when he eats his
food. That’s the sign of a Gruha Lakshmi,
of the, of the, what is, the Goddess of the
family. She’s very kind to him, then he
likes those relaxed moments. She feeds him.
Then he gets up and dresses up and goes to
his work. This kind of peace we should give
to our husbands, if you have to control them.
You have not to compete with them always they
are like children, I tell you. They are so
sweet. Somebody told Me: “Mother, you must
go and describe your self esteem, Mother of
women”. I said: “What?” “Yes, there
are many women who are expecting their Mother
Goddess to come.” I said: “But I’m sorry,
I’m Mother of men as well as of women. For
Me both of them are just the same, two chariot’s,
the two wheels of a chariot. One is on the
left, another in the right”.
Is great thing to be a woman, I must say.
Like this Mother Earth, she bears us because
she’s so powerful. If you are a powerful
person you can bear it up. For example, husband
has to get angry with you sometimes. If he
gets angry with somebody in the office, he
loses his job, he’ll be fired. But if he
sometimes gets angry with you, it’s all
right. Doesn’t matter. It’s just fun.
But a woman has to be that playful, that cheerful
and that understanding should be in a woman.
What is there to compete with them? You are
the power, the potential. You have to give
that power of love to your husbands. In Sahaja
yoga we have changed the entire system of
society, also. It’s such a beautiful relationship
between husband and wife, such a beautiful
one among children and parents and.... It’s
so beautiful, you can’t imagine.
That age has to come. We are not to fight
for any rights, we have every rights. A woman
has every right within herself. She doesn’t
know how to handle it. And they have gone
crazy. They don’t know what to do with these
men. It’s very easy to handle them. You
have to learn the art of expressing your love.
That’s the thing we lack. We should come
from your heart to understand that we can’t
live without each other. This will stop many
things that are going wrong in this country
and the injustice we are doing to the children
who are born to us.
Now this is I am saying because Christ has
blessed marriage. Those who believe in nunneries
and all that are really nonsensical. And the
nuns getting married to this innocence? I
mean, how can innocence marry? This is the
worst thing you can do to Christ is to say
that: “This nun is married to Christ”.
I just can’t bear the idea. Is absurd, is
an insult of innocence. And this is what it
is, we should understand, that marriage is
blessed by Him. Is a sacred thing. We should
not make a mess out of it. Is so pure. Is
very beautiful. You enjoy each other in company,
also in separation you do enjoy. If you know
how to be sweet to each other, is so beautiful.
It’s very beautiful. These traditions will
come back as soon as you become the Spirit.
I’m sure of it.
Now, so we come, I told you about the imbalances
to a great extend, but later on tomorrow also
I‘m going to tell you because Sahaja Yogis
have to look after their imbalances to keep
their health all right and to look after the
health of other people also.
Now about the tenth chakra, the last chakra
as called the seventh chakra, seventh chakra,
which is very important. This chakra has got
all these seven centers in it. It is placed
in the brain. The brain, if you have a transverse
section of that, you can see it looks like
a lotus leaves. It is said there are one thousand
nerves, or one thousand centers or plexuses
for this particular center called as Sahasrara.
Sahasrara means one thousand petals. And these
petals are shown there. Of course they are
not one thousand there, but they look like
living flames of different colors. “I will
appear before you like tongues of flames.”
It’s said. Even the other centers look like
tongues of flames, you see, the flames were
enlighten. But the living flames are very
silent. They are placed as a lotus and as
the Kundalini comes up She pushes this lotus
out and you touch the seat of the Spirit,
which is on top of your head and you enter
into the super consciousness.
Not into the collective subconscious or not
into the collective supraconscious, but into
the super consciousness, where you become
the master, you become the Spirit. And you
start feeling the All Pervading Power around
you. And through your fontanel bone area you
feel the cool breeze, you actually feel it.
It’s an actualization. It is not just that
I baptized you, you are being baptized, it
is not possible. On the contrary, I’ve seen
some people who touch the fontanel bone area
of the children introduce spirits. Yes. It
should be done only by a Realized soul and
not by every Dick, Tom and Harry. Is a very
dangerous thing.
Now, this Sahasrara has got all the seven
centers, the seats of all the seven centers
are there. Start from here is the Agya chakra.
Here is the Vishuddhi. Then here is the Heart.
Now see, it’s so simple. Heart. If it is
not heart felt, if you have not felt it from
your heart... Because some people come from
other gurus, I’ve seen them. They sit here
just to mock and laugh at it and make fun
of it. They never get Realization. If your
heart is caught up with your ego, also is
difficult. If your heart is weak, maybe any
problem with the heart, it can be anything,
I mean, so the Realization here stops. Heart
has to be strong, you have to have a heart
felt desire. That’s the center here of the
heart. So I told you this is the center here
of the Agya chakra, Vishuddhi chakra. This
is the center is the, is the, we can say,
a [SATELLITE, SUBTLE OF IT], of the Agya chakra
between the two, because here these two also
come out a little bit, the Ha Tha, both of
them come out here, down below. It’s Hamsa.
But main chakra is this Agya and then there
is the center of Vishuddhi, then here is the
center of Heart.
Now, behind here, is the center of Mooladhara,
here, just in the center. For example today
I met a lady who told Me she’s loosing her
eyesight. It could be due to two things only.
It could be due to diabetes or it could be
due to some possession you can lose you eyesight.
Now, if it is in the center, it is a possession.
But diabetes is caused by the Swadhishthana
chakra around it. So even if it is due to
diabetes it can constrict the optic globe
by which you can have problem on your eyesight.
Your eyes will be open, but suddenly you can’t
see anything. This is absolutely curable,
absolutely curable. Spirits, they get to it.
How much we have to be careful about spirits
that you will realize very soon, as soon as
you will take to Sahaja yoga.
So the center here of the Agya is caught up
and when it is caught up it just makes the
optic globe ineffective and you can’t see.
Your eyes are open, you can’t see. And when
this diabetes is setting this center around
which is the Swadhishthana chakra, gets affected.
Vishuddhi chakra is here, is here. I mean
Nabhi chakra, is here. This is Nabhi chakra,
which has got left and right. So all these
centers are in
the brain, so the essence of Sahasrara is
integration, unity, complete integration.
You cannot integrate nonsensical things together.
Integration is only possible of the people
who are of the same style, or of the Deities
who stand for God.
You cannot have satanic people and Godly people
integrated, can you? You cannot unite these
people. You try it and you’ll have problem.
That’s the best way you see the destruction
of every unity. So in Sanskrit is a very good,
good word got for integration, Samagra, beautiful
word which means, Agra is the, Agra is the
hole in the needle, and when a thread passes
through this needles, it passes through the
Agra, so it is Samagra. And this integration
has to take place as soon as you cross over.
And because of this you get your Realization
and you feel all the chakras are enlightened.
Unless and until you pass through this fontanel
area you cannot feel the All Pervading Power.
With awakening only, with the awakening of
the Kundalini, you can give Realization even
to people, you may think, but it won’t stay
there. But, of course, you can cure people,
all right. But with Realization, if you establish
yourself, which I’ll tell you how to do
it tomorrow, then you can give Realizations
to others, you can manifest all your powers,
even you can control the element, for your
information. Yes, after some time.
We have some people in India. There’s an
ordinary fisherman, again a fisherman, he
is educated, he’s a graduated, but he’s
a fisherman. His name is Harish Chandra. He’s
a Realized soul. He got his Realization. He
said: “Mother, I never knew you have given
me so many powers.” I said: “Really? What
happened?” He said: “I was going to a
village across to another island and the whole
area was covered with clouds in such a way
that a tempest was expected, absolutely, horrible.
And people said: ’Don’t go out’”.
He said: “I was so much frustrated, I just
stood up there and I said: ‘Now see, I’m
going for God’s work. And will you, please,
behave yourself till I come back?’”. And
he said: “The clouds were removed. Went
there and came back, when I reached my home
in the night, that time it started raining”
and there were 25 people other fishermen with
him. In India the work is taking up a big
form, among the villagers, among the people
who are simple. You do not lack behind. Though
they are simple people, they are good people.
You are the leaders, you are great saints,
you have been seeking for ages and now the
time has come for you to get it. So do not
miss it.
For anybody’s sake, do not plead for any
gurus or anyone. You just plead for yourself.
You have paid them, finish it off. Done your
duty. It was a mistake. Forget it. Get your
Realization. Get to your Spirit. The Sahasrara
is opened out, is opened out because of this
Sahaja yoga has become a mass movement now.
Thousands can get Realization. Thousands.
They have been thousand people, six thousand
people, as he says this, that’s true. It
is true. It is true. It has happened. It’s
so miraculous. But you are miraculous you
are great. Just to find out yourself, what
a great instrument you are. You’ll be amazed
what things you can do.
I can write a chapter like a book on Sahasrara,
because that’s My place. I know it so well.
But today I think that is sufficient and later
on I hope you might be able to get the books
on this, maybe tomorrow, and then you might
be able to read about it. But first get your
Realization, because without Realization if
you read you’ll again become a scholar good
for nothing. That’s why we don’t sell
our books to people who are not realized.
We just don’t, because they become scholars,
you see. They start writing another book.
I mean people are so funny. What’s the use?
Christ has said: “Now, if you want gold,
all right, have it, but be zealous. I eat
with those who enter into the Kingdom of God”.
Take to the Kingdom of God and do not worry
about your intellectual feeds. You’ve had
enough of it. Take to it.
May God bless you all.
Now today, if you have some questions, you
may ask but I think we should go in [UNCLEAR]
experience, but if you have questions and
if you are not representing any guru, then
please ask. I don’t want to talking, answering
[IN CONTROVERSY, QUESTIONS ABOUT]…. I’ve
already told you about them and I do not want
to hear anything about these horrible people.
You know, yesterday somebody argued about
Yogananda. And this lady [UNCLEAR]: “O God,
it’s feeling hot. The certificate is there.”
All right, if you have to ask questions, do
not be aggressive and just get your Realization.
That’s the main thing you should have.
Question: I’d like to know if Mother is
a vegetarian.
Shri Mataji: No, not at all. So, supposing
I was Kali once upon a time, I had to drink
the blood of these horrible devils. How could
I be a vegetarian? Krishna was not a vegetarian,
Rama was not a vegetarian. Don’t become
vegetarians, I cannot save chickens and I
cannot give them Realization. That doesn’t
mean that you all the time eat meat, meat,
meat. Also doesn’t mean all the time think
of food. You see, I’m not bothered what
I eat. If you ask Me what I ate in the morning,
I don’t know. There’s no fuss about food.
I’m not a vegetarian. How could I be? Hindu
Indians know that, that Mother can’t be
a vegetarian. Krishna could not be because
He had to kill so many people. And you should
not be. By becoming vegetarian you won’t
reach to God, I can tell you. On the contrary,
you catch on the left Nabhi if you become
these horrible vegetarians like the Jains
we have in India. Jains, have you heard about
them, Jains? They try to save even the mosquitoes
and
the bugs. Now, I can’t do, I can’t do
anything about mosquitoes and bugs. [I MEAN
IT HAS GONE, AND WE CAN GO] to that absurd,
you [KNOW, SAW]?
Those who talked about it, you read in the
book, where Buddha and Mahavira, they couldn’t
bear the way people were stupid. So they were
born again as Hassan and Hussein, the grandchildren
of Mohammad Saab and they fought in Karbala
to show that when it comes to fighting you
have
to fight. So, onward Christian soldiers.
Question: Mother [UNCLEAR] when you give somebody
a blessing, or when You say: “I am [UNCLEAR],
I am [LOVE, NARADA], what do you come to [UNCLEAR]
on you.
Shri Mataji: I don’t say that, did I? [MISSING
FROM RECORDED SPEECH]