Today we have such a great opportunity to
celebrate the birth of Christ.
He was born in a manger.
All these things are already pre-planned.
That He should be born in a manger in difficult
situations, to show that whether you are born
poor or rich, whether you are born in difficulties
or in problems, if you have Divinity within
you it shines by itself.
As the Christianity took a very wrong deviated
line, they have never been able to understand
the significance of Christ.
To them immaculate conception is absolutely
not possible.
Most of the people think that it's some sort
of a mythical story.
But in India we do believe that Gauri created
Shri Ganesha out of Her own vibrations and
that He became the Deity of Mooladhara.
We accept it.
But not in the West.
They will never accept such a thing because
their mental side is over-developed and dominates
them.
Maybe they are not so very old like Indians
to understand that above all He is God.
Even the concept of God is quite mental.
Moreover, the way Christianity has been, it
has not provided any proper guidance.
On the contrary wherever they have failed
they said: "It's a mystery."
But it's very simple to understand for Indians,
that anything is possible for God.
After all He is God.
He is God Almighty.
Because of this mental attitude which is much
lower than the knowledge of your spirit, the
ordinary, mundane type of the superficial
knowledge can never allow the personality
to accept the greatness of God.
I had a grandma.
She was My father's aunt and she used to tell
us a nice story about somebody who was going
to meet God.
Of course this - in India everybody understands
all these things.
They will not say: "How he is going to meet
God?" but they accept.
All right, he is going to meet God.
So when he was going on the way, on the road,
he found one gentleman sitting there nicely
singing songs, bhajans of God, doing nothing
on the roadside.
So he said: "Oh, so you are going to meet
God?"
"Yes, I am going to meet Him.
So have you any message for Him?"
"Yes, please tell Him that I'm all right,
but He should arrange for my food, because
I think the food is now finishing."
He said: "Really, that's what you want me
to tell Him?"
"Yes, yes, please tell Him.
Oh, of course He'll arrange, but please tell
Him."
So he went ahead and he met another gentleman
who was standing on his head, or in a Christian
way I would say he was going to church every
day with nice suits, and singing hymns every
day, listening to the pastor's sermons, or
whatever you may say; and in the Indian way
we can say he was going to the temple every
day, standing on his head, doing all kinds
of yoga asanas and everything.
And he asked him: "Please go and ask God - I've
tried everything.
When is He going to meet me?
I would like to see Him.
I would like to have His darshan."
He said: "All right."
So he went to God, and whatever work he had
he finished with it, and then God asked him:
"Have you got anything to tell Me?"
He said: "Nothing much, but I met one gentleman
while coming and he said that 'I'm doing all
kinds of things, I have tried everything,
and when will God meet me?
I am standing on my head, and I am doing also
all kinds of yoga asanas, and all kinds of
things, and also I am going to church and
mosque, I am praying, doing all sorts of prayers,
but when will God meet me?'"
So God said: "Tell him he has to do a little
more.
See, it's not easy.
When Sahaja Yoga will come we'll see!"
So then even he said: "And there is another
one who was on the road, You see.
As he was just enjoying himself singing songs,
he suddenly saw me, and he told me: 'You see,
my food is now finishing, ask God to arrange
it for me.'"
He said: "Really, is the food just finishing?"
Immediately God said: "What are you doing,
why don't you go and look after him?
His food is finishing."
"No, no, Sir, we yesterday only, we arranged
it, all that."
He said: "All right, all right, doesn't matter."
You see, he couldn't understand, you know,
that this fellow who is trying all these things
and God is still saying that he has to wait.
And while this fellow is just singing songs
of God and all that, and why is it so much
impressed by this another fellow who is doing
nothing to seek God?
So then God realized that he is in some sort
of an illusion.
So He told him: "All right, you go and tell
them one thing.
To both of them the same thing, that 'When
I went to God what I saw there was that He
made a camel pass through the eye of a needle.'"
So he said: "Really, I should tell them?"
"Yes, yes, you just tell them, and see the
reaction."
So he went down.
So this is, the first one met him, he said:
"What God has said?"
He said that God has said: "Wait till Sahaja
Yoga comes in, then I'll meet you.
Before that you'll go around like this."
"Oh God, when will this Sahaja Yoga come?"
And he said: "So, but He'll meet me sometime.
I hope Sahaja Yoga also comes some time."
And he was quite disappointed.
So he went.
And he asked him that: "What did you see with,
there when you went to see God?"
He said: "I saw that, you know, He passed
a camel through the eye of an, of a needle."
He said: "What?
How is it possible?
It's impossible!"
(Now mental.)
"How is it possible, that a camel gets passed
through the eye, it's not possible, see the
volume of this one and such a little thing.
How can he pass?
No, no, no, no you are just telling me a story
because you have been to God, you are trying
to show off, that's all.
I, I don't believe in all this nonsense.
It's.. you are just telling me lies, and don't
try to befool me."
So he went to another person who was on the
street eating nicely.
He said: "How are you?"
"I know He had arranged before you reached
there, I know it was all right after all.
You see He looks after me all the time.
So what did you see when you went there?"
He said: "I saw that God Almighty passed a
camel through an eye of a needle.
It's a very amazing thing."
He said: "What, amazing?
He is God, do you know He is God?
Do you know He is God?
God can do anything.
He can do anything!"
That's made him understand, that if you understand
that God is all-powerful, all-powerful, it
doesn't mean that He can move Himalayas to
Maharashtra.
It doesn't mean that!
But it means He is all powerful.
Means He can do subtlest and subtlest thing,
and such things which our brain, this mental
side cannot understand.
It's beyond the conception of a human mind.
This is what God is.
He's the One who has created human beings.
He has to be beyond us if He is creating.
If a potter creates a pot that means he is
beyond the pot.
Pot cannot create God.. the potter.
And the potter has created the pot, so that
means that this pot which is created by him
has to be something which is made by him,
so he has to be much more powerful than the
pot is.
But it is unbelievable, or say beyond the
conception of human beings, that what a God
it must be Who has made this great computer.
We take everything for granted.
We cannot even make a particle of clay ourself.
We cannot make anything, human beings cannot
make.
Ha, if there is some stone, all right you
can put this up.
If there is some clay you can make some sort
of a house out of it.
That's all dead from the dead.
But can you make a candle which will burn
badhas?
You have seen it with your own eyes that before
My photograph the badhas burn.
Can you do that?
Now you, we have no, also the idea of the
complete, intricate working, delicate machinery,
and also very dynamic explosive machinery,
how it works to create human beings, to create
all this universe, to create all these beautiful
flowers and trees and everything.
Look at the stars.
Look at how many they are.
Out of that He has chosen this Mother Earth
to create human beings.
How He has made it?
When He wants to send His own Son, He can
send it the way He wants to send it.
Even to challenge this shows the mental mind
which is in, absolutely in mud.
So to accept it is only possible when you
have saints, real saints who tell you, that
this is how Shri Ganesha was born out of Gauri.
But to jump into it, into faith, when you
come to Sahaja Yoga you start seeing miracles
taking place.
Then you can understand that these miracles
are taking place and if there is another miracle
that has to take place it will take place
in any case.
We are not doing anything, it is all done.
And we don't doubt it.
Once you doubt you become again the same human
being which is just embedded in the mud.
I always say that you are like lotuses now
opened out.
You are not flying in the air.
Your roots are down there.
But you are now lotuses, and that's what is
on top of the lotus, this Mahalakshmi principle
is born.
Mahalakshmi principle is the One which came
on this earth as Sitaji, as Radha and also
as Mary, as Mother Mary.
It's said that Mahalakshmi is born out of
the sea.
What is the meaning of "Mary"?
Maria means, you know, Mare means "the sea".
She was born out of the sea.
So She being a Mahalakshmi Herself, She could
create a child.
What's the harm?
She could do anything, and this is the thing
you have to rise above.
Christians have to rise above this Christianity,
and has to understand that it's such a great
thing that was Christ Who came on this earth,
Who was the Incarnation of the principle of
Ganesha.
Ganesha becoming Mahavishnu is a very big
thing which one should try to understand.
Ganesha is the Son of Shiva.
Shri Ganesha is the One Who was first created
before creating anything, any atmosphere,
anything, because He is the Omkara, and the
Omkara is the first breaking of Adi Shakti
from Shiva.
That sound, "Tan-kar", as they call it.
From there started Omkara and He is the One
Who is the embodiment of that Omkara.
So this sound is Shri Ganesh, is His power,
was created first foremost thing, just to
create holiness [SOUNDS LIKE povitrada].
When this holiness was created, this [povitrada]
was created, then everything was created in
the sea of that holiness.
And then He incarnated as Christ, but as Mahavishnu,
not as Shiva's Son, but as Mahavishnu.
And who is Vishnu?
Is an uncle of Shri Ganesh.
His Mother's brother is Shri Vishnu.
So He was brought up, we should say, by Mahavishnu,
we can say, but Mahalakshmi adopted the principle
of Shri Ganesh.
In the Kundalini chart you can see that the
Shri Ganesha is connected on the left hand
side to the Ida Nadi, and the Kundalini is
above that.
So now what has happened is this, that He
transcended that part, and if He had to come
for the redemption, He had to come as the
Son of Mahalakshmi.
So it was Mahalakshmi who adopted Him, or
we should say really, conceived Him within
Himself as Christ, and He became Mahavishnu.
Anything is possible in the family of Gods
and Goddesses, because they are Gods.
It is beyond human mind to understand how
these things are working out in that realm.
Very difficult.
But now you have got Realization you can feel
in the cool breeze, so many new things are
happening to you.
So now believe Me, that there is no unholy
alliances among the Gods and Goddesses, no
unholy alliances.
There is nothing that is human in them.
They're all divine, pure people.
Once you understand this point then you will
understand why Shri Ganesha had to accept
to be a Son of Mahalakshmi, was born to Him
as Christ.
Because He had to come on Agnya, and for the
redemption as Ganesha, He doesn't do the redemption
part, because at that stage He is for the
innocence, for the holiness, for the wisdom
or also for destroying the negativity.
But He had to come up, only He, only Ganesha
could be brought to this very constricted
chakra, Agnya chakra.
Now why is it constricted?
It's quite a scientific thing which I would
not like to discuss today.
But it had to be constricted and it goes on
getting more constricted, this Agnya chakra,
the more, the more we think, the more we go
into the left or right, it goes on really
becoming like this, absolutely like this.
So in this very subtle area only Christ could
be subtle, because He's the subtlest of subtle.
He's even subtler than an atom, because in
the atom those vibrations which move asymmetric
and symmetric movements are subtler than the
atom.
And this is the subtler of that also.
So in that little very constricted area, only
a personality like Christ, which is nothing
but purity.
There is no other element in Him but purity.
All other Incarnations have all the five elements
in it.
He has nothing.
He is nothing but pure vibrations.
That's why He could walk on the water, because
there was no mass in His body, no matter in
His body.
No matter.
No element, except for Chaitanya itself.
Omkara becoming Ganesha in the mud, or the
what you can say, the thing that came out
of Her body.
Only the Chaitanya.
So at Ganesha's stage we can say that the
Chaitanya was kept in that form, but in the
state of Christ it was not there.
But the whole drama was played later on, of
His death and resurrection, because He is
the One who is responsible for our resurrection,
because He is the Gate.
He's the Path because He's Shri Ganesh.
Omkara is the Path, and He's the Gate, but
He is not the destination.
His Mother is the destination.
Even Mahalakshmi is not the Destination.
Even Mahakali, Mahasaraswati.
It's the Adi Shakti is the destination where
you have to reach.
All these things were never told in the Bible,
because He could hardly live for four years
with public life.
Nor did they want to tell about it because
they did not know, also there was a definite
suppression of all Divine things, for these
people are all commercialized institutions,
as we have also in India all kinds of commercial
institutions.
But the only advantage in India is that religion
is not organized.
Thank God for that!
But they organized it, they organized Christ,
they organized all His principles, everything,
and now they think He was a good human being.
What a certificate to give Him!
So today we are here to celebrate the birth
of Omkara.
It's a very big thing.
I don't know if you can realize it, what it
is, which moves into everything, whether it
is [SOUNDS LIKE anu, paramanu], is the atom,
molecules, into all the organizing of chemicals
and also the periodic laws, and also in the
gravity, into every thing that moves is this
Omkara, and your vibrations are nothing but
Omkaras.
Actually, in My photograph the vibrations
have come as Omkaras.
On the head of the people there is Omkara
written.
How is it happening, these lights look like
Omkara?
How is it on top of the heads of the Sahaja
Yogis, there's all the Sahaja Yogis' heads,
there is Omkara? - or Allah in Arabic language
- My name also, in Arabic.
Who is doing this?
It is He who is doing all this.
So Omkara itself takes a form to do things
to convince you of Adi Shakti.
He's the One who is handling all these powers.
He doesn't enter into the photograph, no,
He does not, but He plays a trick.
After all you see, if you go into details,
how do you get a photograph?
Through the light.
The light passes straight, a straight line.
But if He wants He can make the light pass
another way round.
He can just transform the light into something
else.
He can do whatever He likes.
And that's what He does to convince you.
And He said that: "Anything against Me I'll
tolerate, but nothing against the Holy Ghost."
And this Holy Ghost is the Adi Shakti.
Without Him you cannot go to the Sahasrara.
So that in the whole play He is like the [SOUNDS
LIKE sutra dhara], He's the One who is the
conductor, the One moves the strings in a
puppet show.
And so it is very important to pray to Shri
Ganesha every time we have Puja.
We have to pray to Him and we, that's how
we are praying to Lord Jesus Christ.
Every time.
Without His auspiciousness, without His help,
we cannot do Sahaja Yoga.
He's the Manager.
See I'm sitting here and He's the manager.
Supposing there's no management how will I
speak here?
Nothing can happen.
But He is so efficient, and you never see
Him working out everything, doing everything.