secondly I have to tell you that the
women in the West have changed their
styles which is very very dangerous for
their society because they have also
taken to the egoistical ways of men
so if men have gone say ten feet
they have run after them again about say
eight feet and pull back men even to go
further that now this is completely
crossing your egos because women do not
have such possibility fevers normally so
competing men in ego what you did you
have lost your complete maryadas of a
woman
there's no Maria de Ojo man has a
maryada of a man if a man start leaving
like a woman he is not a man in the same
way the women if they start behaving
like men then there are no more women
there lost her maryadas they are out so
they get possessed and that's why women
when they are egoistical they become
horrid their face has become horrid they
look horrid their whole behavior is
horrid they can become dry like beans
Dixie and could be so hard as to hit you
like an iron rod they say the lady
retire in a rod in Iraq all these
happens because we have a Maria
we are the style as we are if it Sara
Rue's it suppose be happy that you are a
flower of rose
now the rose wants to become the thought
so we lose all our maryadas to that
today I will be speaking to you before
we start this here when the people are
coming before that to the ladies and
tell them what's gone wrong with them
and that is how you must know that the
plight of the West is not by men but by
women women have ruined the Society of
Western society is the Indian women who
have kept the society intact all my
really thanks to their self solid
behavior towards life it is the women of
this country who have ruined all that
was so delicate emotional beautiful love
affixed and compassion women are there
to give joy and happiness and emotional
security to the whole society while they
take over do they keep that do that even
the husbands have become just like
servants in the house you haven't done
the cleaning properly you haven't
cleaned the kitchen properly I went to
England I was surprised all kitchen
cleaning and all that is so well done in
England we see you have everything for
cleaning days cleaning that I said why
it has happened is the men you see they
had to do it so they found out all the
ways and methods has to be sparking all
right [ __ ] you up I'll get you such a
thing that if you put you in your hand
you're having burn all the acid with a
big glove in the hand put it everywhere
[Laughter]
then the children you see suffer because
that's the job of a gardener beautiful
things that are born to be looked after
with that kindness but you overindulge
into your children in the beginning a
mother is like a gardener she has to
prove
chef's to cut also so the growth is all
right if your child is pointy or no good
another useless yeah
but you grow me your husband not your
children justa the Waya because ego is
towards her husband all the time
grooming six-year go there what these
money business give me all the money i
keep all the money everything now one
may say that the law is such if the law
is stupid
the sahaja yoginis should not take to
such a level that law has ruined you all
I think because this is such an
important part of life it is such an
important area of life that it should
not have suffered where affection love
kindness all that is required is missing
then you become people without any
meaning life is endless you don't know
what to do that's why the children
commit suicide and then the laughs
should be such that she should be true
for that you must have wisdom which also
one does not develop because if you run
after your mooladhara chakra how can you
have it stuff
here men have befooled you completely
completely there before take it from me
you must keep your wisdom intact and not
only that they have be fully but they
themselves have stooped down to the food
so they have their devious methods they
are not straightforward so i sahaja
Yogi's we are above all these things we
have reached a state where we are above
we are here for correcting all those
things that have gone wrong in the
society because sahaja yoga faces
towards a society not towards yourself
only so at this stage we have to
understand what we have to do is first
of all our own understanding should be
such even now with all this movement of
sahaja yoga understanding women don't
realize that they have to be like women
I have seen that they still what's wrong
still go
and men don't understand that they have
to be like men even after so and if they
become really like men women will
appreciate them and if you become really
like women men will appreciate you this
is the opposites that attracts each
other that should be no but we live in
abnormal way that the men are women and
women are men what do you do that so it
is very important for men to understand
now because I'm going to talk to women
it at all that they should become like
men they must fix up things they must
take decisions they must be the one who
must true but that's outward actually
it's the source is the woman the woman
is the potential and man is the kinetic
for example there is a fan moving
movement of the fan is the kinetic force
you can say but the potential force that
is within us is the one which is the
electricity which is coming from the
source which is higher the fan that
moves or the source let the women decide
and Men understand but if that source
dries out and wants to become the fan no
fan will one upside down situation if
you realize you are the source you are
the one who is going to give all the
Shakti to man will stop behaving like
men it doesn't mean that you cannot go
to work you cannot do but take to work
which is more suitable to women like I
would not like a woman to have a bus
driver job or a truck driver or wrestler
[Laughter]
no I'm not telling empty from experience
once I was Charlie I was a student at
that time in Lahore you see and I'ma
start travelling by train and at some
station you see the train stopped in the
night and a lady came and she said open
the door for me so I said it's so
crowded all right I'll try I try and she
said if you don't open I can break it I
said how can you said you don't know why
I said you I said she said I'm Mohammed
Amano sousou-sama da moneh the wrestler
lady Obama I said tango
I said if you are a wrestler lady why
are you coming in there ladies
Department why don't you go to the men's
and she pushed the door so violently she
came up I looked at her I said wow what
a person and she sat down you see with
the hole hole hole her countenance and
everything her old was a gate and state
of sitting everything was so manly like
that she said are you not come Alana
those who want to say I should not sit
here I said nobody wants that now madam
you seek comfort but we'll have to get
somebody from the other compartment to
have wrestling I bet she was quieted and
she was really I've saw her all her
muscles so over developed and she was
really looking like I would say a
Western cow we can say
[Laughter]
like the Gaussian look like buffaloes
not like cows something very funny I
cannot forget that you see that it's
fear I was very young I really felt like
laughing but I laugh I thought she walks
by so this is what it is that we are
ending up there must know that how far
are we going are we going to become
wrestlers so this is what it is
one has to learn that it has been there
for ages ages it has been there I have
seen have read books some books old
books I have seen some films also where
they have shown even in olden times the
women used to have room in their hand
sitting there husband sort of thing we
do have some of them blessed in India
but very very few very few women take
not a big number but it faint rings got
those see so keep your fingers crossed
but I would say that this is what is
happening so with too much ego of man
which goes into left to GD they say not
let the women take over all right can be
satisfied no more of their aggression
let them have their own so they do what
they like men are not bothered and they
go into their left this thing there's no
enjoyment of marriage or now so now we
have yesterday the other marriage for
the benefit of your children for the
goodness of them all that take your
roles as women and men your roles are as
women and men and you see you'll enjoy
the quarrel should be on that road the
man wants to do something worried should
say no no no how can even that's too
much for me let me do this work as I
have told you many a times how my
husband when he gets angry he wants to
wash his undershirt to see to show his
anger or when he is very angry
then he will clean the bathroom but he
does it so badly that I know that it is
he has done I feel like laughing but I
dare not because I must keep his spirit
on then and then he starts talking in
you know in a very is he a respectable
way to everyone now he calls everyone
Tao you see now he says Dao are like
that now are like that so I know now
he's a really angry for something but he
won't say what what she's here angry me
see then we have to find out what is he
angry with and if so don't feel guilty
correct
now you must find out what are the weak
points of your husband first of all and
of your wife on what points she get
upset
now the attitude should be we should not
upset her we should not make her angry
and another attitude of the wife the
same way much more for the hospital so
now what are the soft points on which
she really gets upset just turn it it's
very simple aliphatic don't take it
seriously
but be careful to avoid that now also
find out what makes him happy like if I
am really sometimes I never get angry as
you should know that I'm never get angry
but if I am showing off my anger just
let it be let it be solid see doc you
understand sahaja yoga
so now how to show that how to
neutralize an anger of a person say now
supposing I am trying to show if you put
a child in my lap finished
anger is gone I cannot show anger with
the child on my lap simple so you must
find out like my husband you see if he
is angry supposing I know him then if I
tell him that what about getting me a
nice sari Oh finished then he is very
happy he said how I have done him the
greatest favor see like that you see you
must find out what thing pleases your
husband what thing pleases your boy and
neutralized and you see little things
like that you must learn this is the art
of living this is the art of living is a
yogi life is the art of living it how
with little few things to see our
manager now you must have seen how in my
lecture I say quite serious things but
in your bubbles of laughter it just
settles down in your mind that's how you
should be because humor is one of the
greatest thing that puts the thing
through makes the person understand and
it doesn't harm anyone that's how things
improve and when you see that you are
settled down in peace that's the first
thing has been wife knows needs to
settle down in peace
children feel all right everyone feels
all right and then gradually let it
correct you have no responsibility of
correcting each other remember that this
is meant for you when you are not sahaja
Yogi's today it is not meant for you so
you won't feel guilt first remember you
are sahaja Yogi's you are my children
and I love you very much
very very much so please have confidence
in your complete confidence in yourself
all right
that's the greatest thing you can give
me today as a present
may God