Shri Mataji: All right, start it.
[Warren Reeves gives an introduction of 8.5
minutes.]
Shri Mataji: Good evening.
Audience: Good evening.
Shri Mataji: Today is the last day, when I
have to go. And you can understand a mother
who has so many children, she has to go from
one to another; she has the expectation to
meet her children and she has the concern
and the longing for whom she has so much love.
That's very difficult to express those feelings:
like waves as if they are taking out something
from you.
I do not know really how to thank you all.
Without you I cannot enjoy anything. As I
told you, even I may be the Capitalist and
I may have all these powers, so-called, I'm
a complete Communist, I can't enjoy it alone.
I have to share it with you. At the very outset,
I would like to thank Mr. Sig Paulsen for
making it available for Me, this beautiful
church. And you all that I could manifest
My love, could have a rapport with you, whom
I have known before. I'm meeting you again,
thanks to him.
I have to thank Betty, specially. She has
been so earnest. She wrote to Me letters,
she telephoned to Me again and again. Oh,
she took so much trouble to see that I come
to Houston. She has made these four days,
fantastic visit for Me. You all have to thank
her for what she's done, it's a very, very
great thing that she thought of you all and
of sharing her joy with you all. She got her
realization in Australia. It's a chain of
thanking, for which I have to thank Doctor
Warren who came to India for his realization,
and I got stuck to him... He was running every
moment and he got his realization.
Then we have other people here from India.
Nirmala Modi has come all the way, she's a
very wise Sahaj yogini. And then we have Hugo,
you know he came all the way. Went to Japan
from Australia, bought these equipments and
he's come to New York, then to Houston. Think
of them, how much they feel responsible that
they should communicate truth to you and that
they should arrange this beautiful program.
Warren's wife has also come here. We have
also, another American, Michael, who is helping
a lot.
The best of all, I would say is one of my
eldest sons, is Mr Gavin Brown. Who had something
to do with Houston. And when I wanted him
to put some money for American tour, I don't
know why, he put it in Houston Bank. I said,
"Why Houston of all the things? I may never
go there."
He says, "No Mother, Houston is the place."
Still the money is lying in the Bank here,
for next years program perhaps. He has worked
very hard and he's going to stay on here.
He's a quiet person. But he knows a lot about
Sahaj Yoga. He knows it thoroughly. He'll
tell you each and every thing: How to cure
you chakras. How to feel all right.
Now today, on this day, I'm going to tell
you about the Spirit. I have told you about
the seven chakras, about the three nadis,
the three channels, that are within us. And
today I want to tell you about the nature
of the Spirit.
The Spirit resides us in our heart. It's the
reflection of God Almighty. In Sanskrit language:
this aspect of God which is all-pervading
and is the first and the last, is called as
Sadashiva, is the Father, who does not incarnate.
We say Yahova, you can say, or the God who
does not incarnate. This great aspect which
encompasses everything ultimately and also
manifests everything, is reflected within
our heart as the Spirit. This aspect is just
the witness aspect. It witnesses the play
of its power, the Primordial Power, the Holy
Ghost, to see what is created by Her. He's
the only enjoyer of the game. He sees the
game, the leela, the fun. She organizes everything,
it is She who gets divided into three powers,
it is She who creates the whole universe,
it is She who gives us this evolution, it
is She who makes us human beings and it is
She who has to make us the higher human being.
That's the Holy Ghost, the Primordial Holy
Ghost and the reflection of that is this Kundalini
within us.
These two have to meet. They are separated;
the Spirit within you and the Holy Ghost within
you have to meet. That is the Yoga, that's
the union.
The seat of the Spirit is on top of your head
here, but He resides in human beings in the
heart; of course it comes out also and watches
you. It is not in our conscious mind, it resides
and watches the whole field. [DEL: In San-
] In Gita He's called as Kshetragya, the one
who knows the field, the knower of the field.
He knows everything, He watches; He's just
watching, where we go, what we do, what compromises
we make, how we run after our seeking, how
we go to falsehood, what we do; everything
it is watching. The Holy Ghost is the one
which receives the information and records
everything in itself but the information is
given by the deity who is the seed or the
spirit of Jesus Christ who is sitting down
there, Ganesha.
The Spirit itself is Sat-Chitt-Ananda. He
exists in the state of truth. Now we do not
know what truth is. People say, "God is Love,
God is Truth." Now what is the truth? The
truth is this all-pervading power. And this
all-pervading power is the nature of the Spirit,
which gives you the absolute knowledge; now
mark it; absolute knowledge. For example,
if you have to say, "What is the shape of
this ...?"
You will say, "It's a pyramid." All right,
but is it a good thing to have a pyramid for
a church or not? There could be hundred opinions
on that.
But if you ask Me, or ask any Sahaj yogi,
they said, "Yes, it has to be a pyramid."
Why? Because in a pyramid there is a coefficience
and you feel the vibrations. It's absolutely,
absolute knowledge. That's the truth you know.
You want to know if a person is fake or not.
You just put your hands like this and ask
a question, "Is he true?" Your vibrations
will stop, you may even get blisters, if you
ask such a question about someone. So you
do not know through your mental activity.
A person may look very nice, as I told you,
he may behave in such a manner, that you'll
feel, "Oh, what a fine man he is." Is such
and such person is a realized soul or not?
How will you know? You'll just put your hands
towards that person and you'll start getting
the vibrations from that person; you'll enjoy
them. Only after realization only we can really
enjoy other person - really enjoy.
One day I was in Calcutta and staying in a
hotel on My way to Singapore, and there was
a very great soul who came to see Me. And
he just sneaked into the room. See, sometimes
it happens that some of these great souls
who live in Himalayas and all that, they come
in. And he just saw Me and he fell at my feet.
And there were at least five, six Sahaj yogis
staying in other rooms and suddenly they felt
tremendous cool, joy falling on them, a cold
shower like thing. And they all came running,
one after another.
"What's happened, what happened?" And he was
at My feet. They opened the door and they
said, "Oh, Mother!" "Mother, how did you come?"
"Oh, Mother!" And then they started feeling
him. He was enjoying Me, I was enjoying him.
And they were all enjoying him.
You don't have to tell whether a person is
true or not. There is no mental deduction,
it just happens. You start feeling. Even children
are like that, even small children. If they
are realized souls, immediately they'll say,
"This is this and this is this," finished.
There's no compromise, how can you compromise?
That's what I told you yesterday that Christ
never compromised. He'd never compromised.
How can you compromise with darkness if you
are light?
So the first thing you are, you are the truth.
The Spirit tells you what is the truth. It
tells you everything about everything. It
is the truth; the knowledge that is pure is
the truth. As I told you, Gavin Brown, when
he got his realization, he said, "My father
has not telephoned" and he put his hands there
and he got a burning here and when they telephoned,
he found out that his father was down with
bronchitis, and I told him the exactly the
same thing. Now a person who came to Me the
other day who had multiple sclerosis - is
a very serious disease according to doctors,
but according to Me it is not. And everybody
told Me the same centers he was catching.
Of course because I have been in the medicine,
I have been in the medical college, I know
these chakras means what. And he told Me that
he had this problem. Even if he not told Me,
I would have known that he had this problem.
Everybody will see the same centre is catching.
So, you are the truth. Then after some time
you cannot bear untruth. You cannot bear falsehood,
I mean, we also are like that, I tell you.
For example, if I tell you that, "You come
along here there's a very nice chair for you."
Now you don't see any chair there. "Oh you
sit down, it is there, believe Me, imagine
there's a chair." I mean, nobody would accept
that, will you?
You don't see any chair. "There is any.-"
"No, no, but the imaginary, there is one,
I have placed it, you can't see, I have made
it invisible. You see you just see, you sit
down you'll get it." All right you sit down
there, and you sit in that position and after
some time you start getting the pain.
"Where's the chair, how do I get the pain."
That's what Warren told you, it's very practical.
You immediately know that this is not the
way.
Now the first centre is very important, is
of the innocence, which gives you the magnetic
powers. In the sense not only that you are
attractive but, I mean you attract people,
but magnetic means that you know whether you
are moving to the north or to the south. Birds
have this power in them, birds have. That's
how they fly from one place to another. Because
they can feel the magnet within. And a person
who is pure at that point, he never gets lost
because he knows which side he's moving. I
mean, I have that power, I have never had
a problem like that. I move either to the
left or to the right, or to forward. And My
husband who is dealing with shipping, he says,
"I have never met a better navigator than
my wife."
And it's so spontaneous, I mean, I don't have
to think, I know for definite that you are
moving in the wrong direction or in the right
direction. Even the material movement I mean
to say. All of them have experience, they
have great drivers and they have got all the
maps and everything. And immediately I know
that you are going on the wrong direction
because the magnet immediately turns round.
So the magnet is placed within you there,
but it is to be awakened. When it is awakened,
these deities when they're awakened, you become
the truth. Like the light that comes in, you
start seeing everything as far as your feelings
are concerned, your experiencing is concerned.
So you become the truth.
Now one may say, "How truth could be love?"
That's a very common question. Truth cannot
be love because, I mean, if you tell somebody
something that is truth, he may not like,
and he may be unhappy and it may not be dear
to him, and he might be very, very worried
about it.
Manu said, long time back that, "You should
speak the truth and you must speak the things
which are dear to others." "Satyam vadet,
priyam vadet."
People said, "It's not possible, it's an absurd
situation, how can you do it?"
So Krishna has put something in between, he
said, "Satyam vadet, hitam vadet, priyam vadet."
You say something that is the truth, always
say the truth, and say something hitam, means
for the pleasing of your Spirit. That's the
condition. And ultimately that becomes a very
dear thing. In the beginning one may not like
it, but ultimately, this will be very much
liked, this truth. So all these three he has
put together and said that, "You have to speak
the truth, the truth has to be pleasing to
the Spirit, and ultimately, the person is
going to enjoy it."
So the truth is: everything is illusion, except
for the Divine Love of God that is all-pervading
which you can feel through your Spirit. This
power has got telecommunication, it has got
all that you have created in the science,
it can coordinate and cooperates. It has got
all the angels and all the great souls to
help it and to look after you. And the top,
topping the whole thing is the quality that
loves, it loves you. So it doesn't come to
you like a sword, it gives you the time to
improve, to judge yourself, to rise, to grow,
just as a mother would look after her child,
forgive mistakes, see that the child rises
and grows into complete manhood. So it is
love and the love that is so powerful is the
truth; and it never fails, it never fails.
For example you might think now, a man like
Sadat has died. [Ed: Anwar el Sadat was assassinated
on 6 Oct 1981, the day before this talk.]
"Mother how do you explain?" I mean, you never
die, that's one thing you do not know. He
can be born again, he would be born in such
a condition where he'll be much more effective.
He has himself died at the top of his glory.
I mean for him, he's a martyr. If you see
from his angle, everywhere in the whole world,
"Sadat." Sa-dat, it's a big name too. But
supposing he had fallen in his glory and all
that, then he would have died, then God would
not have been just to him, I would say. But
he died in all his glory and he can be born
again. And he can take a position from where
he can do much better work, in the name of
God, in the field of God because now we don't
have to do any more work, otherwise in any
other field.
We have had enough of trains, we don't want
any more now. We have had enough of plastics,
now we have mountains. We have got too much
of butter around, too much of food, everything
bit too much, I mean the house becomes a junk.
In any field we have overdone things. We have
exhausted this Mother Earth. Now what do we
have to do? Only in one field and the field
that is of God's work you have to do it. But
first you have to get connected and then do
the God's work. And that connection is only
through your spirit, when you become absolute
and you have the truth within you as a built-in
awareness. Is the awareness that becomes the
truth.
So the first quality of the spirit is that
you become the truth, that you know the truth,
that you take a stand on the truth. Look at
Christ. He had nothing to do with women like
Mary Magdalene, I mean, nothing to do, I mean,
He was virtue. He was innocence. But when
He saw people were stoning her, He took up
a stand. He took up a stand. You have to take
up a stand, stand on the truth. And he said,
"Those who have not committed any sin can
throw, and you can throw the stone at Me".
And nobody did. He did this because He was
standing on the truth. He took a whip and
whipped those people who were selling in the
temple of God. At the age when he was a little
boy, he went and argued with learned people.
Such people have no fear of anything. What
is there to fear? When you are standing on
the truth, what is there to fear? Truth is
such a light that it gives you complete picture
of the whole thing.
There's nothing to fear. Your Father, He is
compassion, He's ocean of compassion. And
He's ocean of love and ocean of forgiveness.
And He is now within you. Who is more powerful
than Him? It's very easy for many human beings
to say, "Oh, we don't believe in God." You
believe it or not, He's there. Those who say,
"We don't believe," it is better that they
should come and get their realization and
understand that there is very little time
left for such kind of nonsensical statements.
I mean you can at the most say that, "I've
not felt God so far and I'm open, if I feel."
But on what basis do you deny? What basis
have you got to say that, "We don't believe
in God"? Not only, after realization you can
prove God, but you can show His miracles.
The second thing, the nature of Spirit is
that He's chitta, He's the attention. He's
the attention means when you become spiritually
enlightened your attention becomes enlightened.
Now enlightenment, what we understand of these
lights is that the lights are falling here,
and we can see things, that's all. But this
attention which is being enlightened, acts,
it works, it has got loops, it has got weapons,
it works. You have to see for yourself how
your attention works.
Today there was somebody who went and told
one of the Sahaj yginis that "I was sitting
there and I was getting all negative thoughts
and was feeling horrible in my hands and I
don't know why it was happening in the program."
So she said, "Here you have come to pay attention
to Mother and to Her work and pay attention
to your Spirit. But if you are paying attention
to all the rest of the people here, then you
are going to catch them."
Is a very simple thing, "Where is your attention?"
Ask this question. This is a very common question
in an Indian home, a mother will ask the child,
"Where is your attention?" The basis of Indian
life is chitta nirodh, is to fix your attention
in a proper way. Where is your attention?
Is it on your Spirit? Or is it on somebody
else, like, "My brother is sitting here, my
mother is sitting there, oh, that woman is
very bad, she's jealous of me," all this nonsense.
Where is your attention? When you get realized
then you start seeing through the window of
the Spirit, your position changes. As you're
looking at Me now, then you come back here
and start looking at you this way. Till you
are realized you are sitting before Me, but
once you are realized you come here and see
others from there, that's your fort. Nobody
can touch you there. From there you see others,
your attention is detached.
So the attention becomes enlightened after
realization. You pay attention to anything,
it works. It does work, no doubt, you try.
Those who have got realization should try
this. Try your attention, but attention has
to be pure. You have to purify your attention,
and the best way to purify it is to keep your
Agnya Chakra open. When this centre is open
which is the centre of Christ, which I have
shown that it can only open through the Lord's
Prayer after realization. When you open that,
then you are in that state where your attention
is divine. And you'll be amazed how things
work out, even the smallest things, the material
things, the useless things and the great things,
and the subtle and subtlest, and how you start
growing. So the growth is to be achieved by
purifying your attention, and to purify this
attention is to keep your Agnya Chakra open
and be in thoughtless awareness. You watch
something, you don't think about it. Zen said
the same thing but I think people didn't understand,
you see, before realization it's like telling
about colors to a blind man. Zen said the
same thing, you watch a thing without thinking
about it. They created patterns which didn't
mean anything, which you see it without thinking.
But that's only possible after realization.
So the thinking process minimizes and you
start witnessing.
The higher state than that of attention is
that you jump into nirvikalpa samadhi, into
the state of doubtless awareness. Now it is
not doubtlessness because you've argued it
out or anything. But is a state where you're
doubtless about things. I mean the way you
speak, the way you behave, the way your attention
is, you can make it out that "I'm doubtlessly
there." The discrimination becomes so sharp
that you can just say, "This is so and so
and so," there's no fanaticism about it.
As I told you this morning that if a blind
man cross over something and says, "Oh there's
a snake here," and he believes it's a snake,
he believes that it's a snake, that's fanaticism.
Because he has no eyes to see and he believes
it's a snake, he says, "Oh, there is a snake
here, I believe!"
But a person who has eyes sees, "No it's a
rope, it's just a rope." And he says, "No,
it's not, it's a rope." But he has eyes and
when he says with his eyes, which can see
that, that it's a rope, he means it, the truth
- then he's not a fanatic. But he's standing
on the truth. This subtle difference people
don't understand. Fanaticism comes through
blindness and the truth comes through realization.
And at any cost you'll not give up the truth,
any cost.
Now when I started My work in 1970, somehow
I knew all about these fake gurus and fake
people, I knew about it. And in My first lecture,
we had about, must be having about two, three
thousand people, it was a very huge hall and
I told the names of all these fake people
and who they were in previous lives and what
they did, by names. And everybody was amazed
at Me, they were frightened. There was a Maharajah
who was a friend of My husband and all that,
and he came and told Me that, "Oh, I'm so...
I'm very frightened for you."
I said, "Why?"
He said, "These people are horrid. They mean
money, they mean their whole earnings out
of it. How did you say these things openly
and you took their names? They will shoot
you."
I said, "Let them shoot. I'll see who shoots
Me."
They said, "You see they will prosecute you."
I said, "Let them prosecute." So many years
have passed, nobody has dared to say that
I'm telling the lies.
There is no fear. You love, but you don't
love satanic people, you don't love Satan.
The Satan who has spoiled the Kundalini of
people, who has spoiled all the chances of
their getting realization, as a mother do
you think I should say, "They are very good
people"? I'm not a political figure and I'm
not seeking elections. Cannot be a compromise!
That's what happens to you also.
But by your own self-esteem, by your own glory,
people see, "Here is the leader." And you
become the leader of the people. You can,
there is nothing to be frightened of. There
should be no half-way, as Christ, as he read
it out to you, that lukewarm people he spits
them out of the mouth. If you are hot, if
you are devils, we'll fight you; if you are
cold, you're my children. But lukewarm people
are static, because all kinds of forces are
pulling, there's no progress of any kind.
You come, you come, negative, positive, they
are pulled this way, that way. There cannot
be compromise with truth. And then you will
see you will have the real collective force,
the real blessings of God, in every way. You
don't have to worry about money, you don't
have to worry about anything, it all works
out, everything works out. You can't believe
it how much it works out.
I will tell you about these Australians: Australians
were finding it very difficult to get a place
to have an ashram, and one day, frantically
one of the girls telephoned to Me, "Mother,
we cannot have a place now, we don't know
where to go, we have sold our houses, we've
no place to go to."
I said, "Don't you worry, tomorrow, you'll
get it." And she was surprised how I told
her, "Tomorrow you'll get it." After telephoning
and all that, she went home and she received
a call... I mean there was a call from a...
estate agent.
When they went to see him next day he said,
"There's an ashram available, would you like
to have it?" At a very cheap rate, they got
a beautiful house for the ashram.
In London, we had a some sort of a small ashram
and they were finding it very difficult for
all these people to live there, because they
wanted to live together. They said, "Mother,
we must have some more rooms and some more
place."
I said, "All right you just pray, it will
work out." You won't believe, we had started
a co-op in London, and they said it will take
eight years to get a room out of this co-op.
That's London speed, just the opposite of
American. And within a month's time, we got
a huge house, huge house with fifteen bedrooms
and two big halls and we didn't know what
to do with it, and at such a cheap rate that
for the whole week, only seventy pounds were
to be paid. But then the Sahaj yogis went
and settled down there because in London we
have in thousands.
Then they said, "Mother what about for others?"
And within fifteen days we got a huge big
hotel with all carpets and with all curtains
and everything provided for, cutlery, crockery,
anything you say was there. Every thing - only
for ninety pounds a week, for at least twenty
people to live very happily and big rooms
each and big halls. Just we got it. You won't
believe but it has happened just before Warren's
marriage and we didn't know where they are
going to stay, all of these who were coming
to get married here, and they had a nice honeymoon
in that hotel. They didn't have to pay anything
for it. Yes, it works out. Krishna has said,
"Yoga kshema vahamyaham." You get to your
yoga first, he never said, "Kshema yoga,"
he said, "Yoga kshema vahamyaham." You get
your realization, you get your yoga and then
the kshema, the well-being works out.
Everything is organized then for you, you
are on the stage, everyone works for you,
believe Me, it happens that way. What is there
to hanker after, what is there to ask for,
I mean you ask for one thing, you get thousand,
you don't know what to do with them. I don't
know really- I don't know with Myself, I don't
know what to do , the way, I'm quite generous,
I mean I try to give away so many things but
still My house, oh God! You can't imagine,
you can't imagine. In their wedding I gave
fifty-one saris, fifty-one, thinking that,
"Now I'll some rest from these saris." Again
I went back, they are still there. I don't
know now what am I to do, I brought now some
to America to give away and all that, you
just give and you get, everything, you get
fed-up!
But only thing that I always, I have been
asking for are the seekers, where are they
lost? Where are they? That's something still
there, they are to be saved. Because as I
told you Christ is going to come back with
eleven destructive powers and there's going
to be no questioning, no realization, just...
All the negative forces will be killed and
those who enter into the kingdom of God will
reside in the kingdom of God, will reside
there, the residents, the citizens. As He
said, "If you want money, I'll give you gold.
But I look after those who hanker after Spirit."
You enter through the door and He eats with
you, He shares with you. For a realized soul
the highest human beings are the seekers.
You may be any king or anything, what does
it matter, there are so many roaming about.
But a seeker is the thing in the eyes of God
as the highest human being, who has to become
a super-human being.
So your attention is filled, so many of these
miracles, you cannot imagine how many have
taken place with Sahaj yogis. One can write
such a big book. So the attention becomes
pure. You just can't see bad things happening,
I mean, you just don't like it, I mean, I
feel like vomiting sometimes the way things
are, sometimes. The things that you enjoy
normally become absolutely garbage, you just
don't like it, the whole, the priorities change.
You become automatically virtuous, I don't
have to tell you, "Be virtuous," you'll just
become, and you start enjoying your virtues
and virtues of others. You start enjoying
other people because attention becomes collectively
conscious. Our central nervous system is our
attention but this central nervous system
becomes collectively conscious, becomes.
You are not bothered; somebody has cancer,
it's all right, "I'll try to cure you." You
are not afraid you'll get cancer, nothing,
you are never afraid of it. "I'll try."
You put your hands like this, like that and
the fellow says, "Oh I'm feeling very much
better, I don't know, what have you done to
me?"
"Nothing." The attention becomes so effective,
so powerful; it does tremendous things and
the attention among yourselves has a rapport.
They all move like the several drops in an
ocean, in a wave of love, it's so beautiful.
The white men came to India long time back
as this or that, but when they came with Me,
you should see, we have some films how the
Indian villagers, you see, took them to their
heart, danced with them, fed them, loved them,
it's so sweet. And they write to them, it's
so beautiful, there's no artificial, it's
not just a feeling, "I love you, you love
me," it's not there. It's just the enjoyment
of the company of other realized souls. We
talk of big things, "Oh, we are all brothers
and sisters," it's all talk, talk, talk, talk,
talk. Then you just become, you forget your
color, you forget your nationality, you forget
everything, you just feel, "Oh, thats a Sahaj
yogi." It's a very different plane into which
you arrive where you feel so happy, joyous,
the whole thing is a fun.
And when it comes to helping, all of them
come together. When they find a negative force
is coming, all of them come together. There
is never a discussion among them, never. They
try to pull him out. They tell him, all of
them will tell by their own ways and method
that, "This is wrong, this is wrong." It's
such a combination, I never have to tell them.
I don't have to tell them that, "I'll give
you some lessons now," for example, "How to
carry on among yourselves," nothing, they
just manage.
Not only that but a person will say, "Now
see," A will say to B, "See I'm catching on
my Agnya, will you please help me there."
That means, "I'm ego."
And the other fellow he'll say, "I'll... I'll
try." They just help each other, without feeling
bad, there is no remorse of anything, there's
no heart burning, no jealousy. What a relationship
is established like one finger doesn't have
jealousy with the other. You have no jealousies
with the other cells of the same primordial
being. There is no need even to talk of love,
you are in love. Everybody can see that your
love. It's really worth seeing how we become
so much adaptable, so much silent and happy
people, when our attention becomes collectively
conscious, because that's the real source
of joy. And the greatest quality of the sSirit
is that you're pure joy. It's pure joy. We
talk of unhappiness and happiness, sorrow
and ecstasy and all these words. But joy is
pure, it hasn't got the duality, it's one,
single, absolute.
I'm leaving you and My heart is wrenching.
The joy is seeing that. Seeing that this Nirmala
is wrenching, bleeding. The joy is seeing
and when I go, this feeling, I will think
and I'll think of you and the joy will be
again repeated. That joy of oneness, even
in separation the oneness I feel it, the concern.
Which cannot be expressed in words, that silent
pulling of your heart - that is also joy.
Joy is absolute, it comes through seeing.
You see it and you get the joy. Joy is the
quality when you gradually move from the brain,
the attention first goes into the brain, specially
in the West, is the brain first, takes place,
means you become the attention, I'm sorry,
you become the truth. Means you start feeling
in the hands, you understand, then you see,
"Yes, it is so and this person has got this
trouble, so he must be having arthritis if
he's catching on this, yes true." You start
tallying, finding out and monitoring it and
again, again verifying it and you are satisfied
with it.
So the attention first is nothing but starts
achieving the truth. It's trying to feel the
truth but it's dry, at that stage, it'sdry
- in the West, specially, because we are differently
made in the West. Then we read the book, "Advent,"
we like it and we see all these things and
knowledge and everything you like, you want
to listen to the t- My speech and all that.
You all like it. Is the knowledge because
you see the truth, the knowledge - that's
the gift of the brain. Is the central path
as I can say "the awareness." Then you feel
your chitta, your attention which is enlightened,
and you're blasted with it. You see the miracles
happening, "That's happening..." you are just
blasted.
Then the third thing happens; is the joy:
that you are in joy all the time. You cannot
keep serious for more than two minutes; it's
very difficult to keep serious. The sense
of humor is so beautiful, you never use vulgarity
or hurting things or personal remarks, but
the whole thing is so beautiful. When you
speak, people feel the flowers throwing their
fragrance at you. Every action that you do
creates joy, ripple of joy. Every movement
you do, every vision you see, gives you joy.
That time you feel perfected. When you see
a picture which is beautiful, immediately
you go into thoughtless awareness, and the
complete joy of that creation starts dropping
on you, you just feel the joy. Then you become
silent, you don't speak... much, you don't
think, you become the joy, ananda. That's
the perfect state in which you should be.
It's so beautiful that you want to be there
all the time.
This joy is the movement of your ocean of
love. Is the beautiful movement of the clouds
that you see. It's fantastic, you just get
drenched into it and you do everything for
love's sake and you don't think you're doing
it for love's sake, you do not feel that way,
you just do it because it's so joy-giving,
that it is the greatest thing. You may have...
anything in the world will not be that much
joy-giving as this joy of the Spirit which
you become. You never feel lonely, you are
never bored. Whether you are alone or with
anyone, you are in joy. One should understand
that if you get your Self-realization or if
somebody says that they are giving you to
some positive lines, you should know, "Are
you peaceful within you? Are you joy?" Forget
about the collective consciousness, is your
health all right? That's the minimum of minimum.
The whole system changes. I just say that
all of you should achieve that state of joy
by the time I come here next year. And I hope
you grow into it, by taking up a stand on
the truth, grow into it. You progress into
it. It's so wonderful and so beautiful and
that's what your Father wants you to have.
He's the most generous Father; He can't enjoy
His kingdom unless and until He has given
it to you, that He has made you sit on His
throne. That's the greatest joy that He wants
to have and that's what you should achieve,
that's what you should have, that's your right
to have.
This is what is Self-realization - you become
just the master. You don't have to consult
anyone, you know it. You have to just consult
your Spirit through your vibratory awareness,
and you know it. These are the blessings of
Self-realization into which you have to grow
and as you grow you start manifesting your
powers: you can raise the Kundalini, you can
give realization at the very outset. Imagine
the Kundalini moves under your finger, nobody
can believe it but it has happened now.
Even very, very great saints, you see, there
is a very great saint who is more than hundred
and eight years of age, and he asked Me, "Mother,
I have spent thousands of years to get these
vibrations and these people have got it without
doing anything."
I said, "What did you... why did you do it,
who asked you to do it? You should have taken
it easy, you would have got it."
He's a very sweet fellow, but because he's
got it through his effort, see he has that
feeling that, "I've got it through my effort."
You'll never get it through effort, I tell
you. When you are finished with your effort
you just get it...
[murmurs of laughter from the Audience.]
Shri Mataji: ...maybe in an abstract way,
or maybe-
Yes! When Buddha was tired, finished, fagged-out,
then he got his realization. When you stop
your efforts then only you will get your realization.
"So why to boast of your efforts?" I told
him. He's a very powerful man because he's
done lots of things and he always goes on
a big, very big tiger and because he's hurt
himself, he says that people have beaten him,
so he's hurt himself so he always uses a tiger.
And he's a man with the idea that he has these
powers, that powers. So when I went to see
him, I knew that time because he told people
that, "Mother has come, so you go and see
Her..." and all that and I knew he was there
so I went to see him. When I went to see him,
we had to climb about three miles, one had
to walk up, and I was walking up and when
I reached there it was raining and I got completely
drenched. And this fellow is supposed have
powers over the rain. And he was so angry
when I went there he was sitting on a little
seat of his made of some stone. He was doing
like this, like this, very angry. So I didn't
say anything, I went inside his cave and sat
down there in that drenched condition.
So he came down and he said, "Mother, did
you do this to kill my ego?"
I said, "What? I didn't do anything. What
did I do?"
He said, "This rain wouldn't listen to me."
I said, "Now, don't be angry," I said, "Sit
down. Haven't you bought a sari for Me, and
you are a sanyasi, I won't take a sari from
a sanyasi, [son?]. You have got a sari for
Me, isn't it? So I have to get drenched, otherwise
I will not take sari from you." And the whole
temper melted away, whole temper melted away.
Then I said, "It was necessary the water to
flow over My body so that all the plains around
you becomes beautiful, is vibrated with water."
But he is a very great soul I must say, because
he doesn't talk to Me like ordinary human
beings talk. His style is different because
he recognizes, he knows who I am. Is a very
different thing, and a day will come when
you will also rise, you will rise and grow
and grow and there will see the glory of this
great new age, new generation... into the
complete newness of the being.
Today I was going to tell you about certain
diseases that one has and how to control them
and I would suggest that we have a book - are
you going to sell it to everyone?
Yogi from the side: There's a few of them
Mother.
Shri Mataji: We don't have many. So we would
say those who have been coming for all the
four lectures should buy the book. We are
sorry we don't have many books but we hope
to send you these books later on and is a
very good book in which you can see what imbalances
can work out, like how you get diabetes, how
you get kidney trouble, blood pressure and
then how you have to balance your liver, and
how to look after the security and all these
things are written in that book at length.
Quite a knowledgeable book I should say.
I took the writer... I should say I really
tortured him. And everyday I used to see him
coming up pulling his ears, you see, that,
"I don't know what mistakes I'm going to do."
And every time he would come, I would say,
"Now, Gregoire you have to be sweet as well.
It's not that sweet, you are still a scholar,
you have to be a Sahaj yogi. And a Sahaj yogi
is different from a scholar so you write this
book in such a manner, in such a way that
it is sweet, it's loving, it's kind," and
I've tried really to curb it down, curb it
down.
But he had written two chapters of his scholarliness,
all the scholarliness that he had, and it
was like a... really a big boulder before
you when you enter into that book. So one
day I told him. "These two chapters, let us
put it at the end of the book," and he really
collapsed.
He said, "Mother, how can You do that to me,
it's too much."
I said, "But why, what's the problem?"
He said, "These two chapters are the ones
which introduce the book and how can we do
it? I mean, it's in the beginning and how
can You put it at the end?"
I said, "Gregoire, while correcting the book,
I saw to it that these chapters have nothing
to do with the beginning, so you put them
at the end."
And he, when he placed them there he said,
"Oh the book has become wonderful." And then
he told Me, "It's a very good play of Mother
in this, that the intellectuals are never
satisfied with the reading once, and they
would like to go into the intellectual rumination.
Like the animals you see, like cows when they
eat, then they take it back and again eat
it, like that, So is better to put these two
chapters for them."
I said, "Now you are not angry with Me?"
He said, "No, this is a very good thing."
But these two chapters definitely prove that
he's a very learned man. And I told him, "Gregoire,
when did you read all these books that you
have quoted?"
He said, "Mother, you'll be surprised, these
quotations just came to me... I never, I never
read them."
I said, "You never read them?"
"Yes, yes, I had read them before, sometimes
I must have read them, but at the right time,
I got the right quotation."
He's now coming to Los Angeles, he is a diplomat
in the Swiss government and he's coming all
the way from Rome to Los Angeles, and he's
a very dynamic person, I'm looking forward
to My visit to Los Angeles. If you have any
friends there or anything you can write to
them, you can take the address from here so
that they can come and see Me. We have now
booked all our days, I am sorry and still
we'll contact somebody from Unity Church,
but all the days are booked. It's all right,
and the people can come in any case wherever
you have the programs.
Anything else you want you can write to Me.
I'm sorry I can't write to you because every
day I work, like this the way I've been working
here: morning, the workshop, evening, the
lecture. It has been on and on for years together
now. So, I do write sometimes, but I don't
have so much time, but somebody will answer
you. Any question, any problem, anything,
please write to Me. I'll be very happy to
receive letters from you and there are so
many people who are sorting them out and looking
after it, so you will have an answer no doubt.
Please get My address also from the ashram
address from these people. Anything that you
want you can ask for it. Even sitting down
here I know your attention, it will work out.
Gradually you will change and your asking
will be different and different and different.
May God bless you to blossom into the beauties
of your Spirit, so that you glorify your Father
and He feels glorified with His gracious love
towards you.
Thank you very much.
Today, if you want you can just put your hands,
if you had put your hands you would have got
the vibrations. I am sure there are some new
people today and they should also feel their
vibrations on top of their heads; they might
be feeling already the Cool Breeze, just take
out your shoes and you'll feel it. On top
of your head.
The tapes are with the Unity Church here,
you can buy them. We have also sending twenty
one tapes.
[Warren next to Shri Mataji]: They're already
being copied.
[Shri Mataji]: They are being copied. We have
so many tapes in London and you can buy from
the gentleman, we don't have to bother about
money part, I mean, we are not bothered. Only
thing, as he must, they must have told you,
a little problem with our trustees, that you
have to just say that we have the copyright,
that's all. We are not bothered as to what
you charge and what you do it. So you can
buy the tapes as you like and you can listen
to them
and enjoy them.
How many have come for the first time today?
[Warren whispers]: Quite a few.
[Shri Mataji]: Now just take out your shoes
please.
[FV VIDEO ENDS 77 minutes]
[edit] Transcript begins here
Now today, on this day, I'm going to tell
you about the spirit. I've told you about
the seven chakras, about the three nadis,
the three channels, that are within us. And
today I want to tell you about the nature
of the spirit.
The spirit resides in our heart. It's the
reflection of God Almighty. In Sanskrit language,
this aspect of God which is all-pervading
and is the first and the last, is called as
Sadashiva, is the Father, who does not incarnate.
We say Yahova, we can say, or the God who
does not incarnate. This great aspect which
encompasses everything ultimately and also
manifests everything, is the reflection within
our heart as the spirit. This aspect is just
the witness aspect. It witnesses the play
of its power, the Primordial Power, the Holy
Ghost, to see what is created by Her. He's
the only enjoyer of the game. He sees the
game, the Leela, the fun. She organises everything,
it is She who gets divided into three powers,
it is She who creates the whole universe,
it is She who gives us this evolution, it
is She who makes us human beings and it is
She who has to make us the higher human being.
That's the Holy Ghost, the Primordial Holy
Ghost and the reflection of that is this Kundalini
within us.
These two have to meet. They're separated.
The spirit within you and the Holy Ghost within
you have to meet. That is the Yoga, that's
the union.
The seat of the spirit is on top of your head
here, but it resides in human beings in the
heart; of course it comes out also and watches.
It is not in our conscious minds, it resides
and watches the whole field. Infact, in Gita
he is called as Kshettranjan, the one who
knows the field, the knower of the field.
He knows everything, He watches; He's just
watching, where we go, what we do, what compromises
we make, how we run after our seeking, how
we go to falsehood, what we do; everything
it is watching. The Holy Ghost is the one
which receives the information and records
everything in itself but the information is
given by the deity who is the seed of the
spirit of Jesus Christ who is sitting down
there, Ganesha.
The spirit itself is Sat Chit Anand. He exists
in the state of truth. Now we do not know
what truth is. People say "God is Love, God
is Truth." Now what is the truth? The truth
is this all-pervading power. And this all-pervading
power is the nature of the spirit, which gives
you the absolute knowledge; now mark this;
absolute knowledge. For example, if you have
to say what is the shape of this, you'll say
it's a pyramid. All right, but is it a good
thing to have a pyramid for a church or not.
There could be hundred opinions on that. But
if you ask Me, or ask any Sahaja Yogi, they'll
say, "yes, it has to be a pyramid." Why? Because
in a pyramid there is a coefficient and you'll
feel the vibrations. It's absolutely, absolute
knowledge. That's the truth you know. You
want to know if a person is fake or not. You
just put your hands like this and ask the
question, "Is he true?" Your vibrations will
stop, you may even get blisters, if you ask
a question about it. So you do not know through
your mental activity. A person may look very
nice, as I told you, he may behave in such
a manner, that you'll say, "Oh, what a fine
man he is." Is such and such person is a realised
soul or not? How will you know? You just put
your hands towards that person and you'll
start getting the vibrations from that person;
you'll enjoy them. Only after realisation
only we can really enjoy other persons, really
enjoy.
One day I was in Calcutta and staying in a
hotel, on My way to Singapore, and there was
a very great soul who came to see Me. He just
slipped into the room. See, sometimes it happens
that some of these great souls who live in
the Himalayas and all that, they come in.
And he just saw Me and he fell at my feet.
And there at least five, six Sahaja Yogis
staying in other rooms and suddenly they felt
tremendous cool joy falling on them. A cold
shower, I think. And they all came running,
one after another. "What happened, what happened?"
And he was at My feet. They opened the door
and they said, "Oh, Mother!" "How did you
come?" "Oh, Mother!" And then they started
feeling it. He was enjoying Me, I was enjoying
him. And they were all enjoying him.
You don't have to tell whether a person is
true or not. There is no mental deduction.
It just happens. You start feeling, even children
are like that. Even poor children. If they're
realised souls, immediately they'll tell,
this is this and this is this, finished. There's
no compromise, how can you compromise. That's
what I told you yesterday that Christ never
compromised. He never compromised. How can
you compromise with darkness if you're light?
So the first thing you are, you are the truth.
The spirit tells you what is the truth. It
tells you everything about everything. It
is the truth; the knowledge that is pure is
the truth. As I told you, Gavin Brown, when
he got his realisation, he said, "My father
has not telephoned" and he put his hands there
and he got the burning here and he telephoned,
he found out that his father was downed with
bronchitis, and I told him exactly the same
thing. Now a person who came to Me the other
day who had multiple sclerosis, is a very
serious disease, according to doctors. But
according to Me it is not. And everybody told
Me the same centres were catching. Of course
because I have been in the medicine, I have
been in the medical college, I know this chakra
means what. And he told Me that he had this
problem. Even if he not told Me, I would have
known that he had this problem. Everybody
will see the same centre is catching, so you
are the truth. Then after some time you cannot
bear untruth. You cannot bear falsehood, I
mean, we also are like that, I tell you. For
example, if I tell you that you come along
here, there's a very nice chair for you. Now
you don't see any chair there. "Oh you sit
down, you sit there, believe Me, imagine there's
a chair." Nobody will accept that, will you?
"We don't see any chair." "There is a chair."
"No, no, but imaginary, there is one, I have
placed it, you can't see it, I have made it
invisible, you see. You just sit down on it."
Alright you sit down, and you sit in that
position and after some time you start getting
the pain. Where's the chair, how do I get
the pain. That's what Warren told you, it's
very practical. You immediately know that
this is not the way.
Now the first centre is very important, is
of the innocence, which gives you the magnetic
power. In the sense not only that you are
attractive but, I mean you attract people,
but magnetic means that you know whether you
are moving to the north or to the south. Birds
have this power in them, birds have. That's
how they fly from one place to another. Because
they can feel the magnet within. And the person
who is pure at that point, he never gets lost
because he knows which side he's moving. I
mean, I have, I have never had a problem like
that. I move either to the left or to the
right, or to forward. And My husband who is
dealing with shipping, he says, "I've never
met a better navigator than my wife." And
it's so spontaneous, I mean, I don't have
to think, I know for definite that you are
moving in the wrong direction or in the right
direction. Even the material movement are
(inaudible). All of them have it, even they're
great drivers and they have got all the maps
and everything. And immediately I know that
you are going on the wrong direction because
the magnet immediately turns round. So the
magnet is placed within you there but it is
to be awakened. When it is awakened - these
deities when they're awakened - you become
the truth, like the light that comes within,
you start seeing everything as far as your
feelings are concerned, your experiencing
is concerned. So you become the truth.
Now one may say how truth could be love. That's
a very common question. Truth cannot be love
because, I mean, if you tell somebody something
that is truth, he may not like, and he may
be unhappy and it may not be dear to him,
and he might be very, very worried about it.
Manu said long time back that you should speak
the truth and you must speak the things which
are dear to others. "Satyam vade, priyam vade."
People said it's not possible, it's an absurd
situation, how can you do it? So Krishna has
put something in between, he said, "Satyam
vade, hitam vade, priyam vade." You say something
that is the truth, always say the truth, and,
saying something, hitam means for the pleasing
of the spirit. That's the condition. And ultimately
that becomes a very dear thing. In the beginning
one may not like it, but ultimately, this
will be very much liked, this truth. So all
these things he has put together and said
that, "You have to speak the truth, the truth
has to be pleasing to the spirit, and ultimately,
the person is going to enjoy it."
So the truth is everything is illusion, except
for the Divine of God that is all-pervading
which you can feel through your spirit. This
power has got telecommunications. It has got
all that you have created in the science.
It can coordinate and cooperate. It has got
all the angels and all the great hosts to
help it and to look after you. And the top,
toppng the whole thing is the quality that
is love, is love. So it doesn't come to you
like a sword, it gives you the time to improve,
to judge yourself, to rise, to grow. Just
as a mother would look after her child, forgive
mistakes, see that the child rises and grows
into complete manhood. So it is love and the
love that is so powerful is the truth; and
it never fails, it never fails. For example
you might think now a man like Sadat has died.
"Mother how do you explain?" I mean, you never
die, that's one thing you do not know. He
can be born again, he would be born in such
a condition where he'll be much more effective.
He has himself died at the top of his glory.
I mean, for him, he's a (inaudible). If you
see from his angle, everywhere in the whole
world, Sadat. Sa-dat, it's a big name too.
But supposing he had fallen in his glory and
all that, then he would have died, then God
would not have been just to him, I would say.
But he died in all his glory and he can be
born again. And he can take a position from
where he can do much better work, in the name
of God, in the field of God because now we
don't have to do any more work, otherwise
in any other field. We have had enough of
trains, we don't want any more now. We have
had enough of plastics, now we have mountains.
We've got too much of butter around, too much
of food, everything abit too much, I mean
the house becomes a junk.
In any field we have overdone things. We have
exhausted this Mother Earth. Now what do we
have to do. Only in one field and the field
that is of God's work you have to do. But
first you have to get connected and then do
the God's work. And that connection is only
through your spirit, when you become absolute
and you have the truth within you as a built-in
awareness. It's the awareness that becomes
the truth. So the first quality of the spirit
is that you become the truth, that you know
the truth, that you take a stand on the truth.
Look at Christ. He had nothing to do with
women like Mary Magdalene, I mean, nothing
to do, I mean, he was virtue, he was innocence.
But when he saw people were stoning her, he
took up a stand. He took up a stand. You have
to take up a stand, stand on the truth. And
he said those who have not committed any sin
can throw, and you can throw the stone at
me. And nobody did. He did this because he
was standing on the truth. He took a whip
and whipped those people who were selling
in the temple of God. At eight, when he was
a little boy, he went and argued with learned
people. Such people have no fear of anything.
What is there to fear?
When you are standing on the truth, what is
there to fear? Truth is such a light that
it gives you complete picture of the whole
thing. There's nothing to fear. Your Father,
He is compassion, He's ocean of compassion.
And He's ocean of love and ocean of forgiveness.
And He is now within you. Who is more powerful
than Him? It's very easy for many human beings
to say, "Oh, we don't believe in God." You
believe it or not, He's there. Those who say,
"We don't believe", it is better that they
should come and get their realisation and
understand that there's very little time left
for such kind of nonsensical statements. I
mean you can at the most say that I've not
felt God so far and I'm open, if I feel. But
on what basis do you deny, what basis have
you got to say that you don't believe in God?
Not only after realisation you can prove God,
but you can show His miracles.
The second thing, the nature of spirit is
that he's chitta, he's the attention. He's
the attention means when you become spiritually
enlightened your attention becomes enlightened.
Now enlightenment, what we understand of these
lights is that the lights are falling here,
and we can see things, that's all. But this
attention which is being enlightened, acts,
it works, it has got loops, it has got weapons,
it works. You have to see for yourself how
your attention works.
Today there was somebody who went and told
one of the Sahaja Yogis that, "I was sitting
there and I was getting all negative thoughts
and feeling horrible in my hands and I don't
know why it was happening in the program."
First he said, "Here you have come to pay
attention to Mother and to Her work and pay
attention to your spirit. But if you're paying
attention to all the people here, then you're
going to suffer." It's a very simple thing,
where is your attention? Ask this question.
This is a very common question in an Indian
home, a mother will ask a child, "Where is
your attention?" The basis of Indian life
is chitta nirodh, is to fix your attention
in a proper way. Where is your attention?
Is it on your spirit? Or is it on somebody
else, like, "My brother is sitting here, my
mother is sitting there, oh, that woman is
very bad, she's jealous of me," all these
nonsense. Where is your attention? When you
get realised then you start seeing through
the window of the spirit, your position changes.
As you're looking at Me now, then you come
back here and start looking at you different.
Till you're realised you are sitting before
Me. But once you're realised you come here
and see others from there, that's your fort.
Nobody can touch you there. From there you'll
see others, your attention is detached.
So the attention becomes enlightened after
realisation. You pay attention to anything,
it works. It does work, no doubt, it fact.
Those who've got realisation should try, try
your attention, but attention has to be pure.
You have to purify your attention, and the
best way to purify it is to keep your agnya
chakra open. When this centre is open, which
is the centre of Christ, which I've shown
that it can only open through the Lord's Prayer,
after realisation. When you open that, then
you are in that state where your attention
is divine. And you'll be amazed how things
work out, even the smallest things, the material
things, the useless things and the great things,
and the subtle and subtlest, and how you start
growing. So the growth is to be achieved by
purifying your attention, and to purify this
attention is to keep your agnya chakra open
and be in thoughtless awareness. You watch
something, you don't think about it. Zen said
the same thing but I think people didn't understand,
you see, before realisation it's like telling
about colours to a blind man. Zen said the
same thing, you watch the thing without thinking
about it. They created patterns which didn't
mean anything, which you see it without thinking.
But that's only possible after realisation.
So the thinking process minimises and you
start witnessing.
The higher state than that of attention is
that you jump into Nirvikalpa Samadhi, into
the state of doubtless awareness. Now it is
not doubtlessness because you've argued it
out or anything. But it's a state where you're
doubtless about things. I mean the way you
feel, the way you behave, the way your attention
is, you can make it out that "I'm doubtlessly
there." The discrimination becomes so sharp
that you can just say, "This is so and so
and so," there's no fanaticism about it. As
I told you this morning that if a blind man
cross over something and says, "Oh there's
a snake here," and you believe it's a snake,
you believe that's a snake, that's fanaticism.
Because he has no eyes to see and you believe
it's a snake, he says, "Oh, there is a snake
there, I believe." But to a person who has
eyes, he knows it's a rope, it's just a rope.
And he says, "No, it's not, it's a rope."
But he has eyes and when he says with his
eyes, he can see that, that it's a rope, he
means it, the truth, then he's not a fanatic.
But he's standing on the truth. This subtle
difference people don't understand. Fanaticism
comes through blindness and the truth comes
through realisation. And at any cost you'll
not give up the truth, any cost.
Now when I started My work in 1970, somehow
I knew all about these fake gurus and fake
people, I knew about them. And in My first
lecture, we had about, must be having about
two, three thousand people, very huge hall,
and I told the names of all these fake people
and who they were in previous lives and what
they did, by name. And everybody was amazed
at Me, they were frightened. There was a Maharajah
who was a friend of My husband and all that,
and he came and told Me that, "Oh Mataji,
I am very frightened for you." I said, "Why?"
He said, "These people are horrid, they mint
money, they mint their whole earnings out
of it. How did you say these things openly,
(inaudible), they will shoot you." I said,
"Let them shoot. I'll see who shoots Me."
They said, "You see they will prosecute you."
I said, "Let them prosecute." So many years
have passed, nobody has dared to say that
I'm telling the lie.
There is no fear. You love, but you don't
love satanic people, you don't love Satans.
The Satan who has spoiled the Kundalini of
people, who have spoiled all the chances of
their getting realisation, as a mother, do
you think I should say they're very good people?
I'm not a political figure and I'm not seeking
election. Cannot be a compromise. That's what
happens to you also. But by your own self-esteem,
by your own glory, people see, "Here is a
leader", and you become the leader of the
people. You can, there is nothing to be frightened
of. There should be no half-bakes, as Christ,
as he read it out to you, that luke-warm people
he spits them out of the mouth. If you're
hot, if you're devils, he'll fight you; if
you're cold, you're my children. But luke-warm
people are cunning, because all kinds of forces
are pulling, there's no progress of any kind.
You come, you come, negative, positive, they're
pulled this way, that way. There cannot be
compromise with truth. And then you would
see you will have the real connecting force,
the real blessings of God, in every way. You
don't have to worry about money, you don't
have to worry about anything, it all works
out, everything works out. You can't believe
it how much it works out.
I'll tell you about these Australians: Australians
were finding it very difficult to get a place
to have an ashram, and, one day, frantically
one of the girls telephoned to me, "Mother,
we cannot have a place, now we don't know
where to go, we've sold our houses, we have
no place to go to." I said, "Don't you worry,
tomorrow, you'll get it." And she was surprised
how I told her, "Tomorrow you'll get it."
After telephoning and all that, she went home
and she received a call, I mean there was
a call from a estate agent. When they went
to see him next day he said, "There is an
ashram available, would you like to have it?".
At a very cheap rate, they got a beautiful
house for the ashram.
In London, we had some sort of a small ashram,
they were finding it very difficult for all
these people to live there, because they wanted
to live together. They said, "Mother, we must
have some more room and some more place."
I said, "Alright you just pray, it will work
out." You won't believe, we had started a
co-op in London, and they said it will take
eight years to get a room out of this co-op.
That's London for you, just the opposite of
America. And within a month's time, we got
a huge house, huge house with fifteen bedrooms
and two big halls and we didn't know what
to do with it, and at such a cheap rate that
for the whole week, only seventy pounds were
to be paid. But then the Sahaja Yogis went
and settled down there because in London we
have in thousands. Then they said, "Mother
what about for others?" And within fifteen
days we got a huge big hotel with all carpets
and with all curtains and everything provided
for, cutlery, crockery, anything you say was
there. Everything, only for ninety pounds
a week, for at least twenty people to live
very happily and big rooms each and big halls.
That we got it. You won't believe that it
has happened just before Warren's marriage
and we didn't know where they're going to
stay, all of these who were coming to get
married here, and they had a nice honeymoon
in that hotel. They didn't have to pay anything
for it. Yes, it works out. Krishna has said,
"Yoga kshema wahamyaham." You get to your
yoga first, he never said, "Kshema yoga,"
he said, "Yoga kshema wahamyaham." You get
your realisation, you get your yoga and then
the kshema, the well-being works out.
Everything is organised then for you, you're
on the stage, everyone works for you, believe
Me, it happens that way. What is there to
hanker after, what is there to ask for, I
mean you ask for one thing, you have thousands,
you don't know what to do with them. I don't
know, really, I don't know with Myself, I
don't know what to do , the way, I'm quite
generous, I mean, I try to give away so many
things but still My house, oh God! You can't
imagine, you can't imagine, in their wedding
I gave fifty-one saris, fifty-one, thinking
that now I'll some left from these saris.
Again I went back, they're still there. I
don't know, now what am I to do, I brought
now some to America, to give away and all
that, you just give and you get, everything,
you get fed-up.
But only thing that I always have been asking
for are the seekers. Where are they lost,
where are they? That's something still there,
they are to be saved, because as I told you
Christ is going to come back with eleven destructive
powers and there's going to be no question,
no realisation, just... All the negative forces
will be killed and those who enter into the
kingdom of God will reside in the kingdom
of God, will reside there, the residents,
the citizens. As he said, if you want money,
I'll give you gold. But I look after those
who hanker after spirit. You enter through
the door and he eats with you, he shares with
you. For a realised soul the highest human
beings are the seekers. You may be any king
or anything, what does it matter, there are
so many roaming about. But a seeker is the
thing in the eyes of God as the highest human
being, first to become a super-human being.
So your attention is (inaudible), so many
of these miracles, you cannot imagine. How
many have taken place with Sahaja Yogis, can
write such a big book. So the attention becomes
pure. You just can't see bad things happening,
I mean, you just don't like it, I mean, I
feel like vomitting sometimes, the way things
are, sometimes. The things that you enjoy
normally become absolutely garbage, with the...
don't like it, the whole, the priority is
changed. If you become automatically virtuous,
I don't have to tell you, "Be virtuous," you
just become, and you start enjoying your virtue
and virtues of others. You start enjoying
other people because attention becomes collectively
conscious. Our central nervous system is our
attention but the central nervous system becomes
collectively conscious, becomes. You're not
bothered, somebody has cancer, it's alright,
I'll try to cure it. You are not afraid you'll
get cancer, nothing, you're never afraid of.
I'll try, you'll put your hands like this,
like that. That fellow says, "Oh I'm feeling
very much better, I don't know, what have
you done for me?" Nothing. The attention becomes
so effective, so powerful, it does tremendous
things and attention among yourselves has
a rapport. They all move like the several
drops in an ocean, in a wave of love, it's
so beautiful.
The white men came to India long time back
as (inaudible), but when they came with Me,
if you see, we have some films, how the Indian
villagers, you see, took them to their heart,
danced with them, fed them, loved them, it's
so sweet. And they write to them, it's so
beautiful, there's no artificiality, it's
not just assuming, "I love you, you love me",
it's not that. It's just the enjoyment of
the company of other realised souls. We talk
of victims, "Oh we are all brothers and sisters,"
it's all talk, talk, talk, talk, talk. Then
you just become, you forget your colour, you
forget your nationality, you forget everything,
you just feel, oh, as a Sahaja Yogi. It's
a very different plane into which you arrive
where you feel so happy, joyous, the whole
thing is a fun. And when it comes to helping,
all of them contribute. When they find a negative
force is coming, all of them come together.
There is never a discussion among them, never.
They try to pull him out. They tell him, all
of them will tell by their own ways and methods
that this is wrong, this is wrong. It's such
a combination, I never have to tell them.
I don't have to tell them that I'll give you
some lessons now, for example how to carry
on, among yourselves, nothing, they just manage.
Not only that but a person will say, "Now
see," A will say to B, "I am catching on my
Agnya, will you help me there." That means,
"I'm ego." And the other fellow will say,
"Alright I'll try" They just help each other,
without feeling bad, there's no remorse of
anything, there's no heart burning, no jealousy.
What a relationship is established like one
singer doesn't have jealousy with the other,
she has no jealousy with the other cell of
the same primordial. There's no need even
to talk of love, you are in love. Everybody
can see that you love. It's really working
how you become so much adaptable, so much
silent and happy people, when our attention
becomes collectively conscious, because that's
the real source of joy. And the greatest quality
of the spirit is that you're pure joy. It's
pure joy. We talk of unhappiness and happiness,
sorrow and ecstasy and all these words, but
joy is pure. It hasn't got the duality. It's
one, single, absolute.
I'm leaving you and My heart is wrenching.
The joy is seeing that. Seeing that this Nirmala
is wrenching, bleeding. The joy is seeing
and when I go, this feeling, everything and
outlook of you and the joy will be again visible.
That joy of oneness even in separation the
oneness I feel, it's such a joy..., that cannot
be expressed in words, that silent (inaudible)
of your heart, that is also joy. Joy is absolute,
it comes through seeing, you see it and you
get the joy. Joy is the quality when you gradually
move from the brain, the attention first goes
into the brain, especially in the West, it's
the brain first, takes place. Here it becomes
the attention, I'm sorry, you become the truth.
You start feeling in the hand, you understand,
then you'll see, "Yes, it is so and this person
has got this trouble, so he must be having
arthritis, he's catching on this (inaudible)."
You start tallying, finding out and monitoring
this and again verifying it and you are satisfied
with it. So the attention first is nothing
but start appealing this truth. It's trying
to feel the truth but it's blocked at that
stage, it's trying. In the West, special,
because we are differently made in the West.
Then you read the book "Advent", you like
it and you see all these things and knowledge
and all the things you like and you want to
listen to My speech and all that. Your life
is (inaudible) knowledge because you're seeing
the truth, the knowledge. That's the gift
of the brain, is the central path as I just
said, the awareness. Then you feel your chitta,
your attention which is enlightened, and you're
blasted with it. You see the miracles happening,
that happening, you're just blasted.
Then the third thing happens; is the joy,
that you are in joy all the time. You cannot
be serious for more than two minutes, it's
very difficult to keep serious. The sense
of humour is so beautiful, you'll never use
vulgarity or hurting things or coarser remarks,
but the whole thing is so beautiful. When
you speak, people feel the flowers throwing
their fragrance at you. Every action that
you do creates joy, ripple of joy. Every movement
you create, every rhythm you speak it gives
you joy. That time you feel perfected. When
you see a picture which is beautiful, immediately
you go into thoughtless awareness, and the
complete joy of that creation starts blossoming,
you just feel the joy. When you become silent,
you don't think much, you don't think, you
become the joy, anand. That's the perfect
state in which you feel peace, it's so beautiful
that you want to be there all the time. This
joy is the movement of your ocean of love.
It's the beautiful movement of the clouds
that you see. It's fantastic, you just get
drenched into it and you do everything for
love's sake and you don't think you're doing
it for love's sake, you do not see that way,
you just do it, because it's so joy-giving;
that it is the greatest thing, you may have
anything in the world will not be that much
joy-giving as this joy of the spirit within.
You'll never feel lonely, you're never bored,
whether you're alone or with anyone, you are
in joy. One should understand that if you
get your self-realisation or if somebody says
that they're giving you some positive mind,
you should know, are you peaceful within you,
are you joy; forget about the collective consciousness,
is your health alright? That's the minimum
of minimum. The whole system changes. I just
pray that all of you should achieve that state
of joy by the time I come here next year.
And I hope you grow in it by taking up a stand
on the truth. Grow into it. You progress into
it. It's so wonderful and so beautiful and
that's what your Father wants you to have.
He's the most generous Father; He can't enjoy
His kingdom unless and until He has given
it to you, that He has made you sit on His
throne. That's the greatest joy that He wants
to have and that's what you should achieve,
that's what you should have, that's your right
to have.
This is what is self-realisation - you become
just the master. You don't have to consult
anyone, you know it. You have to just consult
your spirit, through your vibratory awareness
and you know it. These are the blessings of
self-realisation, into which you have to grow
and as you grow you start manifesting your
powers. You can raise the Kundalini, you can
give realisation at the very outset. Imagine
the Kundalini moves under your fingers, nobody
can believe it but it has happened now. Even
very, very great saints, you see, there is
a very great saint who is more than hundred
and eight years of age, and he asked Me, "Mother,
I have spent thousands of years to get these
vibrations and these people have got it without
any (inaudible)." I said, "Why did you do
it, who asked you to do it? If you'd taken
it easy, you'd have got it." He's a very sweet
fellow, but because he's got it through his
efforts he has that feeling that, "I've got
it through my efforts." You'll never get it
through effort, I tell you. When you're finished
with your efforts you just get it, maybe in
an abstraction, or maybe...Yes, when Buddha
was tired, finished, fagged-out, then he got
his realisation. When you stop your efforts
then only you'll get your realisation. So
why to boast of your efforts, I told him.
He's a very powerful man because he's done
lots of things and he always goes on a big,
very big tiger and because he's hurt himself,
he says that people have beaten him, so he's
hurt himself so he always uses a tiger. And
he's a man with the idea that he has this
power, that power. When I went to see him,
I knew that because he told people that Mother
has come, so you go and see Her and all that
and I knew he was there so I went to see him.
When I went to see him, we had to climb about
three miles, one has to walk up, and I was
walking up and when I reached there it was
raining and I got completely drenched. And
this fellow is supposed powers over the rain.
And he was so angry when I went there he was
sitting on a little seat of his made of some
straws. He was doing like this, like this,
very angry. So I didn't say anything, I went
inside his thing and sat down there in that
drenched condition. He came down and he said,
"Mother, did you do this to kill my ego?"
I said, "What, I didn't do anything. What
did I do?" He said, "This rain wouldn't listen
to me." I said, "Now, don't be angry, sit
down. Haven't you bought a sari for Me, and
you are a sanyasi, I won't take a sari from
a sanyasi now. You've have got a sari for
Me isn't it? So I have to get drenched, otherwise
I will not take a sari from you." And the
whole temper melted, whole temper melted away.
Then I said, "It was necessary the water to
flow over My body so that all the plains around
you become beautiful, is vibrated with water."
But he is a very great soul I must say, because
he doesn't talk to Me like ordinary human
beings talk. His style is different because
he recognises, he knows who I am. He's a very
different being, and a day will come when
you will also rise, you'll rise and grow and
grow and there we'll see the glory of this
great new age, new generation into the complete
newness of the (inaudible).
Today I was going to tell you about certain
diseases that one has and how to control them
and I would suggest that we have a book, are
you going to sell it to everyone? We don't
have many. So we would say those who have
been coming for all the four lectures should
buy the book. We're sorry we don't have many
books but we hope to send you these books
later on and it's a very good book in which
we can see what imbalances can work out, like
how you get diabetes, how you get kidney trouble,
blood pressure and then how you have to balance
your liver, and how to look after the security
and all these things are written in that book
at length. Quite a knowledgeable book I should
say.
I took the writer, I should say I really tortured
him. And everyday I used to see him coming
up pulling his ear, you see, that I don't
know what mistakes I'm going to do. And everytime
he would come, I would say, "Now, Gregoire
you have to be sweeter. It's not that sweet,
you're still a scholar, you have to be a Sahaja
Yogi," and a Sahaja Yogi is different from
a scholar, he writes his book in such a manner,
in such a way that it's sweet, it's lovable,
it's kind and I've tried really to curb it
down, curb it down. But he has written two
chapters of his scholarliness, all the scholarliness
that he has, and it was like the really big
boulder (inaudible) enter into that book.
So one day I told him. "These two chapters
let us put it at the end of the book," and
he really collapsed. He said, "Mother, how
can you do that to me, it's too much." I said,
"But why, what's the problem?" He said, "These
two chapters are the ones which introduce
the book and how can you do it, I mean, it's
in the beginning and how can you put it at
the end." I said, "Gregoire, while correcting
the book, I saw to it that these chapters
have nothing to do with the beginning, so
you put them at the end." And he (inaudible),
"Oh the book has become wonderful." And then
he told me it'a a very good play of Mother
in this, that the intellectuals are never
satisfied with the reason why, and they would
like to go into the intellectual rumination.
Like the animals, you see, like cows when
they eat, then they take it back and again
eat it, like that. It's better to put these
two chapters for them. I said, "Now you are
not angry with me?" He said, "No, it's a very
good thing." But these two chapters definitely
prove that he's a very learned man. And I
told him, "Gregoire, when did you read all
these books that you've quoted." He said,
"Mother, you'll be surprised, these quotations
just came to me, and I never, I never read
them." I said, "You never read them?" "Yes,
yes I've read them before, sometime I must
have read them, but at the right time, I got
the right quotation."
He's now coming to Los Angeles, he is a diplomat
in the Swiss government, and he's coming all
the way from Rome. (inaudible), and he's a
very dynamic person, I'm looking forward to
My visit to Los Angeles. If you have any friends
there or anything you can write to them, you
can take the address from here so that they
can come and see you. We have now booked all
our dates, I'm sorry and still we'll contact
somebody from Unity Church, but all the days
are booked. It's alright, the people can come
in any case whenever you have the program.
Anything else you want you can write to Me.
I'm sorry I can't write to you because everyday
I work, like this the way I've been working,
morning, the workshops, evening, the lecture.
It has been on and on for years together now.
So, I do write sometimes, but I don't have
the time, but somebody will answer you. Any
question, any problem, anything, please write.
I'll be very happy to receive letters from
you and there are so many people who are sorting
them out and looking after this, you will
have an answer no doubt. Please get My address
also from the ashram address from these people.
Anything that you want you can ask for it.
Even sitting down here I know your attention.
It will work out. Gradually you will change
and your asking will be different and different
and different.
May God bless you, blossom into the beauty
of your spirit so that you'll glorify your
Father and this is glorified with His gracious
love towards you.
Thank you very much.