I am so very filled with joy
and My heart is so full of gratitude for
all the Sahaja Yogis who have been able
to create this beautiful place.
I cannot imagine how much they must have worked hard
in such a place to create such  a beautiful
area, such a blissful place.
How in Sahaja Yoga people work together
with tremendous respect and love for each other,
and produce something that is unbelievable.
This was just a wilderness,
and you have brought so much of
life and light in this place.
You wanted to celebrate My birthday.
I don't know what is such a significant about it.
But the way you have really
shown your understanding and respect,
I am just enamored.  I can't  understand
what have I done for you, that
you should do so much for Sahaja Yoga.
As it is, today is also a very auspicious day
which we call as the Holi.
They play Holion this day and show their love
and oneness among themselves.
This is the time when we have to
really understand the value of love,
of respect of others,
because so far we have based all our theories and
all our ideas on the principle that human beings
cannot love each other: they are always trying to overpower others
or to hate others, or to grab things from others.
Such a wrong idea we had all these days,
and that's why all the organizations that were created
to obstruct it also got contaminated with it.
The only way one can really understand
what we are is by knowing yourself.
When you know yourself you are surprised that
what is the greatest thing for you is to love and to be loved.
You enjoy that collective love so much
when you are absolutely overcome
your baser self. In Sahaja Yoga it is so simple.
It works in a very simple manner.
It's very Sahaja, but to grow into it is very important,
and I am so very happy to see so many of you
from all over the world, from Delhi and also from all over India,
enjoying that love among yourselves
and understanding among yourselves.
I never expected that in My lifetime
I'll be able to see all this beautiful
world of love, trust and peace.
But today really I must say it shows
what we are capable of doing.
We human beings, so-called, are very selfish, self-centered
and only worried about ourselves:
that is what is said; but it's surprising
that with Self-Realization, with self-knowledge,
with knowing yourself, you understand how rich you are within,
how great you are within and how capable you are.
This understanding comes to you,
and then that is expressed in such a beautiful manner.
Sahaja Yoga took time to grow, slowly and slowly,
and that you all have slowly and slowly grown also.
But today I must say that it has reached such a height
that it's difficult for people to get out of it.
When you know yourself, when you know what is reality
and what is absolute truth,
you just get dissolved into that knowledge.
Of course you are not knowledgeable in the way people are;
you are knowledgeable in the real sense of the word,
because you realize what is within you is a big power of love.
There's a big power of understanding.
There's a big power of understanding,
a big power of oneness, of collective.
This collectivity works wonders
and gives such joy that we are all one,
we have no enemies, we have no problems.
We are all one together.
This joy that was expressed by you
is like the waves that go to the shores,
touch the shores and come back, creating beautiful patterns.
And I see that happening now,
that these beautiful patterns are showing in your own life,
in your lifestyle, in your behavior.
There is a very special type of human race is sitting before Me.
I am so much thankful to you, absolutely,
that you should take to this simple knowledge of yourself
and enjoy it with others.
It's something remarkable that you know about yourself,
that's only human beings can do.
There can be a diamond, very expensive,
but it doesn't know its value.
There could be some dog or some animal
which must be something par excellence,
but he doesn't know what he is.
Same thing happens with the human beings
till they get their Self-Realization,
and after Realization they suddenly become aware of what they are.
And then suddenly they become very humble, they become very loving.
Now supposing if somebody knows that he is a king,
or he discovers that he is a some great musician or a
prime minister or something: he feels very aloof
and he thinks no end of himself.
But by this knowledge that you have,
you become one with the rest of Sahaja Yogis and enjoy it.
It's very remarkable how it works out
that you enjoy each other so much,
and to do something for this collective work,
you can dedicate yourself to it.
Now My experience of seventy-seven years, as you can say,
has been really checkered with all kinds of incidents,
all kinds of people, all kinds of incidents.
And it's a good vision to see
before your eyes that despite all that,
so many beautiful lotuses have come out,
and they are so fragrant, so beautiful,
so colorful, so attractive.
All this is because we have a innate  value system,
because we have inborn within us a great
sense of love and compassion.
This compassion has to be really
understood and enjoyed, and jump in the ocean of compassion.
So beautiful, and you'll be amazed to see
that automatically you'll swim,
automatically you'll meet other people also in the same ocean,
and without any problems, without any troubles,
all enjoying the bliss of this love,
this compassion, this Divine love.
I must really congratulate
the Delhi people for coming up so well
with this beautiful arrangement  and this beautiful pendal,
and all the beautiful arrangements
they have made outside for your stay.
I mean really it's something,
I have done nothing for it, nothing, I should say.
How these people have worked together:
there have been no quarrels, fighting,
backbiting, nothing of the kind. It's very surprising
that such a beautiful thing has been created by them:
shows their maturity in Sahaja Yoga.
I must congratulate them again and again
for doing this great work
in such a short time.
First I talked in English because
here many people have come from foreign countries
and you don't have any objection
that I talk in English for a little while.
Although it is a great thing of Dehlites
and along with them the people of Uttarpradesh also joined.
People of Rajasthan also joined and the people from Haryana also helped.
All of them have collectively made with love this
very beautiful pandal like a temple.
On seeing it I was Myself surprised
that here are such talented artists.
I didn't know.
Wherefrom this art came?
How did they make it and decorate all this, I can't understand.
I didn't know that there are artists of such caliber in our country
and that too caliber of love.
The power of 'love' and the art of 'love'
the art of loving everybody
whosoever will get it, he only can do such an artistic composition.
One should learn this art
how can we with the help of our speech, mind and wisdom
become artists, artists of 'love'
and how can we give comfort to others
and joy to others.
Which lovable talk is such that we can do.
One it is with the help of speech
then with wisdom how can we think?
How can we shower our love among people?
How can we open our heart in front of others
and establish them in our heart?
And we should think that the heart which doesn't have love
he is not an authority of anything in the world.
Because whatever he gets, he cannot be contented in any way with that
he cannot get contentment.
But when there is an ocean of contentment within you
what is it that cannot content you?
When it happens within you and you get the solution
then, nobody can understand the boundries of that solution
that nobody can understand this business.
Such melodious and such beautiful all that happens
you cannot overlook it.
Can't understand what i am doing and what others are doing
what they are saying and what i am saying.
And how are they covering me with their love
and how shall we shower them with our love.
Day and night the same worry goes on
that today whom I have to meet
and what loving things should I tell them.
What useful things should be talked about.
Because the practice of talking about useless things
leads only to loss.
It has never been useful
and more than that the anger that is there in a human being
leads to all the more complications.
There was no need to teach you not to do violence
don't treat anyone badly
don't destroy anyone
don't grab somebody's money.
There is no need to teach all this.
You became so dignified on your own.
I said now you too have become lotuses
that you know to give only your fragrance
and don't know anything else.
And the joy of giving to others
and to feel its joy is a strange experience.
Only people of unique character can do it.
Now you are the masters of it
and the heritage that we had kept with you
you have utilized fully.
Now that thing is open to everyone
it didn't harm anyone.
Now it is a matter of enjoyment.
Many people in the world are of different types
but they cannot touch you
cannot bother you.
Even if there can be something, that too may be absorbed by you.
let them join you.
Watching your lifestyle
let them have atleast the inclination to change their life.
Let us also change.
I don't say that
I have signed the contract of changing this whole world
but you can sign this contract.
If you will change this world
If you invite moral, kind and gentle people
there is no need to do anything more.
then you go on looking at it.
The only important thing is that you get attatched to it
Get engaged into it and find out how many people can we transform?
I agree that an ordinary man has got a number of flaws.
A man full of flaws you can
very beautifully give knowledge of a good and unknown self
the self within us.
When you come into contact with the spirit inside us
you come to know that others too must do so.
know yourself all the more.
They are lost.
They don't know how much prime wealth they have inside them.
So, they must be given it
and they must get it.
When such conversations will start taking place
you will take its responsibility on your ownself
that we too should give others this prime wealth.
Their keys are with you
and if you somehow give this great contribution
just watch how they will recognize you
and how they will be greatful to you.
The greatest work for you now is that
you bring as many people as you can to Sahaja state
and give them this wealth
and when this will happen
you will yourself get busy and be happy
and a type of joy which cannot be described
you will get.
This has to be done.
Today you have celebrated My Birthday.
I should say a lot of thanks for that
and you have done all this joyfully
but for Me it is so that every year Sahajyoga has been spreading
and even I too cannot understand its boundries.
But today you too must take a decision
that on the birthday of Mother we will try to transform others.
Our transformation has already been done but must do of others as well.
This only  will give you complete contentment of this joy.
Till now the joy you have is limited
when you will distribute it among others
and when it will be echoed in others
when you will come to know about it, understand it
a great new joy will awaken within yourself.
I was watching your young boys, children dancing joyfully.
Krishna got celebrated Holi so that everybody get joy.
Shri Ram's style made a human being very serious type.
His life became serious.
He (Shri Krishna) devised a method so that a human being
cound open up himself and play mirthfully.
Now that thing only Sahajyogis can do practically
can play Holi with love amongst themselves.
Not to trouble others
but to express their own joy and to make feel others joyous as well.
Eternal blessings to everyone.