1
00:00:03,567 --> 00:00:15,801
Face yourself for becoming.

2
00:00:15,801 --> 00:00:32,934
Then the preparation is done to become something

3
00:00:32,934 --> 00:00:42,834
and on the whole, when you know that it is
your ego and superego which are loading you up,

4
00:00:42,834 --> 00:00:53,134
you have to scan them out with vibratory awareness.

5
00:00:53,134 --> 00:01:06,701
Now there are two types of attention we have to pay.

6
00:01:06,701 --> 00:01:13,901
First is a constant attention that is a routine of a Sahaja Yogi,

7
00:01:13,901 --> 00:01:22,934
and the second one is the emergency attention.

8
00:01:22,934 --> 00:01:31,401
I have been saying that all the Sahaja Yogis
must start writing their diaries:

9
00:01:31,401 --> 00:01:36,501
one with every day’s experiences,

10
00:01:36,501 --> 00:01:43,167
if you know that you have to write a diary,
you’ll keep your mind alert,

11
00:01:43,167 --> 00:01:49,734
and another whenever you get any special idea of the past or of the future,

12
00:01:49,734 --> 00:01:50,901
also to jot it down.

13
00:01:50,901 --> 00:01:54,501
So, like that, you should have two diaries.

14
00:01:54,501 --> 00:02:01,401
For your constant attention,
you have to fix up your mind on certain things.

15
00:02:01,401 --> 00:02:06,901
The first one, as I said, that if you keep a diary

16
00:02:06,901 --> 00:02:13,067
then you will know that you have to remember
what important things have happened.

17
00:02:13,067 --> 00:02:18,034
So your attention will be alert and
you will be looking out for such points,

18
00:02:18,034 --> 00:02:21,467
where, what is the thing you see.

19
00:02:21,467 --> 00:02:24,901
And you’ll be amazed, if you make your attention alert,

20
00:02:24,901 --> 00:02:29,501
what new things come to you -

21
00:02:29,501 --> 00:02:33,501
very brilliant ideas.

22
00:02:33,501 --> 00:02:42,034
And the miracles of life and the miracles of God’s beauty and His auspiciousness,

23
00:02:42,034 --> 00:02:45,501
His greatness, His kindness, His blessings -

24
00:02:45,501 --> 00:02:51,401
how they work out if you start writing every day even two lines about it.

25
00:02:51,401 --> 00:02:56,601
It will make your mind constantly involved with it.

26
00:02:56,601 --> 00:03:01,334
That’s a human style of doing things.

27
00:03:01,334 --> 00:03:08,501
Also you can mention in the diary

28
00:03:08,501 --> 00:03:11,501
what happened: did you, could you do your meditation?

29
00:03:11,501 --> 00:03:14,401
Did you get your time for meditation or not?

30
00:03:14,401 --> 00:03:21,901
A little bit as if you are appearing
for some sort of an examination or something,

31
00:03:21,901 --> 00:03:23,601
you prepare a little note like that:

32
00:03:23,601 --> 00:03:27,801
“Did I get up in the morning? Did I?”

33
00:03:27,801 --> 00:03:36,401
Then any special path or any special movement

34
00:03:36,401 --> 00:03:39,467
in the centre or left or right also should be mentioned

35
00:03:39,467 --> 00:03:42,167
so that you keep a watch on your mind.

36
00:03:42,167 --> 00:03:46,134
It’s a very good thing to maintain a diary.

37
00:03:46,134 --> 00:03:51,801
Also, you will see progressively how your ideas are changing,

38
00:03:51,801 --> 00:03:54,734
how new priorities are settling down,

39
00:03:54,734 --> 00:03:59,367
how you give more importance to real things

40
00:03:59,367 --> 00:04:04,667
and very little to unreal things.

41
00:04:04,667 --> 00:04:08,234
I think this is a very, very practical side of human beings

42
00:04:08,234 --> 00:04:10,901
that one should have a diary.

43
00:04:10,901 --> 00:04:16,401
Same diaries, after some time, will become historical things

44
00:04:16,401 --> 00:04:20,467
and people would like to see what you all have written.

45
00:04:20,467 --> 00:04:26,201
Not to be hypocritical about it or deceptive about it,

46
00:04:26,201 --> 00:04:30,501
but quite truthful and understanding.

47
00:04:30,501 --> 00:04:38,667
You should jot down few lines just before sleeping.

48
00:04:38,667 --> 00:04:47,334
Now we have to see that
we have problems for superego and ego.

49
00:04:47,334 --> 00:04:51,834
Now superego is the left side, is darkness,

50
00:04:51,834 --> 00:04:56,801
tamo guna and our past.

51
00:04:56,801 --> 00:05:01,401
Those who have left side problems should think of the future,

52
00:05:01,401 --> 00:05:05,401
it gives them balancing if they think of the future.

53
00:05:05,401 --> 00:05:15,401
For example, a person who is lethargic should take to working.

54
00:05:15,401 --> 00:05:18,701
Put your mind into working for the future planning:

55
00:05:18,701 --> 00:05:21,901
what to do, where to go, how to do.

56
00:05:21,901 --> 00:05:30,167
That will keep you away from drag of the left side

57
00:05:30,167 --> 00:05:40,401
and gradually then you can balance yourself also.

58
00:05:40,401 --> 00:05:52,601
Now the right side of a person, when it is activated very much,

59
00:05:52,601 --> 00:06:01,734
he has to balance it not with the left side but with the centre.

60
00:06:01,734 --> 00:06:09,567
That is, a person who is very hard-working

61
00:06:09,567 --> 00:06:14,801
must develop a witness state.

62
00:06:14,801 --> 00:06:19,801
You try to do a work, any work,

63
00:06:19,801 --> 00:06:28,000
indulge into work in thoughtless awareness, as a witness.

64
00:06:28,000 --> 00:06:35,067
 Whatever work you are doing you just say that:
“I am not doing it."

65
00:06:35,067 --> 00:06:37,701
This You can do it after Realisation.

66
00:06:37,701 --> 00:06:42,834
You become thoughtlessly aware and start doing your work.

67
00:06:42,834 --> 00:06:47,801
So the compensation of the left side is done by movement to the right,

68
00:06:47,801 --> 00:06:50,701
and of the right side [by] movement in the centre.

69
00:06:50,701 --> 00:06:54,401
Left side is the tamo guna, right side is the rajo guna,

70
00:06:54,401 --> 00:06:59,701
the centre is the sattwo guna.
But still these are three gunas.

71
00:06:59,701 --> 00:07:03,301
That’s not the state which we have to achieve.

72
00:07:03,301 --> 00:07:08,934
About this I’ll tell you tomorrow more,
how to go further then.

73
00:07:08,934 --> 00:07:13,401
After scanning out which side is weak,

74
00:07:13,401 --> 00:07:17,667
you should plan out your style of life.

75
00:07:17,667 --> 00:07:22,401
For example, if you are extremely lethargic,
you cannot get up in the morning,

76
00:07:22,401 --> 00:07:26,701
you feel very sleepy in the night, you do not feel alerted

77
00:07:26,701 --> 00:07:31,000
then start planning as to what will you do.
How will you get up?

78
00:07:31,000 --> 00:07:33,801
Even puja is a good idea, homa (havan) is a good idea.

79
00:07:33,801 --> 00:07:37,601
Do something like that, so that you have to do something,

80
00:07:37,601 --> 00:07:41,667
what you call the kriya, is the action,
get into the action.

81
00:07:41,667 --> 00:07:49,734
Some sort of action you go into in Sahaja Yoga as well as in your daily life

82
00:07:49,734 --> 00:07:54,301
you’ll be able to change that mood and come to the right side

83
00:07:54,301 --> 00:07:59,501
and then you’ll go to the,
your movement should be towards the sattwa guna,

84
00:07:59,501 --> 00:08:03,501
is to watch everything.

85
00:08:03,501 --> 00:08:09,901
Now at the sattwa guna point where you are in the centre

86
00:08:09,901 --> 00:08:17,501
you have to see how much you are misidentified.

87
00:08:17,501 --> 00:08:24,034
Say, supposing you are at the first stage of left side,

88
00:08:24,034 --> 00:08:29,167
then you will just do daydreaming,
“Oh! This person is so much identified,

89
00:08:29,167 --> 00:08:32,000
that one is so much identified,” as if you are the best.

90
00:08:32,000 --> 00:08:34,301
It’s just human nature, you see.

91
00:08:34,301 --> 00:08:36,701
“Oh, that person is like that, he is like that,

92
00:08:36,701 --> 00:08:41,701
this is very bad in the society,
that is going bad in the society. It’s better…”

93
00:08:41,701 --> 00:08:45,334
Then we can also go to this limit is to,
“That guru is very bad

94
00:08:45,334 --> 00:08:49,334
and that one is another madcap."
Like that, you see, all daydreaming going on.

95
00:08:49,334 --> 00:08:51,000
How far it is affecting you,

96
00:08:51,000 --> 00:08:53,034
how far are you improving by that is not…

97
00:08:53,034 --> 00:08:58,134
It’s just, you see, thinking, analysing.
It is, it's a lazy stuf,

98
00:08:58,134 --> 00:09:01,801
sitting down and just analysing, it's a lazy stuff.

99
00:09:01,801 --> 00:09:04,834
The second thing could be

100
00:09:04,834 --> 00:09:08,701
when you come to the second side of it, is the kriya.

101
00:09:08,701 --> 00:09:16,567
Then what happens when you start doing it,
then at least your attention is on what you are doing.

102
00:09:16,567 --> 00:09:20,801
It’s not allowed to drift into something
and which goes into any nonsense and can,

103
00:09:20,801 --> 00:09:25,134
I mean, then you don’t know from where the funny thoughts are coming.

104
00:09:25,134 --> 00:09:26,701
So, you start doing something.

105
00:09:26,701 --> 00:09:31,801
You can go and plant some trees
or you can go and plant some flowers

106
00:09:31,801 --> 00:09:34,734
or if you want you can do some cooking, you can do some work.

107
00:09:34,734 --> 00:09:39,167
Take to work! That will help you. Any work.

108
00:09:39,167 --> 00:09:44,467
But while doing the work the problem will be, you’ll develop ego.

109
00:09:44,467 --> 00:09:50,234
That’s why when you are developing the ego you have to tell yourself,

110
00:09:50,234 --> 00:09:53,367
“You are not doing, mister! This you are not doing,

111
00:09:53,367 --> 00:09:55,601
this is not doing, you are not doing.”

112
00:09:55,601 --> 00:09:57,701
If you go on suggesting to yourself,

113
00:09:57,701 --> 00:09:59,901
Mr. Ego will not come up.

114
00:09:59,901 --> 00:10:03,401
And then many things, you see,
which normally trouble you and trouble others

115
00:10:03,401 --> 00:10:06,567
like you have cleaned the room, alright.

116
00:10:06,567 --> 00:10:10,801
Then somebody comes and spoils it
you get angry with that person.

117
00:10:10,801 --> 00:10:14,401
Naturally! Because you think ‘you’ have done.

118
00:10:14,401 --> 00:10:17,834
First of all you don’t clean the room.
If you clean the room then you are prepared,

119
00:10:17,834 --> 00:10:22,601
it will be dirty, otherwise why should you clean?

120
00:10:22,601 --> 00:10:25,101
Now, if it is dirty, well and good;

121
00:10:25,101 --> 00:10:29,401
if it is not dirty, well and good.

122
00:10:29,401 --> 00:10:34,934
This type of attitude you should take to jump onto sattva guna.

123
00:10:34,934 --> 00:10:38,301
On sattva guna you start accepting it.

124
00:10:38,301 --> 00:10:43,701
You become extremely mild.
You become a mild personality.

125
00:10:43,701 --> 00:10:49,167
Then at that time you do not discuss as to, “Oh, I don’t like it;

126
00:10:49,167 --> 00:10:51,467
this was wrong; this should not have been."

127
00:10:51,467 --> 00:10:54,101
All these things do not come to you in sattva guna.

128
00:10:54,101 --> 00:10:58,067
You start seeing it. That time you see it

129
00:10:58,067 --> 00:11:01,134
that, “Alright, doesn’t matter.
 It’s done, it’s done.”

130
00:11:01,134 --> 00:11:05,501
On the contrary, you feel hurt if you are a sattwa guni,

131
00:11:05,501 --> 00:11:12,667
that by any suggestion you have suggested your ego.

132
00:11:12,667 --> 00:11:15,101
Can you get that point?

133
00:11:15,101 --> 00:11:19,101
You feel ashamed of your ego,
I mean to say, if you are a sattwa guni.

134
00:11:19,101 --> 00:11:25,301
For example, even to say that “This is my car,”
you will feel shy. That’s a sattwa guni type.

135
00:11:25,301 --> 00:11:27,601
Or even to say, “Why did you spoil my carpet?”

136
00:11:27,601 --> 00:11:30,167
I mean in India nobody will say,
I can tell you this!

137
00:11:30,167 --> 00:11:33,101
Is regarded [as] bad manners, absolute bad manners.

138
00:11:33,101 --> 00:11:36,367
If anybody comes to your house and the carpet
is spoiled they say, “Let it be, doesn’t matter."

139
00:11:36,367 --> 00:11:40,834
Even it is burnt, “I don’t know. Let it be. Are you burnt?”

140
00:11:40,834 --> 00:11:44,401
They’ll never say that, “You have burnt my carpet,
or done anything to my…”

141
00:11:44,401 --> 00:11:47,134
Is regarded bad manners.

142
00:11:47,134 --> 00:11:52,134
Like here, you see, if somebody’s sleeping
somebody makes the noise.

143
00:11:52,134 --> 00:11:57,167
The person who is sleeping will never say that
“You are making noise,

144
00:11:57,167 --> 00:12:02,167
He’ll just get up and ask,
“Do you need anything?”

145
00:12:02,167 --> 00:12:04,601
That’s difficult for people here to understand

146
00:12:04,601 --> 00:12:09,401
because ego is just sitting on the head.
But is bad manners there.

147
00:12:09,401 --> 00:12:12,501
You will find when you’ll go to India you’ll find this.

148
00:12:12,501 --> 00:12:18,401
These are bad manners to say that.
 Or to say, “Oh, I, I feel very comfortable.

149
00:12:18,401 --> 00:12:21,201
I mean, to say “I feel comfortable” is bad manners.

150
00:12:21,201 --> 00:12:24,701
I mean, they never say “I like it.”

151
00:12:24,701 --> 00:12:28,134
“So what?” All these words are not to be said.

152
00:12:28,134 --> 00:12:31,401
If you are a sattwa guni then you just don’t say,

153
00:12:31,401 --> 00:12:38,067
you will say, “Do you like it?
Is it comfortable? Would you like to have this?”

154
00:12:38,067 --> 00:12:47,067
The whole attention goes from your side.
Do you understand that?

155
00:12:47,067 --> 00:12:50,901
That is the style one has to develop.
Then you are a sattwa guni.

156
00:12:50,901 --> 00:12:54,167
Otherwise, you are still on ego trip.
You see, whatever you may think,

157
00:12:54,167 --> 00:13:00,401
“I don’t like that, I don’t…”
“I”- who are you?

158
00:13:00,401 --> 00:13:03,501
First of all, ask the question, “Who are you?”

159
00:13:03,501 --> 00:13:08,801
If God says, “I don’t like you,”
I can understand, with good reasons,

160
00:13:08,801 --> 00:13:11,134
but for you to say, “I don’t like it” …

161
00:13:11,134 --> 00:13:16,901
After all, how did you come on this earth?

162
00:13:16,901 --> 00:13:20,401
How did you get a human birth?

163
00:13:20,401 --> 00:13:24,801
How did you get all these things?
Now think like that.

164
00:13:24,801 --> 00:13:30,101
“Who am I?"

165
00:13:30,101 --> 00:13:33,101
"I am nothing."

166
00:13:33,101 --> 00:13:37,667
Anybody who thinks, “I am something,”
he should know that he’s nothing;

167
00:13:37,667 --> 00:13:45,801
makes no difference to God whether he exists or
does not exist, you see, he’s nothing, he’s just a drop.

168
00:13:45,801 --> 00:13:48,467
So, this point if you understand,

169
00:13:48,467 --> 00:13:50,067
that even if you do something,

170
00:13:50,067 --> 00:13:53,134
any work you do or anything you are doing,

171
00:13:53,134 --> 00:14:01,167
you are just doing it because you want to do it.

172
00:14:01,167 --> 00:14:04,467
That is how you come on to sattva guna.

173
00:14:04,467 --> 00:14:07,701
But normally it doesn’t happen.
It happens the other way round.

174
00:14:07,701 --> 00:14:17,234
For example, a person is, say, doing something

175
00:14:17,234 --> 00:14:19,534
by any chance he feels hurt

176
00:14:19,534 --> 00:14:22,134
or he thinks that whatever he has done is no good.

177
00:14:22,134 --> 00:14:25,367
People don’t appreciate,
or maybe he might think that,

178
00:14:25,367 --> 00:14:29,667
“Oh, it’s not up to the point,” or whatever it is,

179
00:14:29,667 --> 00:14:33,934
then the reaction for him is not that
he does not try to rise to sattva guna,

180
00:14:33,934 --> 00:14:39,367
but he goes back to tamo guna.

181
00:14:39,367 --> 00:14:44,867
“Alright, I’ll not do it. I’ll sleep over it.
 Let them do it, why should I do it?”

182
00:14:44,867 --> 00:14:52,101
So the training that you have to have
through your rajo guna goes a waste.

183
00:14:52,101 --> 00:14:56,434
It’s just a training period that you are with rajo guna.

184
00:14:56,434 --> 00:14:57,934
You are doing something.

185
00:14:57,934 --> 00:15:05,734
Now in that training period you have to learn
only how to come in the centre.

186
00:15:05,734 --> 00:15:13,734
For example, now, water is required for you to swim.
 If there is no water you cannot swim.

187
00:15:13,734 --> 00:15:20,834
All right? In the same way, rajo guna is required for you to come to sattwa guni.

188
00:15:20,834 --> 00:15:26,034
If you do not do any work you cannot come to sattwa guna.

189
00:15:26,034 --> 00:15:31,534
So you are just working just to train yourself to be a witness.

190
00:15:31,534 --> 00:15:33,267
Now do you follow that point?

191
00:15:33,267 --> 00:15:36,301
You are not doing it because you like particular thing,

192
00:15:36,301 --> 00:15:39,134
you are used to particular thing, because you want to be this.

193
00:15:39,134 --> 00:15:43,201
This is not the way it is.

194
00:15:43,201 --> 00:15:48,201
You are just doing it to learn how to be patient.

195
00:15:48,201 --> 00:15:54,734
To practice your patience.
 To see how much patient, you are.

196
00:15:54,734 --> 00:15:57,967
Once you start doing it, you’ll be amazed

197
00:15:57,967 --> 00:16:03,334
that you will never feel the burden of the work.

198
00:16:03,334 --> 00:16:05,734
But it never happens.

199
00:16:05,734 --> 00:16:13,067
Most of the people, if they find their work is
not effective, they’ll go back to tamo guna.

200
00:16:13,067 --> 00:16:15,734
There are many attitudes.
Say, somebody’s working,

201
00:16:15,734 --> 00:16:19,334
then he thinks, “Why should I do all the work?
Others are not doing!”

202
00:16:19,334 --> 00:16:23,867
He’ll go back to their stage.
 But those who are not working will not think that,

203
00:16:23,867 --> 00:16:27,234
“This person is working, let me also work.”

204
00:16:27,234 --> 00:16:30,634
It’s other way round, you see.

205
00:16:30,634 --> 00:16:32,701
This can be an attitude of some people that

206
00:16:32,701 --> 00:16:38,634
 “if this person is working, let him work."

207
00:16:38,634 --> 00:16:42,967
This is even a meaner stuff, avoid, just.

208
00:16:42,967 --> 00:16:46,101
You go to a restaurant and
somebody takes out the purse,

209
00:16:46,101 --> 00:16:49,534
others start looking this side – is very mean,

210
00:16:49,534 --> 00:16:54,601
it’s a very mean thing to do.
Everybody should come forward

211
00:16:54,601 --> 00:16:56,901
and once you have paid, you have paid it, finished.

212
00:16:56,901 --> 00:17:01,134
Then you just don’t start counting,
“Why did I pay?”

213
00:17:01,134 --> 00:17:05,801
Once you try Or any work has to be done,

214
00:17:05,801 --> 00:17:09,067
go forward with it, do it with your heart.

215
00:17:09,067 --> 00:17:12,467
Don’t worry if others have not done it.

216
00:17:12,467 --> 00:17:16,067
Just do it for its pleasure and
the pleasure only you will get

217
00:17:16,067 --> 00:17:20,367
when you will do it with the understanding that it’s a training period,

218
00:17:20,367 --> 00:17:25,000
you are better trained than the other one is.

219
00:17:25,000 --> 00:17:27,567
You are at a higher class than the other one is.

220
00:17:27,567 --> 00:17:32,701
So we have to be at a higher class.

221
00:17:32,701 --> 00:17:36,101
For that this is just a training on.

222
00:17:36,101 --> 00:17:43,534
And that’s how we can really put our preparation into practice, into all details

223
00:17:43,534 --> 00:17:48,734
to see how we work out our ego and superego.

224
00:17:48,734 --> 00:17:57,000
Today, in the morning, I have told you that your intellect must imbibe this within itself, all right?

225
00:17:57,000 --> 00:18:05,401
And now I’m telling you that your action,
action that you do,

226
00:18:05,401 --> 00:18:20,234
must be every time branded by you
as just your training – any action you do.

227
00:18:20,234 --> 00:18:23,601
Supposing you have to drive for miles together,

228
00:18:23,601 --> 00:18:25,401
you are trying your patience.

229
00:18:25,401 --> 00:18:29,901
You see they’ll do in everything.
Say they have to go for say helicopter,

230
00:18:29,901 --> 00:18:35,067
or say if they have to drop from the…
what you call them, they drop down?

231
00:18:35,067 --> 00:18:36,634
Sahaja Yogis: Parachutes.

232
00:18:36,634 --> 00:18:37,234
Ha?

233
00:18:37,234 --> 00:18:39,167
Shri Mataji: Parachuters!

234
00:18:39,167 --> 00:18:42,567
Or helicopter you take away or whatever it is.

235
00:18:42,567 --> 00:18:47,234
You go on doing it again and again, isn’t it?
You practice it again and again.

236
00:18:47,234 --> 00:18:50,134
You drop many-a-times, you break your legs, you break your hands,

237
00:18:50,134 --> 00:18:56,701
you do this and do that till you become a master.
You understand My point?

238
00:18:56,701 --> 00:18:59,867
Driving – same way, till you become a master, you go on.

239
00:18:59,867 --> 00:19:05,667
In the same way, you are doing this work
just to master your patience.

240
00:19:05,667 --> 00:19:13,034
And then your love, is your love –
how much you love really.

241
00:19:13,034 --> 00:19:20,867
If you really love someone,
you are never tired of working.

242
00:19:20,867 --> 00:19:23,701
You are never upset with work.

243
00:19:23,701 --> 00:19:26,701
But if you don’t love, you start counting,

244
00:19:26,701 --> 00:19:32,767
“How much money, how much work,
how many hours, how much to be paid?”

245
00:19:32,767 --> 00:19:38,901
All artificiality comes because
there is no love involved in your work.

246
00:19:38,901 --> 00:19:45,334
Whatever you don’t want to do, you don’t do it, to begin with.

247
00:19:45,334 --> 00:19:51,367
To begin with you just don’t do
what you don’t like – to begin with.

248
00:19:51,367 --> 00:19:53,734
But once you have mastered that,

249
00:19:53,734 --> 00:19:59,334
then you have to master it that
you do something that you don’t like.

250
00:19:59,334 --> 00:20:02,334
Like meeting some bhooties, for example.

251
00:20:02,334 --> 00:20:05,767
You don’t want to meet, you want to run away,

252
00:20:05,767 --> 00:20:09,067
but you go little nearer it, you see.

253
00:20:09,067 --> 00:20:11,667
Then develop a immunity for these bhooties.

254
00:20:11,667 --> 00:20:16,067
After some time you’ll not catch them.

255
00:20:16,067 --> 00:20:18,801
We have to develop the immunity, isn’t it?

256
00:20:18,801 --> 00:20:24,701
Otherwise one person comes here and everybody’s head goes out.

257
00:20:24,701 --> 00:20:28,867
Instead of the fellow improving, you all go out.

258
00:20:28,867 --> 00:20:36,767
So all these things are, all these events
are for your training, your immunity.

259
00:20:36,767 --> 00:20:41,367
Your immunity is to be trained

260
00:20:41,367 --> 00:20:43,901
and when it is so, when we are training ourselves

261
00:20:43,901 --> 00:20:48,801
we should take it as a job.

262
00:20:48,801 --> 00:20:54,901
But the attitude should be extremely positive,

263
00:20:54,901 --> 00:20:58,067
extremely positive

264
00:20:58,067 --> 00:21:03,734
and all that should be expressed in your notebook:

265
00:21:03,734 --> 00:21:08,601
whether you got dejected or you got upset and disgusted,

266
00:21:08,601 --> 00:21:12,867
you want to run away from it – all sorts of things.

267
00:21:12,867 --> 00:21:19,167
It’s just a training to your mind.

268
00:21:19,167 --> 00:21:24,134
Whatever is the situation, wherever one has to live,

269
00:21:24,134 --> 00:21:30,567
whatever one has to do, we should do.

270
00:21:30,567 --> 00:21:35,334
Whatever may be the circumstances, conditions,

271
00:21:35,334 --> 00:21:38,567
you’ll be amazed, you will not even know
what you have eaten in the morning,

272
00:21:38,567 --> 00:21:43,767
what you have eaten in the evening,
whether you have eaten or not you will not know.

273
00:21:43,767 --> 00:21:47,167
You’ll not fuss about it,

274
00:21:47,167 --> 00:21:53,067
you’ll not worry about it, you’ll not think about it.

275
00:21:53,067 --> 00:22:01,367
But this being, the aim, is to reach to sattwa guna,

276
00:22:01,367 --> 00:22:07,067
every other thing becomes zero.

277
00:22:07,067 --> 00:22:10,601
It’s the greatest hurdle comes to Sahaja Yogis I’ve seen,

278
00:22:10,601 --> 00:22:14,434
when they start organising.

279
00:22:14,434 --> 00:22:19,034
They start organising something.
Now somebody wants something,

280
00:22:19,034 --> 00:22:23,034
so they’ll run up to get the thing for that person.

281
00:22:23,034 --> 00:22:27,000
Now just now I’ve said that you must look after the needs of others,

282
00:22:27,000 --> 00:22:33,000
but if I am sitting here and there’s a lecture on
then you’d better be just listening to Me.

283
00:22:33,000 --> 00:22:37,034
You see, this also is there that:
how to have your priorities,

284
00:22:37,034 --> 00:22:42,167
at this time when something working on you.

285
00:22:42,167 --> 00:22:45,000
This is the first thing you have to do.

286
00:22:45,000 --> 00:22:50,334
Not that at this time you go and cook.

287
00:22:50,334 --> 00:22:56,901
You have known the story of two sisters
attending on Christ. Alright?

288
00:22:56,901 --> 00:23:02,667
So at this time, what is your first job

289
00:23:02,667 --> 00:23:07,101
is to try to be more exposed to Me

290
00:23:07,101 --> 00:23:10,334
so that automatically you’ll go into your sattwa guna.

291
00:23:10,334 --> 00:23:13,234
This is the best!

292
00:23:13,234 --> 00:23:20,767
But if I am not there and when you are alone or when you are with other Sahaja Yogis

293
00:23:20,767 --> 00:23:25,767
you must now compete in rising higher and higher:

294
00:23:25,767 --> 00:23:30,434
from tamo guna to rajo guna and
from rajo guna to sattwo guna.

295
00:23:30,434 --> 00:23:35,734
But actually by Realisation
you have gone beyond these three gunas.

296
00:23:35,734 --> 00:23:42,501
You have gone beyond it.
Actually that is what has happened to you.

297
00:23:42,501 --> 00:23:48,634
But, like clouds, they cover you again and again.

298
00:23:48,634 --> 00:23:53,034
And when the sky is covered with those clouds,

299
00:23:53,034 --> 00:23:59,167
you cannot see the sun, you cannot see the moon,
you cannot see the stars.

300
00:23:59,167 --> 00:24:02,867
So we have to know how these clouds are coming into us

301
00:24:02,867 --> 00:24:06,734
and that’s how we go into our complete analysis.

302
00:24:06,734 --> 00:24:09,401
How these clouds are coming to us,

303
00:24:09,401 --> 00:24:13,701
you find out about our different chakras.

304
00:24:13,701 --> 00:24:17,967
What are the chakras we are catching?

305
00:24:17,967 --> 00:24:24,634
Here comes the another constant attention towards our chakras.

306
00:24:24,634 --> 00:24:30,801
Are our vibrations alright or not?
Are we getting our vibrations?

307
00:24:30,801 --> 00:24:35,734
If not, what chakra am I catching,
what must be the catch?

308
00:24:35,734 --> 00:24:40,367
I must raise my Kundalini, see for myself,
where is the catch.

309
00:24:40,367 --> 00:24:42,534
Do I do my meditation or not?

310
00:24:42,534 --> 00:24:47,634
If I do it, am I doing it just dozingly or am I really in it?

311
00:24:47,634 --> 00:24:52,501
Am I really feeling it or not? Am I alert or not?

312
00:24:52,501 --> 00:25:01,034
All this is to be assiduously, sincerely, absolutely, truthfully should be worked out.

313
00:25:01,034 --> 00:25:06,334
Because it is a process between your self

314
00:25:06,334 --> 00:25:08,834
 "Atamanyeva Atmana tushta"
[The Spirit is satisfied with Itself].

315
00:25:08,834 --> 00:25:13,334
You see it’s a very funny, it is so funny relationship

316
00:25:13,334 --> 00:25:21,034
that it is the Atma is satisfied with Atma!

317
00:25:21,034 --> 00:25:24,767
You have to be satisfied with your Self.

318
00:25:24,767 --> 00:25:27,267
There’s nobody, Mataji is not concerned,
nobody is concerned.

319
00:25:27,267 --> 00:25:32,601
It is you who is concerned with your Self.

320
00:25:32,601 --> 00:25:38,601
For example, you ask somebody and he says,
“I am like this, Mother."

321
00:25:38,601 --> 00:25:41,334
Now think that you are Mother,

322
00:25:41,334 --> 00:25:51,101
one personality, another is, say, Mr. Don or Kingsley or someone X. You are two personalities.

323
00:25:51,101 --> 00:25:57,634
So when you are telling your Self,
means that is Mataji, that, “I am not alright,”

324
00:25:57,634 --> 00:26:00,701
then Mataji must come up and say,
“What do you mean by this?

325
00:26:00,701 --> 00:26:08,167
Why should you say like that? What’s wrong?”

326
00:26:08,167 --> 00:26:17,267
When you say that to yourself which is outside,

327
00:26:17,267 --> 00:26:26,834
then the attention starts moving towards your Self which is Mataji and you start becoming that

328
00:26:26,834 --> 00:26:30,501
and you start seeing through your Atma.

329
00:26:30,501 --> 00:26:35,767
So your Atma is to be satisfied by your Atma only.

330
00:26:35,767 --> 00:26:37,501
There is nothing in between.

331
00:26:37,501 --> 00:26:42,601
It is you only in this dual personality
has to satisfy your Self.

332
00:26:42,601 --> 00:26:46,534
One is in ignorance, one is in knowledge.

333
00:26:46,534 --> 00:26:51,167
Now try to identify yourself with that Mataji, call it,

334
00:26:51,167 --> 00:26:58,967
or any Xyz whatever you call it, Atma.
 And just for, just a drama, say.

335
00:26:58,967 --> 00:27:03,601
You just think that you are the Self, Spirit.

336
00:27:03,601 --> 00:27:08,201
So how will you address your Self? Let’s see.

337
00:27:08,201 --> 00:27:09,834
Supposing you have to sit in My seat,

338
00:27:09,834 --> 00:27:12,234
yes, take it like that, a position.

339
00:27:12,234 --> 00:27:16,301
And then you are sitting in front of Me also, alright?

340
00:27:16,301 --> 00:27:19,734
So you are sitting here and sitting there.
Take a position like that.

341
00:27:19,734 --> 00:27:22,734
Now you put up your Self in a drama
and you start addressing yourself,

342
00:27:22,734 --> 00:27:26,534
“So Bala, how are you?”

343
00:27:26,534 --> 00:27:33,367
 so Bala says, “Better,”

344
00:27:33,367 --> 00:27:38,934
So if you are identified now with Mataji,

345
00:27:38,934 --> 00:27:42,634
gradually Bala will diminish, alright?

346
00:27:42,634 --> 00:27:46,334
But if you are still identified with Bala,

347
00:27:46,334 --> 00:27:50,301
he’ll grow and this will diminish.

348
00:27:50,301 --> 00:28:00,501
You have to try to address yourself as if you are Mataji.

349
00:28:00,501 --> 00:28:07,401
It’s a drama.
You sit before the mirror.

350
00:28:07,401 --> 00:28:10,767
In the mirror you see this outside of yours

351
00:28:10,767 --> 00:28:15,367
and here you are sitting, whatever you are, Mr. Don for example.

352
00:28:15,367 --> 00:28:18,967
Now Mr. Don is addressing the other Don there,

353
00:28:18,967 --> 00:28:22,501
and let him take up a role that, “I am the Spirit.”

354
00:28:22,501 --> 00:28:27,967
He’ll say, “I am the Spirit and I am eternal.
 I am this.

355
00:28:27,967 --> 00:28:31,734
Nobody can destroy me.
 I am above everything."

356
00:28:31,734 --> 00:28:36,134
That thing will go down.

357
00:28:36,134 --> 00:28:38,934
“I am a realised soul.
 I know what Spirit is.

358
00:28:38,934 --> 00:28:46,301
What are you talking?” It will go down.

359
00:28:46,301 --> 00:28:51,867
This is how you start moving.

360
00:28:51,867 --> 00:28:56,967
But it is only possible that first you become a sattwa guni.

361
00:28:56,967 --> 00:29:01,101
If you are not a sattwa guni, with ego, “I am this,”

362
00:29:01,101 --> 00:29:05,534
then you become a guru and you start minting money!

363
00:29:05,534 --> 00:29:08,234
First the ego is to be brought down.

364
00:29:08,234 --> 00:29:14,167
If there is still ego, then without becoming Atma you become an ego.

365
00:29:14,167 --> 00:29:18,934
So first this journey should be brought in to the centre of sattwa guna.

366
00:29:18,934 --> 00:29:25,767
That is why I say that when you are talking or doing anything,

367
00:29:25,767 --> 00:29:32,834
you must know that it is your Spirit which is doing it.

368
00:29:32,834 --> 00:29:38,867
That’s how you put your Spirit in charge

369
00:29:38,867 --> 00:29:43,534
or say at the pedestal – first stage.

370
00:29:43,534 --> 00:29:47,467
Then when the Spirit is there, then from this stage to that stage,

371
00:29:47,467 --> 00:29:52,401
then you say that, “Now I am the Spirit."

372
00:29:52,401 --> 00:29:59,534
For example, if you have a prime minister and a deputy minister and a minister – three persons, alright?

373
00:29:59,534 --> 00:30:06,101
Now, if the prime minister is your Self

374
00:30:06,101 --> 00:30:09,667
and the minister has to become the prime minister,

375
00:30:09,667 --> 00:30:13,667
so he has to first become deputy minister.

376
00:30:13,667 --> 00:30:18,067
After becoming deputy minister he has to become prime minister;

377
00:30:18,067 --> 00:30:21,067
but deputy prime minister and then the prime minister.

378
00:30:21,067 --> 00:30:24,434
But supposing this fellow starts to jump over this,

379
00:30:24,434 --> 00:30:25,901
this will come up and hit him and he’ll say,

380
00:30:25,901 --> 00:30:31,067
 “I’m the one!”
and this one is E-G-O.

381
00:30:31,067 --> 00:30:34,901
Do you understand My point?

382
00:30:34,901 --> 00:30:38,667
So you cannot surpass it.

383
00:30:38,667 --> 00:30:43,167
You have to merge this into this and then this into this.

384
00:30:43,167 --> 00:30:45,167
The movement has to be like that.

385
00:30:45,167 --> 00:30:50,801
But if you try to just become this, actually you will become this, not this,

386
00:30:50,801 --> 00:30:53,701
because you cannot become this.

387
00:30:53,701 --> 00:30:57,367
Do you understand My point?

388
00:30:57,367 --> 00:31:03,067
So, even when doing this exercise of sitting before a mirror

389
00:31:03,067 --> 00:31:08,267
and telling yourself that you are the Spirit,

390
00:31:08,267 --> 00:31:20,134
you are the part of Viraat, that you are the Ocean

391
00:31:20,134 --> 00:31:24,667
because your drop has fallen into the Ocean.

392
00:31:24,667 --> 00:31:29,267
Then you must know that your drop has fallen into the Ocean.

393
00:31:29,267 --> 00:31:33,201
That’s why you’ve become an Ocean.
 If that stage is missing,

394
00:31:33,201 --> 00:31:39,534
then you’re saying that you are an Ocean is absolutely bombastic.

395
00:31:39,534 --> 00:31:43,934
And that is why one has to be very steady and careful,

396
00:31:43,934 --> 00:31:47,767
absolutely steady as far as dealing with oneself.

397
00:31:47,767 --> 00:31:51,334
Because you know how this intelligence can cheat you.

398
00:31:51,334 --> 00:31:56,467
So be very, very careful and when you are dealing with you,

399
00:31:56,467 --> 00:32:01,434
you must know that you have to first overcome this ego.

400
00:32:01,434 --> 00:32:03,567
The best thing to overcome ego

401
00:32:03,567 --> 00:32:06,101
is to change your language style,

402
00:32:06,101 --> 00:32:10,667
is to speak in the third person.
 Is a very good way.

403
00:32:10,667 --> 00:32:13,667
Like you must say, when you are talking about yourself,

404
00:32:13,667 --> 00:32:20,101
“This Mataji won’t listen to Me.
 This Mataji won’t do this,”

405
00:32:20,101 --> 00:32:25,467
you see, so what happens, this ‘Mataji’ means the ego part of it, you see.

406
00:32:25,467 --> 00:32:29,767
And once you start separating this Mataji away from yourself,

407
00:32:29,767 --> 00:32:33,667
then that ego Mataji disappears.
 You understand?

408
00:32:33,667 --> 00:32:38,767
Like you can say, "This Bala is like that.
 He won’t listen."

409
00:32:38,767 --> 00:32:43,834
So whatever the real Bala is left in you is alright.

410
00:32:43,834 --> 00:32:47,000
That’s how you get rid of your ego

411
00:32:47,000 --> 00:32:51,801
and by understanding your centres,
what you are catching, where you are catching,

412
00:32:51,801 --> 00:32:54,801
how you are catching;

413
00:32:54,801 --> 00:33:01,534
it would be very easy for you to get rid of your problems.

414
00:33:01,534 --> 00:33:04,534
Now, see what Sahaja Yogis do.

415
00:33:04,534 --> 00:33:06,867
Supposing there are five Sahaja Yogis sitting.

416
00:33:06,867 --> 00:33:09,767
I mean you know that I know about everyone, everything.

417
00:33:09,767 --> 00:33:14,201
I don’t have to ask, “Where is catching?”

418
00:33:14,201 --> 00:33:19,267
Now why do I ask? I show complete ignorance.

419
00:33:19,267 --> 00:33:22,467
Because perhaps I never catch also, to be very frank.

420
00:33:22,467 --> 00:33:27,367
But if I want to know where I’m catching
I can find out but I don’t want to.

421
00:33:27,367 --> 00:33:31,867
So what I say, “Alright, Chaya, tell Me where is he catching."

422
00:33:31,867 --> 00:33:35,234
At this time one attitude could be that,

423
00:33:35,234 --> 00:33:41,834
 “I must tell, otherwise Mataji won’t know.”
This is very funny.

424
00:33:41,834 --> 00:33:48,767
The second one could be,
and the second one could be that,

425
00:33:48,767 --> 00:33:58,267
that, “I know where she is catching and, and I must tell,

426
00:33:58,267 --> 00:34:06,267
and Mataji also knows but She wants to test me.
 So I should be careful."

427
00:34:06,267 --> 00:34:08,967
At this point people make mistakes.

428
00:34:08,967 --> 00:34:13,967
If I ask them, “Where is it catching?”

429
00:34:13,967 --> 00:34:26,501
“I am catching on left heart but very mildly!”
Finished then! You, you’ll get less marks.

430
00:34:26,501 --> 00:34:30,067
You get less marks.
 You tell Me whatever you think,

431
00:34:30,067 --> 00:34:36,334
because at least you’re honest.
 Whatever you think.

432
00:34:36,334 --> 00:34:39,167
Supposing the fellow is not catching heart

433
00:34:39,167 --> 00:34:43,667
but you are feeling the heart.
 You say, “Heart” That’s being honest.

434
00:34:43,667 --> 00:34:46,667
Then I will tell you who is catching the heart.

435
00:34:46,667 --> 00:34:52,634
But if you are, “Perhaps yes, Mataji. No, Mataji,”

436
00:34:52,634 --> 00:34:58,201
then you get less marks.
 It’s not a very good answer.

437
00:34:58,201 --> 00:35:01,967
“I am not alright, I don’t know,” that’s not a good answer.

438
00:35:01,967 --> 00:35:06,934
You have to tell Me who is catching where.

439
00:35:06,934 --> 00:35:11,134
Then you pay more attention that you have to pass this test.

440
00:35:11,134 --> 00:35:14,401
This is just testing. Why?

441
00:35:14,401 --> 00:35:17,167
Because tomorrow you have to give Realisation.

442
00:35:17,167 --> 00:35:22,667
You have to become the gurus.
 You have to know all this.

443
00:35:22,667 --> 00:35:25,767
So this is all training period.

444
00:35:25,767 --> 00:35:29,567
I’m just training you by asking you to tell Me,

445
00:35:29,567 --> 00:35:34,167
but I have seen people even getting ego with this.
 It’s surprisingly sometimes.

446
00:35:34,167 --> 00:35:39,401
That also gives the ego to people that I say,
“Alright, you tell Me where he is catching?”

447
00:35:39,401 --> 00:35:43,867
“I told correctly!” Finished!

448
00:35:43,867 --> 00:35:51,334
You see, it is just a very, very, I can say, razor stage I tell you,

449
00:35:51,334 --> 00:35:55,967
where one has to see clearly.
 So be a simple person like children are.

450
00:35:55,967 --> 00:36:00,234
They just come.
 This one, that one, finished.

451
00:36:00,234 --> 00:36:04,101
Then they’ll go and sit down,
“Now I’m tired, I’m sitting down!”

452
00:36:04,101 --> 00:36:08,534
They are not bothered that they should…

453
00:36:08,534 --> 00:36:12,467
they must say something or something show off, nothing.

454
00:36:12,467 --> 00:36:16,967
Whatever they see, they say.

455
00:36:16,967 --> 00:36:18,601
But only grownups will say that,

456
00:36:18,601 --> 00:36:22,767
“Maybe I’m catching, maybe it is his.
 I don’t know.”

457
00:36:22,767 --> 00:36:25,734
All this is done by grownup people

458
00:36:25,734 --> 00:36:33,401
because still the sensitivity is alright but they are not sure of themselves.

459
00:36:33,401 --> 00:36:37,467
Children are very sure.
 They are cocksure of everything.

460
00:36:37,467 --> 00:36:40,534
You ask them anything, they’ll tell you,
“Yes, this is this, this is this.”

461
00:36:40,534 --> 00:36:45,567
ولی شما از هر کسی بپرسید:
"این چه رنگی است؟"

462
00:36:45,567 --> 00:36:51,901
They’ll say, “Maybe green, maybe red.”

463
00:36:51,901 --> 00:36:57,000
Like we had one old gentleman, not very old, as old as Myself

464
00:36:57,000 --> 00:37:02,767
but he was to come to My house and he telephoned to Me.

465
00:37:02,767 --> 00:37:05,201
He said, “I want to come to Your house
so how should I come?”

466
00:37:05,201 --> 00:37:08,067
I said, “This place is Oxted, you can come there but

467
00:37:08,067 --> 00:37:11,567
if you don’t get a taxi then it’s very difficult, better come to Hurst Green."

468
00:37:11,567 --> 00:37:14,967
He said, “Where?”
I said, “Hurst Green.”

469
00:37:14,967 --> 00:37:20,167
So he said, “Hurst Blue?”
How he is saying blue to green, I don’t know.

470
00:37:20,167 --> 00:37:23,167
I said, “No, it’s Hurst Green.”

471
00:37:23,167 --> 00:37:29,367
He said, “What did you say?”
I said, “Hurst Green.”

472
00:37:29,367 --> 00:37:33,334
So he couldn’t understand.
 “What is the second one?”

473
00:37:33,334 --> 00:37:52,767
I said, “What is the colour of the leaves?” He said, “Blue.”

474
00:37:52,767 --> 00:37:56,567
I said it to Gregoire, I said, “Now listen to him, what is he saying?

475
00:37:56,567 --> 00:38:00,434
Colour of the leaves is blue?”

476
00:38:00,434 --> 00:38:10,167
So, Gregoire lifted the phone he said,
“Alright, you come to Hurst Blue.”

477
00:38:10,167 --> 00:38:12,901
So he said, “Now at least…”
I said, “What are you telling?”

478
00:38:12,901 --> 00:38:17,067
He said, “Now he won’t come, Mother.
That botheration is gone.

479
00:38:17,067 --> 00:38:21,134
Such a confused personality, mixing between blue and green!

480
00:38:21,134 --> 00:38:27,101
You are fighting. That’s what it is.
The attention drifts.

481
00:38:27,101 --> 00:38:30,234
So try to see that if you are confused, there is confusion,

482
00:38:30,234 --> 00:38:34,334
clear it out by clearing out your chakras.

483
00:38:34,334 --> 00:38:36,267
Now every chakra,

484
00:38:36,267 --> 00:38:40,401
let’s have a little testing of it alright, let’s see?

485
00:38:40,401 --> 00:38:45,401
One by one. So who are going to answer
the questions? Let’s see.

486
00:38:45,401 --> 00:38:51,767
Simple questions. Not ‘Mastermind’
Very simple questions.

487
00:38:51,767 --> 00:38:56,634
Now, say your Hamsa Chakra is catching,
what should we do?

488
00:38:56,634 --> 00:39:01,567
Who will answer the question?

489
00:39:01,567 --> 00:39:06,534
Hamsa Chakra is catching, what should we do?
Let’s see, one by one.

490
00:39:06,534 --> 00:39:10,401
Sahaja Yogi: Hamsa, Hamsa.

491
00:39:10,401 --> 00:39:13,467
That’s the name of the chakra.

492
00:39:13,467 --> 00:39:16,967
Sahaja Yogi: Someone said to me that you say Hamsa.

493
00:39:16,967 --> 00:39:22,101
No…you see this is the Hamsa Chakra so you have to say that,

494
00:39:22,101 --> 00:39:31,134
“Twameva sakshat, Hamsa Chakra Swamini sakshat, Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi namoh, namah.”

495
00:39:31,134 --> 00:39:37,801
See, opened now?

496
00:39:37,801 --> 00:39:39,601
Now say it, all of you,

497
00:39:39,601 --> 00:39:43,701
because just now you are catching.
Now put your finger like this and now say it.

498
00:40:02,434 --> 00:40:04,501
Say it again. Say it thrice.

499
00:40:23,734 --> 00:40:24,667
Now Say it.

500
00:40:44,334 --> 00:40:50,467
See? Better.

501
00:40:50,467 --> 00:40:56,234
Now, what happens in this centre
that both the Nadis, Ha and Tha,

502
00:40:56,234 --> 00:41:01,634
Ida and Pingala, they come and meet and they cross over.

503
00:41:01,634 --> 00:41:09,334
So, for the right Nadi, right side, this one,
the left Nadi flows

504
00:41:09,334 --> 00:41:17,067
and from the right side, the one
which comes from the right side flows into left side.

505
00:41:17,067 --> 00:41:21,934
These two centres meet here,
I mean two Nadis meet here actually,

506
00:41:21,934 --> 00:41:26,634
below the Agnya, it’s below the Agnya at Hamsa, you see,

507
00:41:26,634 --> 00:41:32,234
and the problems come to you
either from the right or from the left.

508
00:41:32,234 --> 00:41:35,534
Most of you catch on Hamsa here,

509
00:41:35,534 --> 00:41:38,834
because of cold or whatever it is.

510
00:41:38,834 --> 00:41:42,134
Now, I have told you many things by which you control your cold.

511
00:41:42,134 --> 00:41:48,901
But if it is due to the left side, left side catching is there,

512
00:41:48,901 --> 00:42:02,501
then for left side Hamsa what should you do? Tell Me.

513
00:42:02,501 --> 00:42:12,101
Sahaja Yogi: Keep your eyes on the ground, on the green.

514
00:42:12,101 --> 00:42:15,000
That’s one of them, but another thing,

515
00:42:15,000 --> 00:42:18,501
I mean as far as mantra is concerned what mantra will you say…

516
00:42:18,501 --> 00:42:22,401
Sahaja Yogi: Ekadasha Rudra.

517
00:42:22,401 --> 00:42:27,101
No that’s much higher, that’s even above the Agnya.

518
00:42:27,101 --> 00:42:29,334
Sahaja Yogi: Mahakali.

519
00:42:29,334 --> 00:42:30,667
Mahakali, correct.

520
00:42:30,667 --> 00:42:33,901
But you can say Ida, Ida Nadi.
Now see just now I have told you

521
00:42:33,901 --> 00:42:41,134
that it is the Ida Nadi which comes
from the left and goes to the right side.

522
00:42:41,134 --> 00:42:46,767
So, you have to say Mahakali or Ida Nadi,
Ida Nadi Swamini.

523
00:42:46,767 --> 00:42:50,901
Now say it.
 Just now you are catching on the left.

524
00:43:10,701 --> 00:43:11,534
Again.

525
00:43:30,567 --> 00:43:31,434
Again.

526
00:43:52,501 --> 00:43:57,434
Now, then another thing, that supposing your right side is catching,

527
00:43:57,434 --> 00:44:01,501
or you have a liver problem, then what should be used

528
00:44:01,501 --> 00:44:12,467
light, sun’s rays or water?

529
00:44:12,467 --> 00:44:15,567
Sahaja Yogi: Water.

530
00:44:15,567 --> 00:44:21,267
See, right side is heat, is Surya Nadi.

531
00:44:21,267 --> 00:44:26,634
So you have problem of Surya Nadi – right side.

532
00:44:26,634 --> 00:44:31,534
So to neutralize it you have to use something else.

533
00:44:31,534 --> 00:44:37,667
So then that time what you have to say, is to

534
00:44:37,667 --> 00:44:46,801
you can say, you can take the name of Chandra,

535
00:44:46,801 --> 00:44:49,767
you’ll cool down.

536
00:44:49,767 --> 00:44:54,201
If there is heat on the right hand side,
you should take the name of Chandra.

537
00:44:54,201 --> 00:44:59,401
If it is the left side catching,
then you have to take the name of Surya.

538
00:44:59,401 --> 00:45:03,134
For example, you are possessed,
then go and sit in the Sun

539
00:45:03,134 --> 00:45:06,567
all the bhoots will run away.
 They run away from the Sun.

540
00:45:06,567 --> 00:45:12,767
But supposing you are an egotistical person then go and sit in the moonlight.

541
00:45:12,767 --> 00:45:19,867
Maybe you’ll be a little lunatic.

542
00:45:19,867 --> 00:45:22,000
It comes from the word ‘luna’, you see?

543
00:45:22,000 --> 00:45:25,734
But if you are a crying type and all the time over-romantic

544
00:45:25,734 --> 00:45:33,801
better not look at the moon and better see the sun.
 See the compensations.

545
00:45:33,801 --> 00:45:36,467
This is absolutely understanding that many people,

546
00:45:36,467 --> 00:45:39,367
if they have liver they put in this.

547
00:45:39,367 --> 00:45:43,734
What can the fire do now? There’s already fire here.

548
00:45:43,734 --> 00:45:46,967
Adding fire to the fire again, you see?

549
00:45:46,967 --> 00:45:56,234
But, also, what one can do is to take out this fire
and give it to this one.

550
00:45:56,234 --> 00:46:02,167
Now, how do you do that?

551
00:46:02,167 --> 00:46:04,667
Sahaja Yogi: Lemon?

552
00:46:04,667 --> 00:46:12,000
No, no. to fire. Supposing I want to treat
My liver with fire. How do I do it?

553
00:46:12,000 --> 00:46:18,467
Sahaja Yogi: You put your finger actually to the flame so that it burns off.

554
00:46:18,467 --> 00:46:20,201
No.

555
00:46:20,201 --> 00:46:23,234
Sahaja Yogi: It'll take too much a week!

556
00:46:23,234 --> 00:46:26,434
Yes, that’s correct but something takes sometimes about it.

557
00:46:26,434 --> 00:46:29,401
Think it over then, think it over, take it over.

558
00:46:29,401 --> 00:46:31,967
You see, you have to take out your heat

559
00:46:31,967 --> 00:46:35,534
and give it to these lights.

560
00:46:35,534 --> 00:46:43,101
How do you do it? Think it over.

561
00:46:43,101 --> 00:46:46,767
I’ll tell you the simple thing is: this left hand is minus,

562
00:46:46,767 --> 00:46:49,000
this is plus, you can take like that, alright?

563
00:46:49,000 --> 00:46:51,301
So whatever you do with your left hand you suck in.

564
00:46:51,301 --> 00:46:56,801
Whatever you do with your right hand, say, for example, you give out. Alright?

565
00:46:56,801 --> 00:47:01,367
So now if you want to give out now, what you do

566
00:47:01,367 --> 00:47:03,401
is to put your left hand on you here

567
00:47:03,401 --> 00:47:07,167
and right hand outside.

568
00:47:07,167 --> 00:47:11,567
So this is cooling it here actually and the heat is going there.

569
00:47:11,567 --> 00:47:17,467
But if you do the other way round, you are sucking heat.

570
00:47:17,467 --> 00:47:22,734
But if you do the other way round, you are sucking heat.

571
00:47:22,734 --> 00:47:27,167
 Just electrons, alright, then?

572
00:47:27,167 --> 00:47:33,734
Now if you burn here is a good idea,
very good idea for Left Nabhi.

573
00:47:33,734 --> 00:47:38,867
So the Left Nabhi gets heated up.
 This side needs heat.

574
00:47:38,867 --> 00:47:43,667
 This side needs cooling.
 This is the basics.

575
00:47:43,667 --> 00:47:47,901
If something is wrong with this side,
you have to give it the cool.

576
00:47:47,901 --> 00:47:53,901
If something is wrong on this side, you have to give it the heat.

577
00:47:53,901 --> 00:47:56,667
Some people get too much cool vibrations.

578
00:47:56,667 --> 00:48:01,067
They’ll perspire and cool, means left is finished.

579
00:48:01,067 --> 00:48:07,534
Now what should they do as far as fire is concerned? Let’s see.

580
00:48:07,534 --> 00:48:11,101
Sahaj Yogi: right hand here

581
00:48:11,101 --> 00:48:13,901
He perspires.
 Right hand on the heart, left hand here.

582
00:48:13,901 --> 00:48:17,267
If anyone perspires, it means his heart is weak.

583
00:48:17,267 --> 00:48:27,167
So put your right hand here at the time on the heart.
 The heat comes in.

584
00:48:27,167 --> 00:48:33,167
Are you following the electronics, no, the electrical?
Sahaja Yogi: Yes, Shri Mataji.

585
00:48:33,167 --> 00:48:36,567
So the basics if you know that the left side is the cool side,

586
00:48:36,567 --> 00:48:40,234
the right side is the hot side.
And about the hands,

587
00:48:40,234 --> 00:48:42,000
this is the minus side,

588
00:48:42,000 --> 00:48:44,367
this is the plus side.

589
00:48:44,367 --> 00:48:48,334
Even if you can do like this and you are balancing yourself.

590
00:48:48,334 --> 00:48:52,134
Just like in India we do,

591
00:48:52,134 --> 00:48:58,701
especially if you see a great bhootish
then you’ll do like this, fully.

592
00:48:58,701 --> 00:49:05,667
You see?
So, these two sides are: one is the hot side,

593
00:49:05,667 --> 00:49:08,701
one is a cold side,

594
00:49:08,701 --> 00:49:19,267
while the Sattva Guna is the meeting point, is lukewarm.

595
00:49:19,267 --> 00:49:25,334
The Sattva Guna gives you the temperature that you have.

596
00:49:25,334 --> 00:49:29,201
Alright? And these two give you either
very cold or very hot.

597
00:49:29,201 --> 00:49:39,101
So we come back to now sinus again.
 It is which side problem?

598
00:49:39,101 --> 00:49:40,967
Sahaja Yogis: Left hand side.

599
00:49:40,967 --> 00:49:42,901
Correct! Left side,

600
00:49:42,901 --> 00:49:46,501
because there are three things now in our bodies.

601
00:49:46,501 --> 00:49:51,901
One is…what do you say to that? Bulgam.

602
00:49:51,901 --> 00:50:03,801
Another is the bile and the third one is the gas or Vayu.
Alright?

603
00:50:03,801 --> 00:50:06,967
So the left side is the Kapha.

604
00:50:06,967 --> 00:50:12,734
All these colds and things are due to the left side.

605
00:50:12,734 --> 00:50:17,167
And the right side is the bile.

606
00:50:17,167 --> 00:50:28,201
The fat is created from bulgam,
which doctors do not know. Do you know that?

607
00:50:28,201 --> 00:50:36,601
When fat is heated up by the right hand side, then it dissolves

608
00:50:36,601 --> 00:50:40,967
and the gas movement is in the centre.

609
00:50:40,967 --> 00:50:49,401
When these five types of gases which are within us, when they all combine together

610
00:50:49,401 --> 00:50:56,634
and get enlightened by the Spirit,
you get the Cool Breeze coming out.

611
00:50:56,634 --> 00:51:04,201
So the centre path is the prana.

612
00:51:04,201 --> 00:51:13,734
When it gets absolutely heated up

613
00:51:13,734 --> 00:51:28,301
then diseases like tuberculosis, all these things can come in.

614
00:51:28,301 --> 00:51:38,067
And when it gets heated up on the left hand side you get tuberculosis and all these things due to too much heat.

615
00:51:38,067 --> 00:51:41,401
When it gets heated too much, then it comes to the right hand side

616
00:51:41,401 --> 00:51:44,234
and you get diseases like liver

617
00:51:44,234 --> 00:51:48,234
and all these heatening things on the right hand side.

618
00:51:48,234 --> 00:51:53,201
So though the left hand side is cold,

619
00:51:53,201 --> 00:52:02,000
if it is heated up then also diseases are caused.

620
00:52:02,000 --> 00:52:06,567
Now we have to go into details sometimes to find out

621
00:52:06,567 --> 00:52:11,234
what, basically, are our diseases within our body.

622
00:52:11,234 --> 00:52:14,234
We should know what our disease is.

623
00:52:14,234 --> 00:52:18,601
Sometimes even if you have an ordinary cold,
it is a disease, according to Sahaja Yoga.

624
00:52:18,601 --> 00:52:21,967
You should be a normal person.

625
00:52:21,967 --> 00:52:24,834
Supposing you are suffering from, say, the terrible disease,

626
00:52:24,834 --> 00:52:33,834
the greatest nuisance and the blessing of London
and England put together – is cold.

627
00:52:33,834 --> 00:52:39,167
Call it hay fever, day fever, or anything!

628
00:52:39,167 --> 00:52:43,101
So it is due to what?

629
00:52:43,101 --> 00:52:52,567
It is due to basically within us less resistance, no immunity.

630
00:52:52,567 --> 00:52:58,801
Less resistance comes to us because of the lack of calcium within us.

631
00:52:58,801 --> 00:53:01,634
Those people who have taken proper care in childhood,

632
00:53:01,634 --> 00:53:05,101
taken vitamin A and D

633
00:53:05,101 --> 00:53:12,401
and good massage, say with cod liver oil or olive oil and things like that,

634
00:53:12,401 --> 00:53:15,034
and proper sunning of the body is done,

635
00:53:15,034 --> 00:53:18,901
such people suffer less from cold.

636
00:53:18,901 --> 00:53:22,901
Especially the Vishuddhi Chakra problem it is.

637
00:53:22,901 --> 00:53:27,000
Now those people who have not been careful about their Vishuddhi Chakra

638
00:53:27,000 --> 00:53:30,967
get the disease settled within themselves,

639
00:53:30,967 --> 00:53:35,201
but when this disease is settled, what happens actually?

640
00:53:35,201 --> 00:53:41,934
What is the reason, as we said that it is the left hand side problem.

641
00:53:41,934 --> 00:53:46,801
Cold is a left hand side problem.

642
00:53:46,801 --> 00:53:53,201
That means cold has something to do with your emotional side.

643
00:53:53,201 --> 00:53:58,034
That means there’s something also wrong emotionally with you.

644
00:53:58,034 --> 00:54:03,634
So it indicates that you have some emotional problem.

645
00:54:03,634 --> 00:54:06,201
According to Sahaja Yoga, to overcome cold

646
00:54:06,201 --> 00:54:12,634
one should see into this emotional life of oneself.

647
00:54:12,634 --> 00:54:14,201
What are you doing about your emotions?

648
00:54:14,201 --> 00:54:27,967
For example, as soon as you’re affected by emotions, you will start crying or sneezing.

649
00:54:27,967 --> 00:54:33,601
This is a fact.
 If these are girls, they’ll start crying.

650
00:54:33,601 --> 00:54:36,401
If they are men, they’ll start coughing or sneezing.

651
00:54:36,401 --> 00:54:46,734
They’ll cough for nothing at all.
You see they will go.

652
00:54:46,734 --> 00:54:52,901
Isn’t it a fact? Unnecessarily they’ll be doing like this.
 Is an emotional thing,

653
00:54:52,901 --> 00:54:58,000
to attract attention maybe or whatever it is.
 To say that how pitiable they are, you see,

654
00:54:58,000 --> 00:55:03,134
is a thing by which we show our pitiable condition.

655
00:55:03,134 --> 00:55:11,000
You see, is a thing, we reduce ourselves to a position by which we try to, you see, excite the pity in other person.

656
00:55:11,000 --> 00:55:15,367
So this cold is due to our emotional problem.

657
00:55:15,367 --> 00:55:19,234
Now so we should see what is our emotional problem.

658
00:55:19,234 --> 00:55:27,267
We should find out how much ‘Romeos’ we are

659
00:55:27,267 --> 00:55:35,467
And how much delight of life we miss by that.

660
00:55:35,467 --> 00:55:39,901
Once you start understanding

661
00:55:39,901 --> 00:55:46,000
that you are your own Romeo and you are your own Juliet,

662
00:55:46,000 --> 00:55:52,167
most of you will get rid of your colds. Take it from Me.

663
00:55:52,167 --> 00:55:58,034
It is some sort of an emotional problem.
Could be with your father.

664
00:55:58,034 --> 00:56:00,801
A person who is very attached to his father.

665
00:56:00,801 --> 00:56:06,767
‘Attached’ is the word best is, gets also attached to cold.

666
00:56:06,767 --> 00:56:10,034
Attached to mother is even worse.

667
00:56:10,034 --> 00:56:13,901
If somebody is very attached to her mother, you see,

668
00:56:13,901 --> 00:56:16,667
then all reasoning fails

669
00:56:16,667 --> 00:56:19,401
and then the mother misbehaves or does something

670
00:56:19,401 --> 00:56:27,334
and the child feels very hurt, the child cries, he gets the cold.

671
00:56:27,334 --> 00:56:33,567
Any such attachment which makes you foolish should be given up,

672
00:56:33,567 --> 00:56:37,334
to get rid of your cold, I mean to say.

673
00:56:37,334 --> 00:56:40,934
Whatever makes you stupid, foolish

674
00:56:40,934 --> 00:56:45,634
or hankering after someone,

675
00:56:45,634 --> 00:56:51,167
creates troubles like colds. ‘Romeos’ specially.

676
00:56:51,167 --> 00:56:54,201
 Then very beloved children,

677
00:56:54,201 --> 00:56:57,767
beloved fathers, beloved mothers, you see,

678
00:56:57,767 --> 00:57:03,667
the ones for them their daughter is important,
their son is important.

679
00:57:03,667 --> 00:57:07,467
Some people just don’t love their children and if someone loves

680
00:57:07,467 --> 00:57:10,234
they’ll dump them onto everybody else.

681
00:57:10,234 --> 00:57:16,667
So these two types of it.
You must know that you are just a trustee of your child

682
00:57:16,667 --> 00:57:19,567
and as far as your ‘Romeo-ness’ is concerned,

683
00:57:19,567 --> 00:57:25,467
you are just to see drama of your Romeo, that’s all.

684
00:57:25,467 --> 00:57:30,534
Then this detachment will take place and a simple disease like cold

685
00:57:30,534 --> 00:57:34,634
which looks so horrible, incurable, can be cured.

686
00:57:34,634 --> 00:57:41,067
As long as you people have cold,
without having any romantic feelings Myself,

687
00:57:41,067 --> 00:57:43,967
I also get it.
So I request you

688
00:57:43,967 --> 00:57:49,434
to rise above these things and become more sensible,

689
00:57:49,434 --> 00:58:02,267
and your attitude should be of enhancing mutual understanding, mutual love, and not romantic feelings.

690
00:58:02,267 --> 00:58:08,434
But worse than that is dry feelings,
on the right hand side you know.

691
00:58:08,434 --> 00:58:14,000
Then if you have a dry throat you cannot even speak.

692
00:58:14,000 --> 00:58:19,201
Suddenly you find -finished.

693
00:58:19,201 --> 00:58:23,334
you just can’t speak because you are dried.

694
00:58:23,334 --> 00:58:28,867
So the other side is where some people try some psychological tricks with their wives or husbands

695
00:58:28,867 --> 00:58:32,801
like “I will not speak”.

696
00:58:32,801 --> 00:58:37,834
This I’m telling you just an emotional side of life.

697
00:58:37,834 --> 00:58:44,067
“I’ll not talk to her. I’ll not speak.
 I’ll behave like this."

698
00:58:44,067 --> 00:58:48,601
Dryness. That also kills the delight.

699
00:58:48,601 --> 00:58:54,167
The one is overdoing it and one is not doing of it.

700
00:58:54,167 --> 00:59:00,067
You see, either you’ll take sugar which is one ton in one glass,

701
00:59:00,067 --> 00:59:06,834
or you will not take sugar at all.

702
00:59:06,834 --> 00:59:11,201
Not more, not less, you see, to have the optimum delight of tea.

703
00:59:11,201 --> 00:59:14,401
In the same way, in life also,

704
00:59:14,401 --> 00:59:20,267
you should not take too much of something and too little of another thing.

705
00:59:20,267 --> 00:59:25,167
Now somebody who’s married now, for that person, Indian women specially,

706
00:59:25,167 --> 00:59:30,801
husband becomes last one, then everything else is zero.

707
00:59:30,801 --> 00:59:33,834
Then such women are useless.

708
00:59:33,834 --> 00:59:39,934
Or men that I’ve seen here, they are just mad at their women.

709
00:59:39,934 --> 00:59:42,367
For them also, life is useless.

710
00:59:42,367 --> 00:59:44,934
So take a balanced attitude of the whole thing is that

711
00:59:44,934 --> 00:59:52,334
it is in you is the person who is loving your wife,

712
00:59:52,334 --> 00:59:57,701
who is also within you.
You are your wife, you are your husband.

713
00:59:57,701 --> 01:00:02,267
Now the wife who is your wife outside,

714
01:00:02,267 --> 01:00:07,501
if she just does not tally with the wife that you have within your mind,

715
01:00:07,501 --> 01:00:13,467
that should not upset you, because that wife is always with you.

716
01:00:13,467 --> 01:00:17,367
Once this understanding develops,
you see your partnership

717
01:00:17,367 --> 01:00:19,701
by the way I found your letter;

718
01:00:19,701 --> 01:00:29,701
the partnership of husband and wife could be absolutely perfect.

719
01:00:29,701 --> 01:00:32,334
Now with the children as I said...

720
01:00:32,334 --> 01:00:41,367
Hello, by what train did you come?
Sahaja Yogi: The late one.

721
01:00:41,367 --> 01:00:44,734
Real late one this one was! What about your food?

722
01:00:44,734 --> 01:00:45,501
Sahaja Yogi: We both had some.

723
01:00:45,501 --> 01:00:47,201
Really? Where?

724
01:00:47,201 --> 01:00:49,134
Sahaja Yogi: In Winchester.

725
01:00:49,134 --> 01:00:51,701
Though you were telling something else.

726
01:00:51,701 --> 01:00:57,834
Where? I mean if you are telling the truth
you’ll tell the same thing.

727
01:00:57,834 --> 01:01:00,167
Sahaja Yogi: We had some chicken from the Fish & chip shop.

728
01:01:00,167 --> 01:01:04,601
Alright. There is some food if you want, please have.

729
01:01:04,601 --> 01:01:09,801
Go, have something, you see it's very late.
Let them have, come along, let them have.

730
01:01:09,801 --> 01:01:13,101
You know? Who knows?
Good idea.

731
01:01:13,101 --> 01:01:16,201
Please Let them have.

732
01:01:16,201 --> 01:01:25,701
Very nice you both could come.
We were just missing you all.

733
01:01:25,701 --> 01:01:34,701
Yes, very good, very cool and nice, Let me see
when have you food, both of you. Now it's very good.

734
01:01:34,701 --> 01:01:39,934
May God bless you. So you go and have your food.
Go and then come in.

735
01:01:39,934 --> 01:01:55,834
Now, why make it so light for you to understand
that marriage is not a serious problem.

736
01:01:55,834 --> 01:01:59,801
As long as you have your ideal with yourself

737
01:01:59,801 --> 01:02:07,834
and you don’t try to impose that on your wife,
or the wife does not try to impose that on your husband.

738
01:02:07,834 --> 01:02:12,267
Let the wife be a wife and husband be a husband.

739
01:02:12,267 --> 01:02:17,701
But the wife should not become the husband
and the husband should not become the wife.

740
01:02:17,701 --> 01:02:20,834
If that happens, then I don’t know how to correct it,

741
01:02:20,834 --> 01:02:24,601
because that’s something absurd if that happens.

742
01:02:24,601 --> 01:02:33,734
Now, on that the main thing one has to know is
that you are married to have children,

743
01:02:33,734 --> 01:02:36,667
not to be Romeo and Juliet anymore.

744
01:02:36,667 --> 01:02:42,701
You better have your children. And then the children that will be born to Sahaja Yogis

745
01:02:42,701 --> 01:02:48,467
are going to be realized souls, a tremendous source of energy.

746
01:02:48,467 --> 01:02:53,067
That’s why you are married,
that’s why you are going to have children.

747
01:02:53,067 --> 01:02:56,601
Then look after your children with respect, regard.

748
01:02:56,601 --> 01:03:03,701
Don’t spoil them! And develop in that love of Sahaja Yoga.

749
01:03:03,701 --> 01:03:08,000
Now this started with our Hamsa Chakra.

750
01:03:08,000 --> 01:03:11,901
Now see the Hamsa Chakra is the left and the right.

751
01:03:11,901 --> 01:03:15,067
The left is the woman, the right is the man.

752
01:03:15,067 --> 01:03:17,167
They meet at Hamsa.

753
01:03:17,167 --> 01:03:23,167
So this is the wedding place of your left and right.

754
01:03:23,167 --> 01:03:29,134
If there is no balance between the two, there is a problem.

755
01:03:29,134 --> 01:03:34,801
They have to be equal.
But they are not similar.

756
01:03:34,801 --> 01:03:38,167
Left is left. Right is right.

757
01:03:38,167 --> 01:03:44,234
 So the right must be on the right hand side,
left must be on the left hand side

758
01:03:44,234 --> 01:03:51,467
and here when they come, they marry,
and this is the point one must know

759
01:03:51,467 --> 01:03:56,467
that, whatever is the function of a wife is,
she should do that first

760
01:03:56,467 --> 01:04:01,701
whatever is the function of the husband is,
 he should do that first.

761
01:04:01,701 --> 01:04:08,067
And then the secondary functions of life can be shared and understood.

762
01:04:08,067 --> 01:04:13,867
But it’s not possible that the wife goes to work and the husband starts producing children.

763
01:04:13,867 --> 01:04:18,267
You cannot do it!

764
01:04:18,267 --> 01:04:24,000
And the other way round.
So whatever is the work is so important.

765
01:04:24,000 --> 01:04:26,867
To be a mother, I think, is the most important.

766
01:04:26,867 --> 01:04:29,667
Today if you didn’t have a mother,

767
01:04:29,667 --> 01:04:32,201
which father would have done this work, you tell Me.

768
01:04:32,201 --> 01:04:34,967
Which one? Can you think of anyone?

769
01:04:34,967 --> 01:04:39,467
There may be ‘Father in Heaven’,
but Father on this Earth

770
01:04:39,467 --> 01:04:43,634
working with all Sahaja Yogis, let Me see which one is there.

771
01:04:43,634 --> 01:04:45,767
Anyone of these fathers, you call them.

772
01:04:45,767 --> 01:04:51,467
Nicely to sit down on Heaven and watch the whole stuff. But who’s going to do the work?

773
01:04:51,467 --> 01:04:58,534
Washing the dirty linen and washing all the napkins
and things is done by Mother.

774
01:04:58,534 --> 01:05:04,634
She does this with love and attention and with care,

775
01:05:04,634 --> 01:05:12,101
and She is the one who knows how to grow Her children. Is the job of a mother.

776
01:05:12,101 --> 01:05:13,767
So Mother’s job Mother can do.

777
01:05:13,767 --> 01:05:16,934
Father can sit in Heaven very nicely.

778
01:05:16,934 --> 01:05:18,667
All thanks goes to the Father.

779
01:05:18,667 --> 01:05:22,534
While the Mother is doing a thankless job here!

780
01:05:22,534 --> 01:05:24,767
Alright, doesn’t matter.

781
01:05:24,767 --> 01:05:28,967
It is so, so should be accepted,
whatever may be the situation,

782
01:05:28,967 --> 01:05:33,367
whatever may be the position.

783
01:05:33,367 --> 01:05:37,734
Now at Hamsa Chakra, this understanding must come

784
01:05:37,734 --> 01:05:44,534
that you must balance both the nadis, the left and the right.

785
01:05:44,534 --> 01:05:50,301
Now to balance the left and the right,
the best way is to do some breathing,

786
01:05:50,301 --> 01:05:57,901
is to take the air through one nostril
and keep it waiting here for a while

787
01:05:57,901 --> 01:06:00,667
and then allow it to go out of the other.

788
01:06:00,667 --> 01:06:02,567
Then you breathe in with this one,

789
01:06:02,567 --> 01:06:06,867
allow it to stay here for a while and
then allow it to go down.

790
01:06:06,867 --> 01:06:10,067
But it is to be done very slowly.

791
01:06:10,067 --> 01:06:14,067
Not in a hurry, not too much.
 Only thrice.

792
01:06:14,067 --> 01:06:16,167
Best thing as I’ve told you is neti.

793
01:06:16,167 --> 01:06:23,000
If not that, another thing I have seen that those inhalers, you see that you get, are very good.

794
01:06:23,000 --> 01:06:32,534
The neti thing that I’ve given you.
 If you fill the water below the spout and fill it,

795
01:06:32,534 --> 01:06:37,967
put in some two, three drops of one of those things
that you get for inhaling

796
01:06:37,967 --> 01:06:44,234
and put that neti thing in one nose only,
and with another nose it goes up.

797
01:06:44,234 --> 01:06:47,867
Then you come, bring it here, it goes up and clears it out.

798
01:06:47,867 --> 01:06:49,801
It’s a very good thing.

799
01:06:49,801 --> 01:06:56,534
If you do it every night before sleeping,
in three, four days you’ll be absolutely cleared out.

800
01:06:56,534 --> 01:07:01,401
But the main thing is: it comes because of imbalances in our temperaments.

801
01:07:01,401 --> 01:07:04,167
Like a man is a man, woman is a woman, alright,

802
01:07:04,167 --> 01:07:09,967
so the woman starts dominating a man
or a man starts dominating the woman.

803
01:07:09,967 --> 01:07:14,767
The balance is broken.
Once you understand the woman is very important

804
01:07:14,767 --> 01:07:17,867
without the woman you cannot, could not have been here.
 Alright?

805
01:07:17,867 --> 01:07:20,634
Without a woman you cannot be here.

806
01:07:20,634 --> 01:07:25,634
Man is very important that a woman has no meaning without a man.

807
01:07:25,634 --> 01:07:31,067
You see, Shakti has no meaning without God.
 For whom is She working?

808
01:07:31,067 --> 01:07:34,567
For whom is She doing all this? For God to be pleased.

809
01:07:34,567 --> 01:07:37,534
If there’s nobody to see the job, why should She do it?

810
01:07:37,534 --> 01:07:40,467
So both have great meaning.
And if you understand

811
01:07:40,467 --> 01:07:45,567
that both beings within us are balanced, understood, respected

812
01:07:45,567 --> 01:07:49,301
 in their proper ways

813
01:07:49,301 --> 01:08:04,701
and shared and coordinated, the personalities
in proper understanding, respect and love,

814
01:08:04,701 --> 01:08:09,234
your Hamsa will be alright.
 You’ll feel better.

815
01:08:09,234 --> 01:08:12,167
So you have to correct your ideas

816
01:08:12,167 --> 01:08:18,567
about marriage, about women,
about men, about yourself.

817
01:08:18,567 --> 01:08:22,967
That’s very important
because it is a very big emotional thing

818
01:08:22,967 --> 01:08:27,767
and, as the left side is weak,

819
01:08:27,767 --> 01:08:31,867
all people who have left side weak get cold.

820
01:08:31,867 --> 01:08:37,901
And all the things that have to do with your...
they call it bulgam, is it? What’s it called?

821
01:08:37,901 --> 01:08:38,801
Sahaja Yogis: Phlegm.

822
01:08:38,801 --> 01:08:45,734
Phlegm. Phlegm. Phlegm.
It has to do with your phlegm.

823
01:08:45,734 --> 01:08:52,801
So the emotional side is to be properly nourished and looked after

824
01:08:52,801 --> 01:09:03,434
and one has to know that your dignity is the most important.

825
01:09:03,434 --> 01:09:10,134
Anything undignified is not love.
Love is very dignified.

826
01:09:10,134 --> 01:09:18,867
And if you keep your dignity, you’ll be amazed how you will be able to solve certain problems.

827
01:09:18,867 --> 01:09:23,467
Now, again I’ll ask you a question.
 Now, how many have answered the questions?

828
01:09:23,467 --> 01:09:26,134
Most of them you answered very well.

829
01:09:26,134 --> 01:09:33,567
Now one more question I will ask.

830
01:09:33,567 --> 01:09:40,467
Very simple, not so difficult.

831
01:09:40,467 --> 01:09:47,201
That: what is the difference between a baddha and a bhoot?

832
01:09:47,201 --> 01:09:57,401
How will you make out? A hindrance and a bhoot.

833
01:09:57,401 --> 01:10:02,201
Sahaja Yogi: Bhoots will move around.

834
01:10:02,201 --> 01:10:03,267
And baddha?

835
01:10:03,267 --> 01:10:07,901
Sahaja Yogi: Stays there. Just describing,
it’s a block at that point.

836
01:10:07,901 --> 01:10:10,434
Though it’s correct, you said is correct,

837
01:10:10,434 --> 01:10:16,867
but it is not absolutely precise.
 It is like this, I tell you. It’s correct.

838
01:10:16,867 --> 01:10:20,434
I mean what he says is the correct answer but it’s not so precise.

839
01:10:20,434 --> 01:10:26,234
Baddha will also move.
 I’ll tell you how.

840
01:10:26,234 --> 01:10:30,334
Baddha is always in the centers or on your organs, say.

841
01:10:30,334 --> 01:10:35,967
If it is, say, in your, for example in the liver,

842
01:10:35,967 --> 01:10:39,567
this baddha may come in the center

843
01:10:39,567 --> 01:10:48,767
and then it will start moving from your here to here as the Kundalini will move. Alright?

844
01:10:48,767 --> 01:10:55,167
But baddha doesn’t have its arbitrary movement.

845
01:10:55,167 --> 01:10:57,667
As you move the Kundalini, the baddha moves.

846
01:10:57,667 --> 01:11:01,134
‘Baddha’ means hindrance. Alright?

847
01:11:01,134 --> 01:11:06,967
But a bhoot is arbitrary.
It moves.

848
01:11:06,967 --> 01:11:10,467
It will be one moment here, it will be one moment there.

849
01:11:10,467 --> 01:11:12,901
It will move this side, it will move that side.

850
01:11:12,901 --> 01:11:16,467
It will go to the right heart, then it will come to the left heart.

851
01:11:16,467 --> 01:11:19,667
If it is arbitrary behaviour,

852
01:11:19,667 --> 01:11:25,801
that means it is not controlled by your movement of your fingers through the Kundalini awakening

853
01:11:25,801 --> 01:11:29,534
that means it is not controlled by your movement of your fingers through the Kundalini awakening

854
01:11:29,534 --> 01:11:32,867
Now understand what I’m saying by decisive thing,

855
01:11:32,867 --> 01:11:37,367
that, one thing is arbitrary, works on its own,

856
01:11:37,367 --> 01:11:46,000
and the other is in your control.
You’re taking it out yourself.

857
01:11:46,000 --> 01:11:51,101
Like you can say that if there’s some lump in the body,

858
01:11:51,101 --> 01:11:54,934
it may start moving with the, say, bloodstream or something,

859
01:11:54,934 --> 01:11:59,601
some force acting upon it.
But by itself, it does not.

860
01:11:59,601 --> 01:12:06,767
But if there’s a worm, a living worm, it will move by itself.

861
01:12:06,767 --> 01:12:17,401
So the last question is then,
how do you manage the baddha and the bhoot?

862
01:12:17,401 --> 01:12:21,667
How will you take out the bhoot of other people without getting yourself into it?

863
01:12:21,667 --> 01:12:25,667
Otherwise the person whose bhoot has to be taken out

864
01:12:25,667 --> 01:12:31,901
will put three bhoots in you and five in the others.

865
01:12:31,901 --> 01:12:39,734
I have seen many a times they’ll come and tell Me,
“Mother, he’s possessed.” Alright.

866
01:12:39,734 --> 01:12:47,734
 And they themselves are!

867
01:12:47,734 --> 01:12:52,834
How do you take out? Come along.

868
01:12:52,834 --> 01:12:54,934
Sahaja Yogini: Bandhan

869
01:12:54,934 --> 01:12:57,034
Sahaja Yogi: You can throw the bhoot into a candle.

870
01:12:57,034 --> 01:13:01,201
What? Bandhan? No!

871
01:13:01,201 --> 01:13:06,267
No, First, first, that of course,
you all know what I’m doing, but…

872
01:13:06,267 --> 01:13:10,301
Sahaja Yogi: You can throw the bhoot into a candle.

873
01:13:10,301 --> 01:13:12,801
I mean, I’m saying a real one.

874
01:13:12,801 --> 01:13:18,000
 He’s not even afraid of candles.

875
01:13:18,000 --> 01:13:25,301
Sahaja Yogini: Say the mantra to Mukti Dayini.

876
01:13:25,301 --> 01:13:27,034
Sahaja Yogini: The Lord’s Prayer

877
01:13:27,034 --> 01:13:31,501
There’s no general thing about it.
Alright?

878
01:13:31,501 --> 01:13:41,701
All answers are correct but they are not complete.

879
01:13:41,701 --> 01:13:56,067
There are ways and methods according to different bhoots.

880
01:13:56,067 --> 01:13:58,501
They are trying to solve the problems

881
01:13:58,501 --> 01:14:08,067
But said it’s rather difficult!

882
01:14:08,067 --> 01:14:14,901
Now, first of all, you see a person who is possessed.

883
01:14:14,901 --> 01:14:25,901
I mean you are sure he is possessed, so you do like this, you see.

884
01:14:25,901 --> 01:14:28,234
Take a form, you have to take a form

885
01:14:28,234 --> 01:14:32,067
because you have to fight it.
 You take an aggressive form.

886
01:14:32,067 --> 01:14:37,501
Sahaja Yogi: Karate, Tony’s Karate [Tony Cooly].

887
01:14:37,501 --> 01:14:39,934
Karate, yes. Something like that.

888
01:14:39,934 --> 01:14:46,367
So then, I mean inside you become higher than that person.

889
01:14:46,367 --> 01:14:56,167
 Otherwise if you go like

890
01:14:56,167 --> 01:15:00,401
After some time

891
01:15:00,401 --> 01:15:06,667
So you go with a great force on that person.

892
01:15:06,667 --> 01:15:10,767
You put a bandhan and say, “Now sit down.”
Talk to him like this.

893
01:15:10,767 --> 01:15:13,734
You don’t go and say, “Please sit down,”

894
01:15:13,734 --> 01:15:17,201
because the thing will come and sit in you.

895
01:15:17,201 --> 01:15:19,567
Just say, “Now sit down.” Alright.

896
01:15:19,567 --> 01:15:25,467
There you have to say as if you are not compromising on this.

897
01:15:25,467 --> 01:15:28,334
No compromises.

898
01:15:28,334 --> 01:15:35,667
Then you ask the person various questions,
after giving yourself a bandhan

899
01:15:35,667 --> 01:15:41,401
and do that to verify what sort of a bhoot it could be.
That’s the best.

900
01:15:41,401 --> 01:15:46,467
First of all you ask that person,
“Have you been to any guru?”

901
01:15:46,467 --> 01:15:53,000
So now you know at least sixteen of them.
And you know how to take them out, also.

902
01:15:53,000 --> 01:15:57,934
So you find out which bhoot he has been to.

903
01:15:57,934 --> 01:16:02,301
If it is a guru, you just ask the person
does he still believe in that guru.

904
01:16:02,301 --> 01:16:04,867
If so, you have nothing to do with that person.

905
01:16:04,867 --> 01:16:07,201
You have no business.
You say, “I’m sorry, sir” …

906
01:16:07,201 --> 01:16:11,167
Not sorry You say, “Please go away.”

907
01:16:11,167 --> 01:16:13,534
If you say “sorry” it will come inside.

908
01:16:13,534 --> 01:16:18,167
Any inviting word you should not use.

909
01:16:18,167 --> 01:16:24,101
Just say, “Alright, finished!” you get out from that one.

910
01:16:24,101 --> 01:16:26,967
But in case he says, “I am possessed.
 I know I am in trouble,

911
01:16:26,967 --> 01:16:31,867
I’ve got this thing” and all that,
then you tell that person that

912
01:16:31,867 --> 01:16:36,101
“What is the name of your guru? What is the mantra you got?

913
01:16:36,101 --> 01:16:39,767
How many years have you been?”
Like that, you ask the question.

914
01:16:39,767 --> 01:16:41,967
If he is truthful and if he tells you that,

915
01:16:41,967 --> 01:16:47,501
then you exactly know where the mantra is,
what has happened to him.

916
01:16:47,501 --> 01:16:53,767
If it is a guru, then it has to be in the Void.

917
01:16:53,767 --> 01:17:03,201
If it is in the Void you tell him to say the mantra of Adi Guru,

918
01:17:03,201 --> 01:17:07,767
or ask the question, “Mother, are You the…?” on the photograph.

919
01:17:07,767 --> 01:17:12,267
Keep the photograph in front of your face like a mask if possible.

920
01:17:12,267 --> 01:17:16,201
Don’t allow you yourself to be exposed but give the photograph to the man.

921
01:17:16,201 --> 01:17:20,167
You say, “Now ask the question to this photograph.”

922
01:17:20,167 --> 01:17:25,534
Now if the person asks the question, the Kundalini
will start coming here doing

923
01:17:25,534 --> 01:17:30,000
“gragaralgagal.” He’ll also see the thing there,
you see, bubbling up.

924
01:17:30,000 --> 01:17:37,334
Then you should say that, after asking the question, “Now you say that, ‘You are the guru’!”

925
01:17:37,334 --> 01:17:41,301
If the person is possessed by a guru, then if you know the name of the guru,

926
01:17:41,301 --> 01:17:43,767
then you know the mantra.
When he’s doing all these things,

927
01:17:43,767 --> 01:17:47,534
you go on saying “NarakasuraMardini”
or “Mahishasura Mardini”

928
01:17:47,534 --> 01:17:52,767
or anything like that, whatever you have to do.
Or “Sarva-asura Mardini”

929
01:17:52,767 --> 01:17:58,067
For guru this thing, the best thing is salt, vibrated salt.

930
01:17:58,067 --> 01:18:02,534
You give some vibrated salt with water to that person to drink.

931
01:18:02,534 --> 01:18:07,167
It’s not easy to get rid of the guru, so you tell him very firmly

932
01:18:07,167 --> 01:18:10,867
that he’s one of the horrible ones we have ever known,

933
01:18:10,867 --> 01:18:13,667
so you have to work very hard to get rid of it.

934
01:18:13,667 --> 01:18:20,734
You give him salt, give him all that, let him do it.
And do not hurry up.

935
01:18:20,734 --> 01:18:24,301
Tell him it is going to take time, it will be alright,

936
01:18:24,301 --> 01:18:26,267
and what troubles people had with this,

937
01:18:26,267 --> 01:18:29,401
and he’ll have to work hard.

938
01:18:29,401 --> 01:18:33,567
This is one type of bhoots you will find.

939
01:18:33,567 --> 01:18:39,234
Then you find these are guru bhoots and which takes time,

940
01:18:39,234 --> 01:18:44,301
which are very difficult and they can take you up,

941
01:18:44,301 --> 01:18:47,067
it can be very dangerous.

942
01:18:47,067 --> 01:18:54,401
But say, somebody becomes blind with a bhoot.

943
01:18:54,401 --> 01:18:56,501
His eyes are open and he’s blind.

944
01:18:56,501 --> 01:19:05,601
That’s sure shot he is blind because of a bhoot.
 Two types of blindness are possible.

945
01:19:05,601 --> 01:19:12,534
The Left Swadhishthana will be catching
and you will see it is due to bhoot.

946
01:19:12,534 --> 01:19:15,034
But it can also be Left Swadhisthana catching

947
01:19:15,034 --> 01:19:20,434
and becoming blind could be with diabetes.

948
01:19:20,434 --> 01:19:22,934
Could be the combination of both.

949
01:19:22,934 --> 01:19:25,034
So you ask him if he has diabetes or not.

950
01:19:25,034 --> 01:19:29,434
If the person has no diabetes, then definitely it is the bhoot.

951
01:19:29,434 --> 01:19:37,401
Now what do you do to take out that kind of a bhoot?

952
01:19:37,401 --> 01:19:39,401
Sahaja Yogi: You use an enlightened candle.

953
01:19:39,401 --> 01:19:43,467
You take My hand.

954
01:19:43,467 --> 01:19:48,401
Photograph, only hand.

955
01:19:48,401 --> 01:19:52,667
You have photographs of My hand,
and put a candle before that photograph.

956
01:19:52,667 --> 01:19:57,534
All these photographs that you have separately have meanings.

957
01:19:57,534 --> 01:20:03,967
Put the candle and behind that is the hand

958
01:20:03,967 --> 01:20:08,534
and ask the person to see the light,
if he can see the light.

959
01:20:08,534 --> 01:20:13,101
Gradually, you’ll be amazed he will start seeing.

960
01:20:13,101 --> 01:20:15,901
This is to be used.
You see, in Sahaja Yoga,

961
01:20:15,901 --> 01:20:19,467
one has also to be precise just like the English words.

962
01:20:19,467 --> 01:20:21,867
If you are precise, it comes out.

963
01:20:21,867 --> 01:20:26,201
If you are not precise then you try this, you try that, it won’t work out.

964
01:20:26,201 --> 01:20:29,467
But if you have a photograph of My hands

965
01:20:29,467 --> 01:20:38,301
you should ask the person to see the photograph of the hand.

966
01:20:38,301 --> 01:20:43,367
By seeing the light, gradually the person will start seeing the hand,

967
01:20:43,367 --> 01:20:46,367
and then gradually the person will become alright.

968
01:20:46,367 --> 01:20:52,801
I’ve seen one person getting the eyes within ten minutes.

969
01:20:52,801 --> 01:20:55,667
But in that, if the Left Swadhishthana is catching,

970
01:20:55,667 --> 01:20:59,567
if the person has no diabetes and eyes are open,

971
01:20:59,567 --> 01:21:03,167
then it is definitely a bhoot, nothing else.

972
01:21:03,167 --> 01:21:06,201
Even if some people might say, “She lost her eyes because of,

973
01:21:06,201 --> 01:21:09,534
this girl lost her eyes because there was a fire in the house.”

974
01:21:09,534 --> 01:21:14,101
But she got frightened and the bhoots sat in here and she became blind. They are connected to both things.

975
01:21:14,101 --> 01:21:18,467
Actually eyes cannot remain open if the eyes are burned out.

976
01:21:18,467 --> 01:21:21,267
So if the eyes are open and absolutely normal to look at

977
01:21:21,267 --> 01:21:23,367
and the person cannot see, the light is out,

978
01:21:23,367 --> 01:21:26,567
that means there’s a bhoot.

979
01:21:26,567 --> 01:21:30,601
So these things can be very easily done.

980
01:21:30,601 --> 01:21:36,101
Sahaja Yogi: How do you do it?

981
01:21:36,101 --> 01:21:39,634
Photograph like this, and the light in front.

982
01:21:39,634 --> 01:21:41,467
It will improve your eyesight also.

983
01:21:41,467 --> 01:21:46,267
My hands should be used, very good for the eyes.

984
01:21:46,267 --> 01:21:50,234
My hands are extremely good for your eyes.

985
01:21:50,234 --> 01:21:53,767
If you can see My hands with the light,

986
01:21:53,767 --> 01:21:57,534
very good for your eyes.

987
01:21:57,534 --> 01:22:07,534
Now what are good My feet for?

988
01:22:07,534 --> 01:22:13,267
Feet photograph, what it is good for?

989
01:22:13,267 --> 01:22:24,434
Sahaja Yogi: Agnya.

990
01:22:24,434 --> 01:22:28,867
Very good for ego.

991
01:22:28,867 --> 01:22:33,667
 And also superego.

992
01:22:33,667 --> 01:22:37,667
Is very good for people who suffer from ego or superego, My feet.

993
01:22:37,667 --> 01:22:44,967
Because, such people are very gross.
 And the feet solve the problem.

994
01:22:44,967 --> 01:22:46,967
So just use My feet.

995
01:22:46,967 --> 01:22:49,967
If they see My Face, the ego will start working,

996
01:22:49,967 --> 01:22:54,167
“This face is like that, it should be like that – this, that.”

997
01:22:54,167 --> 01:23:00,567
Superego might give problems.
 Even supraconscious will give you problems.

998
01:23:00,567 --> 01:23:09,534
But feet, even if you are supraconscious, they’ll correct your problems.

999
01:23:09,534 --> 01:23:13,434
Feet are not only powerful

1000
01:23:13,434 --> 01:23:19,667
but they go up to the grossest point where you are.

1001
01:23:19,667 --> 01:23:22,267
Any type of person. Say, a drunkard

1002
01:23:22,267 --> 01:23:30,901
and all the bad things which are, a criminal, some sort of a man,

1003
01:23:30,901 --> 01:23:35,567
you just use My Feet, You’ll be alright.

1004
01:23:35,567 --> 01:23:42,367
Face won’t work for him.
Face is for the seekers.

1005
01:23:42,367 --> 01:23:50,567
But for all such people who are absolutely incorrigible types,

1006
01:23:50,567 --> 01:23:54,734
feet is the best. Those who have extreme ego,

1007
01:23:54,734 --> 01:24:00,567
those who have extreme superego – extreme.
Feet are very important.

1008
01:24:00,567 --> 01:24:03,767
You also sometimes watch My feet.

1009
01:24:03,767 --> 01:24:06,534
That’s a very good way, exercise.

1010
01:24:06,534 --> 01:24:12,467
Just watch My Feet to get rid of your grossness.

1011
01:24:12,467 --> 01:24:21,101
Just watch with your eyes.
 How are you going to watch through your Sahastrara?

1012
01:24:21,101 --> 01:24:25,567
 But also with Sahastrara you can see.

1013
01:24:25,567 --> 01:24:40,534
 See just see.

1014
01:24:40,534 --> 01:24:45,334
Sahaja Yogi: Mother, do You think if we used Your feet in the photo in the newspaper advertising we’d

1015
01:24:45,334 --> 01:24:46,634
get more people?

1016
01:24:46,634 --> 01:24:48,267
Will be a better idea.

1017
01:24:48,267 --> 01:24:49,434
Sahaja Yogi: We’ll try that.

1018
01:24:49,434 --> 01:24:54,967
But you see I don’t know.
Try. Very good idea.

1019
01:24:54,967 --> 01:24:57,867
You see on My books and all that we have tried.

1020
01:24:57,867 --> 01:25:05,567
On so many things I have tried, put My feet.
 Indians understand it.

1021
01:25:05,567 --> 01:25:10,434
Sahaja Yogi: Do you think they’d understand in the US?

1022
01:25:10,434 --> 01:25:14,467
Sahaja Yogi: Well, you don’t have to say Your name in the same thing.

1023
01:25:14,467 --> 01:25:15,834
Just put My feet.

1024
01:25:15,834 --> 01:25:17,401
Sahaja Yogi: Will just let it work through.

1025
01:25:17,401 --> 01:25:22,201
We’ll put SahajaYoga, we won’t say anything about Whose feet they are.

1026
01:25:22,201 --> 01:25:28,134
Try. It is very good. They’re tremendous.

1027
01:25:28,134 --> 01:25:37,101
See all the lights reacting.

1028
01:25:37,101 --> 01:25:41,867
You see?

