It would be better if you are
All right
We are here we all understand English do you all the people who are reporters English?
We are here
To inform you about
a power
Which is within us?
and the power that
Can give you what is promised by all the same scriptures and all the incarnations
Today when you see the young people in every country specially in the West
You'll find they are not satisfied
With their own atmosphere
Their lives
And they think there is something missing
And they are extremely confused
Now when they are confused
They are seeking for something beyond
Something unknown to them
In that seeking they may take to anything extreme
Drugs could be alcoholism
Or some other perversions, which cause horrible diseases incurable diseases
Instead of condemning them
We have to see why they are doing all these things
What is the purpose
Also some of them went to some gurus
Which are in the market
Especially when they see the religious people and the religions
They cannot believe that religion can give such horrid experiences
And some of them are anti-god anti-religion also
But if you deal with the problem sympathetically you cannot blame them because they are intelligent
Aware people
So now we have to category of people one the ones who are not seeking at all
And another are the once
Who want to find out solutions of the problems
In every generation
We had people who revolutionized
Because they did not like a particular system or did not like a particular style of life, whatever it was
But now the revolution has to come from within
We have to evolve from within
Because the destruction is also coming from within
We are destroying ourselves more from within
Because we are so unhappy so confused
Absolutely quite a percentage is schizophrenic
So then we start seeking this solution
And in that seeking we make mistakes
And we make mistakes because we do not know what to seek
And how to find
Also how to evolve to that state
So logically we have to reach
some conclusions logically
That it has to be some
evolutionary
happening
This is logical to
transform ourselves
There has to be some evolution
You was not an Austrian magic
Freud was invited
All right, so like you have said that
You have to become
Collectively conscious you have to become it's an actualization. It is not just a certificate
It has to be come from within it's an honest thing
It's an innate thing
It is not just a preaching
Or sort of a giving a certificate it is not or taking a name
It is actualization within yourself so
That something has to happen to us
Now as we have evolved from monkey stage to this stage for example
You've done nothing it is a living process
Which has taken place spontaneously
There's a big resistance
To any
Oriental ideas
being accepted in the West
wick resistance I
Find there's a very big resistance for any oriental ideas
Coming to the West
Now these oriental ideas which are coming
Are to be seen with a scientific open mind
Because the Western life has grown like a tree outside
But the roots may be in the East
Maybe we can keep ourselves open to see we're at the roots
Now if the roots are in the East supposing it's an hypothesis
So let us have a look at it. If there is any solution in those
So you go to oriental, I guess
But there also, it's very dangerous
Because you are going in the unknown you might go to false guru. You might go to wrong people
And get completely destroyed
So
What do we do?
First thing we should know we cannot pay for our evolution
We cannot pay money is not there
Nor can we pay for any living process any living process we cannot be
Like if the seat has to sprout the mother earth is sprouted we don't pay the mother earth
All right so first thing they should have known that anybody who asks for money
Is not a truthful person no money should be known
Then the second point comes in that we got to this stage of human awareness
Spontaneously
Without any effort effortlessly
In the same way it should happen
But first of all in every evolution there has been one leader
We can call them as archetypes as they say or whatever you may say want to say
So you was not very clear on that point
So now such a person can decode
the information
Of
symbols and everything and
Can help others without taking any money without taking any gratification?
Can do it and here it is
That people fumble in the West
They don't mind a pope
They don't mind an RPF of canterbury
But they do mind a person who is doing everything free just out of love
You'd be amazed in England the television people told me that we cannot accept anything which does not take money
Can you believe it he's a fact
In I think in Boston or somewhere they asked me a question how many Rolls Royces you have got
This is
And in San Francisco, they would not even publish my advertisement
Because by mistakes we had said that it can cure AIDS
They said no we don't want AIDS to be cured. We don't want anything to deal with our homosexuality
They said that horrible things that
65 percent people are
homosexuals in San Francisco and
the editor if he's a homosexual
and the
Chairman is even the Mary's
so I didn't know what to do I
Thought it better not to advertise because we will be useless for them
This is the problem is
Then the most important thing which is not realized by modern mind
That they believe anything new is to be tried
Is a very dangerous thing
If we are dealing with the living process of evolution we have to know
That
in
spiritual life
Whatever is going to happen
Must relate to scriptures to all the Scriptures must relate
Not to one scripture say for Holy Bible or Holy Quran or any but to all of them
Because it is like a seed that
sprouts
Then it becomes
the stem
then the branches
then the leaves
Then the flower and then the fruit living process it is based on something
Evolves through something, but whatever is dead like we can create a fruit plastic fruit from nowhere. Just like that is you
So which has no basis?
Has no meaning it must have a basis from where it has come its origin must be seen
As in the growth of the
tree
all that is useless drops out in the same way in evolution also all that is useless drops are
Even useless tradition drop out everything drops out but ultimately
You reach to the epitome
Where you become the fruit?
So the time has come for human beings to become the spirit
What's the white cotton
Fabric
So every seed has memory alright and
In the same way within us is our Camry is the Kundalini
And this is to be actually awakened actually awakened
Of course the superficial people who are not worried about the world will not bother about
Their out of question superficial people, but there are another kind
Who is making money in the name of?
spirit
Or living on that money and organizing
We'll definitely oppose us
Naturally we become controversial for them because the basically we'll use them
For no fault of ours we don't mean too much it just happens along
But a person who has
Pure intelligence
You need not be a very well-educated person nothing but pure intelligence can see through the game
Should be able to see through the game
Now in sahaja yoga, we have
thousands of people all over the world
There are people who are we can call them the highest in the society?
There are people who are the lowest in the so-called society?
all of them are
At par with each and every person there is no higher lower feeling
Everyone belongs to that society and so it belongs to that society
Moreover
when this happens
Because we understand
What these incarnations where?
The conflict of
All religions drops out like that
We understand it on central nervous system the conflict drops out
There is no question of not worshiping Christ
Muslims Jews Hindus
all worship Christ
They all worship Muhammad SAW, and they all worship Rama, Krishna
Because
Actually, they see that
when the Kundalini Rises she passes through certain centers and
There you have to take the name of those great
incarnations
so this is the knowledge of the roots and
one must know that you have to become a subtler being
to understand that knowledge
But unless and until we have that knowledge
We are in for a catastrophic there's a big shock awaiting us
And how are we going to avert it?
Just by talking about peace you don't bring peace
Those who talk about peace they don't have peace within themselves
So we are at that point we try
To talk about tell about it persuade people
And media can help us it has helped us a lot in Italy
And also in India of course because in India people know they have the knowledge of the route
So it's very easy in the villages of India
Even in the cities of India's we are
Doing very well not only that but
say for example Delhi University has accepted sahaja yoga for research and
The degree you get is a Doctor of Medicine higher than post graduation after post graduation
You get this degree is very rare Doctor of Medicine
For sahaja yoga, they have accepted even Cambridge University has accepted this for a result
So once you try to see the sense in it
Not they have not done it to criticize him, but with respect
Not to criticize it but with respect with acceptance that there is something about
So I would request the media to give the facts
By understanding it you have nothing to gain
But
Austrian people should be benefited. That's all
As a result of Kundalini awakening it can claim many things
But that can be seen that
Cancer can be cured so many incurable physical diseases can be cured
mental diseases can be cured
Drug addiction can be cured
The problems created
By these gurus can be cured
All these things can be done when you become the spirit
But this should be just at a level
of a hypothesis
When we do it, and it's proof, then you should accept not blindly
There is no blind faith in sahaja, yoga
We have no priest roots nobody is paid
It's a free society
And everyone becomes very knowledgeable
A sahaja yogi, may not be a doctor, but he can cure people
He may not be a sec artist, but he can keep your mad people
He becomes equipped
With the power by which he does it
like Christ was not a
doctor
Sure people in
The same way in the same fashion
Now I would like you to ask me questions because it's a very wide subject and one can go on talking about it
I wanted these people to explain to you for 15 minutes all other things so that you will have your questions ready for me
Any other you've said in the literature any unauthorized tampering
Can harm in some way your yoga?
How do you explain this unauthorized?
Anthony tampering interference written by sahaja Yogi's you see the language is
Probably people who try to awaken the Kundalini of course of course you
See the Kundalini can only be awakened
by a person who has the authority
divine authority
You cannot elect a person you see like we can elect a priest. It's not like that. You must have the power
to raise the Kundalini
Now those people who are leading already
But you can say every in one word dirty life. You can see
Cannot raise the Kundalini
you have to belong to this pure religion inner pure religion and
You have to have these powers
Otherwise those people who try other tricks what they do they disturb your sympathetic nervous system
activated
Kundalini doesn't rise
Kundalini will only rise
by a
proper sahaja yogi
For example I'll tell you
Supposing there is a seed
And you want to plant it
So you have to put it in the mother art
Supposing you put it on this table it won't
But supposing you put it in the fire it will burn
Only the mother earth has the power to sprout
That's what it is all right. I mean when you give communique Muslim is clear-cut all stuff. It's but I wouldn't understand myself
I'm sorry for that
What else these a lot of homework, I must say
It's great
and
That's why you must have read
There were some books in German also about Kundalini horrible books
That it harms you will burn chewed nothing of the kind it does not
It is the sympathetic when activated by wrong type of things like sex
activations another the activation some people
Try to turn this out and all that and you start seeing the light and all that thing. This is not short-circuiting
Actually you suffer a lot with that
It's a spontaneous it just happens to be spontaneously
Are you feeling relaxed yourself you got it
You've got your realization
Only thing you have to little bit know about it. That's all
absolutely relax this or thought
You got it
just while talking to me you got it because you are a positive person want to know about if you come with a
Determined effort just to criticize then nothing can work out is it
It's nothing's got it
You got it
May God bless you
It's your own I've done nothing I was just talking to you
Kundalini knows that you are sitting before me she just rolls by herself. That's your mother
That's your mother your own indeed your mother
That's the Holy Ghost that's the primordial mother
Which Christians don't talk about and then they don't want you to know anything else?
whatever they will teach you should learn nothing more I
Was myself born in a Christian family?
So you have to have you see blinkers on both the sides you're not supposed to see this fight work that side
And this is why young people fell a trap
To these horrible gurus who came to make money here I?
know of somebody who came from jail
Who came to Germany?
wearing those saffron clothes sat on one of the
Centers there somewhere and a relief rock to him he came from jail
Because you don't know
how to make out a good
Guru the sub guru and the a guru is there are books and books on that come India
but they don't know four things and
I don't blame them because they were seeking seeking so honestly that they got into trouble
But I have been talking about them from
But the underworld
Another problem was with young people from the West was that they hated Christianity
That's one problem so when I talked about Christ they just under went back
You can talk to them
They said don't talk of Christ they went out
So this Christianity has done nothing but a harm to them that they just don't want to hear about Christ
Which Christ is a living God no doubt?
And I have to talk about him very much
But they didn't like it. It's such a problem of
Conceptions
Conceptions see reality is what reality is is not a concept
This is what it is see Christ is the son of God. He is the real
personality whatever
Church may do to eat or anyway do to it makes no difference he is what he is
And this is the problem is the concept?
Concept is not reality
that's just a mental prediction just
a mental projection
You have to rise beyond that
to be the spirit
All right
We got this nano your name, please
your name, please
George
Is the name of an angel
Yes st. George and st
George we call him as Bhairava in our Indian language. He's called as head of a st. George
Very great God
accordion
So we have nobody else now here Steve you have any questions
Now must be because you see you're a two-faced journalist, what about you?
Where has this message can spread in the world - which country
It's now 16 countries
There are thousands of people in about six of those countries
Of course of course we
Have here actual RCZ was in the Islam religion
from, Algeria
Then of course you know him very well, and here only you'll find people from different
religions sitting here
There's a lady from a Hindu religion there sitting and
What was your religion? Maybe she?
Born again
You self-certified God again, I thought no, that's same thing guys
All right
So of course no doubt we have an all religions all caste or creed like Sierra
Leone now we have got the Africans there
There we have got
Spain we have gotten even into Bolivia. Will you be eyes what is that religion therefore?
Only we have a kind Bolivia and also in
Now in Peru everywhere
so
It is infinite it goes to everyone it cannot be see even God is one how can you have?
anybody barred
we have Chinese and
We have Japanese all types of people we have from all races from everywhere, so there's no question
what is
But actually I cannot give the list of all the nations, but practically all except for Scandinavian
Nations we have not approved, but we have Scandinavian people in sahaja yoga, but we have not yet established centers
So many people were there
See I think Italians are great sensitive people
Italians are very sensitive and
You will be surprised in Italy there are no gurus except in the north of Italy. They are very sensitive very emotional and sensitive and
they respect love and they have respect for mother all and
When they saw my photograph they did feel something about it. I don't know what they felt about my photograph
I don't know what photograph. It was but they felt peace maybe
Whatever it is
But I was amazed the whole hall was filled with me absolutely and
Italians even as far as the government is concerned
All of them are very open to sahaja, yoga
Surprising they're very sensitive people, and they must have found out about me that I have done all good
There's no objection to anything and now they have invited me to a press conference which we do. I will tell you what it is
It is a press conference of all the people of Italy it's a very big thing called as the press conference
guest of the Year mother most of the
Talking to all of them
Will be nice be nice really nice meeting them all yes
But I feel Austria is one country which is very much in the center somehow
It's very much in the center Austrians are neither East nor West
Centipede and they are very good for sahaja yoga, very sensible people in Austria
And we have found very sensible people in Austria no doubt about it another thing is Austria has never given us any
problem
We never got people who were
schizophrenic or nonsensical or fighting types nothing very nice people did want
surprising
So Austria has a special place. I think in Europe
It's very you know they are very heavy, and you're put very small means there so what happens
If they don't get it
What if they get it
Some people get the Kundalini raise some don't what happens to people after death if they don't
Religions work on a concept that you do it our way, or you end up in a horrible place
No, it's not like that
You see I think
most of the people should get it
to get a very generous
We work the whole thing as the world is today
It will be taken by people they have take to realization. I'm sure
Most of them will get it supposing if they don't get and die then there will be born again, and they'll get it
But those work to go to hell will go to hell in any way
in any way
You see there there. There are people as used
I would say who would never take to anything good would be there could be people I have not known
But maybe we should give all the benefit of doubt
Yes because you see
Yes, that is it now. I'll tell you what happens that your spirit is absolutely. It's absolute
Spirit is an absolute thing
supposing now
You want to know whether I'm good or not?
Or he's good or not
The good is not the way we look at things like you see we see the dress in the face
This is not looking superficially, but when we have to see person is good or not we see
We feel his chakras
What chakras he's catching you can feel them on your fingertips you see like Muhammad Sawa said that your hands will be speaking
So you feed on your centers than other person?
So we don't certify them as good or bad that category doesn't exist in sahaja yoga, what we say
What are the centers catching in a person?
Now what is catching in a person? What centers are wrong? We try to correct it?
We like it. We can say a patient comes to a hospital the doctors
Don't say you have good or bad. They don't categorize like that what they seem
What is the disease let us treat that it's like so the good and bad?
Is not described in sahaja yoga, what is described at the centers which are out of place?
But some people have ruined their centers completely have no Kundalini at all with them
They are like devil some of them must have been I don't want to name them, but could have been
So this is such people then what to do. They must have designer. I mean you cannot force anyone. That's the big problem
If they desire it well and put if they don't desire it you cannot just make them do it no you cannot
They have to desire it in their own freedom
Then they get it the joy
Nothing can be forced. This is the handicapped
So we have don't know category we don't condemn anyone as bad, or we do not elevate somebody as excellent, but
We tell them what are the center sketching and when you get your realization
You will know what sketching in you and you will also know. What is catching in him
And then if I tell you supposing I if I tell him
Dr. Warren your other sketching means your ego is coming up. He won't feel bad because he'll get a headache there
They said better correct it mother
Which is ego will get a headache a little bit Surratt corrected?
so nobody feels bad about
It so there is nothing like good and bad are words used very vague. They are very weak terminologies
This is not procedure about it because fear it is absolute so
Everything related to spirit is the absolute knowledge?
You may say a person is very good
This is an excellent person that we don't accept what we accept is
What are the condition of his chakras are and how much we can help?
That's not we not bothered about who's good who's bad that category doesn't exist that
Type of a category, but of course the condition of the chakras are varying
Any other question Steve. You better ask me. He's an American I
Describe it
I never had it so how much
I'm born like this but
I would say the experience of self-realization that I have seen that happens to people first of all
When the kundalini rises you see of course the mechanism goes into complete force?
and
When she pierces through the fontanel bone area
first thing you feel is the
cool breeze in the hands
But not necessarily some people feel it on top of their heads coming out a cool breeze from their head own head
So the self-certification is there you see the cool breeze, but could be some people have too much heat coming out see supposing
It's a cancer patient especially
Or anybody like that to see this patient you find that a heat comes out
Supposing it's a person. Who is very much possessed and
extremely unhappy type of person maybe
Or an open person whatever it is the Kundalini you can see clearly with your own eyes
It's pulsating at different centers, but especially at the base of
the spine will be called as the
sacrum
Sacrum is sacred both and the sacred book so you can see it very clearly we have got photographs of that absolute
Pulsation you can see like a heart
Then they experience moves with some people it does
I must say they do feel the rising if it is slow rise, but if it shoots off
You don't feel anything you just feel the cool breeze coming out of your head
Then you start feeling out of your fingertips
But the feeling you get first of all
When heat rises about this Center you feel?
You're beyond, thought. You are in the present. We are not
Just enjoying the peace peace of your being
enjoying yourself in the way and
Then when it pierces through a kind of a
Joy that trickles it out in different different people have different
But say for Indians you see they don't think so much as you think you people think think think think too much
So they don't think so they get there first of all they get the joy
But in the West I think the people who get
More the awareness about it. They start feeling his chakras is chakras
They practice these that ultimately they get the gist, but Indians first get the joy they said
It depends on the condition of a person what the experience would be but on the whole
This one thing happens to all of you that your eyes start listening. They said listen. There's a twinkle in the eye
That's one
And their face becomes to see relaxed
The wrinkles drop out you drop out sometimes ten years
like see my aged 64 years of age -
But people can't believe it because you see I don't feel my age at all. I'm we all have forgotten what our ages are and
This is what happens to you because you go in a state of existence only
But takes little time
Gradually to grow into it, but it starts with the sprouting of this seed that is the Kundalini
But experiences people have different like in your case. It was very deep I know
Because he was a great seeker, and he has started a band without knowing the word surge on his own Siraj bad
I don't know how he started. He must have got it from the unconscious really
And he had such a strong
Experience because after that I met him for about five minutes, and then he went away to master and from Boston
He sent me a telegram that mother we are waiting for you in Boston
They said mother who is this one. I said he Steve I know him very well. I'm going down
And they were surprised they said how will you recognize you've seen him only for five minutes?
I said I recognize him don't you worry I'm going down there
So you see all I can feel that also myself it in myself the person who's got it like I told you that
It's in a part of the collective is the collectively part
Because of collective consciousness you can feel another person and you can feel yourself
But he's an experienced on your central nervous system is the thing
But when you get joy, and when you get your awareness, it's a thing depending on the condition of yourself
Mostly the West people first become aware you're aware they start seeing things better
Those who have never noticed say for example a very nice curtain is lying here, but people will come see superficially go away
But the sahaja yogi will see what a nice curtain what a nice pattern? What nice flowers what nice you see
Penetration into everything it starts feeling everything
Penetration is but experiences are different and different
like I think everybody must write about
Other a question that many people ask
At such conferences is this is why in the past was it so easy?
And so difficult, sorry, and why today, it's so easy
That's not embarrassing to ask me
But one should reach a conclusion there must be something about me
That I do it that easily all right one point our second point could be
explained with an analogy
That in the beginning there are very few flower flowers on a tree
Very few one or two
Then when tree comes up in age and plus sometime starts as thousands so the time has come
The time has come and I have come maybe that two things put together
But maybe I know the trick of the trade better perhaps
This is what I have discovered is our mas realization not individual, but
Alma's
That's what I have discovered if you want me to proclaim. I will proclaim that
but
There's nothing
Great about it I think
Because if you have something what is so great I?
Am achieved nothing you have achieved
That's the point is you have a dyad this with me you have achieved a
Channel you must ask me some questions he say he's a barrister
Miss lane miss lane
How they form different different, that's a good point now you see inside why you get into the essence of everything?
Say if you get to the essence of the three
The easels or the SAP of the tree goes to every flower
It doesn't discriminate
But flowers are different
Now what these people have done, they have plucked these flowers like somebody says this is my religion. This is pluck the flower
Then the flowers are dead now, so they are carrying on with dead flowers the religions are dead now
But they are flowering on the same tree and
You get inside the SAP through the root, so you see that everything is the same. It's just a manifestation of the same
Now electricity is flowing it is giving you there. It is giving you a air conditioning
It is working out there, but electricity is the same because you become the essence
But when you see from outside they look different
Especially when deliberately they have plucked out these flowers and established, this is mine Christ is mine how?
Islam is mine how?
It is not you cannot have them as properties they cannot be your property
So this is what you realize
And that's why you see that everything has the same you see because now you have become aneesa's new eyes have opened out you see
That everything is the same you cannot become a fanatic now you cannot
Even if you try to be
It just cannot become fanatic anymore because you see the essence is the same I
Mean shoe got put into this you got put into that sugar put into that if you become the sugar you are
Everything isn't it I?
Mean religion had to be little different in its form because of the times that were there
Times where this way that way you see every time they had to change the outward
Form and things like that on social level and political level this that but he says was the same
Of course you can't have it anymore
That's very true because you see the essence is the same how can you see fanaticism comes from what finite we should say
When you go into infinity how can you have fanaticism?
You finite yourselves, I am these are these that is clubbing actually it is nothing but ordinary clubbing see
we have clubs like somebody puts the say the
Table where on the left side is one a club they put it on the right side another
They distribute you see this is just like stupid clubbing that sorts
You cannot club outcry God or Christ or any one of these incarnations? They are all brothers and sisters and relations of each other
They are all related Legion
But those people who were in charge
Try to destroy them as soon as possible I take the charge
Christ Lee for four years how moments are believed. You know every one of them how they were tortured
That's what happened
Because they wanted to take advantage of that
But forgive them now all right
Any other question from you yes, yes
Hungry should we approach?
Seekers in these countries, which are not free such as Hungary and Czechoslovakia and in a way they're better off I did
I've been to Russia
I know they are not free
But you see when freedom is
One one should be able to very quickly see what is happening to the free countries today. If you see that warrant
If you go to America
You can't wear your watch. You can't wear your bangles. You can't wear anything
Maybe tomorrow they'll pull out your hair also
It's such a chaotic country so this freedom also human beings cannot be in a way
As far as other these free countries are I tell you the people are so simple I?
Went to China I went to Russia because of my husband's job
I where all people are extremely simple the governments are not at all, right
But it will take no time for you to ignite. No actually it is already gone in a way
Logically they are understanding it now that sahaja yoga it
So it will come through Russia it will come through China from these bigger countries
But what about the free countries first of all tell me about them
Free it's a license
Because we will have people of that quality what we need is a transformation of human beings
Hypocrites talk of big big things cannot achieve anything isn't it?
But the people who believe not believe but no as
An actual thing that we are part and parcel of the whole
Will not think of one government another government will think of one world the world
All these so-called politics is because we are divided the nose is fighting guys eyes is fighting the years
When they discover we are one body what is there to find?
So most of the politics will be dissolved completely as it is now see look at us
We have powers
So we are capitalists, and we want to give it to others so we have communists already
If you want to carry we don't want to conserve it
So we are already
Doing the right thing the integration
So all these problems come out of human beings and as soon as they become the spirit the problems will be dissolved
Social problems see we have already solved so many social problems in sahaja yoga. We don't have problems what you normally see
Our children are great our marriages are great. We are enjoying our lives
It's heavenly
One or two mishaps are there doesn't matter but mostly
We have a beautiful society no quarrel no jealousies no Fighting's no malice no hair trade nothing
Isn't it great to have such a society and no dictation nothing absolutely free
I know Mary. What did you want to ask?
Why is it that people
Are missing the chance they read the poster?
and they walk by it happened to me in 82 I saw your poster I
See people are some are very superficial
Something known of themselves
They think they don't need anything all kinds of things that I know I agree with you, but it happens yes, please
What're you
Saying that the advertising by the sahaja Yogi's
For this program sounds a bit like an ad for instant coffee. He thinks it is instant coffee
But he's saying that
CI tell you, but I tell you we buy instant coffee isn't it now in modern times everything is done
so we had to have instant you about
It is what to do
It is but you see now we can say that you can get it after a lot of sufferings
And you have to sacrifice the same sacrifice that all right, but it's not true now what?
It is instant coffee, but we take instant coffee. We want everything instant in this modern time why not yoga
So you tell us now how to advertise
Yeah, you see what I'm saying that that's a fact. I really did it. That's a fact
That's a fact the Kundalini. I call it a jet Kundalini in modern times really I'm myself surprised that it's working
Just shoot wrong Oh
thousands of people in India thousands
See just shoot shuttle
What am I to do it works like that?
It's just I think the divine is anxious that let's have it down like that. It is in modern times. It's working very fast
Not only me ask him how many people he has given realization every one of them have given to thousands
realization I mean it seeing is believing but
Advertising we do not know what to say now. What is it written here now?
Perhaps thinks it's I don't know the English where it might be it's a little slick. It's a little smart, but
or
Something like that perhaps you mean more profound. Do you do you mean more deep more?
Sounding like the other gurus that come I don't know about observables what they write
But why don't you see tweet what you should write? I have no idea but
What should we see what should we say here and now is a fact I tell you we need
Now we can what should we say?
All right
But what I am saying for people to be attractive what is saying that when you have to attract people from outside
then we should put
Try to change it, I don't know what
I
Think perhaps implied in Mary's question was is there a time?
Is there a certain stage when you come to Santiago?
Or is it that everybody should be brought in right now?
Do you reach a stage in your awareness where you're ready for it?
Or is it something that you just come if the advertising department is good is it worth?
You just I don't know what what what to say on this point because you
Cannot say certainly that people have to reach a certain stage because a person you see
His wife brought her saying that he's the worst man
He indulges in to this indulge us into that and all kinds of things bad
Certificates about that fellow and as soon as he came in he got his realization
You see the really true IT
People suffering from cancer got realization in no time
So what is the stage I don't know, but maybe we can say the
Attitude towards life maybe
That's to towards life is you see say for example in the West
like these BBC people telling me that if you say that it is without money nobody will listen to
When I cannot say it is for money, that's one part. He said when you say free admission
Things is useless
The conditioning is so bad that if the free admission oh must be something funny
This is what?
Anglo-saxons brain cannot understand anything without money, can you imagine he told me frankly you said do you change this?
I said well. What should I say I don't take really you don't take any money what am I to say?
This is what it is you see is the conditioning of the mind, but in in English is not so
In India if you see from the villages they'll come on bullet cards, they'll have miles together they'll walk when they will know I'm going
Also the knowledge is not here
They don't have no background what I would say
My background is needed, and I don't know the sensitivity is needed for Italians did not have the background, but sensitivity is their
Worst reason I would say in Switzerland or America is the worst of all
America fell for all kinds of guru because for sahaja yoga zero very bad
I'm sorry what it is. They don't look at sahaja yoga now
They are after they have had all the experience of all the guru shopping
They did now they're coming they want to do shopping. You know it's a fashion guru is a fashion
It's nothing deep it's a fashion
Going to this guru that will do that guru so how to talk to them they have money they want to shop it
How many cover the worst of all I must say
Experience wise supposed to be the most advanced most free country. They have the worst of all
But in Austria I've seen the Falls are filled
They're full
In Austria we always get the how Falls are completely filled
just like
also in Italy
There is never death of people. I mean people have to sit on the stairs in Austria isn't it we don't have that problem
but getting realization
Is not possible for everyone perhaps
There's some sort of an understanding needed I
can't explain why because the house are also lighted you see in the
Halls are absolutely filled people sit on the stairs you see some are sitting outside some are standing on the street
Is there despite those facts there are sex and brain ceases?
Did you write free
Please come now gradually. They will see they have to learn their lessons a little bit more. I think that's all
They have to learn their lessons a little bit more now you with you
I'll tell you why because you are in the you and a big boss there
Working in the you and itself's pulse your head
I tell you I know my husband is there so I know all of them and
Their heads get swollen up to see you and personalities
And you are attending big conferences you see so-called big big people receive it because you see me to
Be the big head these things do not go in so it's alright, but now you are alright
But that is one of the things you want people bureaucrats at the worst of all
There will be the last to come to sahaja yoga, my husband is a bit of that and I would deal with them
I never talked to them about sahaja yoga, never never never
Bureaucrats Anthony you see they they only want to serve government. That's all
They don't understand anything. They are so bureaucracy is like that
Now what else you have in Austria bureaucracy, then you have military
Students
Yes
Why should you have to
Do why should you have to rush it?
There's no need at all I would be very happy if they don't worship like you see those who worship me
And found out something good out of it
that's whatever so actually you know I hate that I
Always see that these puja should be so much lengthy that I have some time to rest this
But I don't want them to worship me at all. It's very good. That's very good of them
I tell you some of them when they touch my feet I get blisters
Horrible as if yesterday. I was telling you like scorpion I
get such big big blisters on my feet I
Don't want them to wash it if you ask me
But they would like to because you know what it means
What's shipping me?
You all know it very well
What's shipping? What do you give me nothing?
You just say certain mantras is that what do you give me nothing?
That's nothing to worship me for example now see my photograph this one
Is when I was sitting in a village
When I entered the village I told him there is a very great soul who lived in this village
They said there was one. He was a Muslim his name was Mia
So I said now
He must have been still here, and I sat down to be my lecture and I saw the spirit
Coming as a light of two. Hexa words to say on top of my head
I saw it right
but you can't see I mean people can't see but camera captured it the camera captured it and
Then the the sun's rays through that prism like spirit
Started coming as all seven colours on me. I could see
I could see then I was very happy with increasing in this report, but nobody could see and then I said alright now
It's more than sufficient like that I said
But nobody can see it now. What's this am I telling them that yeah, you should see because you will not see
So why'd you tell anybody about my worshipping also till they understand it, but the camera caught it. What can I do?
And what the camera caught it I didn't say
Why do they worship Christ I've never seen in you
Why do they worship Christ murder they have never seen her what did she do she was just crying all her life
she didn't give realization to anybody even Christ did not give realization to
Anyone why do they worship him
You are a Christian you should ask them a question
Why do the Muslims worship Kaaba
But in sahaja yoga, I am a discovery for you. I never asked anyone to worship me never, baba
It's horrible for me
I have frightened of people trying to worship me because you see I have to take up everything of the stuff in everything that you
Well yeah, they can tell me you that I just don't like it
And I want to make a big gaps in between you see so that at least have some time to rest
Do something the whole thing digest it and take it out
So you need not tell them at all in the beginning you should not tell them anything concerns that you are great come along
Let them have the realization
then if they're saying
Then we should consider whether they should worship me or not and everybody is not allowed to worship also
Do you know that Mary we don't allow everyone to come
You have to be a clean person, otherwise they are not allowed
So the this worship is your privilege not mind by any chance. I tell you
Any chance and which you will all say that mother is chance it I
Really, shun it and these false gurus because nothing happens to them they like it so
There's no explanation for this it is to be seen
if they come to sahaja, yoga
They can see it very well unless until they come in it you should not talk of me as anything as incarnation anything
Just don't talk you should not tell them how to worship or anything just tell them that you have to get your realization
Let them first open their eyes then talk to them about these things
In the beginning if you start talking they will be stuck no doubt they are stuck because they have not reached that thought
They have to be seaworthy to be in the sea isn't it
Yes
Nothing is needed to begin with actually and I don't want anything really
If there is anything that
Is to be done is to give realization to everyone, that's all
but to progress further
They have to worship
They will worship somebody who is dead and gone
They never worship Christ when he lived they never worshipped his mother when he lived she lived
They never worship drama. They never worship, Krishna now when they are dead were nice to worship because they are stones now
What can they do to you?
That's human nature when somebody is dead
Then be perfect all right the ones who crucified Christ have raised these churches
When person leaves you see in the present you never appreciate
Because we don't allow anybody to worship, also. It's very it's a great privilege for anyone to be there
You know that?
It's not for everyone so
Many people have been denied in England and all that just now you have to prepare yourself
Everywhere
And yesterday I was telling me know that you should not have brought clad lady. She was no good
The one who was your roommate Oh?
Was pestering you I said, she was very caught up, and you should not have brought her from the Buddhist that disturbs me
It's very significant, but like a person who has to be a postgraduate student to understand certain things
You have to be a postgraduate in sahaja yoga to be in aversion
Otherwise you should not so you don't stock of these things. It'll get stuck no doubt when I have no doubts about it
Anybody would get stuck
Because looks so funny isn't it that you have to worship another human being it is so we have to use discretion
Anybody would be stuck that way unless until you are a first-class sahaja yogi
And you understand the value of it you have gone deep into it. Then only you realize
It's to be appreciated
I never talked about me at all to anyone now. I really some Saints started talking about me
Some Saints only told some people that this is this
Then they came and asked me and I said all right you find out for yourself
You see with human beings you have to be very very careful and cautious, I do not want to get crucified
See
To be very very cautious with them because ego is the first thing they come in they don't understand. What is beneficial for them
See what did Christ do to them did he ruin them, or do any bad to them, but they crucified him isn't it?
They gave poison to Muhammad SAW
Why what was the thing?
Because he go so should we calculate
Even when you write supposing in your wherever you write should write it cautiously she make it so that
According to your own understanding that they come to my program
Use your wisdom
What you want to put it how to put it?
or if you want to say you can say that at the first instance the Kundalini rises and
Then you have to grow into it if you don't want to say quick
instant coffee business, so you may say like this that might might reprise I
Would suggest that way?
All right that you turn
But with the people some of the very deep people they just get realization in
Thousand it because they have been deep people all their lives not life, but lies
So they just hit it
So it attracts people who are superficial then it's not a good thing to say
That may be one of the reasons that only superficial come to our program
We should find out how to write that the deep people are attracted
Isn't it we should find out ways and methods by deep people are attracted not superficial I?
Gave you the whole gets filled up because maybe superficial
Like a saint on see nobody buys anything. It's just to say law and everybody comes to see the same
This is Kali why is he this is a
Confused state in this. This is a this is the age of confusion
This is the age of confusion really?
Also some people say that why should I give realization? I said better you give very good idea
I would like to return
See this is ego. Isn't it? Why should you do it?
I mean I'm doing it because I do it alright, but if you can do it nothing like it. I'll return
I'll be very happy I
Mean my age has is beyond doubt retirement I would have retired long time back see going on and on
So also you should see the people who they are and
Then talk to them
Must use discretion very important to use discretion
As he said it may be some people may not get it in this lifetime, maybe next time
Also it happens that the seer some
people get realization say for example and the transform and
become something very beautiful
Then the mediocre mediocre people you see
May see that and try to follow it
The mediocre may try to follow it
Like when I went to Italy this gentleman was a very famous person who interviewed me
He said first you give me realization then I'll Italy
Because
Perhaps he believed in me whatever. It was or may not have believed might be doubting whatever it is
He got his realization, then he started laughing
And he said also, I've got it now. I said yes, you got it now
It is he who is organizing all this thing so maybe like this it might forgot
Depends all you see human beings are quite complicated in modern times
Very difficult to hold on to them if you give them this they'll come this way if you give them that they'll come this way
Just I don't want to have it
Just some hooks or excuses it's terrible I know
Especially in the West it's very difficult
But they'll accept her something stupid like Punk's
Thanks you will find thousands now
People in very high positions are punks now. Can you believe it imagine our Prime Minister going as a punk?
They accept stupid things without any questioning
Think of it drugs for example
They accept it without any understanding without any asking and very
educated
highly placed people doing
Absurd things like that
Alcoholism womanizing everything all nonsensical things
But to do something good to yourself it takes time a
Very self-destructive by temperament
Just do something nice to ourselves
To get some blessings upon ourselves yes
We'll be all right
They have to learn their lessons that's collecting as they have to learn their lesson
Satisfied
I'm happy he's a very wise man
He's done the homework the other people just came just like any that for fuck out you see it's a deep subject
It's a very deep subject
you cannot just
Up here and go out
Steve are you going to?
Put this into the world
No, but you see well one point
I see in is what he's saying that one of the things this really come to my mind is this
That this may be that we get superficial people
So we should put something deep in it because it's very deep experience
Suggestion you see there is something which explains certain things
They like my lectures all right, they like to listen to my lecture because you see it appeals to them mind
But they don't get realization so that means they are not very deep
Yes, that is one thing yeah
Now for example in Switzerland we put our these things
Nobody removed it still their last three years. It is there. It's very surprising in Switzerland
Where people are so meticulous they have kept my photographs?
In Italy us
All my three year old photographs are there
It is there. What about also I must say that advertising whatever it was in
Australia
Australia is
very progressive in such
Australians imagine
Can you believe it that they were?
Sent there as criminals their forefathers and today. They are the ones who are going to take everyone to
spirituality
So how can you say good and bad?
Australia is the best
Well Stella is the best now I?
Mean in progress. We have the leader from Australia for the Warren started the whole thing and we have James has he come
May God bless you may God bless you