Like fumes.
Fumo.
And it is such an absurd place.
And there is, also very surprising that,
every 28 minutes, in a place
water comes out of the Mother Earth,
every 28 minutes.
It shoots off, exactly after 28 minutes.
It’s a very funny place and lot of sulphur,
lot of sulphur there.
Sulphur just bubbling out of,
you find suddenly from somewhere
there’s a hot water coming out
like just pouring out water.
Can you imagine such a place?
Now, Andes is another site.
Andes is a kind that will give tremors, earthquakes.
It will give lots of earthquakes
and it has lots of gold also because it’s a right-sided,
lot of gold and it will be giving lots of earthquakes.
When it will come to destruction,
it will be used as earthquakes.
They will, it will act as earthquakes.
America is that whole portion,
it is all Andes from top to bottom,
and all that will be shattered by earthquakes.
So, these two forces will act
more at the time of destruction.
So, one has to be careful about it.
Because, you see, Bolivia,
say Peru and all these places,
these people went from here.
They killed so many of these people.
So many of these races were killed completely.
Then dead bodies were there.
Killing is very bad, because when you kill a person,
that person cannot take birth and
hangs in the air and becomes a bhoot.
So, they have overpowered Americans.
That’s why Americans are like that.
You see, they killed all the people
from New York to the whole of America
was all people who were aboriginal.
So, they have possessed them also.
And in the same way in the South it’s happening.
So, it is all, again,
though it is right-sided but it’s supraconscious,
all supraconscious things.
So, they have to be very careful now.
They have to take to Sahaja Yoga
and those who will be taking to
Sahaja Yoga will be only saved.
The rest will be destroyed,
because Andes will act as a
supraconscious thing for destruction.
And Fujiyama and all that, will have,
not, they will have those, what you call them?
Volcanoes.
Mother, I‘m terribly sorry, but
the tape, we ran out of tape.
Would You just explain again the left side,
the right side and the Himalayas?
I’m sorry to do this to You.
Of what?
Just as You described just a moment ago,
how the Himalayas is this and the two columns.
You see, you think of Himalaya as the central point,
Kailash
Yes. Sahasrara.
Yes, fontanelle bone
And this is the plate of the Ekadesha.
All right!
Now all the, even this Zermatt and this alps
and all that is in the same.
In the same line?
On the right and left side, both sides.
(Unclear) Argentina we have all these on that
so it’s all Ekadesha
But, on both the sides, we have got Andes
and this side, we have got Fujiyama and all this.
Out of these two, the left-sided one is the Andes.
I‘ve treated it as Andes as left-sided actually,
because the sun rises from this side,
and the right-sided one should be
the Japanese according to Sahaja Yoga style.
But in the thing, if you see,
this is right and this is left.
Now, what has happened is that
the right-sided people like Spanish and all that,
went down there
and killed so many of these people,
who were all right-sided too.
So the whole thing we should call it as right-sided
now. The Andes as right-sided.
Because right-sided people
will be punished by the right-sided defects
and left will be punished by the left-sided defects.
So, because the right-sided people have gone there
and have killed the right-sided people,
the right-sided people there
have overpowered these people.
That’s why the speed is there,
and the Americans are, you see, like this
all very violent all these things, because of that.
Now all these things put together forms this,
the Andes, you see, is there, standing,
waiting for its chance.
And when the things will be horrible absolutely,
there won’t be any atomic bomb blast or anything.
These, themselves will have earthquakes.
Now, earthquake is the quality of Mother Earth.
And she will assert through these.
And on the right-hand side…
Actually, it is actually not on the right-hand side,
but now it’s the left-hand side
of these Japanese what will happen…
Because they were made into left-hand sided,
because they were given these drugs,
opium, this thing, that thing.
So they became left-sided.
Now, these left-handed people
will be finished with volcanoes
There will be volcanoes. There will be typhoons,
they’ll be finished.
While on this side, the
people who have been following
these all wrong things will be finished with earthquakes.
And all these places like,
you can say, the west coast...
The west coast of America is very dangerous,
because there were so many
atrocities done by Americans.
They cannot get away with it,
so themselves they’ll be finished
because they’ll become lunatics,
mad and apart from that, the Mother Earth
itself will finish them, partly.
Now on the right-hand side,
I think volcanoes will be finished this way,
at the destruction time they’ll be used….
But just now as far as now is concerned
we have to see how many people we can bring out.
If the number of Sahaja yogis
increases in those areas,
then maybe, that Mother will be pacified.
The same that was written in the Bible,
The same is written in the Bible,
when God wants to come and
kill the Sodom and Gomorrah
and Abraham perhaps asked to God,
“but God if there is ten good people,
what will you do?”
and God said “O.K., I will save them,”
and then Abraham say, “but if there
are nine people, good people?”
and God say, “O.K. I will save them.”
so he asked, "And if there's just one good people?"
Then God said: “O.K., I will save that town.”
And now Mother, are we the same?
Now we are thousands.
But in the Bible, it is written only how many?
Hundred and forty-four thousand.
That's all?
We’re about reaching that number,
one hundred and forty-four thousand.
Only!
It's written.
It is written in the Bible.
Shri Mataji, does it mean that the Last Judgement
at the time of destruction will manifest in these forms,
earthquake and volcanoes?
Of course, that will be there.
So many things will happen
and people will be killed and destroyed.
And then they'll be put to the last thing,
they will go to hell.
People will descend to the hell.
You see, what will happen on this Earth only,
people will become mad,
they’ll start eating faeces, Naraka
they will be creating for themselves.
Now only the way, say, they are following Rajneesh.
What are they doing?
It's Naraka.
That’s how they’ll be punished.
And those who are described now, one thousand...
one hundred and forty-four
thousand is a very small number.
Can I ask a question about those people
who get killed, Mother and become bhoots?
Is there never any chance?
Difficult.
Those who are killed might be,
but those who are possessed...
You see, what has happened that those
who are killed are reborn again.
And some, those who are...
have been killing are also reborn.
So there is a chance for such people.
But those who are killed are possessing people
who killed them.
Why did they kill?
They had no business.
“Thou shalt not kill.”
I mean after all, if you do not
follow one rule and regulation
of your hopeless government,
you are punished. What about God?
He said “thou shalt not kill” and you have killed.
So, you should not be punished?
I was thinking of those that got killed,
those who were killed, the victims.
If they are reborn they will not,
but if they are taking a revenge, then how to save?
And they can choose?
They can choose.
If they want, they should take
their birth, get realisation.
But they are trying to become bhoots.
The idea of revenge should not be there.
Now, you see, Indians have only this sense, actually.
How much Britishers have tortured Indians,
you have no idea.
I mean, I cannot tell you how much they have done.
I can only tell you about my own family,
that my father’s all houses,
everything was taken away.
We were living in palaces, we started living in huts.
Cars, everything, all ornaments,
everything of my mother was taken away.
Only we had one big...
mother had a big family gold thing we called Vaijayanti mala,
that’s the only thing that she had hidden,
which she pawned and on that she educated us.
To me, they have beaten,
they have given me electric shocks.
They put me on the ice slabs.
I was a young girl of 18-19 years, you see.
To so many people they have tortured like this.
Oh, they have tortured and tortured
to such an extent, you have no idea.
But... and raping, prostitution,
everything they did to Indians.
But Indians don’t hate English.
They don’t hate them.
They are very kind. If English go there, you see
some English barristers went in to India and
the holiday was given to the High Court.
They are so respectful, but when English now,
when the Indians, because they misbehaved
and they brought so many Indians with them.
Now they were given British passports
and sent as slaves to East Africa to work there.
But when East Africa became independent they had British passports, so they came as Britishers.
Now they are treated as immigrants in England.
Think of it.
Actually, they have only British
passport, they have no other passport.
And 80% of Indians are like that.
10% are students and 10% may be Pakistanis.
Can you imagine?
And see the condition of Indians in England,
the way these English feel about them.
So, naturally, one would feel very
embittered with them. Isn’t it?
But I have never seen any Indian
criticising English people.
My husband once said it is Indians who are responsible,
they behave in such a manner, they wash
their clothes, they hang them outside.
This, that!
He will always blame the Indians;
they don’t know how to eat on a table,
they use their hands, this that. Indians!
Not embittered at all!
They are the only people who have really forgiven.
There is no embitterment and you know, in India
it’s a law, unwritten law.
I was on the censor board, that no
film can be made against the English.
Nothing!
No film is made about our freedom,
independence or about Gandhi.
This is an Englishman who made it.
We were not allowed to do that.
There was a big series, very popular series showing how awful the British had been to the Indians, which was on in England.
They always tried to debase
Indians, to make fun of them.
Everybody’s horrified, because we
don’t know. We just read in the books
What is the name of the series?
The Jewel in the Crown! It’s called “The Jewel in the Crown”.
It is about the last days of the British
Raj. And it is horrible. You can't watch.
I mean, what do they show there.
They show bestiality, they show absolute cruelty,
beating some boy with sticks, accusing
him of raping a girl that he never did.
Who? English?
English, yes.
They did?
It shows the English in a very bad light. Very bad!
Good, it's being at least exposed.
Somebody must have talked about it.
When we watched the film of Gandhi, in
Delhi, when you took us to see that movie,
at the half time, everybody walked out.
About forty of the British Sahaja yogis
were just absolutely like stunned mullets
they couldn’t move.
That is nothing,
They have shown nothing, compared
to what people have seen.
This series is much more brutal than that.
Watching it was so horrible.
I heard about it.
Horrible.
And you see now, as they were saying
there were no arches or bridges.
Now, the British must have
removed everything that was there.
They never respected anything. Even now
they have no respect for our culture,
for our music, for anything.
They haven’t got brains to understand.
In such ego!
Shri Mataji, you were saying this
afternoon that a lot of the culture, and
history and architecture and so on, of India
predates, so much, a lot of the west.
Most! I mean, I told them that
these people say Greeks brought us all these things,
but, they have not seen that in India we have something called Ajanta Caves.
Made in the caves!
Caves mean like palaces, huge and
one stone, huge, for miles like that.
I said, if we have learned from the Greeks,
why don’t the Greeks have something like that.
They don’t have anything.
The kind of art we have in our country, you don’t
find it anywhere in the whole world, I think.
I mean this now... I've said it of
course, (unclear) but it is built from down upwards.
It is a cave, you see, from top downwards, in ten centuries.
Excuse me, Mother, do you want me to translate
for the people that doesn’t understand?
Please, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
All the engineering, everything
had to be calculated from...
She’s explained that, what you explained today
that we started from the roof and then we go down...
Like you were explaining today to this fellow.
You explained today to [unclear] today
that we start from the roof and then we go down,
not from the firmament we go up, it’s just the same.
It’s India style. It’s a very clever.
Yes, Mother, but she would just like
to ask some questions about Masonry,
but you were talking about Ajanta, and perhaps
it’s better You finish…
That I've finished off
You finish Your talk.
No, I am just saying that the Indians, you see,
have got something about them,
that they are very forgiving.
There is no embitterness in them, they’re very forgiving.
They don’t carry any embitterness in their mind.
And secondly, they are very anonymous.
You will never find name written in any painting.( unclear)
You will never find an Indian
writing the name or anything.
This is all modern. Of course, modern
people, they are westernised.
But even now, you go anywhere
and ask them, 'Who has done it?"
Somebody, someone must have done it?
That ego.
Very anonymous people and that is only because
it is a very spiritual country, you see.
The whole tradition is of spirituality.
That’s why people are very spiritual,
they are not so materially equipped,
because they never paid much
attention to material advancement, you know.
Perhaps Mother, I know that Coomaraswamy.
Coomaraswami is the greatest Indian critic.
and now everybody has set him
as a master in Indian art.
I read all of his book and he is an excellent man,
I think. Perhaps he is also realised, I don't know.
What is his name?
Coomaraswamy!
Coomaraswamy, I have not read it.
I think he is a good man.
He said also that they didn’t
write their name on the [unclear]
just because they see himself
just as an instrument of God,
he was just a channel of God.
He was nothing, just a channel and in fact
a man who worked in Ellora just
wrote on the walls of Ellora,
“Oh God, how I made it." And he was just meaning that...
You are... I am the instrument.
“I am just an instrument, God. Because,
I couldn’t do it, You have done it”. And...
It is very beautiful.
And we couldn't understand it in our culture
Mother, we think that we do “I do, I do, I do.”
But they say “God, You do, I am just a channel.”
That’s the reason, but you see,
but we had a very bad invasion
of the tantrikas with the
same kind of thing, you see,
that those people who started practicing meditation.
And perhaps they saw Ganesha at Mooladhara
and they thought this is the Kundalini.
They started taking to sexual things
and all that, and did all wrong things.
Then they found out that they went into the realm
of the subconscious, the collective subconscious.
Then, they got the bhoots in their heads.
They got ideas that, if you can
destroy the purity of a temple,
then you can get all the bhoots there.
So, they tried to destroy all the temples
with their horrible tantric things.
Erotics they put in, to insult the Goddess.
If you insult the Goddess, she goes away from there. Supposing, say before me, somebody is misbehaving, I’ll go away.
Like that, to remove the attention.
And the tantrism started.
But, you know, we had no idea
that tantrism is like that.
We never see these things.
I, myself went to Nepal with my
children, my daughters, my husband
and we saw all the temples.
We never saw anything erotic.
Never saw!
Then when I went to Gregoire, went to write
the book. He said, "Mother it's everywhere."
I said, "Where?"
There were some Japanese with
some zoom lenses, you see,
with these.. .sticks. These....
Tripod.
What you call? These ladders.
They had brought all the
ladders from Japan, you see?
In India, you don’t get this kind of ladder.
Ladders with zoom lenses, standing there.
and somebody falling and somebody (unclear)
I said, "What are they doing?"
He said, "They are taking photographs of these erotics."
I said, "At that point what do these men want to see?"
These Japanese, I tell you, even somebody
was doing work on this... your...
I think.... in Sistine Chapel, some Japanese.
And he enlarged all
the private parts of all the things,
Every body's!
Can you believe these dirty people?
So, this is what it is. You see, we had an attack,
we would not say no.
But, these tantrikas came in,
in the Advent it is given these things..
Yes.
These tantrikas did come
and they did attack us.
But we are innocent, we never
knew these things at all.
And in India, we don’t know
many things, I tell you.
I did not know what was homosexual,
I had no idea and when,
you see, somebody explained to me I
really didn’t eat my food for 8 days.
I couldn’t believe there could be such people.
Many people don’t know there are such people.
In India, I think at least 90% of people don’t know. At least!
Maybe 95.
May I just say Mother?
Mother, just another thing,
You know that in all Italy is impossible
to find books about the Indian art.
It is really impossible, but you can find
a book about all the erotics out of India,
about all the erotics out of China.
Because we did not know anything existed,
we did not know anything existed like this.
We had no idea anything was there.
It is only in the West when we came, 'Oh
this is Kaama, this is..." What is this?
Kamasutra!
Kamasutra. How many Indians have
read this book, even heard about it?
What is that?
I mean it's pornography.
How can you have pornography?
But here people are, I mean, I don’t
know what sort of people they are.
Educated, uneducated,
everybody viewed pornography?
What is the level?
I had never known there were
books written like that Kamasutra.
This must be some tantrika must
have written long time back.
During the Gupta age, Mother.
Is it?
Yes, Mother.
Gupta Age?
A little before the Gupta age, because You
know Gupta-ism, [unclear] capitalism in India.
Gupta, it cannot be, because in the 7th
century, the tantrism took root 6th century,
after the... after the birth of...
Adi Shankara
Adi Shankaracharya it took roots, real roots.
But could be other.
It really took a complete form in a very
big way, Tantrism, after the 6th century.
Just to oust Shankaracharya.
And then the Buddhist, they went into tantric.
And these Masonics are another
tantrics in the Occident.
Masonry is Tantrism.
But still, Indian people are very innocent.
You won’t find such people anywhere.
Even Africans are not like that,
nor Russians are not like that.
They are very innocent, they don’t understand.
Such a big man like that Modi, he's a stupid
fool, he doesn’t understand anything.
He is worse than Me.
Completely innocent.
Absolutley!
and they remain potent until they die,
because they are so innocent.
This is all bathroom culture.
Khajuraho all that is extremely...
and we never even saw all
these things. We were surprised.
Khajuraho is the worst, because the
architect himself was a Tantric.
That is the worst, Khajuraho
No, not Khajuraho, Konark. Konark is the worst.
But Khajuraho, the king was a very bad man.
And his disciples,
no, no, his ministers were Jains.
They wanted to have Jain temples.
So, to please the king they said
alright, we’ll have erotics outside.
But they had to tell all kinds of stories to the artists.
They had competition. Artists
were very clever, you see,
they made very thin erotic pictures,
and Gods & Goddesses are very healthy, fat.
And in one corner, you see,
I did not know where it was.
I went throughout Khajuraho without seeing anything.
So, I told one lady, “I have read there are
erotics, what is that? I would like to see.”
So she came around, "In this corner, that corner."
And one could not see because all the
Europeans and all were so busy there.
And Mother if you open [unclear] and ask book about
India, you just see this picture. All right.
Only Khajuraho
Indian art from the book is only Khajuraho
Can you imagine?
And Konark, Khajuraho and Konark.
And we didn’t even see these things.
You know, we went with our
daughters. Can you imagine?
My husband, they won’t even see a
film together with my daughters.
He’s so shy and we went to Nepal, we never knew.
My son-in-law who has been so many
days in Nepal, he did not know.
Can you imagine?
This is Romel, who seems to
be a very intelligent man.
He didn’t know anything.
But it is very far-fetched you know.
You have to really zoom lenses to see that.
Yes Mother, on the roof.
I mean, can’t understand.
Of course, it entered into our sculpture and all
that in 10th century, but not so visible.
But they went to another limit of things,
these Kings, some of them, were very bad Kings,
but they were after the 7th
century, and they did it.
But we Indians don’t know.
I’ve read lots of Sanskrit, I should
say, my mother was a Sanskrit scholar.
My father was a Sanskrit scholar,
but they never knew there was a book called Kamasutra.
We never knew, I mean, it was like pornography.
I mean, you don't bring pornography
for an educated man, do you?
I mean, do you study pornography?
Is it done here for research? Do you have?
They have art exhibitions of it.
They have big, big art exhibitions
of pornography and erotica.
For what?
Art exhibitions, in the big public galleries.
Really?  Yes.
I mean, you mean you have PhD’s on that, do you?
Probably.
Not in Italy Mother, nor European.
In Spain, I think it is.
One week, erotic  culture.
They have one week, they have that red
rag for the bull and then next week
they have this erotica.
Stupid people.
What can I do with them, tell
me? Now I have to go to Spain.
I have been in Spain....
You have been?
two months and I found also yogis
Then why don’t you go and see the Sahaja Yogis?
I will, Mother.
Poor, this Don. I went with his wife.
She is now in Barcelona, but now we have a centre also in Madrid
and we have Spanish people there.
I met them, Mother
You met them?
I met them, Mother and I convinced them
to come to the Guru Puja and they come.
Very good.
Nice people, very nice, poor things, but, you
see, the majority is nonsensical like that.
They’re so stupid. My husband went to Spain,
they gave him a present of an erotic thing, you see?
I said, "What is this you have got?"
I said, “Who gave you?”
He said, "There’s something special for you.
Very secretly they gave me”
I said “This is erotics.” He said,  “Throw it away.”
These stupid people wanted to insult me.
Same in Greece.
In Greece, they gave him erotic stuff, you see.
To me, they gave me Mary’s face.
He said, “What do they think me
to be?” And he threw it away.
They think it is intellectual.
They show their freedom, perhaps.
Freedom is what? Bathroom? Bathroom freedom.
I think, in all Spain, they say that
now is a reaction of the Catholic church,
with the previous government.
Franco!
He is worst, forced them. Oppressing them, in all sense.
Now is the reaction, they say, to the Catholic church.
But that means you have no personality.
Liberation!
Liberation, the drugs, it’s published, even the
minister said why not to smoke marijuana.
In every bar you have slot machines, in every bar.
Now supposing you have a problem
because of Catholic church,
say they suppressed you.
So, must you become stupid?
No, I mean, you must have some
personality of your own, isn’t it?
And whatever Catholic church preached
there was nothing wrong with it. I
don’t think there was anything wrong,
what they said was correct.
But they did not give you the power to do that.
The Catholic church themselves
did not have the power,
nor did they give you the power to do that.
After Sahaja Yoga, you see it is very easy.
You enjoy it, being virtuous. Isn’t it?
I mean, human beings have
become nothing but sex points.
See? I mean, even the dogs and the
monkeys and the donkeys have it.
What is so special about it?
You see, people talk about sex here.
You see, in India those, who are
... what we call the hijras people;
the people who are third person.
Eunach
Hermaphrodites.
You see, and they talk about having a child,
that’s how human beings talk here.
Sex is so natural what is so great about it?
I just don’t understand, really.
I think these are impotent people who'll...
To them, it is great thing, to talk about sex, perhaps.
What is there to talk and to educate, what is there?
It is so natural.
To be...  first of all, you have all become unnatural
and then behave like unnatural people.
It’s all unnaturalness, that’s why you are like this.
Horrible it is. Absolutely horrifying.
Despite all that, we produce
more children than you do.
We have potent men and women.
We have very good married lives.
And we enjoy everything that we have.
What have you achieved out of your sex?
Nothing. Divorce, rapist, this, that, prostitution.
Without Sahaja Yoga, there is no solution, Shri Mataji
Without Sahaja Yoga, there is no solution, right?
There is no solution.
No solution
They are all going in a mass way to hell, straight.
Direct to hell.
I mean what are they becoming? Just think of it.
It is sensational, this that, nonsense, as if like dead
bodies, you see they need sensations all the time.
Mother, We were so blind, that we
couldn’t see what we had lost.
It is so much. How can we try to
explain to the people what we have lost?
It is too much.
It will happen, gradually they will.
You don’t have to talk about
their past. Forget the past.
You see gradually, because you
develop innocence, you see?
Innocence comes into your eyes.
The relationships are so pure.
So relationships are pure, no complications. Nothing. So beautiful.
And with purity of relationship
only, your married lives will be alright.
Otherwise, every man, his wife
is running with another woman.
Err... with another man and the man
What sort of morality is that?
Complete confusion,
Complete confusion, it is nonsense.
It is nonsense.
I can’t understand this.
I tell you, there’s a gentleman, he became my rakhi brother.
You see once he just tied a rakhi.
So I tied him a rahki,
because he had no sister.
So, he must be about now, 70 years
of age, or something like this.
Once I was going to Bombay, uh, to Delhi.
So my husband said, "Alright, you better go
with him because he is going by train."
So he booked a coupé for both of us. You see!
And we went together. I mean he is my brother.
So my brother from his wife and from
my husband as if he is my brother
And we went by coupé
and when we reached there my husband came
to receive me with some foreigners also.
They were quite surprised. They said,
“Are you divorced Mr Shrivastava?”
He said, "No!"
But she is coming out with another man.
“That’s her brother.” "Oh brother!"
"But doesn’t look like her.”
He said, “That’s her brother, she
has accepted him as a brother.”
But brother cannot travel in
the same coupé, under law.
If there’s a brother and a sister, they
can’t live in one room, under law.
What a filth it is!
Can you imagine? There is no purity
between real brothers and sisters.
Here is just a brother, which..sort of a Rakhi brother.
Imagine, and never goes into our heads.
Nothing, not even my husband’s head,
or his wife’s head or anything.
So, this is something surprising
that people don’t understand
that, as you have to have rules and
regulations for a good civic life,
for good married life also there has to be certain
rules and regulations which are to be respected.
For your good married life, there
has to be some rules and regulations.
Otherwise, how can you have a good married life?
That is not, that is not curbing yourself.
Every freedom has to have certain rules and
regulations so that the freedom is preserved.
For the preservation of the freedom only.
This is abandonment. Licence...
Maryada Purushottama.
Yes.
Maryada Purushottam
This is licence. This is not... this
is in no way freedom. It is licence.
It is abandonment.
Do you see my point?
This is in no way this is freedom.
What is freedom?
The husband is worried about the wife.
Wife is worried about the husband.
Actually, we are free people.
Like my husband goes all over the world
and I know for definite
he is not going to look at any woman.
And he knows for me also,
so we are free people moving everywhere, happily.
This is the true freedom, Mother
It’s the true freedom.
Yes, we are the free people
Supposing now,
he is there, in the house he comes,
if he sleeps in the same bed
my husband won’t doubt it, won't doubt it.
He is like my son.
Of course!
My sons-in-law will come and sleep with me.
You won't believe.
They sleep on the same bed.
“Just hug me, Mummy, Mummy.”
Nobody says anything.
Nobody can even think,
you know, it doesn’t go into our heads.
I can’t understand.
With all this thinking
if people have become mad, like this,
just sex points.
I mean you have reduced yourself to nothing
but sex points.
Think about it? What a degradation!
We were like that before the Realisation.
But now you have become Shri Ganeshas.
You all have become Shri Ganeshas.
You have become such great people now.
But I think, still, I can’t forgive the English
for what they did to You.
English people now has, in South America,
people are [unclear] against English people,
just because of Malvinas. (the Falkland Islands.)
The what?
The war, that they did unto Argentina.
I didn't understand?
Argentina?
Yes, Argentina war with England
The Malvina Islands
That war was... people don't like it
I have seen in all South America,
I usually go by, my job.
Unclear
That was very stupid.
(Tape cuts out and resumes)
Germans were teaching them and
they had those goose steps.
Do you know what is a goose step
is? Left right, left right,
and I asked, "How is it that you know all this?"
They kept quiet.
I said, "This is German."
And there are lots of Germans who have built
up their bases there, horrible Germans.
So in a way, it is I agree
that they should not have,
but Argentina is saved,
because these Germans would
have really finished them off.
On Friday, I have been in Buenos Aires
I came to the Puja.
And I feel now, there is a group waiting for You
or maybe waiting for me to make the decision.
I spoke about You and they are really waiting.
They’ll get it. They’ll get it, because,
you see, their prestige has gone.
Argentina is in the UN, and all that.
They have not lost much prestige.
English has lost prestige more.
But the Germans are finished.
They were horrible people there, Germans.
And Germans were training all their
military, all their navy, everything.
They have built a huge, big barricade,
which I have seen Myself
and I was quite frightened.
So, in a way it's good.
In a way it’s good, in a way also
Argentina has not lost prestige.
So it's alright. Doesn’t matter.
In the war, though, English has won the
war, Argentina has not lost its face, no doubt.
People feel that Argentina was not wrong,
in keeping Falklands.
And still, there is a lot of
reaction against Mrs Thatcher.
The other day they were asking her,
“How did you bombard that ship?"
People detest Mrs Thatcher.
The truth of the real aggressiveness
is coming out now in the war files.
It is all being exposed, as to how they
overdid the boundaries of normal defense.
Changing the course of the ship also,
the ship went and bombarded
and two hundred sixty-five (unclear)
So all this, prestige wise they have not lost.
But these Germans are reduced
I am very happy about them,
because these Germans, if you
allow them to grow like that.
They are still in Chile, Mother, now.
They are still in Chile now.
Chile
They have moved in Chile?
They are now there, with Pinochet
and all these people, doing the same.
But Chile people are also…Chile
government is very, very tough government.
Shri Mataji, they’d like to give you dinner now.
All right?
Thank You very much for talking to us.
I’m going to eat what you have brought for me.