I bow to all the seekers of Truth.
These days there are people who are going
all over the places to find out the Truth,
the enlightenment. And there are so many books
available, so many people who talk about enlightenment.
And this is only in this special age, which
I call as " the blossom time ", is happening.
If they are not seeking the Truth, that means
they are not yet evolved as this should have
been. But this is a special time that we call
as the "Last Judgement" and that time has
come. In the Koran it's called as Kiyama and
described very clearly what will happen at
this time. All these have been indicated in
all the books which are, I would say, mystical
or we can call as religious - whatever you
may call it - the mystic part of it. They've
all indicated this time, this time by the
end of this century, this should happen. And
this has bewildered many people, they are
going hither and thither, getting into problems.
As it's very embarrassing what Dr. Derek Lee
has told Me. Is a fact that I went to Russia
and a scientist came forward and he said that:
" Mother, I have seen your photographs and
it says so much because I haven't seen more
than one line showing. " It is very embarassing,
the whole thing was very embarrassing for
Me. And he said: " I've proved it now, through
all equations and everything. " And he showed
Me the book which is in Russian language and
all mathematical calculations, that one has
to go to a vacuum state, a physical vacuum
state, for Reality to be understood. It was,
I think, too much of science in it.
For whatever it is, all these ideas, say of
Koran, of Bible, of other religious books,
all the religious books from India could be
called as a myth and they were treated as
myths. Many people thought it was just a myth
and they said there's no use believing in
all these things, there is nothing. And also
through these books, people have been misled
to do wrong things, so the whole thing got
challenged also in a way: that it's not practical,
it's not beneficial, is no good.
But when it becomes a real experience - you
may call it subjective, may call it anything
- but when it becomes a real experience, then
you start believing in it as Reality. But
if a scientist proves it with his scientific
knowledge, then I don't know what to say,
then it really becomes the fact. And when
it becomes the fact it becomes the science.
Science can be challenged. First of all, science
is amoral. It is not bothered, as a science
as it exists today, if they create atom-bombs,
they create other things destructive and use
it for wrong purposes, there is no binding
force on the scientist. They can do whatever
they like and people can use it the way they
want to use it. But when it comes to Divine
force, the science is perfect, I must tell
you. You cannot challenge that science, you
cannot - everything that you know through
the science of Sahaja Yoga, you can easily
verify it.
For example, firstly it is said that your
physical elements disappear, it's a fact.
Without any money, without any fees or anything,
just you get cured of your troubles. And when
you get cured of your troubles, then you are
amazed how through your own power you have
been cured. But it happens, it has happened
- you know, we have many doctors here - English
doctors, not easy to convince - and they have
seen with their own experience that many patients
who were supposed to be incurable are cured.
They have seen that many drug addicts got
all right overnight. How? Without paying for
it, without taking any medicine, just through
their own power of Kundalini.
Now this power of Kundalini was known all
over the world, I think, because I find in
their museums Kundalini drawn in the triangular
bone even in Sweden I saw. But I should say,
it's in Finland, I saw. Then also, I went
to Ukraine in their museum, there are all
pictures of these chakras and of the Kundalini.
And in a farfetched place like Bolivia, where
it could not reach there even by air about,
I think, six years back, you find the pictures
of Kundalini. And Colombia, the ancient Colombia
had created statues in which Kundalini was
the main thing. So somebody must have told
them or they might have known about Her. But
somebody went from Italy to Bolivia and the
Bolivian people said " We know all about it,
yes, we know. But we don't know how to raise
the Kundalini. " And now there are I think
eight, nine thousand people in that farfetched
place of Bolivia who have got their Realization.
For which you don't have to pay. Is the main
thing one should understand. It's like you
don't pay for your breathing, you don't pay
for your digestion - in the same way for your
ascent to a new life, last, we can say, the
breakthrough of your evolution, for which
you don't have to pay. As soon as you understand
this point, you'll be amazed that you'll give
up all nonsensical people who are marketing
their things, selling their things. You see,
it's something absurd, the absurdity to such
a limit that you become blind and you don't
know what they are doing, what they're up
to. And don't want to listen to anybody who
wants to tell you the truth.
Now if we have to see for our own ascent - as
they say in Koran, Miraj - in India this thing
is called as Self-realization, Atma Darshan,
or you can call it, Atma Sakshatkar. If you
really want it - it's very easy and has to
be easy, because it is so vital. And when
that works out, you actually experience it
and it can be tallied with the description
of it. The trouble is we are so mental. We
want to derive everything on a mental level.
But thank God, this scientist has found out
something for your mind to go round and round
and round and reach the point. Because I think
sometimes this mind, which is filled with
all kinds of false ideas - sometimes slightly
right ideas or sometimes real ideas - they
go on bombarding in your head. And this scientist
has said that you have to go to the vacuum,
which Jung has described as thoughtless awareness,
to become thoughtless. When you become thoughtless,
then you can see, feel Reality.
So, what happens, how do we get thought? When
we go to some place, we see something - immediately
we react, that's our habit. This can be also
proved scientifically why we always react.
Either we react towards it or we absorb it.
So, all the time our mind is working - and
it is a wobbly mind. You are all the time
bothered with it and the modern times are
the worst, though this is a special time,
as I said, because this is the time when people
think the most and this thinking goes on acting
in such a way that they suffer from all kinds
of diseases. Also sometimes this mind doesn't
tell you that this is wrong, that is wrong.
You go on doing things you know, for example,
Hitler, how he behaved, how he killed so many
people, but he never realized he was doing
something wrong, never. Ultimately, he killed
himself because he was afraid that he'll be
caught, but not that he repented. So, they
go on doing wrong things all the time without
knowing that they are doing wrong things.
Now, to say this is sin, that is sin only
fills people with fear, that's all and guilt.
But actually when you become the Self, in
the light of the Self, you know what is right
and what is wrong, what should be avoided,
what is not beneficial for you. You just know,
because you know about your Self, you get
the Self knowledge that is you can feel your
centres - has been told to you - on your finger
tips, this again is said in the Koran that
" at the time of Kiyama - the Last Judgement
- your hands will speak ". But whole thing
gets perverted sometimes by using it for a
wrong purpose, that's how we have destroyed
sometimes the real knowledge, the subtle knowledge
of our being. It's nothing to stand for hours
together on one leg in Himalayas torturing
your body. You don't have to torture your
body at all. People think that if you have
to perfect yourself, you must torture. This
body is the temple. What is the use of building
temples after temples when you cannot build
your own temple? This body is the temple and
why should you torture this body? You must
look after this body, look after with love,
with respect and then only you will realize
how important is to have a body. All these
funny ideas, you know, of renunciation and
all false kind of approach is not going to
help.
My daughter was coming from India. She said,
there were some fair people travelling with
us in first class. So, they wouldn't allow
the air hostess to come and serve them, because
they cannot allow the air hostess to talk
to them. So I said " Did you talk to them?
" Said "How could I, I'm a woman, who would
talk to me?" Because she's a woman, nobody
would talk. Then, sat on the ground. There's
no ground but they wouldn't sit on the chair
and eat the food. For what? Because they are
renouncing everything, I think they have renounced
their brains, that's what it is.
All kinds of stupid things people do, for
what? To achieve that state of tranquility,
the state of Self realization, of Self knowledge.
But just think of it, which is what has to
happen inside. What's the use of doing something
outside unnecessarily making a mess of yourself
and of others? It is absurd, the way people
try to understand that by troubling your body,
by making a mess of your body, making a mess
of the whole society that you can achieve
something which is so subtle and beautiful.
Now, the scientists call this All Pervading
Power, or which I say, of Divine love, as
cosmic energy, or they may call it by any
name. But it's nothing solid, it is Love,
it is love of God. And this Divine love of
God is an energy that runs the whole universe,
universes of universes. Just see the miracle
of life. All that is managed by this energy
of Divine love! Well, we have never felt it
before, so we don't know what it is, but in
every scripture it's written there - that
there is the power of Divine love. For example,
in Sanskrit, this is called Parama Chaitanya
or Brahma Chaitanya. In every scripture it
is being described, but for people it's some
sort of a... unknown thing.
But now, with science, if it can be proved
that the whole universe is managed by this
energy which thinks, which understands, which
loves. For example, the same scientist came
to see Me, to have an interview with Me. He
was smiling all the time and he asked Me very
interesting questions. One of them he asked
about the picture he had seen. Where? Here
in this hall. They were singing the song " Sitting
in the heart of the Universe " and all over
Me came: heart, heart, heart, heart, just
like a doctor would draw the line of the heart
- so many hearts drawn with the rays of light.
And he asked " What is this, Mother? How do
they know that they are singing this song?
" I said " Because I know, so they also know.
" Precisely how do they do things? Because
they know, they know more than anyone can
know. Not only that but the way our genes
and all those things are there is a very subtle
thing, no doubt, but is all managed by this
power of Divine love. Please understand: there
is nothing to fear, nothing to get upset,
nothing to starve, nothing to climb Himalayas,
nothing needed. This power loves you and it
is around you, here it is. It is everywhere
and it pulsates, it vibrates, it creates everything.
Also the scientist told Me about Einstein,
who said that " All these ideas come to me
not from within but from without as if somebody
is pouring these ideas into me. " And he said
" I felt the same way and so many scientists
feel that. " Surprisingly, in Russia the scientists
are very open hearted. And at the time of
Stalin, they were all arrested and put in
a place called Novosibirsk (?), where they
were living, and there they developed, you
see, this subtler side - because they were
not allowed very much to do other things.
So they developed the subtler side of human
beings, and there they found out also about
auras - he is one of them - auras: that human
beings have auras and from the auras, you
can diagnose their diseases. But now, after
seeing My photographs and all that he has
reached the proper conclusion surprisingly.
And I think, I hope I'll be saved from all
kinds of people who criticize Sahaja Yoga
as a cult or this and that. It is not. It's
a living process whether you are a hindu,
muslim, christian, anything, is meant for
you and it is your right, your birth right
to have it. And then after that, once you
get the sprouting of the seed, you must allow
this tree to grow. Actually, those people
who talk of social work, talk of helping others,
doing this for them and doing that for them
have to understand: first you should be empowered,
you must have the power within yourself to
help others. But if you just come to My program,
they always say " Mother, for Your program
the whole hall is full. " and then they start
disappearing - specially in England, very
surprising. England is the heart of the universe,
and how could they be so careless about their
ascent and so careless about developing their
own huge big tree of love. They are the best
suited and they have to work it out. But they
don't, they don't take it seriously. Why,
I don't understand. Maybe they don't know
what they are. They are very powerful people,
they are, I should say, the instrument of
the Divine. Only thing, they have to develop.
But they stick on to this or stick on to that
- then you can't grow. This is a seed already
placed within you - undisturbed, unspoiled.
Only thing is a little water of love has to
be poured on it, then the seed sprouts, and
when the seed sprouts, it rises, the plumule
sprouts out into and it rises, goes up and
comes out of your fontanel bone area, which
is called as Brahmarandra in Sanskrit language,
meaning the hole to feel the Brahma, the All-pervading
power.
I've seen people who know also Sanskrit very
well. They are running here organizations,
but they don't know anything about Kundalini,
it's very surprising. What do they read, I
don't know. And if you go to them, they'll
argue so much with you that you feel like
running away from them. Only they know how
to argue. No argument needed actually, it
is there, within you, this power is. Do you
argue with your stomach how to digest the
food? And even if you do, will the stomach
understand? It's as stupid as that, to argue
about something which is so spontaneous, which
is a living process - it's a living process
of your evolution. Now, by the way, how did
we become human beings? Do we know? And how
do we become a super human being? If there
is a way, there's a method, you don't have
to spend anything. But you have to grow. If
you don't grow, it's useless, as Christ has
described, just as some seeds fell onto the
land which was not fertile. Is it so? Are
we living in a land which is not fertile for
spirituality or we are running after some
things which are illusive? Why should we run
after illusive things? Here, you get the experience,
all right, after that you must grow. If you
grow, you can change this world - it's a global
movement. Like in Russia, I would say, there
are millions, millions in Russia. While in
India, too, we have may be millions. And also
Austria - so many countries have got it - Italy,
imagine. Their people have awakened, so why
not in England? And the leaders of England
are rather upset with the English. They think
this... " It doesn't work out, Mother. " I
can't understand. Because this is the seventh
time I'm here, and seventh heavens you have
to know, that you can know without any difficulties,
without paying anything, the whole knowledge
is free! Is it because it is free you don't
care? They've asked Me to talk about it. Otherwise
it's not worth talking about these things.
Your country as such is like really the heart
and it circulates all over the world. All
your newspapers - they may be useless - but
they circulate. All your media - whatever
they may publish - it circulates all over
the world. You don't know about Americans,
though it's supposed to be a very great country.
We don't know about any other country so much
as we know about England. How? Why? Monarchy
in so many places, but we know everything
about monarchy from England. Why? How? How
do we manage? Is worth asking this question:
there's something special about this country.
I lived here for years, I've worked hard,
I went from North to South, East to West.
Perhaps, I left no city which I did not visit.
But the situation is such that when they get
Realization, they are very happy, they start
jumping, and after that they forget about
it. It's a great responsibility on people
of UK that they can do so much in spirituality.
Not...it's not something also so cheap that
it can be sold, it's invaluable. It's invaluable.
It's your right to get it. And also it's your
sensibility that you should grow into it.
For example, in England, when I first came,
I had to deal with the drug addicts, they
were the first who came. Perhaps, they were
seeking in drugs the Truth. When they came,
overnight they gave up their drugs - overnight
- even alcohol - people gave up overnight,
overnight. Believe Me, they are here now,
I know they are sitting here.
Now, this is the minimum, and so many people
got cured. I really wanted that something
should be written about the miracles of Sahaja
Yoga. So I told one gentleman, Englishman
he is, he wrote to Me " Mother, it's not even
one month, from both the sides, all the letters
have gone up over my head. I don't know how
to select. So, can you give me some time?
Myself, I have no time at all. You can select
yourself. " With all this, why don't you experiment
and why don't you grow? You are very important,
this is what you don't understand: that you
have been born in this country or you have
come to this country - whatever it is - it
is a very important, significant place and
a life of yours. But you should understand
that it's very important and that you should
grow. But it is beyond Me to understand that
in a place like Austria, in a place like Italy,
how is it, they have understood it and they're
automatically working it out? I, you know,
I have crossed My 75 years of age and I don't
know how long I will have to live to face
the English people and how will they understand!
Sometimes, it's beyond Me.
But now you will know that it is a science
and the scientists have said that they have
seen the cosmic energy emitted out of My head.
That's a fact that Sahaja Yogis know. Sahaja
Yogis know, they have felt it, they have got
this experience. For them, it's nothing new
- not through science - but they have known
it as an experience.
Now for you... You are also very well-educated
people, everywhere, you are respected very
much, it is for you now to evaluate your own
personality and understand: Why are you on
this earth? What is the purpose? So many of
you got Realization last time, but you are
nowhere, you've done nothing... I mean, you've
got your Realization, all right. Each person
can give Realization to thousands of people
if he gets out of his own, I should say, own
ideas. And this can do such a lot of good
to the whole world. Formerly, in America it
was terrible, because all kinds of funny people
went there, to make money. So, they told Me
" If you don't ask for money, Mother, in America
nobody will come. They have to pay for it,
otherwise they don't value it. " I said " But,
sorry, you cannot, how much, you tell Me how
much should I charge. How much do you charge
for your mother's love? Then you tell Me how
much you charge and then we can work it out.
" And it was surprising that it hit their
heads. Now it's better. Same thing, I have
to request that, please, find out, when you
have this experience of Kundalini awakening
that you are a chosen person for a special
work.
For example now, this instrument, if it is
not connected to the mains, what is the identification,
what is the purpose? That's why then people
become hippies, they become this, then punks
- because they have no identification. But
the identification is only one: that you are
the Spirit, that's the Truth. And it has to
happen to you, that you are the Spirit, you
have the power of the Spirit. In the light
of the Spirit you start seeing, start seeing
and understanding so well about all the problems
that are in the whole world and your own problems
also. It's not only Self knowledge but also
global knowledge of a very subtle nature.
And that is all is within you, all this horizon
is there waiting for you to greet it. But
I don't know why people have no confidence
or no understanding. Anything can be done,
but first of all you must have the pure desire
to become that. Forget about everything else.
For example, this power of, which resides
in the triangular bone. This bone is called
as Sacrum, means the Greeks also knew that
this is a sacred bone. This power is of pure
desire. And if you have the pure desire you
can become so dynamically aware of yourself
and aware of everything. I was surprised that
in a far-fetched place like Russia we have
to always take a stadium, you can't do it
in this hall, you cannot manage, I think.
How is it, in that country it is working?
Because of communism, perhaps. They were so
oppressed, that all the search started going
inside. But just in such a short time, I was
surprised, these people, how did they get
it and how did they develop and they are still
developing, all of them are developing. And
only I am the person allowed in Russia now
to go and preach - this is also another thing.
This ignorance that we have, the problems
we have - physical problems, mental problems
- it will all be controlled.
Now there's a new disease, as you know, Alzheimer.
How it comes? If a person is extremely aggressive
and torturing people, doing this. When he
gets old, his brain deviates and only that
bad stuff start working and that person who
is suffering is not aware of it. And you cannot
cure it, also. But in the lifetime, if you
get your Realization and you become absolutely
peaceful within yourself, such diseases cannot
touch you, they cannot disturb you and you
become a loving beautiful person. You don't
bother about what he earns, what the other
person has got a personality, this, that,
nothing. It's just a subtle love you feel
for everyone. For everyone, whatever religion
he may belong, whatever country he may belong,
whatever problems he may have. Can you believe
in a place, in a country like Turkey Sahaja
Yoga sparked like this. There are two thousand
Turkish people who are meditating and their
Prime Minister's wife came to see Me, just
to get her Realisation. Now, what is so great
about? They say Ataturk was their leader and
it is the one who has led the path. Why?
You had such great people: William Blake and
so many... Shakespeare, this, that - they
were all realized souls. Their poetry is not
just to read, but to read between the lines
what they are saying.
It is very important now, I request you, at
the end of this century, that once you get
your Realization here, please, grow, become
more collective. Certain funny-funny ideas
I heard and I was surprised - that the hall
is not all right, and that... - there's nothing
to do. It's something that happens inside
you, something that works inside and gives
you that beautiful feeling of being the Self.
As a result, your health improves, you become
mentally a very satisfied and a very balanced
person, all your stress, this and that disappears.
Thirdly, you look much younger than what you
are, because inside you are younger.
Fourthly, you understand others, you love
others, love to do things for others and all
these stupid problems of fighting with these,
taking revenge on the person, killing somebody
- this all disappears. That with the name
of God all these stupid ideas, which has created
the global problem, will disappear. The time
has come and it is the Last Judgement. I think,
the levels are changing: those who are chosen,
I should say, this path of Divine love are
going higher and others, who are negative,
are going downward, they are getting exposed,
everywhere, they are getting exposed. They'll
be exposed. That is for you to decide which
way you want to move, what you want to have.
I think, this is the first time I am saying
this to you, I've never said this way. I told
you what you are - you are so great, this,
that and this, that - but despite that, if
you don't realize your value is wasted. So
when you become the Spirit, then everything
changes for you. I am surprised how people
start understanding the follies of their brothers
and sisters, who are forming a big society,
things like that.
For example, they give up drinking. When they
give up drinking in France, Sahaja Yogis were
thought to be mad - because how can you do
without drinking? And now the French are taking
to Sahaja Yoga very much. Imagine, French
are much more than they are here. And they
are saving money because they are not wasting
on anything: no drugs, no smoking, no drinking.
But we don't say " Don't do it! ", because
otherwise half of you will go away, but it
just happens to you. For example, if there
is light, you can see everything clearly:
whatever is destructive, you just don't do
it. But whatever is constructive we accept
and work it out. Such love and such affection.
For example, these people who were singing,
they're from all over the world, they are
not only British. Especially the British,
very difficult to learn Indian language, it's
impossible. And look at them how they are
singing. And not only that, but singing Indian
classical music, which is a very difficult
thing. I didn't teach them. It's very surprising,
how things work out. So many artists I know,
who have earned the world fame with Sahaja
Yoga. But we have an Academy and so many foreign
boys went there and studied Indian music.
I was amazed: in three months they were singing
Malkaus raga with all elaborations. Impossible!
How can they do all that? Also there's one
boy I know - he was hardly fourteen years
of age when he came to Me - and within one
year's time he is a great violonist, he plays
Mozart without seeing any papers, anything.
How can do it? He was not like that. And he
writes such beautiful poetry. You can't believe
it! I asked him " When did you start? " - " After
seeing You, Mother, I don't know why I'm writing.
" I have seen people, who are scientists have
become poets. Can't understand, how your sleeping
- or I would say - dormant qualities just
come out. You don't run after success, you
don't run after competition, but automatically
it happens. For that you don't have to worry
" I am old, how can it happen? " - nothing.
At any age it can happen to you. At any time
it can happen to you. So don't doubt about
yourself also. Then you become a very loving
sweet person, very sensible and dignified.
You don't insult others, don't trouble others,
but you help, you share the difficulties of
others. Suddenly you find, you've become a
part and parcel of a great collective which
is working in the whole world. It is very
surprising, how you have brothers and sisters
all over the world and wherever you go, they'll
give their life for you. Have you seen such
a family anywhere? Beautiful people!
So, I have to make a request to you. Today,
of course, I'll try to give you Self-Realisation,
if possible, it works out. But you must respect,
you must respect and you must grow. All the
saints have talked about it in India.
Now, we have here lots of people from, say,
Punjab, the Sikhs are there. And all these
books have been described for Sahaj. He himself,
Guru Nanaka said " Sahaja samadhi laago ". He
has used this word, all of them have used
this word. But Indians who are here, I don't
know, they are... they say " We cannot digest
Sahaja Yoga. " They can only digest pounds,
I think. Very surprising. It's very surprising
how this materialism has come over. But does
it give happiness to anyone? Does it give
joy, does it give friendship? Full of jealousy,
competition - all nonsense is going on. You
overcome all that just like this, you enjoy,
everything. If somebody has a good furniture,
all right, this is a very nice carpet, all
right, so what you do, you look at it, you
enjoy. You enjoy whatever is created beautiful.
You don't think about it, you don't react.
The reaction is that there's joy. What a beauty
it is! You don't think who has made it, how
much it will cost, nothing. You become thoughtless.
And thoughtless awareness is nothing but such
a pouring sense of joy. Joy which is neither
happiness or unhappiness, but singular. You
cannot describe it in words but you can really
feel it inside yourself, that joy of being
the Self. And that's the time has come for
you to get it. You are also here for that
and this is the special time when it is going
to work out. Now you feel also a collective
consciousness, that you can feel on your fingertips
the chakras, the centres of other people and
who is the other? On your centres you can
feel your problems, in the same way you can
see the problems of others. If you can cure
your own centres, you can easily cure the
centres of others. Without any money, without
any fuss, without anything. It's very, very
simple, it is all built-in within you. All
this is built-in within you and this built-in
power starts working. You don't have to do
anything. It's all there, for example you
see so many lights are here: you switch on
and you get all the lights. But you know how
to switch on: it's all built-in. Again I say,
you don't have to stand on your heads, you
don't have to break your necks, nothing. As
you are you are wonderful. And this is your
own individual mother: She is your own, She
has no other child, and She knows everything
about you. As you have in the tape, you see:
She knows your past, She knows your aspirations,
She knows you very well and She is the one
who is going to give your second birth. She
is your mother. She loves you. Now there are
books saying that if you have the Kundalini,
She disturbs you, it is the modern ones. Well,
they say that "burns you". She is your mother.
Have you heard, I mean maybe in these modern
times everything is possible, but can a mother
burn her own child? She has been waiting for
ages to give you this Realization. For ages
She is within you and now you don't give Her
a chance to give you a second birth? How can
that be?
You will understand that all these great incarnations
who came on this earth have helped to build
up this. They are all there within you, on
these centres, which you'll find out. And
all these fights going on stupidly in the
name of God or anything is nonsense because
they are all one. We are only fighting. So
all your global problems, all your fighting
problems, all your family problems and the
word "problems" disappears. It happens. It
must happen, because you are specially blessed,
and you are the Spirit. This collectiveness
gives you the feeling of oneness with others.
Not out of jealousy, not out of greed, not
out of any carnal love or anything, but it
is just pure love, pure love which you have
not experienced. All the perversions drop
out... But you don't become sort of an abnormal
person on the street, you see, walking with
your closed eyes, no. You become an enlightened
person, absolutely normal. You dress up normally
outside, you can live with your life. But
then you understand what is your dignity,
your decency and everything. There's no show
outside of your achievement but you know within
yourself. You also know who is a Realised
soul and then you meet. There's such a connection.
Has been always, but now it becomes obvious,
evident and you can work it out. The most
important thing is that your brain opens out
like this, like a lotus. It opens out. All
the problems of brain drop out. How many diseases
there are of brain, I wanted to know, so there's
such a big book. I said, "My Goodness, more
than the petals we have in the brain". And
it can happen to anybody in the modern times.
It's very common, it's awaiting at your door,
sort. All this can be solved, absolutely you
can be saved, you can be protected. And every
time you will be feeling this: you are protected,
there is somebody to protect you, to encourage
you, to look after. Who is that? That is this
Param Chaitanya. That is this, they call it
Ruh, they call it the All-pervading Power
of Divine Love, they also call it the Cool
Breeze of the Holy Ghost, as you feel a cool
breeze on your fingertips. It's all written
there in all the books, but symbolically,
so people don't understand.
Once it happens, then you are in another world.
Such miracles, such help and such protection!
It's a thing where you feel, you can never
be drowned in the ocean of this mad world,
because now you are in the Ocean of joy. You
are enjoying and this is what you have to
have. But you must grow, all of you must grow.
I am staying on for one day more just to come
to follow-up meeting. Also if you have any
complaints you better bring them. But there
is nothing to complain actually, you should
complain against yourself. Either you are
lazy, or you are too enthusiastic or you are
infatuated by some sort of a nonsensical guru
or something is there. Just don't try to criticize
others but see for yourself, introspect: why
is it, why can't I do it? All this can work
out, I assure you. I assure you very much
that you should realize that My coming to
England, living here for years together. I
didn't come for Sahaja Yoga. I came because
My husband got a job here. And then, seeing
people in England, I thought, they can really
achieve a lot.
May God bless you all!
Derek is asking Me, "Better give them Realization."
I know, they are ready to get it, but they
have to grow, that's the point, I'm telling
you. He feels quite helpless and he doesn't
know what is the matter with them. I told
him " You grow some beard, moustaches. " Maybe
a better idea. Might be they're used to things
like that. It's nothing external. It is the
internal beauty that we have to know.
Now, it's very simple. If it doesn't shock
you, I'll tell you there are two, three conditions.
The first one is you have to take out your
shoes, if it doesn't shock. Because this Mother
Earth helps us a lot - She absorbs all our
problems.
All right. Now, the second condition is - which
is also not very absurd - that please don't
feel guilty about anything. It's a fashion:
"I'm very guilty." - "Why are you guilty?"
- "No, I've to confess - I am very guilty."
- "About what?" - "You know, the other day
I was eating the food and I was holding knife
on the right hand." - finished. These norms
are human beings have created this kind of
stupid things for which you should feel guilty.
And that this center here, on the left hand
side, you get spondylitis, also angina, it's
a fact - so, not to feel guilty! What are
you guilty about? If you were guilty, you
would have been in jail, not here. So, please,
first of all, forgive yourself completely.
You are not guilty, I assure you. There's
a new evolution with people's mind that they
should feel guilty - finished. If you are
guilty, when it happens, you should have done
something about it, forget it. Why are you
carrying that load on your left Vishuddhi,
here? This is the second one.
And the third one is - I think, is also very
simple - is to forgive yourself, as I said,
and forgive others. Now, you say " Mother,
we can't, just we can't, it's very difficult.
" But try to understand the logic: whether
you forgive or don't forgive, what do you
do? Nothing, just the same. But say, if you
don't forgive, then what happens: you play
into wrong hands, you torture yourself. So,
just say in your heart " Mother, I forgive
myself fully, I forgive others fully " - whether
they are in your mind or not, just say that
and your this center will open now in no time.
This will all help Me a lot. These tree things
are very important and I know you can get
your Realization in no time.
So to put your hands like this towards Me,
like this, just simple, as if you are asking
for your Self realization, like this. Need
not be higher, just whatever is comfortable.
People can't believe that sitting in the hall,
how can we get Realization? But you deserve
it. You get it because that's the time, and
because you are seekers.
Don't doubt yourself, please. Have your hands
like that. Now, you can close your eyes, if
you want to. If you don't want to close, don't
close your eyes. Because there is no mesmerism
going on: at least, I close My eyes.
Now, put the right hand towards Me, and put
the left hand on top of your fontanel bone
area. Now, you'll feel some cool or hot breeze,
coming out of your fontanel bone area, which
was a soft bone in your childhood. Don't put
your hand on top of it, you have to put it
away from you, and you can move the hand to
see yourself. Don't say that you've got it
unless and until you've got it. You are not
to cheat ourselves, all right. Now, please,
put your left hand towards Me and put the
right hand on top of your head. You can bend
your head, that's better if you bend your
head, and with the right hand you see.
Once more, please, put your right hand towards
Me, and again with the left hand you see for
yourself, if there's a cool or a hot breeze
is coming. Now, don't doubt it: if it is coming,
it is there. Could be hot, it will cool down.
Can move up on the sides and see for yourself.
Now, open your eyes and put your both the
hands towards Me like this. Now, watch Me
without thinking, without thinking, just try,
you can do it.
Ah?
Now, raise your both the hands towards the
sky like this, push back your head. And ask
anyone of these three questions three times,
anyone of them:
First one " Mother, is this the Cool Breeze
of the Holy Ghost? " - first question is " Is
this the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost? " Second
question is " Mother, is this the All-pervading
Power of Divine love? " Third question is
" Mother, is this the Ruh, or the Param Chaitanya?
" Ask anyone of these questions three times
in your heart.
Now, again put down your hands, that's all.
Now, put your hands like this towards Me,
just like this.
All those who have felt cool or hot breeze
on their palms or on their fingertips or out
of their fontanel bone area, please raise
your both the hands.
Just look at that! You're proving what I've
said. Just look at that! Now, you've got it,
now this is a responsibility to grow.
May God bless you! May God bless you!
Such a joy, such a happiness! I wish you best
of luck and also wish you a very, very deep
understanding of your being.