Her Holiness Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi
Public Program, Cincinnati, USA
June 14th, 1989
At the very outset we have to understand that
truth is what it is. We cannot organize it,
we cannot order it, nor can we conceptualize
it. It has to be felt on your central nervous
system and this is what it is called, what
we call as Self Realization, or we can say
the second birth as told by Christ. It’s
not an artificial way of accepting any baptism.
That we say that we are baptized but whether
you are baptized or not baptized, you are
just the same. There’s nothing special has
happened to you, nothing has happened to your
awareness, nothing has happened to your personality.
So when we say that we have to have our Self
Realization means, whatever is our human awareness,
has to achieve a new break-through. In the
process of our evolutionary process – which
is, as you know, is a living process – we
have achieved a state, what we call as human
beings. And human beings have freedom to choose
whatever they like - till they realize with
their own trial-and-error-methods that this
is wrong, this is wrong. It takes too much
time for them really to reach a point to understand
what is really good and what is bad for their
society, for their country and also for themselves.
Today when we are standing on the brink of
a delusion and a shock we don’t know what’s
going to happen to us in future. One has to
realize the One who has created this beautiful
universe is not going to allow this work of
His to be destroyed. Only thing He has given
you chance - full chance to realize your freedom,
to develop your wisdom and to see how far
you really understand what is right and what
is wrong. In the human awareness whatever
we know about is in a relative terminology.
We are not absolutely sure, there’s no absolute
knowledge with us – because we are not in
the state of absoluteness. Also the development
- the material, the physical, the scientific,
all development that has taken place has evolved
us outside, just like a tree has grown. But
we have lost our roots and whatever just now
you have heard about is the knowledge of our
roots. And if we do not know our roots we
are waiting really for a complete destructive
shock. It’s an evolutionary process which
has come to this point and the break-through
is a very small journey, say at the most of
three to four feet that you have to allow
your Kundalini to rise and break through.
About which thousands of years back people
have talked. In every country there has been
lots of prophecies that such a time will come
when men of God will know the truth. And this
is what it is. Today we have so many seekers,
so many seekers of truth who are genuine,
honest, trying to find out what is the truth
of life. Why are we here? What are we to do?
You are here to enter into the kingdom of
God, to enjoy the blessings of God – not
to torture yourself, not to trouble yourself,
but to abide in that beautiful land of God’s
joyous, blissful state. For that you cannot
pay. Please remember that God doesn’t understand
money – and you can’t pay for it. Anybody
who takes money in the name of God is a false
personality, he’s a false person because
you cannot pay for it. But when this happening
takes place, when your Kundalini, which is
the pure desire within you - the pure desire
- because all other desires, as described
in the economics, that they are not satiable
in general. This desire is the one - this
energy when it rises then you become the giver
of desires, all desires subside and just you
enjoy each and everything of this creation.
This is all within us, is all your own. Just
like one candle can enlighten another candle
- it works. It’s very spontaneous because
it’s a living process – as you can understand
one seed if it has to sprout you have to just
put it in the Mother Earth, and the Mother
Earth has got the power to sprout it. And
when it sprouts it comes up by itself – in
the same way this Kundalini comes up by itself
and you can feel the Cool Breeze of the Holy
Ghost around you. Now this Cool Breeze of
the Holy Ghost has been described in the Bible,
has been described in all Indian Scriptures
as the all-pervading Power of God’s Love.
It’s described in all the western and eastern,
northern and southern scriptures, all the
treaties of all the saints.
So actually what happens to you that you become
a saint – but you don’t give up anything.
You exist wherever you belong. You don’t
give up anything – what is there to be given
up? Only thing you become a witness of the
whole play and you enjoy all that is created.
All that you see – it seems to be a very
dangerous thing sometimes and sometimes very
frustrating and sometimes very depressing,
everything becomes like a play. Like a thought
that rises and falls off, another thought
rises and falls off and we are jumping on
the cusp of the thought. You are thinking
about the future and the past, but we have
to be in the present. When the Kundalini rises
than you stand in the present and you see
the past and the future. And when you see
the past and the future you are surprised
that you are silent. There is no thought.
Now when you are out of the water it’s much
easy to solve the problem. You can see the
water and you are not afraid of it – you
are in the boat, you can enjoy the ride. But
supposing you become a master who can swim
then you can save others also. The time has
come for humanity, for all of us to get this
blessing. This is all built-in within you,
I don’t have to do anything. It’s like
one candle which is enlightened can enlighten
another candle. It’s enlightenment which
is just spontaneous, happens spontaneously.
So I do not deserve any credit for you and
you don’t have to be obliged about it. It’s
just your own, it’s your own property by
which you achieve. Now the knowledge about
the Kundalini, all the knowledge about all
these things are to be taken in a very open-minded
way like a scientific attitude.
Now I put before you, or he has put before
you this hypothesis and you should see for
yourself - it works or not. If it does not
work, all right – we should work harder
to see that it works out. But when it works,
honestly you must believe in it and you must
go with it, and you must take upon yourself
that now you are a light and you have to give
light to others. This is a very, very important
thing. As a result of this happening, of course,
diseases get cured, many incurable diseases
have been cured by Sahaja Yoga. There are
mental cases which are being cured, people
feel absolutely peaceful, the so-called tension-business
disappears. Because I think a little hole
is created and the whole heat comes out of
your heads as the tension passes out and you
feel absolutely relaxed. You look very young,
you feel very young and the whole attitude
of life changes as if you are asking for something
always, now you are standing here to give
something. All these things are at hand, you
don’t have to do anything difficult. And
why not, why not we all get our Realization?
I am sorry to say that I am here only for
tonight. On My way I - just as if I have stopped
here, I wish I was here for a longer period
to be with you all. But we have here some
very good Sahaja Yogis who are very senior
people, who have mastered this and they’ll
be very good to you. And they are very compassionate,
they are very righteous people and they lead
a very beautiful life. So you’ll be happy
to meet them and they will help you and then,
as one light enlightens another, you can go
on enlightening another people. It’s a very
simple method, there’s nothing much is to
be done and children are the best for it.
Now I have to just say that supposing in this
place if I have to come and put on the light
we just have to switch on. That’s all. I
need not tell you about the whole electricity,
about the history of electricity, how it was
brought and the source of electricity. In
the same way you are built-in, it’s within
you. Through your different stages of evolution
everything is built-in within you. So you
don’t have to do much about it, but once
you get the light then it’s better to know
more about it. For example if somebody is
holding a snake in the hand, he is in the
darkness, he can’t see anything, and if
you tell him, “You know it’s a snake”,
he’ll say, “No, it’s a rope.” He’ll
argue with you. It’s better is to put on
the light and let him see for himself so he
drops it. In the same way as he has told you
all your conditionings and habits drop out,
because there is light. But it’s not mental,
it’s just a happening, the center which
is here as Agnya chakra is shown there which
crosses, this center when awakened, this is
the center of Christ. When this center is
awakened it sucks in all our conditioning
and our ego, that’s why we say that He died
for our sins. But He is to be awakened, if
He is awakened then He sucks in and then you
get your Realization. This is a very simple
method built within us for our second birth
which is a reality, which is not something
just talking or words. I hope most of you
get your Realization in this beautiful atmosphere.
May God bless you all!
Now, I would like to have some questions from
you, but it’s so far away, you are so far
away from Me, I don’t know how will I be
able to relate, but if you have some good
questions – not to challenge or not to sort
of criticize, but ask questions which are
related to the subject, which will help you.
Because I am not here for seeking votes or
for any money or anything. You can’t give
Me anything, it’s better you take something
from Me, will be a better idea. So if you
want to ask some questions, please ask.
A lot can be said about Sahaja Yoga – I
must have given at least 4,000 lectures or
5,000 lectures in English language.
Aside: Yes, all right.
But that’s different, I said first have
your enlightenment and then we can talk about
it.
Yes please.
YOGI: Why this time in history can they have
a gift like this?
SHRI MATAJI: It’s a blossomtime, Sir. (Shri
Mataji laughing) You see, in the beginning
of the Tree of Life we had very few flowers,
but now it’s a blossomtime. We have so many
people who are seeking the truth. It was all
prophesized long time back, that the modern
times - as they call it, the Kali Yuga - you’ll
find people who will be leading a normal life,
normal householders will be seeking the truth
and they’ll find it.
SEEKER: [ What will be the result of this
special time? INDIST…]
YOGI: He wants to know, what will be the results
of this special time, this blossoms, what
will it mean, what will it do in their lives?
SHRI MATAJI: Now I would say, I mean so many
things it can do. But you see around, we have
people who are Christians, Hindus, Muslims,
Sikhs – all kinds of people we have. We
have Americans, Indians, all types - human
beings. And everybody is capable of committing
any horrible thing, any violent thing, any
sinful thing. There is no binding force. So
when we talk of peace they have no peace within
themselves. You just talk of peace, there
are foundations of peace and organizations
of peace - at the slightest pretext you find
they themselves become violent. So what you
need is the transformation of a human being
who expresses the Spirit. The Spirit which
is knowledge, knowledge which is not relative,
which is not mental, but which is absolute,
compassion and love that expresses joy. And
attention that can work out things. All this
is within the reach of human beings in these
modern times, the blossomtime.
We have to transform human beings. All the
problems of this world are created by human
beings and not by God – so that transformation
creates a beautiful race of people who are
collective. They act as collective beings
because your Spirit is the collective being
within you. So it’s like you become part
and parcel of the whole. If this finger is
suffering immediately My another hand helps
it. It doesn’t think I have to oblige or
anything because it’s a part and parcel
of the whole. In the same way we become genuinely
collective. As a result the complete emancipation
of humanity can be achieved.
The best part of the whole thing is that today
it is acting en masse. The righteousness,
the compassion, the love, the wisdom of saints
is now manifesting en masse. Other things
happen also, I would say I have known people
who never knew what is art have become artists
- artists who create things which emit divine
vibrations. Then there are people who never
could sing have started singing; those who
could not do good in their work have become
dynamic – but despite all that they are
compassionate and honest.
I’m sorry this is the first time I’ve
come to Cincinnati, that’s why it sounds
little fantastic – but we are fantastic,
we are fantastic. In a village of India, if
supposing you take a television and say that,
“You can see all kinds of beautiful images”,
nobody is going to believe you. They’ll
say, “Ah, he’s telling stories, this is
just a box of plastic.” But when you put
to the mains it starts working. In the same
way you start working like a computer. You
are a divine computer – only thing you have
to be aware of it. And if it is going to be
that way - why not?
FEMALE SEEKER: Could you please elaborate
on how when the Kundalini is awakened, how
that’ll erase the negative karma?
SHRI MATAJI: What’s it?
YOGI: She wants to know, she is asking You
to elaborate on how when the Kundalini is
awakened it removes negative karma.
SHRI MATAJI: It does. You see we judge ourselves
in a very funny way, all the time we are judging
ourselves and feeling guilty and for small,
small things we think, “Oh! We should not
have done this way.” Even if you spill a
little coffee you think you have done a disastrous
thing. After all we are human beings – if
you make mistakes it’s all right. After
all we are not God, are we? All the time we
try condemning ourselves, we done this bad,
that one, we are negative. Also the suggestion
comes from so many ways, people say you are
sinner, you have done this sin, that sin – just
imagine. It’s not so, we are all human beings.
So let your Kundalini which is your own individual
Mother decide what karmas you have done. And
She’ll see to it that you get rid of them.
Don’t condemn yourself. Don’t feel guilty.
That’s the first condition, if you feel
guilty I do not promise you Kundalini awakening,
to begin with. Not to feel guilty at all.
That’s first condition. Second is, we have
to forgive everyone. After all, whether we
forgive or if you don’t forgive, we don’t
do anything. I mean it’s a myth. We say
it’s very difficult to forgive, but what
are you doing about it? Only thing, by not
forgiving we are playing into the wrong hands.
So it’s a very great weapon we have got,
just you say, “I forgive everyone.” Don’t
count how many you have to forgive, don’t
count their mistakes and your mistakes. In
short - forget the past for the time being.
And not to feel miserable about yourself.
You have to be pleasantly placed - especially
towards yourself. If you are not pleasantly
placed towards yourself, you cannot be pleasantly
placed towards anyone.
All right? So should we have our Realization
now?
**** part 2 ****
It’s they are too far away, if they can
come a little forward would be better.
Yes, My child?
FEMALE SEEKER: [INDIST.]
SHRI MATAJI: I can’t hear.
SEEKER: [INDIST.]
SHRI MATAJI: What’s they say?
YOGI: She’s saying that children are supposed
to be born in a more enlightened stage, and
what can we do to help them maintain their
enlightening.
SHRI MATAJI: Ahh, you should get your own…
Oh Ma, they have all come here, look at that
– that’s Cincinnati really. May God bless
you! Oh!
Look at that! May God bless you all! Ah, but
– yes, yes – by getting Realization you’ll
understand your children much better and you
can do much better for them. Oh, it’s great,
isn’t it? Please put Me forward.
I have just to ask you to take out your shoes,
because shoes little bit tighten your feet.
So just take out your shoes if possible.
Aside: It’s all right, I have a shawl on
Me.
With such earnestness, what beautiful people
you are - really so beautiful.
So we are all going to enter into the kingdom
of God, and nobody has to feel guilty. When
you are going on a big journey, so pleasant
at that we have to be very pleasant, we have
to be very happy and enthusiastic.
All right, it’s very, very simple – extremely
simple as I told you. They – as he has told
that we have to little bit help our centers.
And on the left-hand side we’ll be helping
our centers. All those who are sitting up
on the chair should take out their shoes also,
please – and put your feet on the Mother
Earth because this Mother Earth helps us a
lot, She is a very helpful thing. And so,
if you could take out your shoes I’ll be
thankful. For a little while, only ten minutes
at the most. (Shri Mataji laughing)
Takes about ten minutes, not more than that
– and that much time we can always give
to ourselves. And those who are sitting on
a chair have to put both the feet apart from
each other. The best are those who are sitting
on the ground. All right. But in any case
it will work, I am sure.
Now what we have to do is to understand as
he has told you in a very short form, that
the left side is the power of desire, so you
put the left hand towards Me, just like this,
very comfortably, without troubling much,
just the left hand like that. Be comfortable.
You can’t sit with the legs like that? Those
who can’t sit like that, it will be difficult,
so at least have one foot up and another like
that – so that you can put the left hand
towards Me. And the right hand on the Mother
Earth – here on the heart. On the heart.
In the heart resides the Spirit – so first
we put our hand on the center where resides
the Spirit. Then we take down our hand and
put it on the upper part of our abdomen on
the left-hand side. Left hand all the time
like this – desiring to get your Realization.
Then one has to understand that if you are
the Spirit you are also your master, you are
also your guide – because there is light
and you know what is to be done, you don’t
need any master, you don’t need any guru.
You become your own guru. Then you take your
right hand and put it in the lower part of
your abdomen, lower part on the left-hand
side.
The upper one was the center of your mastery,
the lower one is the center which gives you
the manifestation of the Divine Power in your
central nervous system – means it’s the
pure knowledge. It’s not the knowledge that
you just know through your mental activity,
but is the pure knowledge. Like I can feel
this is hot, or cold, this is red, this is
pink – in the same way. Absolutely. That’s
the center for your pure knowledge.
Then you take back your hand on the upper
part of your abdomen, again on the left-hand
side, to raise the Kundalini as we’ll do
later on with closing our eyes.
Then you have to take it to your heart. And
then you have to take your hand in the corner
of your neck and your shoulder and turn your
head to your right. Now this is the center
I was talking about which is always very much
caught up, because we feel guilty. And is
the worst center, because it causes horrible
diseases like angina, spondylitis - all kinds
of headaches. So please put your hand as far
as possible on the back and turn your head
to your right.
Now this hand again is brought onto the forehead
across – as we put it sometimes for our
headache, and press it on both the sides.
This is the center of forgiveness. Then we
take back our hand and put it on the backside
of our head and push our head on top and look
up. Now, this is the center for asking forgiveness
without counting your mistakes, your guilts
and all kinds of condemnations.
Then you stretch your hand, stretch your hand
and put the left hand with the center of your
palm, you put the center of your palm, bend
your head in the - on the fontanel bone area,
which was a soft bone in your childhood. Just
adjust it properly and then push back your
fingers, press it hard and move your scalp
very slowly seven times. Very slowly, clockwise.
All this we have to do just now closing our
eyes. Just we have to close our eyes, because
our attention has to go inside. Please put
your left hand towards Me. And you can take
out your spectacles, would be better because
your eyes also are helped. Now, please put
your right hand on your heart and left hand
towards Me with both the legs apart from each
other, not for the sitting people but otherwise.
Now, at this point you have to ask Me a questions
three times, a very important question. You
can call Me Shri Mataji or you can call Me
Mother, “Mother, am I the Spirit?” Ask
this question three times. It’s a computer-style
of meditation, so ask a question, “Mother,
am I the Spirit?” Ask this question three
times. You are not to be diffident about anything
at this moment.
Now - if you are the Spirit you are also the
master, so take down your hand in the upper
portion of your abdomen on the left-hand side
and press it hard which is the center of mastery
and ask another question three times, “Mother,
am I my own master?” Please ask this question
three times, “Mother, am I my own master?
Mother, am I my own master?” Please ask
this question - within your heart.
Now, please take your hand in the lower portion
of your abdomen on the left-hand side and
press it hard. As I told you this is the center
of pure knowledge but I cannot force you to
accept pure knowledge, it cannot be done.
So you have to ask for it in your freedom
and glory. So please say six times, because
this petal has got - this center has got six
petals, so please say it six times, “Mother,
please give me pure knowledge.” Please ask
six times.
As soon as you ask for pure knowledge the
Kundalini starts moving and so we have to
help the other centers to be opened out with
our right hand. So we put our right hand in
the upper portion of our abdomen on the left-hand
side and here we say with full confidence
to open this center of mastery ten times,
we say it ten times, “Mother, I am my own
master. Mother, I am my own master”, we
say it ten times.
Now, one has to know the truth and the truth
is, you are not this body, you are not this
mind, you are not this intelligence, you are
not your ego nor your conditioning - you are
the pure Spirit. So please raise your right
hand on your heart and say with full confidence
twelve times - please say it with full confidence
- twelve times, “Mother, I am the Spirit.
Mother, I am the Spirit.”
Now one has to know that the Divine is the
ocean of bliss and joy, it is the ocean of
love and compassion, but above all it is the
ocean of forgiveness. And we cannot do anything
that cannot be dissolved by this ocean of
forgiveness. So now raise your hand in the
corner of your neck and your shoulder, as
far as back you can take it, and turn your
head to your right. Here with full confidence
you have to say sixteen times, with full confidence,
sixteen times you have to say, “Mother - Mother
I’m not guilty at all.” Please say it
sixteen times. “Mother, I’m not guilty
at all.” And don’t think, “How can I
say and how can I not say.” Let your Kundalini
judge you, you should not judge yourself.
Please say it sixteen times with full confidence.
Now - sixteen times.
We have to know, the greatest weapon we have
is that we can forgive others. When we forgive
others we get out of the clutches of other
people and the Divine looks after them. So
please now raise your hand onto your forehead
and bend your head and press it hard on both
the sides. Bend your head and press it hard
on both the sides. Here you have to say from
your heart, not how many times but from your
heart, genuinely please say, “Mother, I
forgive everyone.” Please say that, “Mother,
I forgive everyone.” It’s very simple
to say, just you have to say it. Earnestly
from your heart, please say.
Now take back your hand on the backside of
your head and push back your head. Rest on
the hand. Here – without feeling guilty,
without finding faults with you, without counting
how many mistakes you have committed – for
your own satisfaction, in general you have
to say, “Oh Divine, if I have done any mistakes
please forgive. Oh Divine, if I have done
any mistakes please forgive.” From your
heart. Not how many times, but from your heart.
Now, please stretch your hand and put the
center of your palm on the soft bone that
you have, on top of your head when you were
a child, press it hard, push back your fingers,
press the scalp and move it slowly. But here
again, I cannot force Self Realization on
you, you have to ask for it. You have to ask
for self-enlightenment, so please say, “Mother,
please give me my Self Realization.” Seven
times, when you move your scalp seven times
clockwise, please.
(Shri Mataji blows eight times into the microphone.)
Now take down your hand, put down both, put
your hands towards Me, both of them and open
your eyes slowly. Watch Me without thinking,
you can do it. Now put the right hand towards
Me and see for yourself, bend your head, and
see for yourself if there’s a Cool Breeze
coming out of your fontanel bone area. Just
see for yourself. You have to certify yourself,
I’m not going to say anything, just see
yourself. Bend your head - better to be seen
this way. Now, not to – be close to your
[ head ?]. Little higher. You have to put
it little higher. See for yourself if there
is – some people get it very much away.
Just see, some people will get hot air, doesn’t
matter. The heat has to come out, then the
Cool Breeze starts coming.
Now, put the left hand towards Me. With the
right hand you try to feel the Cool Breeze.
Now – again - at last, put again the left
hand - little further. See for yourself if
there is a Cool Breeze coming out of your
fontanel bone area. Hmm.
Now, you put your both the hands towards the
sky and look up. Ask a question, anyone of
these questions, three times, “Mother, is
this the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost? Mother,
is this the all-pervading Power of God’s
Love? Mother is this the Brahma Chaitanya?”
Ask this question three times.
Now please take down your hands. Now see,
if you are feeling the Cool Breeze in your
hands. Now watch, there is no tree moving,
no leaf - not a single leaf is moving. They’re
all watching you, if you are feeling the Cool
Breeze. There is no air-conditioning or anything.
Now all those who have felt the Cool Breeze
in their hands or out of their head – or
heat – please raise your hands. Both the
hands. Oh My God. Oh, may God bless you. What
a place Cincinnati is, really what a place,
so many seekers. I really bow to you all very
much and next time I’m going to come here
for more time to be with you. So heartening.
May God bless you!
We have a follow-on course and they are going
to look after you. Those who have not felt
also Cool Breeze will feel. Everybody can
feel it. And only thing is, it is beyond your
thought. So you can’t argue it out, you
cannot think about it. Try to remain in thoughtless
awareness. Please come and see these people
and they will definitely help you out to fix
your connections. In any case I would like
to meet you, if you want to shake hands with
Me – I’ll be very happy.
Thank you!
Aside: Please, can you remove this?
So many people now, what to say? (Shri Mataji
laughing) Tremendous, they are tremendous!
YOGI: You want the microphones off?
SHRI MATAJI: Ah? No, no. No more.