I
have to
tell
you thank you very much for this celebration,
for all these beautiful balloons; but, looking
at these balloons, we have to
also see some of them who have lost their
air completely.
This is another problem we face in the West
because to have ego itself, according to the
Western culture, is a very great achievement.
And when we start living with our ego I know
how one looks like.
He really looks like a stupid fellow.
When he talks, when he describes himself,
you don't know where to look because just
feel like laughing at his stupidity.
Ego is the outcome of stupidity.
I don't know what to say; how to give a simile
to ego, because it's just bloated and makes
you float in the air, and when it bursts you
are down on the earth.
But you are not down on the earth the way
Sahaja Yogis should be down to earth; but
you are completely finished.
All your arrogance goes to waste.
You can never understand Sahaja Yoga if you
have this ego in your head.
I have known people who have this ego.
They have come to Sahaja Yoga and still they
want to think that they know more than anybody
else.
To know about yourself you have to go deep
down, and to go deep down you have to give
up all this idea which makes you float in
the air.
Imagine if you have a big balloon attached
to you.
How can you go deep down into the sea?
You cannot.
That kind of a air which makes you float in
the air, absolutely in an area of stupidity,
what else -I mean English you will think there
are no words- stupidity means everything.
Then you may think no end of yourself.
You may think whatever you like, you can behave
the way you like and all that but what do
you achieve?
You achieve nothing out of it.
Whatever you achieve people are jealous of
you.
They want to harm you.
You have no friends.
Nobody cares for you, and in Sahaja Yoga people
know who has got this problem.
So, I've seen people when they start talking
they say, “Ah!
We know, we know him.”
Once I had an experience, long, long time
back in Pune where the people who were owning
that wada said that we cannot have Shri Mataji's
program because She is not a Brahmin.
So the Sahaja Yogis said, all right we'll
give it in the newspaper because She is not
a Brahmin we cannot have a program.
So, these people came to My program and the
owner of that was sitting on the gallery on
top.
He couldn't even walk.
He was suffering from some sort of a funny
disease.
So these people suddenly start.
I didn't know.
They didn't tell Me anything.
They didn't tell Me that these people have
protested or whatever it is.
So they all started shaking like this, like
this, like this.
I said, “What is this?”
So I said, “What is it?”
They said “Mother, stop it.
We know You are Shakti but stop it.
It's too much, too much.”
“But what did you do?”
They said, “We didn't do anything.
We just said this is a Brahmin's thing and
a Brahmin's wada, and this area is mostly
resided by Brahmins, so we thought that You
cannot have your program.”
I said, “Really, that's all ?”
“Yes, yes, that's all.
But it's, you see on the other side, you see
those people?
They are also shaking with Your power.”
So I asked them, “Who are you?
Are you also Brahmins ?”
They said, "No, no.
We are certified mad people from Thana.”
“And how are you here?”
They said, “There was one fellow who was
mad was cured by You.”
“Really?”
“So our superintendent is here.
He has brought us here.
We are certified mad.
Certified.”
My goodness, these people looked at Me.
I said, “See now, you tally.
You are shaking and they are shaking.
Now you tally.
Where are you?”
And they all became Sahaja Yogis.
Not only that but the gentleman sitting upstairs
I told him, "You get up and come down."
He came
and since that day he has surrendered his
life and did a lot of work in Pune.
So what I'm saying that anybody who talks
like that; that “This is wrong, in Sahaja
Yoga, this should not happen, we should not
have paid so much, or this leader is not good”;
should take a paper, thin paper, on his hand,
and put it before the photograph.
If you can stop the shaking then you are all
right.
All of you can try this.
Then try on the right hand.
Very practical.
If the paper is shaking that means Mr. Ego
is shaking, and you know how to treat your
ego in Sahaja Yoga, thanks to Mohammed Sahib.
He has told us how to treat it.
Now these two problems are within us.
One of them is our conditioning and another
is this ego business, and we make our mind
out of that and we are playing under the governance
of these two things which we have used to
make this mind.
Now you have to be careful.
You find out with left hand.
Now let's see.
If the left hand is shaking then you are conditioned.
If the right hand is shaking then you are
egoistical.
So now you treat it.
You treat these two things.
Before Me you'll get vibrations all right
because you see I am your Mother.
All right.
But that doesn't mean you are all right.
You try on My photograph; that's much more
sharp.
So being Mother you know I play around.
I think, I don't know what I should say, but
maybe you may not feel that way.
But before the photograph you put on the left
hand side a newspaper or a little paper or
a thin paper.
On the right hand side another paper.
One by one you try and judge yourself, what
are you?
After all you have not come here in Sahaja
Yoga to emancipate Me.
You have come here to evolve yourself and
because of that you have to face yourself
and see for yourself what is within you which
is very strong, which is troublesome, which
is dragging you down, which is killing.
Sahaja Yoga is nothing but Ocean of Joy.
I thought that in My absence you'll be all
enjoying it all right; you do.
Airport I have seen sometimes I am late because
of the plane, about four hours, five hours,
and everybody is so fresh, and so nice early
in the morning.
I said, “What's happened ?”
“The whole night we have been enjoying Mother.”
So what you enjoy in that is collectivity:
Sangat That collectivity you should enjoy
only by getting rid of your nonsensical boundaries
that you have built, and then you see the
joy.
All the time you'll be floating in joy.
There is a sense which people have which you
may not have before realization.
Some of the people, I was amazed how deep
they are, how they took to Sahaja Yoga.
Supposed to be very great men.
Supposed to be people of very great principles
but very hot-tempered, intolerant about people,
and they take to Sahaja Yoga just like this
because inside there's a big depth, so that
everything is absorbed without any problem.
Everybody can achieve but one has to be careful
as to the two wheels of our mind.
One is the ego, another is the conditioning.
All kinds of conditionings are there, especially
in India.
In the West it is all kinds of egos you know,
different, different types.
I have seen so many types and varieties of
egos, I was surprised; to face that.
I didn't know what to say.
It's a very, very subtle thing which people
have carved out of their minds.
So for you today it is to be decided that
you are only still small children, and like
small children you must have a very clean
heart to accept, to absorb the beauty of peace
that is within you; and also the beauty of
purity.
Without purity you cannot enjoy anything.
So in Sahaja Yoga though we have so many people
I must say the purity of these few saints,
who lived earlier, we have to yet achieve.
For example, yesterday they were singing about
Ali.
I was so very happy because He was an Incarnation.
And His purity people are singing now; not
at that time.
He was killed at that time, He was tortured.
That always they do.
Then we have many others.
We have here Dam Dam Sahib.
See what a great thing to come to.
We have here Nizamuddin Auliya.
We have so many people in our country itself
that nobody, no other country can claim.
They have one, say in England they have William
Blake or this and that.
We had so many people.
Why?
Not because we were very good people, but
because we were to be improved.
Things had to be done.
So they were born.
Though this is a Yoga Bhoomi anywhere you
go in India, I was surprised, in Haryana so
many great saints lived there.
But they were all tortured, troubled, never
understood.
It was so painful and hurts you how this stupid,
ignorant, blind people tortured them.
So now it is our duty of Sahaja Yogis to,
first of all, find out who is a saint.
Even among Sahaja Yogis, as I described in
Hindi language, there are people who try to
trouble, trouble others.
If you have no recognition and understanding
of what is the truth, what is love, what is
pure compassion, then you are not a Sahaja
Yogi.
It's like an obtuse angle you see, you have.
You look at a person with an obtuse angle
you don't see anything, one-sided.
Now, at this juncture when I am so very old
now; I have to request that you turn your
eyes to yourself.
Introspect.
Because among you there are some people who
will try to divert your attention, will try
to say things.
Very easy to say, “He is very dishonest,
he is very immoral”; very easy to say.
What are you?
We have to now understand that Sahaja Yoga
is to be consolidated through synthesis.
We are believers of synthesis.
Any divisive thing that comes into your mind
you should just throw it away.
This is a request on this day I make you - that
you please introspect.
Unless and until you introspect you cannot
even respect yourself.
You cannot even love yourself.
If you love yourself you will introspect and
find out what's wrong.
Supposing I love this sari, then if I find
any doubt about it or see any dot somewhere
or something I'll get it cleaned.
I'll not be proud of it, wear it and go round
saying, “Ah!
See I've got so many spots.”
In the same way, you should be not proud of
whatever asahaj temperaments you have within
yourself.
And don't talk like that.
Christ has called them 'murmuring souls'.
He said, “Beware of the murmuring souls”.
I would say: "Throw away all the murmuring
souls".
That's the only way.
In Hindi as they say 'bakwas’; their name
is bakwas; means the ones who just chatter,
chatter, chatter; talk all nonsense about
others.
He doesn't know what he is.
It is much more in India, I must confess.
I'm sorry, though I'm an Indian.
It is a habit of talking ill of others, sitting
down just chit-chatting.
They will not talk of Sahaja Yoga.
How many people know Sahaja Yoga in the proper
way?
I mean if I have to give degrees, what degrees
I should give to you?
Tell Me.
You don't know even about your vibrations.
Of course you are Sahaja Yogis because you
have fallen into this trap of achieving evolution.
But how many are really grown up into it?
You can.
So I have to again and again tell you, to
make Me happy, you have to give up all these
nonsensical, cheapish talks; but try to understand
from each other what we know of Sahaja Yoga.
Discuss it and contribute to this knowledge
by describing your experiences of Sahaja Yoga.
There are many who do it.
I am not saying they don't do.
But even there's one bad fellow he can spoil
all of them; like one bad apple can spoil
all the apples.
So what do we do -throw away the apple out
of the basket.
It is important see, even I feel all this,
standing like a witness to you, silent witness.
When I see big, big mountains, and I think
they are like great saints who are watching,
and they are trying to record what is happening
in this world because they also understand.
They also know.
I have to again, and again, tell you that
today is the day to see your own self, your
own chakras, your own - I should say - defects.
That will give you permanently the joy that
is promised.
You will get thoughtless awareness.
Also you'll get doubtless awareness.
But never get into the trap of your conditioning
and of your ego.
This is what I have to tell you today, on
this day where you are celebrating, that you
celebrate your own birthday.
Celebrate it.
See for yourself what you have achieved and
what you are going to achieve.
It's time for you to celebrate than to celebrate
My birthday.
I'll be very happy to celebrate your birthday
than to celebrate Mine.
So may God bless you.
Today, I was thinking, that we had given a
nice chance to children to come up.
But all the leaders are also My children.
So they should come here on the stage and
can say Atharva Sheersha.
Not the children which are really children,
in the real sense of the word, but those who
have become child-like.
All such people should come up and say Arthava
Sheersha, We all should say Atharva Sheersha.
It’s going to be a very small puja because
you are worshipping Me as I am.
It’s not like anything.