Today, it’s a great day that you are here
to worship your Guru in the realm of the heart
of the universe. If we can do that in our
domain of the heart, we don’t have to do
anything else.
Today, also, I feel I have to tell you about
Sahaja Yoga and its value, which is related
to other Yogas which were accepted in the
olden days all over the world. They called
it, one, as the Yoga – not Sahaja Yoga,
Yoga. It started with various types of practices
of ‘Ashtanga’ [Sanskrit/Hindi meaning
‘having eight stages/parts’] Yogas – eightfold
yogas – with a Guru. And one had to go through
lots of hardships. Nobody who was married
was allowed into that Ashtanga Yoga, and they
had to give up their families, give up their
relationships. They had to become
absolutely without any attachments, to go
to a Guru. All their property, all their possessions
were given up. Not to the Guru as is done
in modern times, but given away. And this
was called as Yoga.
The another style was called as Sankhya. Sankhya
is where all your life you have to gather
things with detachment, and then to distribute
them completely and take to a Guru, in a way
completely surrendered, and then get realization.
Sankhya was the left-sided behavior. And the
Yoga was the right-sided. Where the Gayatri
Mantra was used was the Sankhya. Because they
were left-sided, they used to use Gayatri
Mantra. They went so much to the left side
- that is to gather things, to gather possessions,
to gather properties, to gather all kinds
of friends and relations and societies - that
they were afraid that they may be completely
lost into all those things. They would go
to Gayatri, the Mantra of Gayatri which teaches
you the essences of all our Chakras – the
centers. I have told about this before also
– ‘Bhu’, ‘Bhurv’, ‘Swaha’. ‘Bhu’
stands for the essence or the ‘Bija’ of
the ‘Mooladhara’; ‘Bhuv’ for the universe
that is created that is Swadisthana’s ‘Bija’;
‘Swaha’ is the ‘Bija’ of the Nabhi;
‘Manah’ is the essence of the Heart Chakra.
Then, ‘Janah’ is the people, collectivity,
is the essence or the ‘Bija’ of the Vishuddhi
Chakra. Then, ‘Tapah’ is the one where
you go into ‘tapasya’, into renunciation,
into hardships – is the essence of the Agnya
Chakra. And then the ‘Satya’ is the truth,
is the essence of the Sahasrara – not the
truth that we think as truth, but the truth
that is expressed in our central nervous system.
So, this is discovered at the seventh stage
of the Sahasrara. So the people who did Sankhya
were, sort of, not so much respected as spiritual
people, because they thought these are all
involved into worldly things and worldly possessions
and worldly happenings. So, they were regarded
as something secondary. Or those who were
yogis of the Gurus were regarded higher, because
they had already given up everything, and
they have gone to a Guru giving up all the
things that they have. But here, these Gurus
had a problem within themselves because they
found that those who came to them gave up
everything – no doubt – but still there
was lurking attachments. In their own ‘Ashramas’
[Hindi/Sanskrit meaning hermitages] they found,
these people had their own attachments to
things. Though outwardly they had given up,
but inside they had not given up. So, they
were still sticking on to these ideas that,
‘Oh, its all right. But still we can have
little things like that, doesn’t matter.’
Like that, there was little compromises going
on. Like, as we have here nunneries and all
that. So both, in a way, were artificial.
The one side, is the Sankhyas, were trying
to ascend with all the luggage they were carrying.
And another were trying to descend with all
the ambitions of ascent.
So, it was a very funny thing in every aspect,
in both these styles of Yoga. As you can see
that now, if you go to America you’ll find,
‘Oh God, what is this America? It’s not
democracy, it’s demonocracy.’ But if you
go from that in the realm of another country
like Russia, you find - what is this? You
are working here under complete pressures
and fears. But as soon as a Russian comes
out of that country, he can become worse than
an American. So what is this? One theory works
here, another theory works there. So which
is the theory that is all right? Same you
find about religion. Say, a religion, which
believes in many Gods, like the Hindus, they
are also believing now into the ‘Bhoots’.
And they are also following the path of possessions.
If you go to a temple, every temple has got
nice arrangement for you to get possessed.
Or even a church, or a mosque – where God
has to reside, you find suddenly you get attacked
and you come out absolutely puzzled about
yourself, ending up into lunatic asylums.
So what sort of worshipping places are these,
where you go to find God and you get the horrible
satanic forces acting on you? That’s why,
in the modern times, people have become so
very confused. We do not find truth in anything
– in any ideologies, any philosophies, anything
that started… say, Confusius started humanism,
Socrates started another thing, Mohammad Saheb
started another thing. Like Mohammad Saheb
said let us not worship God as an idol; let
us worship Him in the ‘Nirakara’, in the
formless God. But you see the formless? How
they are killing each other now? I mean, after
seeing the Muslim countries, you can’t believe
there could be any formless or formful God
existing anywhere – all must have run away
- the way they are fighting. Then you see
the Christian countries. Wherever they have
gone, they have tried to dominate other people
who were not Christians, just as if they had
a right to do it because they were Christians.
The Disciples of Christ, who said, “Forgive
them for they do not know what they are doing.”
And I have to say the same for all the Christians,
“Forgive them for they do not know what
they are doing.” And when you are shocked
at all these things, one must sit down and
think what is to be done, what’s the problem
is.
So, it is neither Sankhya nor Yoga; then what
is it you have to achieve? That is Sahaja
Yoga. Sahaja Yog is a system in which first
you are not given a theory, but the light
in your hand to see for yourself in which
both things look the same. For example, now
you have got this beautiful house made for
your Mother, while your Mother doesn’t know
how to get attached to even a pin. It’s
a funny situation.
Everybody has to remind Me, “Mother it is
Your house.”
“Oh I see.”
And I have to be reminded I must thank you
all, specially the English, specially the
leaders of English Sahaja yogis, for making
full effort to get this house. But then, I
think why should I thank? It’s not mine,
it’s theirs – and that’s what it is.
So a new type of confusion starts, and that’s
what I felt that this confusion is very sweet
and beautiful. It’s a fact that nothing
belongs to us, but every thing belongs to
us. When I think about how beautifully you
have done this place, it belongs to Me, all
right; this house belongs to Me; England belongs
to Me and above all, the whole world belongs
to Me. That’s how we see Sankhya and Yoga
become one in Sahaja Yoga. And it’s said
that when you see Sankhya and Yoga as one,
then only ‘Sapashyati’ – that’s the
one who sees; that’s the one is the witness.
So, for normal people it could be that how
is it your Mother is supposed to be a Guru
and She wears all ornaments? But what to do?
She’s also a Mother and She is also a Goddess.
Another confusion. How to make these two things
be? You see a Guru has to be a very angry
person, wearing only single dress either upwards
or downwards, I don’t know how, with a big
thick rod in the hand, never smiling – laughing
no question – smiling. And the Gurus have
to be very long faced, developing big, big
beards, and no ladies allowed. In such a situation,
where the women are not to be seen at all,
I mean I shouldn’t even see My face - it’s
like that. There is a big discussion in all
the scriptures - not scriptures, I would say
the critiques, whether a woman should be allowed
to do the spiritual practices or not – imagine.
Not only among Christians, you’ll be surprised,
even in Indian scriptures - whether is woman
is allowed or not to do spiritual practices.
Now when your Mother is a woman and She is
your Guru, what will you do? This is another
confusion because it is wrong, the whole thing
is falsehood, based on no basis at all. You
may try anything to say that women are not
meant for spiritual life, try any argument,
it fails. The other day I met one big John
in a University, big fellow, I might say really
hard nut, and he started saying, “We Christians
cannot accept a woman to be God.”
I said, “Why?”
“Because…”
So to put all these upside-down stories right,
your Mother had to come on this earth as a
Guru. I got to this point out of one little
confusion I had about Myself. The other day,
somebody was after My life that I should buy
a bracelet. I said, “I have no money anymore;
I don’t want to buy.”
“All right we will give it in Puja.”
I said, “But now there is only Guru Puja.”
Said, “All right, we will give it in Guru
Puja.”
I said, “To buy a bracelet in Guru Puja
is something funny I have done.”
After all, in a Guru Puja you don’t give
a bracelet to your Guru, do you? You can give,
say, a big rod; or you might give him a sandalwood
‘Khada’ - what is it called - ‘Chappals’,
or you may give him a shawl. But here it is…
I have asked… all right give it in Guru
Puja. What was the reason? And I became aware
of My own confusion and I thought of it. I
said, “This is what it is, that it has to
happen this way that, on a Guru Puja you have
to give a bracelet to your Guru.” Let us
change it over. The whole thing has to be
brought up this way that everything faces
reality. All these false ideas have to be
given up. Like, if you have a carpet upside-down,
the whole design is upside-down. But, if you
put the carpet right, everything falls in
line. And that’s why you needed a Mother
to give you realization, and a Guru as a Mother
to teach you that for ascent of God nobody
can be prohibited.
That is how the Sahaja Yoga today is working
out. In all directions, if you find, to put
all upside-down things into right direction,
to expose it to reality, to bring all real
values, to abolish all rotten value systems,
all political, economic systems, all spiritual
theologies, all psychological and all such
nonsensical ideas into its proper direction.
How in one incarnation it has worked out,
you can imagine. How in one incarnation all
these ideas have been put right.
Another idea exists, among Hindus, that if
you are a religious people, you should be
a vegetarian. All the Brahmins believe this,
and even the non-Brahmins. But we had a Brahmin
working in one of the places where I was living,
and they said that for Mother we have to give
meat, She doesn’t eat anything else. She
has to eat proteins. She said, “Yes,yes,
Of course. For a Mother, She must have.”
Whether it’s a Brahmin or a non-Brahmin,
all understand that Mother has to eat proteins.
Because She has to drink the blood of all
these ‘rakshasas’ [Hindi meaning demons],
how can She be vegetarian? And if She has
to kill so many devils, how can She be non-violent?
So the contrast that you see in the description
of the Mother - that She is the one who is
the most furious personality when it comes
to the killing of the people who are of the
negative land, who are trying to destroy Her
creation, Her own children; and She is the
sweetest and the mildest person for Her own
children. These two contrasts should be seen.
Even in animals you’ll find the same contrast,
but very evident in an incarnation like this.
And today, through Sahaja Yoga, we have been
able to prove that Sankhya and Yoga are the
same.
Whether you collect things, whether you have
possessions or whether you give away, makes
no difference to a person who is detached
from within. If you collect them for others,
even better. But if you collect for yourself
and then give away, that’s even much better.
Because first you collect for yourself then
you think, “Oh it’s good for me, I will
use this one for myself, will be a good idea”
- so the self is there - but then, that you
give away. That means your detachment is complete.
Or the third personality could be liking [not
clear]… which just goes on collecting and
just goes on giving. Without thinking it collects
and without thinking it gives because thinking
is not My job. That is one thing I have given
up – is to think. I don’t want to think
– that’s your work, not Me. And without
thinking, how many things we have achieved
through Sahaja Yoga. Yoga and Sankhya both
are products of thinking, not products of
spontaneity. This house itself is a product
of spontaneity. I mean, as we call the English
as ‘Saablogs’, you see. So I took some
‘Saablogs’ with Me around to see some
houses and they wanted to (see) some houses
with some character – means something must
fall out, something must be crooked, this
should not be straightforward. I said, “Now
please, I can’t bear all this crookedness.”
So, “No, no, but it has character.”
I said, “Now, this kind of a crooked nose
I don’t want.” Straightforward it should
be. So they were rather disappointed at Me.
And the ‘Saablog’ had some other ideas
also that, say for example, if you go to,
say, to a place called Windmere, it’s a
posh place; if you go to the Northside, little
less; then if you go to the east, it’s useless
– like that. I said, “Let’s go the north,
northest as far as we can go.” Because,
you know, the Godess has to be ‘Dakshinamurthy’.
She has to be on the north side to be on the
- Her eyes on the south. That’s the reason
She has to be… I mean we could not have
been in Scotland – that would have been
too much for you. But that would have been
the ideal for all of us because then our ‘Drishti’
is towards - our vision is towards the south
and we see the whole universe under our own
beautiful visions. So that’s how, spontaneously,
we found this place. And ‘Saablog’ were,
“Yes, No, No, Yes.” But spontaneously
we got it. And then we found out it has a
history; then we found out its beautiful vibrations;
then we found out the potential about it.
Whatever you get spontaneously, it is full
of potentials.
On this point, I have to say a few words,
is important. I had to get - few points I
have to say about spontaneity part which is
quite interesting – the way people think
spontaneity works. Like, it’s mostly ego
part which says, ‘This is spontaneous,’
with so many people. Specially the very old
Sahaja Yogis think they are authorities on
spontaneity. Like, we had a land in Vaitarna.
So one of the older ones went there and he
said, “This land is vibrating and this is
not vibrating.” So everybody accepted, ‘All
right, all right, all right.’ Then they
said, “In this part of the land nobody should
eat their food.” Now, from where does this
knowledge come? Eating food is not a sin,
is it? As if it is a sin that you are eating
food in there. Then religiously they follow
a, b, c, d, e, f, g, h, z and again a, b,
c, d of Sahaja Yoga to such an extent, ‘ki’
[Hindi meaning ‘that’] I start thinking
now they have become another fanatic Sahaja
Yogis. Fanaticism is against Sahaja Yoga – absolutely.
Now they will ask, “How many times we should
say this ‘Mantra’?” Then I say, “Zero
times.”
“How many drops we should put, the ghee,
in our nose?” Then I say, “A full jug.”
Then, “Oh, I should not have gone from the
left side, I should have gone from the right
side.”
Then, I would say, “You just jump up.”
You have to be like children. But the ideas
are so settled down in Sahaja Yoga, now it’s
so many years of course, but they should not
settle down. If they settle down, it’s not
Sahaja; it’s not spontaneous. ‘If you
do this way, then it is wrong; that way, it’s
wrong’ – nothing of the kind. Nothing
is wrong for you people. If you do anything
wrong, your vibrations will be lost, finished.
What is there to be so cautious? Like, somebody
said, “I don’t want to look at the cigarette.”
I said, “Why?”
“Looking at it also is sinful.”
I said, “Looking at it what happens?”
“Then I feel like smoking.”
So I said, “Better smoke once for all.”
Or, “I cannot hold a wine bottle in my hand.”
“Why?”
“No, holding the wine bottle is sinful.”
I mean, you can swim in the wine. So this
kind of understanding should be there. Though
I have always said that if I say one thing,
you will clinch on to it. So I always say
the other side of it - that don’t stick
on to something; Sahaja Yoga is not for sticking
on to something. Like somebody who had learnt
certain say, lessons about Sahaja Yoga in
the beginning of it, certain Mantras they
had learnt, and still they are sticking on
to the same step. No, no, no, no – you have
to go ahead. This is just a staircase. Don’t
get stuck at a point. We have had so many
such cases here. People get really outworn
as they say. They will go on telling you so
many nonsensical ideas – “You see, if
you do like this, then this happens.” First
of all, you don’t give ideas to others.
That’s one thing - if you decide that we
don’t give ideas about what’s wrong with
another person, half of your job is done.
Because you don’t have to do any job, as
I don’t do. Anybody who comes, “You are
a ‘bhoot’.” You better have it. I get
reports from others. They say that your Sahaja
Yogis are wicked people. I said, “Why?”
“Oh, they tell you, ‘You are evil.’
They tell you, ‘You are possessed’, they
tell you, ‘You are this, you are that’;
they are very wicked people.”
I am really shocked to hear that Sahaja Yogis
- how can they be wicked? If somebody is suffering
from something, in the phone they say, “Oh
you better have it. It’s good for you.”
That’s not the way. We have to be not only
humble, very tactful and sweet to new people
– if you want any more to come in. But if
you have decided not to have anymore, because
you will have to put another marquee, then
I have nothing to say. But if you want others
to come in, then it’s important that you
talk to them in a very sweet and beautiful
language, the way they understand. Rudeness,
arrogance, showing off, is of no use. One
should understand Sahaja Yoga is where you
are in complete enjoyment about it; you are
just lost into that enjoyment. Where is the
time to remember how many times to give a
‘Bandhan’ to yourself? What is the need
to give ‘Bandhan’ to yourself? It’s
all a joke now for you, should be. A little
child sucks the milk from the bottle, all
right, because it has no teeth. But what about
you people having that kind of a thing? It’s
very childish and shows no growth at all.
Sahaja Yoga must grow within. You should not
be, anymore, regarded as immature Sahaja Yogis.
I would say: a person who is a matured Sahaja
Yogi is the one who can combine so many things
together, with all beautiful lines, thin lines,
thin ‘Maryadas’ [Hindi/Sanskrit meaning
code of conduct] maintained. But, you cannot
do the other way round.
For example, you shouldn’t say, “All right,
now I will be sweet. Then I will be angry;
then I will be sweet; then I’ll be like
this; then I’ll be like that.” It will
be a hotchpotch. It is a funny personality
you see - suddenly I get angry, like that
[facial expression?], and then I [presumably
Mother demonstrates with facial expression].
People will think you are doing ‘Bharatnatyam’
[a form of Indian classical dance] or something
like that. Showing all your moods – in five
minutes you show ten moods. This is the growth
within you, which will show. So, we have to
have our growth, and for growth, let us be
silent within. Let us not react to others
- “This person is like that, that person
is like that.” What about yourself? Also
there… other ways. Like, I tell somebody
that, you see, you have this problem. So that
person immediately goes to the second person
and says, “You see, Mother told me that
you too have this problem, better look after
it.” I didn’t tell that person; I told
you. Keep it to yourself. So, ‘Mother says’
is to be given up, absolutely. If Mother has
to say, She’ll say it. Why should you communicate;
why should you say? I never asked you to say
that.
Understanding Sahaja Yoga is very simple,
extremely simple, when you understand one
thing - that you have to have your innocence
intact. Now, “How to get to innocence?”
people will say. How to get to innocence?
It’s a vicious circle. How to get to innocence?
– It’s a very vicious circle. We have
to get to innocence, through what? Your ego
or superego? How will you get to innocence?
Mother says, “Don’t raise your Kundalini.”
I mean, I am sitting here - people are just
doing like that. What’s happening? I am
sitting here - your Kundalini is up there
on your head. What are you raising? Now how
to manage is the problem. Very simple it is.
In the beginning I said, “Let your Guru
reside in your heart.” How to manage – why?
Let Mother manage. Mother is managing me.
Keep it at that. Your right side will clear.
Your left side will clear when you say, “Nobody
can manage me but Mother can manage me”
- two things together. Things will work out.
Thank God you have somebody like Me, who is
sitting here, who can say so. Think of those
who never had anyone to tell them, or to be
in their presence to say that I can manage
this, or you can manage that. That now you
can balance. Allow your Kundalini to grow.
Everything works out. Like this house when
I purchased, or when they purchased, or who
purchased - So many questions and complications
– How, how, how? But it’s worked; it’s
there, quite intact; nothing has fallen off;
nothing has gone wrong. I had to shout once,
all right. But let Me shout, you don’t start
shouting. As soon as I finish, they will take
a loudspeaker, shout even louder. “Mother
said so, you are this, that.” I am saying
about you, (to) whom are you preaching? But
only, you must know that when I tell you something,
please do it; please do it. See because I
know quite a lot. Because I am Guru, your
Guru; because I am the Guru of all the Gurus.
And those who is a real Guru, knows that my
Mother knows everything. She is knowledge
Herself. If She says something, it means something.
And even I may test you sometimes, doesn’t
matter. That’s how you become the Guru.
Shivaji had a Guru called Ramadasa. In those
days, Gurus used to take lot of test of their
disciples. I never took your test or anything.
But you are testing yourself, that’s all.
And his Guru one day said that, “I think
I need the milk of a tigress. I have to drink
the milk of a tigress.” Half of them died
and most of them didn’t hear it. Shivaji
said, “All right. I’ll get you.” He
went in the jungles. He saw a tigress and
there were little little, small little children
she had, and those cubs were lying on the
side. He went and he just said ‘Namaskar’
[Hindi word meaning salutation] to her. (He)
Said, “My Guru wants your milk,” that’s
all – because Gurus are ‘Parabrahma’
[Hindi/Sanskrit meaning God Almighty], their
orders are listened to by the ‘Parabrahma’.
“My Guru, Shri Ramadasa, wants your milk.
So please, will you give me your milk?”
So nicely she got up, stood up before him.
He milked her and took that milk for his Guru.
This is what it is. Have you understood the
meaning of ‘Gurupada’ [Hindi/Sanskrit
meaning the status/position of Guru]?
When you become absolutely one with the desires
of your Guru, you achieve the position of
a Guru. But if you still have certain ideas
about it, then Shri Ramadasa has said that
then God ‘Alpadhrishtapaye … [not clear]’
sees your little courage [?] - “All right,
go ahead. Break your heads and then come back.
I’ll fix them up.” So it is important
that we should do one thing seriously – is
to take your Mother very seriously when it
comes to some request.
Of course, in English language I always say,
“Please, will you do it?” Or I may even
say, “I am afraid will you do it?” But
that should make no difference. Other day
only, when we were coming for Cardiff, I said
that the first class will be coming on the
other side. But everybody at the platform
said, “No, it is coming on the other side.”
I said, “All right.” We sat down, and
then they announced that the first class is
coming on this side. So we all again walked
back. It’s all right for those people, but
what about you? Many a times you have seen.
And at the asking of a Guru, if something
goes wrong also, it should be always accepted
as the law of the Divine - because, Guru is
the giver of the law of the Divine, not the
worldly laws. The law of the Divine He gives
you. The law of the Divine you understand,
then you have to surrender to that law of
the Divine, and that’s how you will become
masters of that law.
Today, for a Guru Puja, I can go on talking
to you. But today, I would request you to
understand that whilst surrendering, as Islam
is called, was so important -
that if God is your Guru, let Him guide you;
Thy will be done. Let us not guide ourselves
and also, sometimes they try to guide the
Guru as well. Then the Guru plays tricks,
and then you fall into the trap of tricks,
and then you find it’s too much.
It is better to listen to what the Guru is
telling you, and better to do it. Whatever
the Guru says is all right. Gurus can ask
you anything. I mean, I am quite a nice Guru.
Like, this Ramadasa himself asked his disciples
that, “I have got a very bad, septic, big
boil and please try to suck it out because
it is full of pus.” Imagine. So they didn’t
know what to do, you know. How to suck the
pus of the Guru is too much. But Shivaji came
forward. He took down his hat, sat down next
to him, started sucking. People said, “How
is it?” Said, “It’s very sweet, very
nice.” Actually, he had tied a mango there.
That is how the Gurus took lot of tests. I
have never taken your test, and you do not
take the tests of others. Leave them to Me,
I’ll manage all of them one by one. Whatever
has to happen happens. In Sahaja Yoga, to
think that 100% will be rich, healthy, wealthy
and on top of the world, is a nonsense. If
we become very wealthy, then there will be
recession because others will be very poor.
If we become very healthy then nobody will
come near us; if we all look like wrestlers,
who will come near us? If we become very wise,
then people will be frightened of such wise
people; nothing will… they cannot understand
anything, it will go over their heads. So
let us be in the center. We should be wealthy,
but not too much; we should be healthy, but
not too much; we should be wise, but not too
much. So far, so good – that’s how we
should move.
So we keep to our ‘Maryadas’ and we become
beautiful Sahaja Yogis, who will be congenial
to others, who will be able to get others
to us, who will be able to project an image
of magnetic personalities. And this is what
we have to do. If we try to show off in any
way - like I have seen people try to show
off unnecessarily – there is no need. Just
be in the background. If you are very much
in the background, just be in the foreground.
Try to balance yourself. Try to watch yourself
and guide yourself and tell yourself, “Become
your own Gurus.” Judge yourself how far
you are in the center, how far you are growing,
how much growth have you achieved. Are you
still attached to small things here and there?
Are you still bothered about small things?
– “Mother, I should have got 80% marks,
I have got only 75% marks.” Oh God. Because
he got 75% marks, there is something good
has to come out. He has to learn a lesson,
maybe. Or maybe that he has to take some other
course. Maybe something that is good for his
ascent has to work out – is to be seen if
you have to be Gurus. If you can’t see that,
how can others see that? This is to be realized.
Not to be put in the mind, but to be realized
in the heart. In the realm of your heart you
have to realize it; you have to understand
it in the realm of your heart. Nice that we
are in England, the heart of the universe,
that we are talking about opening our hearts.
If you have to put Me there, is the ocean
of love, and to contain this ocean of love,
you have to have a very, very large heart
– bigger than your personalities, bigger
than your countries, bigger than this world,
bigger than this universe.
May God bless you.
End of transcript.