[UNCLEAR]
See born with you is the right achieve is yoga
This is yoga is the union
with the all-pervading
Divine love
so first
you have to
Take it as a hypothesis
But keep your mind open
If it exists there is a power
Which has come to us this knowledge has come to us from ancient times [UNCLEAR], and it stays
Right from Markendaya, Adi sankaracharya
Then we had 13th-century Dnyaneshwara
who described [UNCLEAR]
then we had Kabira, Janaka
Namadeva all of them all these saints sung the Sahaj Samadhi
He needs awareness the Samadhi mean where it is united with all pervading power
This is our heritage
This cannot come from British. They're still primitive as far as
our spiritual life is concerned
It's so primitive that recently there was a big quarrel
Whether the women
should
Become the priest or not. I mean in India women is regarded as Sakthi
So I mean as far as the spirituality is concerned
They do not have much ideas
Now this is our heritage
from ancient times it has been with us
we had three types of
you can say
Search by people
Three institutions you can say or three types of people were searching the truth, perhaps our country is so good that
We can live in a forest
See in India if you have to go out of the house takes half an hour to dress up yourself
we have to always fight with nature. Our country so congenial
The people could live in the forest they don't have to worry about all these outside things
And so this knowledge was you can say
One of three types first one by which they went into research
of all the creation
why these creation is done I mean all the material side of it, so that's how we had
Since now all the idea about all the Antariksha means all the
Heavenly bodies that we call as [UNCLEAR] all these things they knew. the astrology has come from India
So they knew about the stars this is that everything
apart from that
they wanted to
make the matter to work out
And hence he would do those of [UNCLEAR] all that
Because they wanted to utilize the matter as science. Just like science, but this time was different
Now people won't believe you saying we had vimanas and all that, but we have this worse
People won't believe, we are supposed to be most primitive people according to them, but we had all these sciences
gradually built-up by people because they wanted to excite through Mantras
those matters
there are words like Anu, Renu. Renu is the molecule and
Anu means Atom
so we had all these words within us we knew all these things
[UNCLEAR] in a way
This what one side they use Vedas. by using the Vedas it written that
by reading this if you do not
get [Vidita?] Vidita is the word
Vidita means what?
Vidita doesn't mean know through your brain it means you should know on your central nervous system
As you can see me and feel me in the same way you should be able to feel this all-pervading power
that is Vidita
another word
Bodha like Buddha. Bodha
both is the same that you should know it on your central nervous system that is Bodha
so this Vidha and Bodha
These things you should have if you are [UNCLEAR] you should get that
other [UNCLEAR]
So what was the thing is that scientists must be realised souls? They should be evolved souls?
this was the thing
That came another type of worship they call it as left side worship is Bakthi
Because see people were not bother so much of Material things in India
So they were all searching
So they thought there is some higher power it works. We saw the saints and Saints told them that you make Bakthi
Bakthi a lot, by which you will keep your life [UNCLEAR]
These days Bakthi have no meaning because in the mouth to say something and do something else it's different in those days, they use to do Bakthi
By that we used to remember what they're supposed to
What is should be the lifestyle? What is good for you? What is bad for you?
so this Bakthi started
But there was another third
this was called as [Nath?]
first one was right side another was left side, and this is in the center
And you'll be surprised, that in this Maharastra of yours this [UNCLEAR]
And [UNCLEAR]
they believed
In awakening that is residual power called Kundalani
By which they could transform themselves
So this knowledge was mostly in Sanskrit language. 6th century Adi shankaracharya talked about it
But all in Sanskrit
general public did not [know?]
But also, there's a tradition at one guru will have only one disciple only one
Till the [crunch?] it
now this Guru nanaka came much later, but before that Janaka had only one disciple.
His name was Nachiketa[UNCLEAR] then in the first century Gyneswara tremendous personality at the age of 20 what he has written
I mean I tell you people who anything about spirituality really can get lost tremendous
Now this Gyneswara asked permission from his Guru to his brother
You should allow me at-least to write it
Gyneswari at least to write it
Tell them what it is in a way that I am not going to work it out
But let me tell the masses
So he wrote it Gyneswari the sixth chapter
six are there about Kundalini
But because you see [UNCLEAR] those who were in charge of religion?
could not accept it because they do it mean to so they said sixth chapter is [UNCLEAR] means to be abandon
not to be written
The whole thing went into another darkness
Because see in a moment fundamental said they need want something really come out
they didn't know what to do
All right
Then came after 16th century was full of saints
not only Maharastra everywhere
even in Punjab you know that
Guru nanak, Kabira
[UNCLEAR] so many all over at the time of Shivaji there was
she all full of it and
they were talked about Kundalani. They asked
[UNCLEAR]
How much time do you think Kundalini to rise?
So he said tatkSaNam that moment but the
there should be a person who is giver and  person who take it that moment
So in that authority he should not go to that  modern writers about Kundalini these are our authorities
But as it is very few people got realisation
Kabira as throughout written about nothing
he says Surathi Kundalini called Surathi
can you imagine human beings how they are
Surathi is the name of
[Tabba?]
In Bihar where he they called Shruti tabbaa?
She works in
then Kabira not only Kabira [UNCLEAR] he went from Maharastra to Punjab and Guru nanak respected him
and he has written
Such a big book in Punjabi
[UNCLEAR]
many of his poems are in [UNCLEAR] and also of
Because Guru nanaka thought best is to collect all the verses from all these
saints and group them together
Not to write anything else, but what they said so keep it pure
And that's how Namadeva
who try really learn Punjabi language, and he wrote all these things in Punjabi
That is how it came, but they all have talked about right Guru Nanak said Sahaja samadhi. so that is how it came
Sahaj samadhi lavo
we can say Sahaj means something spontaneous or easy
I have told you the meaning of the word Sahaj
But everything is even it is in the book
I've seen that
People think by reading book you can get that sense
like this if you have headache
then I write down prescription take Anacin then you go on reading take Anacin take Anacin then headache won't go it will be worse even
It's like this so all these books you see has put limitations in [UNCLEAR]
But I've seen people who go on reading akhand ramayan akhand geeta part they go on reading
they go on akhand
What they have said, they have not seen in it
Nanaka Said [UNCLEAR] why are you going to the jungle
He says it is in with in you why are you going to Jungles?
So all the Saints had to suffer in a way
because nobody understood
See the bond has to be established nobody understood
So this Kundalini awakening
It's a residual power within us as you know we have three autonomous nervous system within us
One is left side Other is right side sympathetic and in the center we have parasympathetic nervous system
And whatever we have achieved in our evolutionary process as human being
Is Expressed by our central nervous system?
Alright
Like see if you want to take this dog to a dirty he can go we have
We have conception of beauty
We can see beauty we can understand colors he does not
So in evolutionary process whatever we have achieved is expressed in our central nervous system
Now it should be treated as hypothesis to begin with to see because you should not take it for granted at all
Now this Kundalini resides in the triangular bone
Which is called as sacrum
That means that the greek knew it's a sacred bone
It's a greek word sacred in greek word
is
at the base of the
spinal chord there is a bone triangular
is lies with that
And about that are six centers
below that is one center
below that is the center
Which we call as Mooladhar
Because Kundalini is the Mool means a root
because is the support of root. Mooladhar
Now in the medical terminology and understand
that
the center of looks after on the physical side
Our pelvic plexus
Which deals or which functions or all of our excretion including sex
now this is
to be understood very clearly that it is like below the Kundalini
So sex does not play any part in rising its a very important point
Okay, people have
perverted the whole thing. I don't know all kinds of things that they have done
and they said that to the sex energy which has to increase
There's nothing like sex energy It's like any other energy
But only thing with that
this Energy is
used for a particular purpose of excretion or
communication
Of your desires or whatever it is, but it had nothing to do either ascending ascent of the Kundalini nothing to do
on the contrary
when the Kundalini awakened
this center absolutely stops
no excretion of any
You will be surprised sometimes I have program for 10 hours
11 hours I won't go to bathroom
It just stops
That's why Christ have said you have to become a children to enter it to the Kingdom because this is the innocence
Now this going little further
is that
on the center
is placed
the deity of Shri Ganesha
it has great meaning
What is Shri Ganesha how this is placed there all that suff we will learn
but I told this scientist in America
that this center is made of carbon atom
Carbon atom has got four leaves?
if you see
this center
has a carbon atom
you make the model out of carbon atom
Then you watch if you see this one, how many are you trained?
the
Scientist is here
So if you see it from right side on the left side what you see of that atom is Swastika
clearly
see
just show them they are journalist
[UNCLEAR]
So you see from left side the right side you see Swastika
Then you should go see them see from the left side to the right side you see Omkara
If you see from down upward then you see alpha and omega
Alpha and Omega
see now this I stated in one of my lectures these people immediately jumped on to it
They took a atom of carbon took the model made it how about the scientists cleaner now?
He's made this out of that beautifully made, but first they made huge myth?
and what Christ has said I am the alpha and omega
In these symbols alpha Omega which we use in our mathematics are ancient
so Christ is
incarnation of
the Ganesha.. it a scientific proof
[UNCLEAR]
So Ganesha is an eternal child
That's why he has got trunk of elephant
Innocence is our innocence
so when the Kundalini rises
And she's awaken, she can be awaken
somehow I
Must say that
this Modern Sahaja yoga
Only thing if I discovered anything is this that?
amass awakening of the Kundalini amass
thousands can get it
That's all I will serve nothing much
This is very ancient science they used to do to one person two person
now it can be done amass
in Russia
We always have program in a big stadium 16000 minimum people
Practically everybody is released Russians are the best. I don't know what Communism has turned
They are not at all idioit. They're not American style
very straight forward and very introspective
Think he'll be stupid choices that democracy side you'll see
in America even a lock has to be different tiles
has to be different
door of the
car is differently handle is different
I mean if you get into their bathroom everything has to be different the choices are so maddening
And there are all the time busy. What should we do something more to show that wear something different
whole energy wasted these people
He provided for all material things because that make them a little lethargically careless
but on the whole there were not bothered about politics they didn't have to worry who coming to Chief Minister nothing
so
see their attention was
introspective
And the whole thing are always be because if you see Dostoyevsky? or any one of the items
You have read Crime and punishment
You can see how introspective even the hero was
so wonderful knwoledge
These people that they even the hero introspect before falling in love why I'm falling in love
What is the thing but it's wonderful so these people are very introspective and so in Russia it has become extremely
Extremely successful, but all other your gurus and all of them
And they have a sense also, I think
what is truth and what is not
Moreover if anybody who asks for money
They don't like they understand you can't sell spirituality they don't like
how you can't sell spirituality
Not in India even we don't understand this of course American's understand this
The more you charge the better it is
They would say like this is a these gurus are very good they have sale
It's all shopping its marketting
But they understood and we have now
200 doctors in Russia practising Sahaja yoga
and the scientists
300 of them invited
And when I talk about science, they said no more science we had enough we have reached the last end of it
We don't want anything of you you tell us about gods law
Divine laws please don't talk about science
They also he come like this is somebody here, but was working really well
So what happens when the Kundalini awakens?
it passes through
Six centers as I told you the first is establish is innocence. That's the support
Then it rises through six centers
now on the physical side we suffer because our centers are out of real
extreme living
So Kundalini what she does, these are the centers so the left and right sympathetic
they combine and form a center like this in the spinal chord
spinal chord
and what happens if you start thinking too much on right side because you are very futuristic planning time
Journalist use later like that and so we start would be more towards the right
All right those are very emotional type they go towards left
Sometimes something can happen they just break and things like cancer [UNCLEAR] what you got?
Psychosomatic diseases can be caused this kind of imbalance left
not that even if you are on the right or on the left if you go too far you might get those
Psychosomatic which are supposed to be incurable
Now this Kundalini what she does is she goes here and passes through here
just like we put the beats into threads
Into what you call threads in that it goes on threading all over
So she integrates our center
Let's see
Normally if you want to do something
You decide to do something, but really your intelligence will say no. Oh, maybe you're attention may not be there
and then you become an integrated personality
Whatever you do
With your heart with your brain
Complete integration. There's no problem
First is that but what is the outward manifestation is that
once she crosses over first dilatation of the pupils takes place isn't it kind of a
in
little shine in the eyes comes
And then it pierces through here, which is that fontanel bone area which in our language we call it Talu?
In Sanskrit its Talu
this thing suddenly opens out and it comes out and
That energy becomes one with the subtle energies all pervading power
So now first we have to accept one is that first truth is
That there is all-pervading power which does all the living work
We never questioned who does living work. How do we grow how does the seed becomes a tree we never questioned
accept it look at our eyes what a camera
Look at our brain what a computer?We never bother question from where do we get this is done by this all-pervading divine
second truth is
That you are not this body mind intellect  you're not because it's my intellect
You say my heart my body
What is yourself?
is the Spirit
So you are the Spirit the rest is my this my that. My mother my sister my house my body my eyes
So who is this my  - who is this I obviously saw through in this Spirit so this spirit
you have to become
So far your attention is on the body your attention is on your eyes and everything
then what happens as
if you watch a house from outside
the beginning and
Then they will go inside after inside you watch
So the whole awareness becomes very different
this we call Turiya in Sanskrit we call it as a Fourth dimension. We live in Three dimension. This is the fourth dimension we get
the fourth Dimension, what do we get in that dimension is?
firstly
you stand in your present
Now for Example you can think of the future or the past but in the present I say now be in the present you can't
So what happens you become thoughtlessly aware you're aware, but absolutely no thought
because thoughts come to
you
from the past
or from the future
In between these thoughts there is a little space
so when this Kundalini rises she
Makes that space, and that's the space is the present [UNCLEAR]
And spiritual life you grow only in the present because that's truth
You see the past is finished the future doesn't exist
But in the present in the reality now is sitting me to be if the reality just number is it you don't know what will
Happen in the future, or what her past finished
So first in your dimension you become thoughtlessly aware
but the second thing that happens to very wonderful
That you start feeling
This all-pervading power on your fingertips
as very gently cool breeze on your finger tips
Adi sankaracharya has called Salilam Satyam even Christ has said cool breeze of the holy ghost
Kundalini is the reflection
of
Adi Shakti or holy ghost in human beings
as a result of that you're all these
sympathetically system
You have an ending to the sympathetic nervous system the Left-hand side seven five
six and seven
five six and seven
So the left side is emotional side right side is your physical and mental side
we will give you the books so it is easy for you know then you can start feeling
Not only is power, but he start feeling others
Americans they called it Vibes  they don't know what they mean by Vibes very good vibes actually vibes
Mr.. Charlie said mother you get all these things listed or something as for. He said, they're writing down all your thing that
is very good idea nothing wrong
Awakening has to be done now first of all the main thing
That has to be done if you just take my words and write it down. What is that?
I don't want to become the monopoly of that. It's very good [UNCLEAR]
The result of that okay now
feel the centers of
yourself so it's the self-knowledge and
You can feel
Center of others
on your finger tips
Can feel what's wrong with you? What's wrong with you. You don't have to tell anything you just know that this is wrong
now
somehow if I know
how to correct this centers you can be cured
But all this is is mental physical emotion all of them are due to this
And also spiritual problems, but if you put wrong gurus this that you get spiritual problems
False people
So a new dimension in your awareness comes
called as collective consciousness collective
Samuhik chetana
So now who is other
I Can feel you I can feel them and every eight so with them you become part and parcel of the whole
and then another great thing at the side
all your fingertips you can feel absolute truth
absolute truth which cannot be challenged
Absolute
Say you have ten children
they are realised soul and tie up their eyes
Ask them. What's the matter of this lady
they raise one finder. you ask the lady have you got throat trouble?
Is how you know?
because this finger is not right
Everybody will say the same. I'm in a program
one man came why everybody's asking what is your relationship with your father? What is really?
Why we bother with my father I said its the center you are catching on your heart
That's what they ask
Everybody asking they feeling it
So everybody feels the same
And you want to know about anybody say about Christ. Was he a son of God? Just put your hands like this. suddenly it flows!
But somebody is a thieves. or false man you put your hands
just even if he's not in here you get burnings you get these little
Things and he gets all you might even get sometimes you blisters so you become enlighten now imagine how fantastic
This is outside and inside you can completely transformed
We have people were supposed to be
Like burning fire as far as the temper was concern they become now like himalayas suddenly
People have changed apart from the health we of course
We have definitely seen
So many people world of blood cancer as ordinary cancer heart cancer so many. I mean there's so many them
Rahul? - really when asked he had a massive heart attack
And he got cured with Sahaja yoga you won't believe he went to houston and doctor shouted him
So it is like that so many people have been cured
but it's far anybody's power which cures
It's your own this within you its your own power
as a result of that power
Which is actually is your own mother everybody has individual Kundalini own  mother and she gives you the new birth
She looks after you... so this Kundalini will not only cure your incurable disease so many have been cured that you won't believe that now we have doctor in every country practising Sahaja yoga.
Third one
Third & Fourth  both came from TM
Transmitting disease, but they developed
issues homesexual even after getting cured they went back to same habit. so they got it back
One fellow we still have who survived for 8 years for healthy is doing very well. He is in Australia
The trouble with that age differences is they have no will power
see what you call center hearth means they are so insecure so insecure
That you see after getting cure also you have keep to certain [matya?]
you have to be
But they don't then then indulge into homosexuality
or
Outside will show we are like martyr
inside they are very weak
So it happens like that
If they really want live they can if they really want to work it out they can
But with Sahaja yoga you can never get AIDS that's one thing guaranteed
Because all your priority changes
in Sahaja Yoga the doctors are now
really nobody goes to any doctor
He knows all these things, but the doctors are finished as far as sahaja yogi's are concerned
So at the most they might get some cold or something at most
But they are so healthy
They are so energetic that
You can't imagine how a person could be like that
[UNCLEAR]
she get too much cold and rash and all those what you call allergy and and all
Now is such a dynamic felow today he will be in Germany tomorrow in Japan he is so
So healthy and so happy and so relaxed
become absolutely a relaxed person
It's balanced balanced very much and above all compassion very compassionate. Now all these Sahaja yogis
they are swimming in ocean of Joy but what their headache is that mother why not have more people remain in ocean of Joy. I'm all the time travelling I went to south America I'm 70 years I'm travelling all over
all the time but what I'm going to do If people want to come I have to do this but if but people want to come I will have to but people they don't want to come what can I do? so this is trouble they so anxious more to come and they are running up and down all over the world they are running here to there. they are trying to find more people. Even in Maharastra we goto villages bringing people. so it a country wide propagation.
But you see actually got detached about it that you don't worry about your health
you don't worry about your age  you don't even think of it
you feel very Young and all the time the active over this just don't feel for it
There is no group like young, old. We all enjoyed together. Whatever maybe there is a small boy
adult that doesn't exist. also that doesn't exist in religion as far as the outside religion nothing, for example we worship Rama
We worship Shri Krishna
Also, be worship Mohammad Saheb because he was Dattatreya. They don't know but we know
He was Dattatreya
And Fathima we worship because she came as Sita latter on, so we worship we know that
It's not just
Sarva Dharma Sambhav
Even Gandhiji was not like this the way these people work. Gandhiji in his prayers
I was with him from my child actually I helped him in writing his
Sequels of [UNCLEAR] all about Kundalini we wrote. He was a realised soul
But we were fighting for freedom that time and he said without freedom what is the use of Spirituality
so Gandhiji
if he was living today he would have definitely helped me a lot. Even Lal bahadur shastri was a realised soul
we are very unfortunate. we lost them
Gurbachan?
Gurbachan is realised soul? yes, he was a realised soul.
But his wife you know you see?!. He is very high level person. Very good person. He has done his job.No doubt.
so now this, I was tell you about
Mohammed?
Gandhiji?
he was a realized soul, no doubt! and he
He was the one who believed in Sarva Dharma Sambhav
In his Sarva Dharma Sambhav
He made everyone worship
everyone
like Muslim
Maybe a congress man or anybody used to come to Ashram
He had to say the Mantras of Shri Ganesha
He have to take a Mantras of Vishnu
Saraswathi
You see it starts with the first of all
whatever in my my heart [UNCLEAR] resides the Spirit
See with the Spirit then he starts with Ganesh and every deity then he goes to the
Quran and you have to say the quranic and then you have to say also this
from the another
Farsi
Yes
all that matters
So you have to worship to all of them
He followed [UNCLEAR] said see if you just say Sambav means you don't worship why don't you worship?
Everybody should worship to follow them because they are different
They are not politicians or anything
They are not religious Christ has said those who are not against us, are with us.
Even Mohammed saheb said also there have been 1 lac of Nabis
He respected Christ mother more than all Deity
Christ father
He says she's a holy woman
but Paul is the one who ruined Christianity
so much, we said
Human beings are very good ruining everything sublime or somehow or other they manage it.
if you see through a essence of christ
As I told you now, alpha and omega, Christ resides in our Agnya chakra
on the six center. Christ very important
yeah, on the optic chiasm.
There is on one side is the pituitary and the another side is
the
pineal body
pituitary looks after our Ego
of the whole of up down working
And the pineal body towards our conditionings
In Chinese its Yin, Yang
So one is Ego and another is Super ego
psychological terminology
So one is the ego and another is the conditioning so these two balloons go up like this gradually
so when they cover us we are cut off
as children Beyond one, but we don't feel but we are one, but when the Kundalini connect us
then only you can feel it. Now you see for example this instrument or whatever you have to put it to the mains otherwise it doesn't work
So you can call this as Kundalini
Which is in a coil?
And some other threads come up open Sahastrara and conects
It's subtle very subtle
How do we live?
we live in three Dimensions
like I
Am here, and I'm looking at the mirror
So I'm the one who is observing my reflection is what I'm observing
There is a action of observance, so there is the observer
observed and also the observance, which is the Kriya
activity that we live in this three
But supposing you become the mirror
suppose
Then all these things drop out
This is what is called witness state where you just watch,
the whole thing is Drama
But when we are not realised we get lost in the drama
[HINDI]
so we become
Ourselves means we know ourselves
we don't have to take the mirror, we know ourself
to know yourself is the only point
And this is our heritage
this is the import point we Indian must understand. when they come you know they come and touch our mother land and say Namaskar
Some of them kiss these foreigners
the respect! Because they know what it is. I send them to Devagudu Thukaram place
and
other Sahaja yogis told me that mother they are rolling on the ground
so I said what were you doing, they said mother all over mother earth this vibrations coming out. so we are rolling on-it.
[HINDI]
overnight people have given up drug, drug addicts
Alcoholics
overnight
[HINDI]
but if overnight a
They have really become righteous they really become religious
[HINDI]
Because once you get the light, you know what it is that?
if you have snake in the hand if you are in the darkness you can't see, you can say its just a rope
once you get the light, you just leave it, because you know its a snake
that's what happens to them
[HINDI]
they become strong
they give up aggressiveness. they are not aggressive. In their silence they become powerful
My husband always used to say that [HINDI]
But you cannot make anybody?
Now he says so many angels now he has to accept
I had to work out our years together
What is the problem why we cannot have a amass realisation the time has come then I worked it out
In our country especially the young generation has no destination
They don't know what to do with themselves
[HINDI]
if they take to Sahaja Yoga now see in our Sahaja yoga
Yuva sakthi
nobody than it worked
all boys get first class first
All
wherever they are educated
all girls get married now we also have marriage system
84 Marriage, 13 Indian from Pune. They are all abroad.
So many boys got marriage and in abroad.
Mataji, you take personal interest in the marriage alliances?
[HINDI]
Mean I'm just saying there hello
I'm just telling them how you people are married to Indian boys and how Indian girls are married
[HINDI]
And how you are enjoying your life, it's good. She coaches together
[INAUDIBLE]
[HINDI]
A dog doesn't think [UNCLEAR] only human beings think. We think we are doing it.
The whole ego and the Super-ego both of them are sucked
And all your karma's are finished
One goes Beyond the influence of planets. Yes
of course
Human destiny go after not after realisation, do you they affect? In the beginning may be
before not after
[HINDI]
Nothing. [HINDI]
All right
That's what dance
[HINDI]
Lot of beauty within yourself lot of glory. All knowledge
See actually
our experience in ourselves
Something that is small
We don't think what we are seeing
for example if you take television in our remove villages and show them and tell them this is very fantastic television.
You put to mains, the whole glory comes up. Wonderful
self-confidence,[HINDI]
[HINDI]
He decent evening and be stations evening corruption. We are professionally arranges
They that we are in urgent need of the worst of it since I'm in Trinity
It will be restarting
Market is moving and I'm not interested in it. We have Peterson I
Know I didn't do anything
Whatever. I do this some sort of a
exposures mean forever it's forever
Mirage will be ordinary
Thomas hours
for a typical
So many other stinson where I purchased the house
Justin Smoak entire who's in Celsius a money market or up to be please come here?
For some who say that we never can imitate
A
time do
You advise the rent only thoughts picture. Yeah, we are hD
Yeah
Haha is a problem. Heavy relates to the earlier. What is responsible cousin Smith? No, it's every business
The but this is how should we deal with it?
Eating is I would say that what we had to first
for tomorrow's at least you should not go from becoming stances and
We are starting yeah
which
Give up easily. Yeah, you see
Any high anything?
for the children
Naseem attorney or how many for the children?
The money it's shameful. I mean you myself up a little bit
but very surprising Hp about 500 solutions
Multiplying the first in a lot of it. Yeah, really the
Facility in Personnel in Rangoon, How could he won the election below?
You know detail he lost his own
And his own daughter and my father thought I will not dead a friend of mine said
I mean your father is much better than my father. Why should I hit piper let's do?
It noble a children. Yes, you
But you can now be covered in this earth
Or he asked at meet country he has such a detail
Just in Sahaja Yoga established in any event beginning
after cancer Turkish Turkish identity ever given money architects
Have a positive, Limonada
What?
the doctors who Sahaja Yoga MVI
in Unison in Bihar used
Nine, I mean I see in actual data people peter put a million. I tell it oh shirley Bassey about me here
and I
Could hear another strip on there?
We are silky but remember Steve Emerick chill. He said this I wouldn t have to
surgery didn't along we're
not
Maybe do anyone
could I have also professional said even a
tiny mosh pit my sister : but the anti so-called class is going us their
Surplus
follow me
For me a my 17th birthday man away
Although socially stopped riding here
science and chemistry appealed
or not Rise O
mas que Viene una
Tocqueville said is established then he'd be amazed see house, and you guys you
scientific
It's all a medical term yeah get sooner experiments you can yeah
you know
about it
Why don't we give this one a bit equal money Sonya?
Now or even until it just start being much older than having achieved a final either
Very very something yeah
dispose of the crossover
although too Shallow, but if it
Tears up for a person to go together, it ought to
Sit down
Well Romanika offending anyone in such a brutal
attack in Baboon are
Deciding to have an idea
when after this horrible table our battalion in hunting
Moose calves are behind him are mine only you manipulate the point. I'm making here and many company Pacific advocacy
Come on. E what we preach and we'll break everything oh Maura be done with such in Charlie
overweight or Young got me 45 years of a
Higher probability yahoo, never beautiful. I think I think albeit under in each other, but any chinese relate
to and
Hope you lose give up on it, okay?
Am I applying foreigners some human weakness beautifully that in our view is
a beautiful
woman police spoke with
Me son, just a medium inside
Or up. We saw before right again you starting at the company Morale or McRaven son
You talk of a generation
due to another
But there they are disciples of Alicia
This isn't for me
And they want to teach business. It's already she she
Must be shopify which will be an economy then he eats Mogambo's completed Virginian
Or you started loving Target in
each one Americas
The whole world has refused to him again complaining that her
Son was a violent
Attack in Connecticut are married, but in camelina Maurice. I was in
I need only camera person can
See what I think it's a timing
certain seconds we want
to seven million your honor, I
said it hard to be I
Wearily starting with a bit more are coordinating
In pune yes, and I'm thinking of starting the scientific
papers with immunization
And they should understand because since you are in it. You should know this is your knowledge
all other college
We suffered after the leader who Steve is it?
Evil England
Nine Years back, and he was playing very organic
It's a little bit early boyd he wants to meet you. Yeah, never see
So agreed the state subset of upon man even as soon as she saw me
the dough
Immediately start she started
And he failed baba. I haven't thanked my Morocco
But my divine her the one coming after me rehearsal in a medical Battalion of Nafta
And he brought his future at for rewrites the Partisan song Yeah, I
Think you have seafood, wannabe, China
They disappeared unity
so many become happy artists musicians or
Merely a Kiowa Hawaii
Even got the cutter well list of them only do we have not recorded them. We have no restock people
as one the first email
I
Will since we have many mistakes us inside reminding me about Muslims in Australia about Muslim?
Mia, but also some muslims in
India right around lydia millimetres posture
and reimbursable schemes in
France
Austria
Austria we have posture it up. Well. I mean
We have also a school for them of this foreigners. Don't want their children meat eater
You want inaudible couple of jokes exhibition?
so
It's a very streamlined through lately so Canada
Such you want to make them very peterson
since half of a teaspoon shallower and help see
It is a looking for the children on their backs on
Those worried children what he writes?
And also the other sasuke Bacteria like so soon
But you find out they realized
Come on
Technically they look terrible in excel
Clearly our eyes. Are you in command usually they were just an ordinary list
but what ceo here he can be able to open them there and then
Maybe Otellini
but once
They are born
You cannot force it on
See you have to ask her yes, really for sure is he human but every idea
Okay, I'll probably decide see if you have the pure desire. It was Kundalini is the power of pure desire
party some desire, sorry pure
Because economics make agatha in General
Once cannot be such they are not session in july
We are you changing to convert you after this?
sighs
Jessica no choir sang or all recess will come and the mother is awakened
the pregnant man
Whoo-Hoo Selita Jana get
500 me but I was meaning a mirror to in any year
But was raised under cleaning our cast you split who studied up a narrative
Audiences say here an animal is not equal to n. Alpha
this astrology, maybe a
Generator both astrology, Jessica pain or a histology system with each other who save incarnation see
business over some of the unspoken also some
Of Japan's have them breathable
otherwise
That he daughters and full pension
She movements and with rebirth a cycle of rebirth of course
There is no
You can operate but our concern here
or myself
She'll show you easy civet
It is here. How a true parameter
System since then ee rebirth cycle of people going to boost him up you see become free
And you have any time take over if you want?
Now you have a feeling but you mean because you would like to say the word
He said to that depending up to
Go to town you say actually needed a friend search is not a stenographer Mattia
After Caliban if there is some problem
optional
What's the matter so he means enough?
She's some matter who?
This is happening in Korean beings on a hotel mania
arrival in our own liberated
of anomalous remain secure for but I mean Ii do
Sth
Our child but a movie illegal, but after Chinese
To save me hardy has a deep emotion emotion
emotion
But it has to blow
because we go to that stage where
You become out riskier there because I believe that I just come up. Do you know you start bring everything?
never feel very
first
automatic
Mike Arizona anybody sending crab lifestyle on our language today as time sit here in the chair and never
Think you're traveling. You're early who will not have