I bow to all the Sahaja Yogis, and all the
seekers of truth, may God bless you all. Is
such a great thing to be back home with all
of you and to see you here blooming with joy
and happiness. That's the fate of a Mother
who has so many children, that she goes from
places to places leaving some children behind
but looking forward to meeting others. Somehow
that compensates for the separation.
Today I think we should start on a very subtler
ideas about Sahaja Yoga, because you people
have understood it on the other plane of mechanism
that works it out, the Kundalini, the chakras
and all those things. But we have to see what
is the problem that faces actually human beings
and why we make such mistakes in our seeking.
Is a very important thing to understand, because
unless and until we understand why we really
make mistakes or others make mistakes we can
never forgive them, and we might have a kind
of a high handed attitude towards others who
are now coming to Sahaja Yoga, thinking that,
why did they do like that, and why did they
commit this mistake and they could have done
better. But I personally think that if you
look at yourself you will know that you also
committed mistakes. Everybody has committed
mistakes. Some have committed more mistakes,
and some have committed less. But what is
the reason why human being has been committing
mistake? That's what we should look into it.
The first and foremost thing is without getting
-
(Shri Mataji speaks aside: Come along here
you can sit there is a lot of space here,
come along. Move out, move out you can sit
in the center, come along, come along, come
along not to feel shy there's lot of space
in here. I think you'll have to have a bigger
hall now Matha? Yes come along, come there's
room here you can sit down here, come along.
So sweet of you. Thank you very much, so very
kind of you thank you, thank you. Please make
yourself comfortable come along. So how are
you? Congratulations and God Bless. Are you
all right there all of you?)
Now those who have got Realization and those
who have felt the cool breeze and have matured
in Sahaja Yoga know that automatically you
drop out many things, automatically. Now why
do we do it, you see, why do we drop things?
Even I don't ask you for it, you just drop
them, why? The reason is the light of the
Spirit within ourselves empowers us to see
that this is wrong. Like as we have got eyes,
once we have eyes we know whether we are going
to fall here, or we are going to slip, or
what's going to happen. In the same way, when
you get this vibratory awareness it is not
an awareness only of the fingers, is the awareness
of the whole being and you just drop out everything
that is against your Spirit. I don't have
to tell you. But without Self-Realization
what happens that reality is just a myth.
It's only a mental projection with which you
live. You project your mind and you think
this is reality. You can call anything as
reality. Any hallucination can be a reality,
any theory can be a reality, any absurd ideas
could be a reality. I mean all religions have
taken that form now, it's very sad. But all
religions, which came from truth and from
reality, are nothing but mental projections,
and they're very far away from reality. You
can only feel, understand and assimilate reality
if you are a self-realized person. Unless
and until this Self has expressed itself or
manifested within yourself, the light has
come into you, how are you to manage? Whatever
you try is a mental projection. Like many
people who came first, "Oh, we believe that
we are born again." All right, now how can
you challenge it, if you believe into something?
"I believe" is the one of the great sentences
we use. But what is that I that believes?
That's that ego. That's not your Self, because
you have not yet felt the Self. So to feel
the Self is the most important thing if you
have to know the reality. So you must excuse
all others who have not felt the Self, who
have their own mental projections. They might
look like fanatic; they might look like stupid
people. They may look like to be very high
handed or maybe you might think they are these
ego orientated pseudo-intellectuals and all
sorts of things. But all that is mythical
because that plane on which they move is mythical
itself. Whatever you know through your mental
projection is imagination itself.
But Spirit is the reality, and to know the
reality you have to be the Spirit. And once
the Spirit starts shining within you, you
just drop everything like hot brick. Like
I would say, as I've many times told you,
that in our human awareness we know what is
beauty is, we know what cleanliness is. For
a dog he doesn't understand cleanliness. If
you don't give him a bath he'll be quite happy,
actually to give him a bath is a problem.
But to a human being, you see, what is a sin
or what is wrong? Sin is nothing but whatever
is against the Spirit, is sin. Even fear is
a sin. Any such small little sins or the big
sins, all are nothing, but they are all against
the Spirit. But if you have not felt the Spirit
whatever you do will amount to something like
anti-Spirit, because you don't know what you
are doing. Now the prophets have tried their
level best to tell you that you must keep
your balance, you have to follow a certain
religion as they call it, or as we call it
dharma within yourself. But that to for what?
Why to have the balance within you? People
will always say, "What's wrong?" "What's wrong
if we are not in balance, what's there? What's
wrong in drinking?" I never said don't drink
before Realization. After Realization you
yourself drop out. But they say, "What's wrong,
why does he tell us like this? Why should
we listen to them?" Why the balance? The balance
is needed for the ascent. Unless and until
you have a balance how will you ascend? Imagine
an aeroplane without any balance. Say a wing
is missing, will it be able to take off from
the ground, cannot. So for the ascent it is
necessary to have the necessary balance. So
they said, "Keep in the balance."
But even when we're just told simple thing
to keep to the central path, to lead a life
of balancing yourself or moderation in your
life, in that also the moderation part of
it they have made it an extreme. Everything
has been made into an extreme, because religion
also they want to follow through their mental
conception. That's why you find all these
religions is a mess. But I would not blame
them for that because they had no other instrument
to go ahead, and they wanted to go ahead.
They had no other way to proceed further so
they used only one engine they had was this
mental projection. And they made all these
various projections and that's how they are
so diversified and separated from each other.
But as soon as your Spirit shines, then, everything
drops out by itself because it is beyond mind.
Spirit is beyond mind, I don't have to tell
you anything that you must have balance, you
develop a balance. If you don't have a balance
you'll just get vibrations in one hand, other
hand will be just cold or will be hot, so
you start giving your balance. But I don't
say that give a balance means following a
particular religion or anything because if
I say that half of you may run away. The beauty
of Self-Realization lies in secretly working
out within you, everything that is virtuous,
that is beautiful, that is joyful, secretly,
it doesn't tell you. For example now supposing
somebody has an imbalance on the right hand
side. Very intellectual fellow, and thinking
for the future and futuristic man you see,
forgetting all his past. Even there are people
I've known they have forgotten their names,
and the names of their wives. But they are
so futuristic. For such a person if you tell
them don't think about the future, he can't
do it because he's put his attention like
this. The whole ego portion has gone that
side and he's all looking forward to the future.
But if you put him somehow or other, in a
state where his Self-Realization takes place
then immediately he will say, "Mother, my
right hand is burning and there's nothing
in the left hand."
So you start talking on a very mundane way,
not in a very subtle manner like all the philosophers
talk. All right that means your right is not
getting proper vibrations, so you raise your
left to the right? Now for an intellectual
he can't understand, "What is this raising
left to the right. I have read Bhagavad-Gita,
I have read Bible, I've done Koran, I have
done this, nowhere written left to the right.
What do you mean by this kind of a nonsense,
you see that you have to put your hand just
left to the right and you get the balance?"
I cannot appeal to a mind which has been thinking
about God, religion, everything, all right.
So the secretive working of the Kundalini
is such, that She goes in that portion where
you need help. She works it out and She raises
you and gradually She transforms you.
But if it is not awakened, if it has not yet
touched the Sahasrara, means if it has not
touched the feet of your Spirit, it may not
be interested, it may not be interested. So
the first and foremost thing is to raise the
Kundalini, and to let Her at least once know
that She has touched the Spirit. Then She
has interest, otherwise She hasn't got any
interest. That's why you must have seen some
people who come to Sahaja Yoga and just drop
out. The reason is the Kundalini Itself is
not interested. So the foremost duty of every
Sahaja Yogi is, first of all, not to be angry
or annoyed with people who have done lots
of wrong. But be very kind to them and gentle
because they are just seekers of truth. How
can you be angry with them? Already we have
lost so many of them because of their stupidity.
But we must try to salvage as many as possible.
And then the second duty of every Sahaja Yogi
is to slowly steadily to convince the person
that he should become the Spirit. Of course
you'll meet so many who will be self-appointed
people they'll say, "Oh, I've already met
the Spirit, I am the Spirit. I'm Christ."
They can say anything, so soothe them down
a little, bring them down and raise their
Kundalini, but don't leave it half way, must
touch the Sahasrara. I have seen some of the
Sahaja Yogis, even in India I've seen, they
just give up. They'll sit down, "Oh Mother
forget it, we don't want to do it, it's like
a mountain we can't raise it." But we have
to work, that's what we have to do is to work
it out. Raise the Kundalini, pierce through
the Sahasrara, and then Kundalini will work
it out.
It was a question asked to Me, "Mother that
we gave Realization to so many people, out
of that only about thirty percent people are
coming up the rest are lost." The reason is
you have left it half done. So this is one
of the reasons why we have lost some people
and there is no connection still established.
Now those people who come to Sahaja Yoga you
have to really work hard on them. Instead
of arguing with them, because what will you
argue is all mental projection. On what point
are you going to argue with them because that
is not going to give them the light of the
Spirit. So somehow or other work it out in
such a way that they feel light of the Spirit,
then talk. But we think that if we talk to
them it will help. It's not question of conviction,
is the question of happening, is question
of becoming, which is important. Unless and
until they become, what is the use of argument,
there's no law court here. There is no debate
going on, there is no election. There's nothing
of the kind, it is something that has to happen
to all those people that they should get their
light of their Spirit. And once they get it,
then it is very much easier for you to talk
to them and tell them about it.
The
philosophy of Sahaja Yoga is extremely simple.
Is the simplest of all philosophy you can
think of. Is a very simple philosophy, is
that, once you get your Realization you start
feeling for the first time, the All Pervading
Power and forget everything else. Once you
get that feeling of the All Pervading Power
only you have know how to maneuver it, how
to work it out and how to use it for your
own growth. It is made easy, it has to be
as it is the most vital force that has to
take place in the realm of spirituality.
Now thank God, many gurus are exposed. Thank
God many myths that were working out are being
now blasted. When I was telling you people
about the promiscuousness and all those things,
that this will never lead you to God but to
hell, I remember when people criticized Me
to be Victorian. I mean people have ideas,
which is a very Victorian ideas, and also
saying that Mother is very matronly and all
sorts of English language you see, that they
could use about Me. But now you see, what
have recently I've told, thank God there have
been a film showing the diseases we get by
promiscuous life. The right sane attitude
towards life definitely helps you very much.
But thank God, the grace of God is so great
that once you get Realization you become such
a different person that everything drops out.
You are really a transformed personality and
so that one should know whatever was the past
is finished now, is no more there. The egg
is finished, is the bird. And whom to blame,
whom to talk about is the bird there, now
let the bird find its own wings and fly. Once
you understand this simple thing of Sahaja
Yoga is that we have to make every one feel
the All Pervading Power of God, to begin with.
Unless and until they have felt it we have
not to accept them as realized souls. They
have to feel it.
Now of course as you know if the Vishuddhi
chakra is not all right they may not feel
it in the hands. But still no use if you tell
them that according to us you are a realized
soul but according to you, you are not feeling.
You see because the mind is working. Instead
of feeling a little disturbed about it, upset
about it, they may just think that, you see,
it's just a make believe or a psychological
stuff and I didn't feel it, I'm a person of
great will power, that attitude, yes, many
feel like that. So they can be lost. For now
as our Sahaja Yoga is increasing everywhere
in the world, we have so many good Sahaja
Yogis in England now. They are sensible people
and uniquely placed in this great country.
And they have to understand that wisdom is
higher than intellect, and discretion is higher
than debating. Take a very kindly and a compassionate
attitude towards the rest of the people, and
then work it out that they should somehow
or other, feel this subtle force of God's
love. Then gradually try to bring them round
and teach them what you've got. Is easy to
blame their ego, it's very easy, to say, "Oh,
they're ego orientated, throw them away,"
very easy to say that. But that's not their
mistake. That's not their doing. It was because
they never felt the Spirit before. Whatever
they have they have used that instrument whether
ego or super ego and they have built up their
own self, in that kind of a fort. But this
barrier can be broken very easily as soon
as they get their Realization.
I found the same thing in Australia. When
I went there so many came back, so many. And
now we have everywhere quite a lot of people.
In every ashram now we have coming at least
thousand to two thousand people. We have five
centers now and it's working out very well.
Same thing is in England, we can work it out.
But I told them the same thing that reality
is a different thing, and a mental projection
is a different thing. You still do not talk
on that level to these people. Because you
just increase their mental projection and
their barriers within them and this has helped
them a lot. And you'll be amazed that those
people who were lost have come back to Sahaja
Yoga and are growing very fast within themselves.
Now for the new people I have to tell, you
have to have patience with yourself. You have
to have patience. As I have patience for you,
I have love for you, I am here only because
of you. You also must have patience for yourself
and full confidence in yourself that you'll
become the Spirit. If you have these two things,
I'm sure it will work out. It is going to
work out. Once you get your Realization you
have to work out on other people, and gradually
you will be amazed that it will grow, and
it will convince you, and you will know that
you have become the realized soul. But the
realized souls are very simple people. If
they say, "I am a realized soul," nobody can
believe them because there are no horns around
them. No gurudom around them, nothing of the
kind, they're extremely simple people. So
what is going to help you is a simple attitude
toward yourself and toward these Sahaja Yogis,
and towards Sahaja Yoga that you have come
here to become the Spirit. We have to gain
nothing from you. There's no clientele as
such, there's no money proposition, nothing.
It is you who have come to the Ganges, to
take the holy water, it is you who has to
take it. We are here to help you. If that
attitude is developed I'm sure, with your
co-operation, we can change the face of this
world. And as William Blake has said in this
Hampstead, "We have to build up Jerusalem
here."
May God Bless you all.
Any questions you have you ask?
(Shri Mataji speaks aside: This is not a loud
speaker. I think I better present you with
a loud speaker. What happened, you presented
one to India why don't you get one. Further
conversation about the speaker)
Any questions to request Me?
Seeker asks a question: - How can one who
is new this subject distinguish between what
is psychic phenomena and what is actually
the manifestation of the Spirit itself? [Seeker
gives a long introduction to this question
which is unclear.]
Shri Mataji: is good idea. May God bless you.
You see when they say they have felt the cool
breeze the psychic people they are telling
lies, simple as that. Because the cool breeze
of the Holy Ghost, that you feel, has not
only the cool breeze it has its own powers.
For example, now I say there is a flame here,
all right. Now if there is a blind man also
if he puts his finger round there he will
know it's a flame isn't it, because he can
feel the heat. In the same way this cool breeze
is just to feel this cool breeze but is a
dynamic stuff. You can, when you get this
cool breeze established within yourself, you'll
be amazed that under your hand the Kundalini
will pulsate, it will rise, and you will feel
the cool breeze of another person. With this
cool breeze you can cure diseases like cancer
and many other. With this cool breeze you
can give balances to people. Everything you
can do with this cool breeze, is tremendous.
If you have any, say question, any question,
supposing you are a realized soul, you want
to know about a guru if he is real or not.
If it's a psychic thing you won't get anything.
You won't know why psychic people are all
going to parapsychology, is all wrong, it's
a horrible stuff. This parapsychology is one
of the worst things that can happen to a human
being, but they don't know what it is. There's
nothing absolute about it. But the cool breeze
is the one that gives you complete absolute
idea. Like you want to know is there God?
Ask a simple question like that, "Mother is
there God?" You'll get a cool breeze. Now
it's so, discrimination is so great and so
precise that supposing you want to know about
a guru how he is, supposing he's a devil then
you might get even blisters on your hand.
You might even get tremendous heat in your
hand and vibrations will stop completely.
But supposing he's half way then you may not
get such bad effects but there won't be any
breeze at all.
But supposing he's a realized soul, for William
Blake for example, I don't have to ask I know,
but unless and until you really feel that
cool breeze in your hand in a real way, also
it's coming out of your head then you should
not believe that you have got a Realization,
you should not believe into it. Now they are
many psychic cases I know who told Me, "We
have always felt the cool breeze," because
they cannot accept it, just say, and their
Kundalini just frozen there. Nothing of the
kind, I'm getting terrible heat and just praying
if this person goes away for a while will
be good rest for Me. And he says, "No, no
but I have felt the cool breeze." All the
time he's telling Me lies. "I have always
felt the cool breeze everywhere." But the
Kundalini is down below you can feel it yourself,
you can see for yourself. If the Kundalini
is not here how are you feeling the cool breeze?
You cannot. Is a phenomena as a result of
something it's not just a phenomena of the
cool breeze. But when the Kundalini rises
above the Sahasrara then only you can feel
the cool breeze. I've seen many people like
that. They don't want to accept, oh that I've
got all this.
But supposing there are people who are born
realized. There are people, some people who
feel the cool breeze. Now you have to differentiate
between them and the unreal people. There
can be some people who are born realized.
But nowadays we have decided not to tell them
that they are born realized because, those
who came to us we told them they're born realized,
their ego suddenly inflated like this. You
see absolutely gone cases and we lost them.
Because you see, if you are a born realized
it's nothing great, nothing great, because
so many are realized. Supposing you get Realization
today all right, so you'll be a realized soul,
but you're not a Sahaja Yogi. Sahaja Yogi
is a person who not only is a realized soul
but he knows all the technique of this pure
knowledge. He knows all the laws of the Divine
happening and also he knows how to handle
the Kundalini. Sahaja Yogi is a knowledgeable
person the one who knows all about it. Who
knows all the permutations and combinations,
who knows how to maneuver it and everything
about it. So he's you can say a boy who enters
into the first class. He just knows one plus
one is two. But say a professor of mathematics,
there's a big difference between the two.
So even if somebody's a born realized it's
better not to tell him that you are born realized
because he suddenly thinks he has become a
professor. Imagine a little boy thinking that
he's become a professor. It is very detrimental
to him as well as to others. So best thing
is to get the cool breeze in the right sense,
in the right way and understand that it works,
it must work. As you see how do you make out
a real note and an unreal note? The real note
it works. So it's not a myth it's a reality,
again I say it's a reality. Supposing this
is an artificial thing it won't work. Anything
that is artificial doesn't work, all right?
You go to this Madame Tussaud's place and
you'll find so many people sitting looking
exactly like us you see, but they are not
living, all right, you understand My point?
So you have to master it, know it fully. You
have to master it and understand it. You see
unless and until you understand it to that
extent, you cannot reach any conclusion, all
right, and we have to work it out. May God
Bless you.
Is not only thing that is cool breeze, where
is your Kundalini, whether it has risen or
not, if the cool breeze is coming out of the
head. Only a Sahaja Yogi can say, nobody can
say that. I've seen many people who get even
the cool breeze coming out of their head they
cannot feel it because their hands are not
sensitive. Only a Sahaja Yogi can say, is
true. But that doesn't mean that a Sahaja
Yogi is something out of the blue, is just
like you. Only thing is he has grown into
a new awareness, which you are going to grow
yourself.
(UNCLEAR- Mother speaks to seeker)
In Sahaja Yoga there are so many ways and
methods how we work out all the help from
all the elements, how we work it. For example,
this gentleman say for example, I find his
left side is overloaded. You can ask the Mother
Earth to take away the problem. Just put left
hand towards Me and right hand on the Mother
Earth, you can get cured, you will feel better.
Feeling better now? Just wait, have patience.
It will work.
Any other question?
You must see that the person is transformed.
They may say anything the person must be transformed.
He must become a saint. And the saint is not
a person who calls himself a saint, but a
saintly person is that one who drops out all
nonsensical things, automatically. Nothing
sticks to it. As they say, "The lotus leaf
you see, if you put water on the lotus leaf
the water drops out, nothing sticks to it."
I think in England at least seventy percent
or maybe say sixty percent people have been
drug addicts, Sahaja Yogis, you can't believe
they were. If not addicts they were something
like that. I used to call them drugists and
chemists, but they're different today.
Any other question please?
(Question- Is the artificial raising of the
Kundalini dangerous?)
Yes first. You see the trouble is, those who
have written about it have no authority. I
have said about it many a times. Like say
a villager comes to the city and puts his
hand in the plug you see, and gets a shock
and says electricity is very dangerous, all
right, is like that. But Kundalini is your
Mother. You have only one Mother and She has
only one son. It's your individual Mother.
You don't share it even with your brother
or sister. She's your Mother. She doesn't
trouble you at all. She's your the greatest
well wisher who's born again and again with
you waiting for this time, there's no question.
But those who are unauthorized harm the Kundalinis
of thousands of people. People have seen that.
Because you see that's My nature perhaps that
I can do it. But then people feel very hurt
you know they can't understand why should
Mother do it. I said, "You better do it. It's
good I should retire, I'm sixty years of age
is better for Me to retire, you should do
it." But if you are doing so many things,
you know I don't know how to drive, I don't
know many things that you do. I know one thing,
how to raise Kundalini. So if something is
difficult and is done easily means that person
is a master of that. And if that person is
a master doesn't matter there are masters
of everything, all right. So far I haven't
seen anybody suffering because of Kundalini
and should not. But it's not an easy thing
for many people because I met some saints
this time and they said, "It's only You who
can do it Mother we can't." There's a fellow
called Gaugan (Not sure of the name - SG)
Maharaja, a very old man and he lives in a
forest on top of a hill and he's come to Me
also. And he has many disciples and one of
them he told him to do this and do that you
see, the balancing part of it, and he did
all those things for fourteen years. And suddenly
in a program in Kolhapur he just came to see
Me, and got his Realization. He was shocked
that, "Fourteen years I've been doing all
this and I never got it and how is it in a
short time I got it?" So he went to see Gaugan
Maharaja so he told him about Me. He said,
"She's different." So that's how it is, and
I feel rather embarrassed to talk about it,
all right? May God Bless you.
(Question by seeker: -: How do you relate
Your experiences or what You are talking to
us about with traditional yogic practices?)
Very much so. Very much, it is the most traditional
thing, you see. Because the yogic practices
you do here is some sort of a, I don't know
what to call it, but it's like just a wee
bit of it you've have taken are doing that,
that's not yogic practice at all. You see
Patanjali Yoga, which was practiced thousands
of years back, when people led a different
type of life. When the children went to school
with the gurus, who was a realized soul. Nobody
who was not a realized soul was called a guru.
And the children had to lead a very celibate
life because according to your university,
you see, you're called as your gotras. And
you could not believe it today, say my gotra
is Shandilya. Shandilya was the muni of My
family. I can't marry a man from the same
gotra even today. Thousands of years have
passed since then, Shandilya lived about forty,
fifty thousand years back, but even today
I can't marry a man who belongs to
the same gotra. So the celibacy you can imagine,
that from one university you could not marry.
That's how they lived a life and then they
went, after five years of age, they went to
those schools, they lived there and they came
out of that in complete celibate living they
were. And then they got married and then when
they had children they sent them back, like
that the system was. But if you read Patanjali
Yoga the first thing that Patanjali Yoga said
that, "Ishwara Pranitana (MAYBE Prathistana
- SG)," means the establishment of God. First
you must establish the Spirit. It's like we
have not yet started the car for example,
all right, it's very logical. Now I'm coming
to Hampstead, I don't know the way, supposing,
and I don't know which way to go. Now supposing
I say that all right now I have to go to Hampstead,
from the very beginning I'll turn to the left
and not to the right, can I do it, no? So
when the Kundalini rises then only you will
know which chakra is catching what is your
problem.
Beforehand supposing you are doing any, at
random, any exercises. Say example, the way
people are doing these days yoga, so called,
it has nothing to do with yoga. You see these
exercises when you do, you are not aware as
to what are your problems. You don't know
what you are suffering from and what particular
asana is needed for a particular type of a
chakra, which is blocked, all right. So what
you're doing is indiscriminate, taking medicines
without understanding. But the practice of
these things are a very minimum part of the
whole of Patanjali. First is Ishwara Pranitana
(MAYBE Prathistana - SG) means when you establish
the Spirit. Ishwara Pranitana (MAYBE Prathistana
- SG) means the establishment of the God.
Once you have established that, then the Kundalini
starts moving and then you know where to stop,
where to turn, how to do. This is real tradition,
but the last fifty years, you see, all sorts
of nonsensical people have come up. They've
changed this, changed that and is logical,
is logical you see. Supposing you are suffering
from Agnya chakra all right, and you are doing
the exercise of this chakra you will spoil
this as well as spoil this. There's no logic,
there's no understanding, nothing. You see
this is just physical exercises because people
want to become actors and actresses I think.
(Seeker speaks to Mother. Mentions the eight
limbs of yoga the whole astanga going through
the nearma and the asanas, prameara, pratchara
to try to work toward samadhi)
All those things you see, no, no it does not,
it does not, it does not. That's the other
way round you see, this is the problem. You
see what happens that, unless and until you
get your Realization you have no entry into
yourself you don't know where you are going.
This will never work out. On the contrary,
all those who have done Hatha Yoga catch on
their heart center very much, because the
whole attention is on the body. Because the
attention is on the body the left heart catches.
Just now I have been to one organization where
I met three of them.
They all had their left side absolutely frozen,
so they said, "Mother what should we do?"
I said, "You must sing the praise of God.
Forget, you have become so dry like a bamboo
now, fill it up with the love of God." Forget
it all your asanas and everything, just like,
you see, dried fishes. There's no emotions
left. It's such an imbalance, ha and tha both
the things, they've not said only ha, ha is
the surya nadi they said ha and tha. What
are you doing about tha, nothing? So you are
doing ha yoga, all right. You have to do Hatha
Yoga but, without Ishwara Pranitana (MAYBE
Prathistana - SG), without Realization we
also do, not that we don't do, whatever is
needed that we do. For example, now when I
went there I told them what should be given
to a person who is suffering from mental diseases.
He said, "All this for mental diseases, also
all these for egoistical people, also all
these for liver patients, also all these for,
I mean it's horrible."
I said, "How can that be, on the contrary
to a mental patient if you make him bend forward
he'll suffer more, he must bend backwards.
A person who is ego oriented should bend forward."
They changed of course, I mean they're sensible
people as well as I'm concerned, they believe
in Me, they think in India of course I'm accepted
as some sort of a, something like that. But
you see these are little, little things they
don't know.
Supposing a person is ego oriented, right-sided
person as we call it. Right-sided person if
he tries to bend backwards he'll become even
worse. And a person who is a superego person,
suffering from mental troubles and all that
has to, not to bend forward at all, he has
to bend backwards. Because they're two types
of people, there are actually three types
as you know. The people who are, I mean, in
vulgar language we can call it masochist and
sadist but they are extreme cases, but I'm
saying that style. We call them tamo gunis
and rajo gunis. So the rajo gunis the sadists,
if they become more like this, God save the
world, see the point? And the emotions are
drained out of such people, there no feelings
left, no emotions, nothing, zero.
I met one dentist who came and he said, "Mother
now I have become a sthitapragya."
I said, "How?"
"I have no feelings. Nothing happens to me.
You see my child is sick I'm not bothered."
What a nice man you are. "I have no feelings.
My mother calls me I have no feelings. I am
living somewhere alone."
I said, "All right." I said, "Is that the
way the saints have lived? They have been
worried not only about their people but about
everyone." There's no love. There's no love
in the modern yoga, no love. Is only the love
of God, can be only felt through Spirit. You
have to have a balance. Is very one sided,
extremely one sided. One side is those who
are singing the devotional songs and the other
side are (inaudible). Both are equally mad
I tell you. Both can be equally mad. Come
to the balance, again you have to come to
the balance, otherwise you cannot enjoy Sahaja
Yoga. Sahaja Yoga is an enjoyment, enjoyment
of your balance, of the beauty of God's love,
and the truth of His work. Everything has
to be enjoyed, all right. You just work it
out.
Shri Mataji: Have you done yoga very much?
Seeker: Sorry?
Shri Mataji: Have you done lot of yoga?
Seeker: Reasonable. I do follow the Buddhist
practice which is based upon...
Shri Mataji: Now Buddhist also! Now I'll tell
you about Buddhism, all right? What are Buddhists
doing? Is true about everyone Christians,
Hindus, everybody. Just because you asked
about Buddhist I must tell you. Where is Buddha
placed within us do they know? Where is Buddha?
Buddha is placed within us at a point...
Seeker: Well, yes... Shri Mataji: And what
does He control within us? We have to know
this knowledge of the roots. Unless and until
you know the knowledge of the roots how will
you know about the tree? You cannot treat
the tree on its leaves or branches you have
to go to the roots. And first you find out
the roots within. Buddhism is so superficial
now, that I Myself amazed and Buddha must
be thinking, oh God from where it has come.
He says "Buddham, Sharanam, Gachami." What
is Buddha? Is an enlightened soul? Buddham
means the one who is enlightened. "Sangham
sharanam gachami" means to the collective
being. Sangham means the collective being.
"Dhamam sharanam gachami." Dhamam is the balance
within you. How many Buddhists know about
it? They don't know even where Buddha is sitting
on their heads. And what I find most of the
Buddhists that their center of Buddha is finished.
Buddha has disappeared from them once for
all.
He controls our ego, and he's settled down
here on the head on the left hand side. We
can prove it on Kundalini. Supposing somebody
is following Buddha immediately people will
know that you are a Buddhist because there's
a catch here. And then some methods are there
to awaken Him, if you awaken Him your Kundalini
will rise otherwise it won't, all right? So
you must know the knowledge of the roots.
We should not just depend on Budhhism or any
"ism." That's what I'm saying.
Seeker: Yes, it's just the thing You said
in the beginning, I mean I agree...
Shri Mataji: Yes, you see we have to have
the complete integrated knowledge of the roots,
which nourishes, isn't it?
Seeker ask the question:- Are you advocating
a system or a practice to get closer to these
roots?
Shri Mataji: No, no, no, no there is no system
about this. There is no system no practice,
no courses. Actually it is spontaneous. I'm
talking of your evolution. Your evolution
comes through a living force of the living
God. You cannot have a course in that, can
you have? How do you sprout a seed? You have
to just put it in the Mother Earth it sprouts
by itself, is built in. In the same way within
you it's built in and it sprouts, that's all.
There's no course. Maybe you may not get it
today you'll get it tomorrow, some seeds sprout
faster.
Seeker makes a comment: I see the Buddhist
tradition as growing out of a yogic insight.
No, no, no, you are sadly mistaken about Buddhism.
The trouble is with the western people they're
so fed up with Christianity that they think
Buddhism is going to solve the problem. They
are just like any other Christian church,
take it from Me. All these lamas should be
hanged by the nearest tree, I tell you. Horrible
people they are, horrible. You should see
their vibrations. You know this Dalai Lama
when they're sitting next to Me, I was invited
to the Prime Minister's place, I just couldn't
bear him. And the Prime Minister Lal Bahadur
Shastri himself was a realized soul and he
could feel it and he said, "Is he very hot?"
I said, "Yes."
Is in Hindi he said, "He's an extremely hot
fellow." He said, "All right, you get on the
other side," he made the foreign minister
sit here.
You won't understand, just now you don't understand.
Even a little child who is a realized soul
will understand, but you won't because you're
not yet realized, this is the point. The difference
is you are mentally understanding. I have
a grand daughter she was hardly five years
of age when My daughter and the son-in-law
went to Ladakh, it's an interesting story.
And there was a lama sitting you see like
this, and everybody was touching his feet.
This little child was a realized soul, she
couldn't bear it any more, when the father
went and touched his foot she just stood back
and she said, "What do you mean by shaving
your head and wearing this big stuff you think
you are a realized soul? Why are you making
everybody touch your feet?" Just she stood
up. And My son-in-law felt quite embarrassed
and he told that he's not even a realized
soul why do you touch his feet. You won't
understand, even a little child will understand,
you won't understand. Realized soul is a person
who can feel it.
This is what Buddha has said, that's the traditional
thing, he has said, "First of all seek yourself."
Buddha didn't talk about God. Why, because
he thought if you talk about God again another
religion will start. He just said first of
all, as I say, "First of all seek yourself,
get your Self-Realization. Nothing else but
get your Realization." All right that's it.
So better have it, better have it. You see
you have Buddhism there's nothing like "ism"
about Buddha these people are mental. To have
it means to get Realization. What tradition
are they following, carrying that ring like
this, like that, mad kip (sic) people, horrible.
Is that what Buddha did? He sought His Realization.
He didn't do all these nonsensical things
these lamas. And they even beat people and
do all kinds of things, horrible cruel people.
Thank God there out of that Lhasa. You should
see the Tibetans now they're sitting on our
heads like parasites in India and we had a
parliament question on them. You see they
look very attractive because you are fed up
with your Christianity, that's what. Don't
believe in all these please whether they're
Hindus, Christians or Muslim, all are just
the same. There's no difference. You become
the realized soul first of all. You have to
be the Buddha, all right, that's what I am
saying as a Mother.
And then they started another one Shambhala
business you see. This is another new thing.
Taking everybody to Gobi Desert to get samadhi.
Walk in that Gobi Desert even one mile you'll
get a samadhi permanently. [laughter] You
can't even get a glass of water there to drink,
My child. What things they are preaching,
you don't know, all nonsense. In Spain some
Spanish people have started this nonsense.
They are recruiting people to go to Gobi Desert.
I mean what is going to happen to them? Think
of the Gobi Desert, is one of the worst deserts
of the world. Can you imagine going to a desert,
how will you reach God? You have to seek Him
within yourself. He's within, all right?
Question from seeker:- Mother please tell
us about the dangers of mis-using mantras
by religious sects.
Shri Mataji: Mantras, all right, dangers of
mantras? You see mantra is a thing by which
you awaken the Deity within you. The Deity,
which is on this chakra. Now here the chakras
and we have deities. On these we have to awaken
the Deities. So, a person who is awakened
himself can only tell you what mantra to be
said, isn't it, a simple thing as that? The
one who has no eyes, what can he tell to another
blind person? So first an enlightened soul,
who knows about chakras can only tell you
what chakras are catching within you. But
the Kundalini should solve. Supposing you
are just now caught in your Nabhi chakra and
I tell you that you say the mantra. Not that
you, but the realized soul should say the
mantra and awaken that. Maybe the Kundalini
has gone there, so from there you have to
come here. You have to see the movement of
the Kundalini. Like a car is going now, very
simple, the car is going so we come to a toll
gate, all right. There we have to pay the
toll. But where the car is going, and then
there is a toll gate you pay there to a particular
toll gate, isn't it? Like when you are going
you see -
(Shri Mataji speaks aside: I've given up tea.
I have, just given up. Just take it. Sixty
years I thought I have drunk too much of tea.
But that doesn't mean you should give up.
[laughter])
So you see the thing is the movement of the
Kundalini will only tell you which chakra
is catching, all right, otherwise you will
not know. Unless until you move the car, before
that, how will you know where the car is going
to get the toll. Can you pay it before the
car starts?
So what happens, if they give you a mantra
mostly people don't know what they're doing.
You see it is a big enterprise. Giving mantras
is a very big enterprise. Like they have given
mantras, which I was amazed to hear, if you
tell some Indians, they'll be laughing at
you. What they say is a great secret, and
the mantras they gave was, one was I heard,
was "tinga" means like this you show to someone
you see this is "tinga", in Hindi language.
There is nothing like "ing" in Sanskrit Language.
Another mantra I heard was "inga". "Inga"
means the tail of the, the sting of a scorpion,
can you imagine that could be it. And then,
where is the director of the flying squad,
is he there? He's hiding there at the back.
Now what is the mantra for they gave you for
flying? What tubes? Who is there? Come along
where is he?
Yogi: "Bronchial tubes, Mother."
Shri Mataji: Bronchial tubes. Bronchial tubes,
bronchial tubes, they paid six thousand pounds
for getting that mantra for you. [laughter]
Just imagine this bronchial tube is one of
them. Then they'll give a mantra of Rama.
Take a more sensible thing, they might give
a mantra of Rama. But Rama where does He exist?
Supposing I want to give a mantra of Buddha,
for example. Where is Buddha? Are you catching
on Buddha or not, is the main point. Where
are you catching? Where is Rama? Rama resides
in what part? Is it necessary to give this
mantra or not? They don't know anything, no
knowledge of any kind just at random. At the
age of six years to twenty years give the
mantra what is it, "pinga" then another one
"tinga", another "ringa", according to the
age, not according to the Kundalin where it
is. Now what is the danger of that, that's
the main point is. That supposing they give
you a name of Rama, they are not awakened
people they are not connected with God, they
are not authorized. Now you go on saying Rama,
Rama, Rama, Rama, Rama, Rama, Rama, Rama like
that, you see. The other way round you say
mara, mara means I'm dead, I'm dead I'm dead.
So you go on saying a mantra Rama, Rama, Rama,
now what happens that you are not connected
with Rama at all, because you are not a realized
soul, neither the guru, the one who has taken
three thousand pounds for giving you this
Rama mantra, is a realized soul. So when you
are shouting like that Rama, Rama, Rama, who
will come to your help will be somebody dead
as Mr. Rama somewhere. He will come to your
help and he'll possess you. With that you
may start thinking because you get an added
personality and suddenly you feel you see
you get more powers so called.
Like Gauguin if you go on saying Gauguin,
Gauguin, Gauguin he might enter into you.
You might start painting something and after
that finished you have no energy left because
one horse is riding two men. But the worse
thing that happens to you by saying mantra
is that you develop a terrible dent in this
very important center called Vishuddhi, specially
the left Vishuddhi. And then they are frightened.
If you ask them, "What is your mantra?"
"Mother I won't tell you."
"Why?"
"No that is not to be told."
All secrets in God's vision, in God's realm
there should be no secret at all, everything
should be known, everybody should know what
is what. Why should there be any secrets,
I can't understand. For example everybody
will know those who are realized souls, where
you are catching, what is your chakra, they'll
tell you. Everybody will say the same. Like
one day one gentleman came he said, "Why are
they all coming and asking me 'How is your
father?'" I said, "Because your Rama's chakra
is catching." That's exactly the mantra you
will take. So your chakra is caught, that
is the one that the name they give you because
you're insulting the deity and this Vishuddhi
chakra, by which you say also is caught up,
and from there it goes as guilt to the left.
If you should try to correct a person it acts
as a guilt and he gets a problem on the left
hand side Vishuddhi which is a very, very
big problem.
Seeker: Japanese religious sect gives Buddhist
mantra called Nam-myoho-renge-kyo. )
Shri Mataji: Nam-myoho-renge-kyo, I know.
You see Nam-myoho-renge-kyo is a great thing,
but not by these Japanese people. Japanese
less said the better. I met the person called,
his name I have forgotten. He was the head
of the Zen system. Now see Zen is Sahaja Yoga.
To be realized is to be Zen. But this fellow
had a frozen Kundalini just like that there
just sitting settled down. So I told him,
"Sir with very humble understanding I would
like to say, that are you really a Zen?"
He said, "I'm teaching Zen, but I'm not."
I said, "Why?"
He said, "Altogether from the sixth century
till today, only up to the eight century we
had Prashapas [MAYBE Prashapas or Pashyapas
or Kashyapas - SG] means realized souls."
Only till the eighth century and after that
what followed was this kind of people who
had the Kundalini just settled down there.
But at least he was honest. And he was suffering
from a horrible disease for which he came
to Me. So I said, "At least you do not propagate
now Zen, because you are not a Zen."
You are a Christian, are you? Ask anyone who
is he. This artificial baptism is not Christianity.
Is the real baptism, raising of the Kundalini.
Is the Kundalini piercing through? Are you
a muslim? You are not because you are not
a pir, you are to be a realized soul first.
So imagine all these people who are teaching
all these things are not authorized at all.
But they'll come round, I'm sure.
Seeker asks a question: I was interested in
Your comment when You said Nam-myoho-renge-kyo
is fine but not any Japanese...
Shri Mataji: You see now I'll tell you. It
is very simple to understand, you understand
one point which you are missing all the time.
Is this that supposing there is a constable
standing there and he says, "Go this way,"
all right, we have to obey him otherwise you'll
end in jail he's authorized, isn't it? But
supposing I go and stand there and say, "Go
this way," they'll put Me in jail. They have
no authority from God to do it because they
are not realized souls. The same mantra becomes
a great mantra when it comes from an authorized
person from God. But the same mantra becomes
a sinful thing when it comes from a person
who is not authorized, who's just commercialized
it. [Seeker interrupts] Is it gone into your
head what I told you, that you are to be authorized
by God? That is you should be self-realized.
If you are not self-realized you have no right
to give any mantras or anything, do you follow
this point, simple point.
Seeker: Sure.
Shri Mataji: Now that's all. So you get your
Realization, that's important, which you should.
But I don't know how it works out, you see
that is not My guarantee. If it works out
well and good, may not work out today. So
better put attention to that, it's important.
May God Bless you.
Is there any other question now?
Put attention to that, that is important.
But one thing more, when you follow them you
never ask questions. I had one lady from a
lama she came down from Norway, she was horrid,
absolutely horrid. Her vibrations were, what
was her name Gavin?
Gavin: Pia
Shri Mataji: Pia. She came to My house I said,
"Baba! How to raise her Kundalini, baba, dreadful."
And she was thinking no end of herself and
arguing, arguing with Me throughout, and all
that. I said, "How did you happen," I mean
she has been to this lama. I said, "What happened?"
She said, "No, he wrote to us that I can't
live in an ordinary house you have to make
a marble floor. So first we all starved ourselves,
within one year we collected money made a
marble floor for the fellow. So he came and
was sitting on the seventh step and we were
first one year we had to just go and bow to
him just like this."
One thousand and one time can you imagine
everyday and "I've done that course." But
I said, "Didn't you argue with him?"
She said, "No."
Then I said, "Why are you arguing with Me?"
Of course I like that you argue because that
shows you are free to argue, I've not mesmerized
you, but must see the sense.
How do we accept Buddha, let's see. Have you
seen Buddha? Have you met him? Have you met
anybody who is a Buddhist who says he can
give Realization? But then why are we the
pleaders of Buddha whom we have never seen,
who has gone away, we don't know anything
about Him. Why? Because I am living He is
not. When He was living there were people
who were asking about other people. So better
be in the present and get it your Realization,
all right, that's what it is. That's what
happened with Buddha he couldn't give Realization
to anyone whatsoever. Sariputa, Mogallana,
all were wasted people. Same with Christ.
Because when Krishna came they said, "What
about Rama?" When Rama came they said, "What
about Dattatreya?" But where is Dattatreya
now? Rama is standing here why not get it
from Him. So everybody failed. They said,
"They are talking about the past only." What
about the present? You are sitting before
Me, I am sitting before you, have your Realization.
Why argue about it? If there's a diamond and
if I say you can have it free will you argue?
You understand diamond better than our Spirit.
Always we did that but this time better not
miss it. I'm telling you better have your
Realization, it's important. Of course Buddha
plays a very big role within us but first
get your Spirit otherwise it has no authority.
The knowledge of Buddha has no authority within
you unless and until you become the Buddha
yourself. All right, now let's have it. At
the end of it I would request you to have
your Realization.
Put your hands like this towards Me just like
this. Better now, relaxed, all right, nice.
Put your hands like this. It works, it works
that's the point is, it should work, isn't
it? Now close your eyes, please. Just close
your eyes, you have to keep your eyes shut
that's important because when the Kundalini
rises above the Agnya chakra if your eyes
are not closed it will fall down, so please
close your eyes. There's no mesmerism that's
why you have to close your eyes. Just keep
your eyes shut.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside: Take the baby out,
please.]
Just sit comfortably don't move, don't make
any gestures nothing, nothing outward. You
have to be inside, it will work out inside.
Nothing should work out outside. Just keep
quiet. Just put your hand towards Me. Whatever
has to work out will work out inside, not
outside. Don't open your eyes but don't fix
your attention anywhere, keep it loose, just
keep it loose, don't fix it at a point, please.
Don't try to fix it at - some people are fixing
it at the point what we call the Agnya chakra
or anything. At the most you can put your
attention on top of your head. But don't try
to fix it anywhere keep it loose, absolutely
loose. Now with your right hand, which is
the hand of your creativity or the action
power, you have to use the right hand to express
your action and the left hand is a desire.
So you have to put the left hand towards Me
for the desire but don't open your eyes, just
on the lap you can keep it comfortably as
it is and you have to just move your right
hand but keep the fingers straight. Straight
fingers toward Me and move the right hand
as I tell you.
No, on the lap left hand on the lap and the
right hand I'll tell you how to move it. Now
put the right hand, no left hand toward Me.
Sahaja Yogis should see left hand towards
Me now move the right hand. Left hand on your
lap comfortably, please put left hand on your
lap. Left hand on your lap, yes very comfortably.
Now the right hand you have to put it on your
heart. Heart where resides your Spirit. Now
in your heart you have to ask a question to
Me, "Mother am I the Spirit?" Just put it
on the right hand side. Those who are very
much on the left but actually it is on the
left hand side is the heart. You see those
who are putting it too much toward the left
should put it at the proper place of your
heart is on the left hand side. Now press
it with your fingers. And just ask a question,
"Mother am I the spirit?" Say it thrice, ask
a question with full confidence.
Now please put this right hand, don't open
your eyes, on your stomach on the left hand
side again. Lower part of the stomach and
push it and ask the question again to Me,
"Mother am I my own Master, am I my own Guru?"
Because you are, and this Spirit is your Guru.
But when you are asking Me a question, "Mother
am I the Spirit?" you have to ask the second
question, "Mother am I my own Guru, am I my
own Spirit?" Because the Spirit is the Guru,
which is awakened within you, when you get
your Realization. So you have to say, "Mother
am I my own Guru?" Say it ten times. Ask the
question ten times. The times are according
to the chakras.
Keep the left hand the same way and now put
again the right hand on the heart. And now
you assert with confidence that, "Mother I
am the Spirit," which you are. This you have
to do it twelve times, twelve times. Ten plus
two, twelve times you have to say, "Mother
I am the Spirit." With confidence, with full
confidence you should say, "Mother I am the
Spirit," full confidence.
Now take this right hand across to the left
side of your neck, left side of your neck.
Again was I said left Vishuddhi. Because the
Spirit is immaculate, absolute, it never does
any mistakes so there is no question of feeling
guilty. So you have to say sixteen times now
that, "Mother I am not guilty." Say it sixteen
times, again with full confidence, because
we're talking about God Almighty who is the
ocean of love, ocean of forgiveness, ocean
of compassion, sixteen times.
Now again raise the left hand without opening
your eyes, to your forehead. Across your forehead,
across your forehead, and hold your forehead
in your hand, right hand, left hand being
towards Me. At this point is the Agnya chakra
where you have to say that, "Mother I forgive
everyone." Now some of you might say that
I cannot forgive is a very common thing people
tell Me. But when you don't forgive what you
are doing is to play into the hands of people
who try to harm you. So you just say, "Mother
I forgive everyone." With full understanding,
without any reservation, "I forgive everyone."
Unless and until you forgive everyone how
can God forgive you? So let God forgive you
for your mistakes what you have done in your
ignorance but don't feel guilty about it.
Only you just say, "Mother I forgive everyone."
Now put this hand on top of your head, right
hand again where the soft bone was there when
you were a child. Press it with your palm
that portion and move it in a clockwise manner.
Press that palm and move it in a clockwise
manner. Now at this point I cannot cross your
freedom. It's your freedom, which I respect,
you have to say that you want ealization.
So, here you have to say, "Mother we want
our realization. Please give us the Realization,"
otherwise I cannot cross. So please say this
seven times.
Now you can raise your hand and see if there
is a cool breeze coming. Some people might
be getting the heat coming out of their heads.
Raise it higher to see if there is a cool
breeze coming out. So many of you are still
feeling guilty, is a wrong thing. I've told
you not to feel guilty. Just see if there
is a cool breeze coming out. Now you can take
another hand, left hand and see with your
left hand. You can change over and see if
there is a cool breeze coming out. Not very
much higher say about four inches higher.
You can change over another hand.
You just see if this gentleman has got it,
Ruth see his. You got it, you feeling in the
hand also, not in the hand. He's got in the
hand, you got it, it's very subtle.
It's a subtle thing. You are coming from a
gross level to a subtler place.
All right, you have to do that left to the
right.
Put your hands toward Me still, see the Sahaja
Yogis will help you now. Once you become Sahaja
Yogis you have to help others, all right.
They know about your chakras.
Is he all right? All right try to help Matha?
See this gentleman, no. Left to the right,
put him left to the right. Is he all right,
all right? Not yet in the hand.
You just watch Me without thinking. Can you
do it?
Got it, got it she said she's a Sahaja Yogini.
What about him? Got it, see there.
(Shri Mataji speaks to someone in Marathi)
See the new people please. No, no don't stop
yet put (inaudible.) Put it left to the right.
(Shri Mataji speaks to someone in Marathi)
Vishuddi , Nabhi (Shri Mataji speaks to someone
in Marathi).