You see, in Sahaja Yoga, you are not given
any mantra or anything.
There’s no, nothing like giving you into
a big course, like teaching you one after
another any mantra, or anything, it’s not
like that.
What you have to know: where the Kundalini
is, how it is moving, where it is, what is
the charka catching and what is the mantra
for that.
It doesn’t take anything, hardly it takes
about a week for you to understand the all
thing.
But gradually, as you start using it, you
become proficient and you how to do it for
yourself and for others.
There is not much of a thing- like a child,
when he comes up a little age, he starts speaking
up language, because he has a built-in capacity
to create sounds.
And he does it.
In the same way, once you get it, when you
get the cool breeze in you hand, you learn
it by using it, you understand it yourself,
you become yourself quite proficient.
And you will be amazed how fast you learn
this.
You don’t have to learn it just like a science
book or anything, you just start learning,
you can: this is charka which is catching
because now, say, for example, this charka
is catching [fore finger], right side.
Now, there’s a mantra for this is of Shri
Krishna.
Say, this charka is catching [forehead], here,
then there’s a mantra of Jesus Christ.
Like that, you must know the mantras and the
charkas.
But the charkas you just know as a, absolutely,
a knowledge which is built-in your nerves:
you just feel it.
This is- now this gentleman is saying: ” it’s
hot here” [left palm].
Alright, what is that?
Hot here means what?
That’s the Sahasrara, at the left side.
First it was, the Sahasrara on the right side.
Now, on the left side it’s there.
So that means there’s a mantra for that,
and that one must be used.
If you use that mantra, this will be cleared
out.
Alright?
That is how you have to know.
And that’s why I said it takes time for
people sometimes to establish, because first
you have to know it and then use it.
Shri Mataji: Come along.
Have you come for the first time?
Seeker: [Inaudible]
Shri Mataji: All right, come along.
Come along this side.
Shri Mataji: So, it is not a difficult thing,
it is not at all a difficult thing to learn
it, it’s very easy.
You can pick it up in no time, as soon as
you start using your hands on other people.
Shri Mataji: Please, be seated.
Alright.
[To a Yogi] Just see them, some people come
along.
Now these people, say- who are the latest
who have come to Sahaja Yoga?
Let’s see.
The latest ones.
Say, those who have come about a month back.
Seeker: Yes.
Shri Mataji: See, he came back, she came back
only one month back.
And.
Sahaja Yogini: This is his first time.
Seeker: I was here on Monday.
Shri Mataji: How much?
Sahaja Yogini: Ah.
Ok, he was here on Monday.
Shri Mataji: Monday, alright.
He’s got it.
But you see, [to someone else] Have you been
giving vibrations now?
Lady: Yes.
Shri Mataji: In one month, it’s done.
So you can imagine.
And you know about the charkas now?
Lady: Yes.
Shri Mataji: About the mantras?
Not all of them.
Shri Mataji: Yes, you see, that’s it.
It’s very simple.
If you pay attention to it, you can do it
much faster.
There are many people who are here, within
a month, one month’s time, they pick up
so many things.
Many like that, within one month‘s time.
[To a Sahaja Yogi:] He’s alright.
Because you become the knowledge.
You start feeling it on your fingers, you
know this is the charka.
If this finger is, say, burning, [left auricular]
that means your left heart is catching.
If your left heart is catching, then you know
because it’s burning!
Then, there’s nothing to go to the books
or anything to find out, it’s just burning,
it’s there.
Isn’t it?
That means the left heart is catching.
Now, only you have to know what [Inaudible]
left heart is catching, the decoding only,
what does that mean.
Your hands will speak Christ has said, alright?
They will speak, I am just recording it.
Now you see for self if it’s true or not.
What does that mean?
Left heart means there’s a problem on the
heart: may be, the person is over hard working,
he has forgotten about his Spirit.
The mantra you have to say is: “I am the
Spirit”, for left heart.
It’s so simple.
Because you have forgotten about your Spirit,
you are more on the right side in the sense,
you are more extra- you are an extravert and
more attention is outside, not towards your
Spirit.
Left heart is catching.
You start understanding Sahaja Yoga so well
when your vibrations are steady.
Now this finger, this is catching [left thumb].
Now this is catching means the person has
been to somebody who s unauthorized in spiritual
life.
Anything, say ISP, you call it IST.
Then you have got parapsychology, even psychology.
Then you have got other things like all these
gurus, false gurus, you can say this aura
business- what else is there, just now he
was telling.
Sahaja Yogini: Supernatural, Mother.
Shri Mataji: Supernatural and under-natural,
and [Big laugh].
All these things, you know, all alternatives
you can think of.
Anything you can think of, all these things
and the books, and the Lams and the Dhamas,
and every thing.
[Laugh].
Even people who go, sort of adhere to a chuch
too much, or adhere to Catholicism again.
Because they are not connected with God and
they are unauthorized.
[Shri Mataji shows her left palm].
But if you have been to a real guru, then
immediately I will know.
You won’t have this problem and ascent will
be very fast if you have been to a real guru.
But how many are real these days?
In the market, only those who are marketing
are they, as I said it: in the market only
the buyers and the shopkeepers.
It’s a market place now!
So the real gurus are not to be seen, there
are, of course I know, there are many real
gurus also, but wherever they are, they are
not in the market.
I am the only person fighting them and telling
them off, you see.
None of them are willing to come down or to
concede to anything, they said these human
beings are hopeless.
They said: ” twelve years you work Mother,
then we’ll come down “. They want me alone
to fight the [ordeal?]
[Shri Mataji laughs] doesn’t matter.
So now, it’s a market place, where there
are buyers and they are simple naïve customers.
They just put such absurd things like somebody
says: “alright, I want to sell a big palace,
with this and that, and all that, only you
have to deposit 2 thousand pounds.”
Alright, people will be quite willing to do:
“Oh, what a bargain, let’s pay 2 thousands.”
And the palace may belong to the Queen.
If you go there and ask them: “which palace
you want to sell?”
“This palace.
” And that belongs to the Queen, you see.
This is unauthorized.
Unauthorized people who have nothing to do
with God, who claim that they have something
to do with God, which is false, and that’s
why they catch on this finger [left thumb].
And what do they do?
They use all these techniques; these techniques
are called, in Sanskrit language, as “avidya”.
” Avidya” means, non-knowledge, you can
say that it’s not knowledge, something anti-knowledge,
anti-God, this is anti-God.
So for that the mantra is: “Shuddha vidya”,
means the pure technique.
It’s the mantra : pure technique, it’s
the mantra.
“Pure” means the one that comes from the
Spirit.
Now what they are doing [The Sahaja Yogis]
is the pure technique because it’s flowing
in them.
If they are moving their hands, there’s
a power flowing through them and they are
working it out.
It’s not just a, acrobatic thing that is
going on.
So the pure knowledge: for example, the way
they are raising theses candles now in my
presence, and they themselves are Realized
souls, it’s working out.
So this is all, it’ the pure “vidya”
it’s the pure knowledge and the pure technique,
and those who have not done this, have gone
to such people, they have put their heads
before them, kneeled before them, have done
something that should not have been done!
So this is it.
And that’s how if you catch on this finger,
this thumb, left hand, that means a person
has been to somebody like that.
But, with that, if you have any catch on this
Void [on the palm], or Void here in the stomach
part- this is left Swaddithana, it’s placed
here down below, which moves like that all
over, and this becomes right Swaddisthana,
this side.
Now supposing a person catches all round here,
his Void, and all round here.
Seeker: How do you call it?
Shri Mataji: It’s called as the Void, we
call it Void.
It’s not the Zen Void.
But the Void is the crossing point which is,
it’s the viscera, it’s the stomach part,
where-abdomen you can call it, abdomen part
– and this part, if it is catching that
means these are the ten principles of the
guru.
If this is catching, means you have hurt your
principle of guru, your principle of a master.
That means you have gone to some very wrong
master.
If this is catching, that means that.
Now, just now as they said, his Void is catching.
The Kundalini will be wobbling there, you
can see it with your own eyes also.
You can see the Kundalini just potting [?] – pulsating
there, you can see the all stomach going into
a trauma.
And then you have to say the mantra of the
Primordial master.
Anyone you can do it you see, Guru Nanaka’s
name you can take, Muhammad’s name you can
take, all of them are Prophets.
Moses’ name, Abraham, all these are there.
So if you take their names, the Kundalini
can be brought up.
You can strengthen that part, then the Kundalini’s
pushed up.
So all these so-called Yogas, also like physical
yoga.
Now, in the physical Yoga, you will catch
this finger [right annular], this one [right
major] and this finger [left auricular].
This ring finger here and this finger [left
auricular].
This is heart, means you have been paying
too much attention to your physical thing.
Anybody who is working also physically too
much can also catch this, plus this [right
annular].
Because when you go into action too much,
also, as a result of that, the fumes or your
actions create your ego.
And this is one of the biggest problem of
the West you see, they are not aware that
they have an ego.
But after Realization they start seeing the
ballon [floating?] like that [Shri Mataji
laughs], they see that and then they come
and tell me: “Mother I ‘m catching on
my right Agnya” [right side].
It’s a very delicate stuff.
You can’t tell anybody: “You have got
ego”.
They [do really?] have it, you see.
So you have to be very careful when you are
talking to them.
But actually, so many people felt that there
is ego in them, so they took to- even people,
when they feel they have too much ego they
take to alcoholism, because they are frightened
of themselves, they can’t just bear, they
want to escape that part.
So people are quite conscious.
But after Realization, it becomes a complete
understanding because you start feeling a
little pain sometimes, in this finger [right
annular], you feel a pain here and you know
that you have got this Mister ego just coming
out.
So then you know how to twist it and take
it out, how to bring it out.
So you start understanding yourself and you
start understanding others.
I don’t have to tell you, you know yourself.
Now we have certain things, like we use vibrated
water for clearing your Void.
Now what is vibrated water?
It’s nothing that- but these divine vibrations
are put into it.
And they go and start bombarding that area
and try to improve it.
We have cured so many people of stomach cancers
and all those things with it.
Even, we can cure what you call blood cancers
something with Sahaja Yoga, so many have been
cured.
You can cure, you can do it, no problem, you
can do it, but, what one has to do [is] to
be steadily moving about with Sahaja Yoga.
Now for example, you have a conception about
Christ, say for example.
Now, that conception my not be the real conception
of Christ, may not be, may be.
So keep your eyes opened.
Now what I say in Sahaja Yoga, you can verify
it.
But do not deny, first verify.
Supposing you go as a scientist, you have
to go and see for yourself, isn’t it?
You just deny [?]”no this cannot be true.”
Because whatever you know is your own conception.
Get inside alright.
Now when you get inside, keep you eyes opened
and see for yourself.
And then, once you start seeing it, that’s
the best way, is knowing, because what you
see is trough your vibrated awareness.
For example, now you want to ask a question,
say, Mother is there God?
Just ask a question thrice and you’ll find
the vibrations will increase.
It’s a fact.
But if you ask about T.M., you may get even
burning.
Vibrations will stop.
Better ask about God, so that we have vibrations.