I could not accommodate all of you in my house then I thought better to come here all of you would fit here!
And today is the last day for our Sahaj Yogis (before India Tour).
We have to understand certain very, very important
things about ourselves and our organisation that is Divine.
Now, in broad lines, I can tell you, not individual
problems and individual things because you are no more individuals now.
You have become part and parcel of the divine Being and you are awakened cells.
And so, in a broad way we must understand what we have to do about it.
First thing, we have to kno that we are Realised souls,
and that you have got Realisation and that you are saints; that you have all the powers that a saint could have.
No saint ever had more powers than you have, as it is, which is manifesting.
No saint had any knowledge that you have today.
You’ll be amazed, none of the books which have been written so far have been able to
tell you about the spiritual being that is
within you as you have come to know through
Sahaja Yoga.
One has to accept it.
It is so.
Any one of them, whosoever has written any
books – even, I would say, Adi Shankaracharya,
he could not explain so many things which
you know.
But the quality of Adi Shankaracharya is very
great, or people of his type – Markandeya
or Buddha.
The quality is very high because they are
extremely pure people – purity.
They have achieved individual salvation of
a very high degree.
While you have achieved your collective salvation
better.
But individually they are of a very, very
high quality.
I mean, they had no doubts about Divine Power,
they had no doubts about God.
They never had any doubts and they were very
dignified.
And they never bothered as to their petty
problems of life.
For them this was too petty to think about.
Anything which is so petty, we spent so much
time over it.
I know we had to do it because, after all,
we are human beings and are coming into Sahaja
Yoga with our human awareness and then we
got our Realisation.
So the purification time is very, very short.
And while they had such a lot of time to purify
themselves.
Now, for example, Moses was an incarnation,
a very pure form of a personality or, you
can say, Jesus was an incarnation, absolutely
purest form of incarnation.
But they are there to be our ideals while
what we have done is to become, from human
beings, a prophet.
So you understand both the things very well,
what the weaknesses human beings have, what
are their problems, how they get away from
reality, how they are deluded.
But still we do not use our vibratory power
as we should use.
And this is the point I want to tell you – that
you all have vibratory powers.
When we start using our vibratory powers also
we do not know what dignity, protocol we should
have for using this power.
It is the power of the Deities within us and it’s a ritual by which we get their power
working in us.
As you know that people of ancient times did lot of miracles through this power but they
were very dignified people.
There was no frivolousness in their character
and not useless problems within them, absolutely
of no spiritual value.
When you use your vibratory awareness you
should not use them for useless powers like,
for example, going to a cinema and there’s
a traffic and you think that there’s a traffic
so you must use your vibratory powers to reach
that place.
Because it’s frivolous; it does not matter.
In Sahaja Yoga it does not matter whether you go to a cinema or not.
What matters is: what are your spiritual powers, how far you have come in your spirituality.
It (the cinema) does not matter at all.
You are a saint, and what saintliness you are achieving within you is the main problem.
Otherwise, all the rest of the things that
you have, has no meaning.
Or all these problems have no meaning in spirituality.
So, all the Sahaja Yogis must realise that you are now newly born and you are people
of new awareness and you have to have that
dignity.
I’ll just give an example because I was
discussing with someone today,
that when you give somebody a sort of a bandhan, you just turn your hand like this or like that.
This is not the way it should be done.
Your hands itself are to be respected because these are the hands of a saint.
And all the deities reside on your hands and
fingers so when you have to give them bandhan
or anything, you have to use them properly.
Use them in such a way that it’s dignified
to do it.
Any indignity or cheap behaviour should be
absolutely avoided.
Then dealing with each other you have to know
that you are all now in the circulation of
Divine Power.
You have to respect each other and really
love each other.
You must respect because you are all saints.
Every saint must respect another saint.
That’s the minimum of minimum.
And if you do not respect each other, your
chakras will go out of order, especially Vishuddhi
because it’s the collective thing.
And also Mother’s Chakra will go out because
your sense of security is your collectivity.
And the love between each other has to be
not only looked after but is to be nourished
and to be worshipped and it should be a virtue.
You should not treat each other as human beings
treat each other.
No!
It’s a precious thing.
And even while talking to anyone very close
– say your brother, sister, husband, wife
– you must respect, you must respect, otherwise,
it has no meaning.
You must respect your parents much more than
you ever respected because they are Sahaja
Yogis, because they are saints and they are
your parents.
Respect is the keynote of relationship with
each other to begin with.
And respect without love has no meaning.
Respect and love for each other.
Whether somebody is highly placed in life,
somebody is lowly placed in life, in Sahaja
Yoga it does not matter.
How much you earn, what is your position in
life, where you live is not important.
The main important thing is that we are one
and we are the people who have become now
prophets and we are the ones who have got
the powers to raise the Kundalini of others
and such a power has come into us because
our Mother loves us very much and it is our
duty that we should love each other.
And how I respect you?
I need not because you know that there’s
a big gap between you and me.
But I respect you because you are saints.
And where the saints are not respected that country goes to dogs.
So first of all you must learn how to respect
each other.
And that is a very, very important training
we should have.
Whether he’s your husband or wife, whether
he’s your brother or sister, father, mother
or child, because he’s a saint – respect!
But I do not know how you will react to this
one that immediately you start thinking about
people who do not respect you.
Think how many people you do not respect.
It’s a typical ego-oriented reaction that
immediately we start thinking, “Oh, that
man does not respect me!
That man does not respect!”
But just think how many people you have not respected yourself.
When I am not here, I am here much more.
I have not been to Australia, and you know how tremendously these people have come up
– so pure and so good and so fantastic.
But that has not happened so much here because
I had to work, really labour here.
Not that England is that bad.
But all the time to feel that, “Mother is
around.
We’ll put all our problems to Her and She
can solve them.
” Even small, small problems you bring to
me – it’s all right – but now you are
capable of solving your problems as well as
solving the problems of others.
Unless it is something fundamental you need
not bother about me and you need not also
ask me about it.
You can go ahead with it.
But you must think everything in the terms
of Sahaja Yoga by which – how much, by that,
you are doing for Sahaja Yoga?
How much you are working out for Sahaja Yoga?
This was the meeting of the Sahaja Yogis today.
And fundamentally we have to understand one
thing: that we have to grow and we have to
let others grow with our growth.
Not by curbing our growth, but with our growth.
You’ll only grow if you make others grow
with you.
Otherwise, there will be no growth.
Now, whatever I say goes into the books, sometimes
into the brains of the people.
It has to go into the heart.
The whole Sahaja Yoga system works on the
heart; that is the Spirit.
Spirit is the thing I’m talking about.
It’s the Spirit [that] is happy by that.
Some people, I am told, are using their hands
like a weapon and all that.
This is very dangerous!
You are not supposed to do all this for yourself.
You are still saints, you are not yet gods!
So don’t try such things.
Some people have a habit of also hitting a
person with the hand like that.
In my presence, if I say, it’s all right.
But otherwise you should not.
You have to respect.
Use all tender and gentle methods, never anything
by which you show any disrespect to a saint.
Of course, you are hitting the negativity
in another person, I know that.
But you have no business to do that or to
discard anyone or to put somebody out of this
thing.
You will go down very much.
This is a serious thing one must understand.
You have all the powers you know how far to
go.
You must keep to your maryadas.
Don’t go beyond, because these things give
you ego, and ego is the most dangerous thing
which we face always.
Try to improve your language.
Be gentle.
Be very gentle with each other.
I expect that you’ll have many more people
by the time I come.
I expect fantastic things from you.
I don’t know if I should but I have given
you something so fantastic, so tremendous.
It is unbelievable.
I expect it from you, no doubt, because you
are specially selected and I have worked with
you for years together.
You have got the tapes in English.
French people, poor things, they don’t have
tapes in French and they have to be translated.
They haven’t got a book in French and they
have big problems of understanding me.
But how dedicated they were, how deep they
are.
Each one of them came and said, “Mother,
I love You very much.
I love You.
“I have many defects and I offer myself
to You.”
Will you accept me?”
All of them said this way.
Just imagine!
I mean, I was surprised how they were saying
all these things to me and the way they were
understanding their defects within themselves.
Now, we have to change our mode of behaviour
towards financial, material, emotional, physical
and all these things.
For example, say, one is married – marriages
should be successful.
If your marriage is not successful and happy,
you are not going to be blessed, not at all.
Try to make your marriage very happy and successful.
That’s very important.
Marriage is the institution established by
Adi Shakti.
You cannot dishonour it.
Do not play frivolously with your marriages.
Then you must also allow the children to be
born to you so that you get great souls coming
down on this earth by which we are giving
them a chance, a very good chance, to lead
a very happy life.
But if husbands, wives are not happy, and
even if Realised-souls are born, they have
a trouble with you and they do not prosper
well and they have problems.
So, first of all, create a family of happiness
and joy.
Some people think if they get away from Sahaja
Yogis, they’ll make a good, happy married
life.
It’s absolutely wrong!
Absolutely wrong!
If you cannot make a happy married life in
the ashram, you cannot make it anywhere else.
First try in the ashram.
[It’s] worth trying.
Otherwise, you cannot make it.
Because then you understand how you share
your life with others and your married life.
Any such thing like any material thing, like
getting a house or getting this thing, that
thing is not so important.
Your house should be clean within yourself,
your temple of your heart.
We are not here to build houses, not to accumulate
money.
We are here to build our temples within ourselves.
The real temples which are growing, which are the living temples of living God within us.
So these material things are important up to a point, not more than that.
Most important is not how you are substantiated by Sahaja Yoga but how much you have substantiated Sahaja Yoga through.
Many people think, “We should get a good house because we have come to Mataji.
Yes, you do get. You get good jobs. All right.
You get it. You get your financial conditions improved.
All right. Everything happens to you.
But how much have you given to Sahaja Yoga?
In the way: how much have you substantiated?
People think sometimes that if they donate money that’s sufficient. It’s not.
To enrich it with your heart, with your lovingness, with your friendship, with your sweet understanding of each other,
enjoyment of each other’s company in the purest form, not with any purpose
or with any intention of getting any low type of joy or low type of happiness from someone
ego-oriented or sex-oriented.
But it’s pure joy, pure joy.
Purity is the theme we have to take to.
We have to try to be purer and purer.
And the purity will be shown brilliantly on your faces, in your behaviour, in the whole being as you would be.
Your presence itself will show that you are Sahaja Yogis.
You won’t have to certify.
You won’t have to wear some special dresses to say, but people will know from your faces
that you are saints, from your behaviour.
You have to stand back in the last queue.
You should be the people who should look at things.
You should not be the first, unique, to get into the thing first, to getting into the queue first.
No, you are the last because you are with yourself. They are not.
They have not [got] their own securities.
They are trying to find securities in these things.
You have your own securities.
Change, according to the Spirit, all your priorities, and then joy is your own.
I really expect fantastic things from you and I hope you all will join together and
work it out and create something fantastic.
I don’t know how to tell individually about things but as it is I have already spoken
to these Sahaja Yogis in Paris and I have told them that Sahaja Yoga is a very speedy
thing.
And it’s very speedy.
It’s such a speed and if you do not keep with the speed of Sahaja Yoga you’ll be
thrown out.
You have to keep to the speed of Sahaja Yoga.
Those who cannot keep by some method or other,
or [who] get locked up by something or some
misidentification, will drop out.
You’ll only grow when you will keep to the speed of Sahaja Yoga.
It is going to be tremendous in India.
I know these five years are going to be tremendous
in Australia.
England may be, depending on your people putting
up the speed.
It’s going to be tremendously speedy and
you have to understand that – drop out all
your shackles and drop out all your misidentifications,
all nonsenses of fanaticism or of misidentifications
that you are British, this, that, all this.
And just become Sahaja Yogis and universal
beings.
It’s very important.
The time has come now.
From next year it will start.
So, I wish you a very Happy New Year
and a very, very happy and cheerful Christmas. May God bless you.