[Music]
now the best way would be to play really
physically
4:33 with your heart
first of all you want to ask for
strength from mother give me strength so
that's either generous I won't deceive
myself yet defeating orders morning
today give me strength that I'll face
myself and think in my heart that I try
to improvise because these are defects
which are not your own
they are often they if they fall off you
photographer now then you should ask for
forgiveness thankful for this there
should be prayer say that's for you
because I've been ignorant I do not know
what to do I've done mistake that is the
first thing one has to ask either for
you then second thing you are for is a
sweetener a method by which I become
communicated with other specifically
like like my presence
give me give me now give me that beauty
of culture beauty of understand that
everybody loves me wants ask for thing
the failure are that a lot
give me the sense of security of my
strength so that I do not read insecure
by which I trouble others of attack you
make sense of my own dignity so that I
do not feel that I am minute rate or
somebody has little if your attire
positions nobody can innocence if only
you'll be little buying your foolishness
I talked to her after saying that give
me my
give me satisfaction let me feel my
satisfaction from what I whatever I have
whatever I eat everything
take off my attention away from all
these you know that your attention is in
the box and those who are very much
interested in food we get liver in any
case whatever you make up in anything
like this
wherever my attention is voice please
give me strength to pull it back
chief tanni go teach me how to avoid
things that them that take away matter
take away my cut
you may resist it by which I see the
whole drama let me never to each other
and criticize it let me see my PC not
other let me see why people are not
happy with me mister you have a very
sweet tub and it's inflated so that
other nice madam they enjoy my husband
let me be like a flower and not like a
thorn you have to play all of these
there are thousands of us then ask for
the latest threat each of you should ask
that please keep me away from ego that
is nice the ideas that I'm superior to
others are better than others or in any
way it takes away my mission and my
humanity here the natural humility by
which I can penetrate into the hearts of
these just try to bend your head and you
go up to your heart you have to bend
your head just to bang your head and
there is your heart where this Isis they
deal with it if you are any way hurt in
your ego or you know hurting somebody
zero is testing will behave in the same
manner in the family mystical man so try
to understand that these things have to
go this path is to pray and ask for help
there is a baby thing but with your
heart three
Kirra J and that group that we can
please our mother sometimes we want to
please our mother you want to see her
happy
the only things that remain you give me
happiness
the way I love you You Love