Public Program Day 1, Seekers are the Highest Creation
Heartwood Community Center, Santa Cruz (United States)
17-10-1981
I am very fortunate and I am very happy that
I could come to Santa Cruz.
I can see what I am facing is the ocean of
Love, the seekers of Love, the people who
are seeking the Truth.
Gregoire has told you all these things because
he is very earnest, he is very concerned,
he knows you are seekers and that’s why
he has told you in these words, so don’t
be frightened.
There is nothing to be frightened about anything.
You are seekers and you are a special category.
In the eyes of God, seekers are the highest
creation that He has created.
You are the highest of all.
To Him it does not matter who are rich, who
are in power, who are leading a life of so-called
success.
It does not matter to Him at all, He does
not understand that, He does not know that.
Christ has said that these people if they
want gold, let them have.
They’ll have bars of gold and live with
it.
But “if they seek Me, if they love Me,”
then these people who are seekers today are
going to enter into the Kingdom of God and
He will eat with them.
They will sit at the same table.
You are respected because you are seekers.
You are loved because you are seekers.
And you have survived despite all the attacks
on you.
These are all attacks.
You are naîve, you are simple, you were innocent
at that time when attacks came in.
Now gradually you are discovering that it
was an attack.
Everything that you did was just to put you
down.
And one person who was negative of that kind
would come forward and assert and use all
the negative forces to push you down.
To me you are my children.
To me I don’t think what you have done because
you didn’t meet me that time.
I take the load upon myself.
I did come to San Jose last time.
They said that there are lots of seekers settling
down in Santa Cruz.
I wanted to come and see you here that time
only, but the experience I had of the people
who were there, I thought, “They are not
just now seeking God, but they are sort of
seeking ego or superego, they are seeking
into a new style of life and a new style of
understanding, because they have found out
that material life is of no value, it’s
not going to give them joy."
At that time, when I said that, and you are
thinking of these things, how can you pay
for it?
Nobody could understand these things.
It was very difficult to talk to them – that
it is spontaneous, it is your own right, that
you have to get it.
You have been seeking for ages now, not only
in this life time.
You have been saints in many lives and now
you are born here to seek it.
It’s so simple as that.
It has to happen, that’s your nature, that’s
what you are.
You try anything else, you won’t be satisfied
‘till you have found out the Truth.
But that time nobody would listen to me.
It was a very funny situation and I ultimately
decided that let them find out for themselves
to begin with.
When they will find it out, they have to reach
the right conclusion.
Because there is one problem in the seeking,
that you have to seek in your own freedom,
in your own glory of your own choice.
Because if you are to be liberated, it has
to be a free choice.
If a person is not free, say, he is enticed
or he is hypnotised or he is overpowered by
others, he has no freedom at all of any kind.
Such a person is useless to enter into the
Kingdom of God.
If you have to become the King, then you have
to have that basic freedom in yourself intact.
But freedom doesn’t mean ego by any chance.
If you think: “I like it, I love it, I do
it,” that’s not the Spirit.
You are not seekers of ego, I must tell you
very frankly, you are not.
You are seekers of Truth, of Love, of Joy.
For ages you’ve been seeking that.
Joy is the result when you get to that position
where you become your Spirit, your Atma.
You should be in Joy, not talking about it,
but enjoying it.
And that has to happen to you.
It’s a happening for which you have built
in for ages.
Today, in general, I will tell you what you
are really and what you have to expect.
To become what?
Nobody has told you about it.
They said, “All right, you’ll come to
us into a new age."
“All right,” people said.
“Let’s go and join!” Somebody says that
you’ll get this.
You joined.
William Blake is one of the greatest prophets
of the modern times.
For you Western people, he said that “The
men of God,” that means you people.
You are people of God.
You are not of this gross level.
If people don’t understand you that does
not mean that I don’t understand.
I know you, what you are.
I know what it is, I can feel it.
He said, “Men of God will become prophets,
and these prophets will have powers to make
others prophets."
This is what we have to expect within ourselves.
So you have to become the prophet and you
have to make others prophet.
Now this is the point you should judge: Have
you become the prophet?
What is a prophet?
Prophet is a person who can feel the all-pervading
power around.
Now I said there is all-pervading power of
Love.
Oh you also sing the song, they say, “Yes,
there is all-pervading power."
Many people also feel that they are feeling
it, but it’s not true.
We have to be honest to ourselves because
we are seekers, we should not cheat ourselves
because this is ego that makes you cheat.
This intelligence is the worst thing.
Gregoire himself told me one day, “I find
my intelligence is trying to cheat me."
Very intelligently.
So one has to be very careful to understand
that you have to become that.
You are the loser, you are the loser. Nobody else.
If you play around with your ego, your superego,
your conditionings or mesmerism or hypnosis,
and your ideas about having a kind of life,
you are the loser.
All that could be a great barrier to be the
Spirit, which is a different thing altogether,
is beyond this.
So when you become the Spirit, what happens
to you, what should you expect?
Of course it’s true that this all-pervading
power is there.
Now if I say there are lots of plays going on
here, there is a music going on here, you
won’t believe.
If I bring the television and say, “Now,
this is the one which is going to show you."
You will say, “Oh."
I mean, you know it.
But in India, if I take it to a village who
has never seen a television, they’ll say,
“This box?
How can it do it?” But you put it to the
mains and fantastic things can happen.
It catches all that.
In the same way, when you become that, when
you get a little breakthrough, it’s just
the plugging to the mains.
You are all ready for that.
And the fantastic thing happens.
First you start feeling it all around.
Now don’t jump into ego.
That’s not the end of it.
You first start feeling it.
Then you start understanding that your centres
are on your fingertips.
It means that you are the master of that.
And then you start feeling around
and you know it is there
Then I´m here jus to decode it, to tell you,
this is what this finger mean "this"
You verify it.
It is so much surprising when people verify
it.
There was a gentleman in London.
I had seven hippies in London and I worked
on them for four years, English people are
a little difficult to crack.
But after four years they really got their
realization in a proper way and after that
now we have thousands of people who are realized
in England.
Because once they find something, then they
get to it.
They’re not the people who are shifty.
Somehow they have that much wisdom, that balance
in them.
They understand that if you have found a little
water in a place, then go on digging there
alone to have the well.
They don’t leave that and go to another
place and dig well and dig well and dig well.
They can know where to stop.
So these people were very skeptical in the
beginning.
One of them got Realization and he said, “Mother,
it is all pervading, it has got telecommunication
and everything.
What about my Father who has not telephoned
to me and who always writes to me and has
not written to me?
He’s in Scotland."
I said, “You trunk call him just now."
I said, “You feel it.
Just put your hands like that."
And he said,”I am getting a burning here."
I said:”That means he must be down with
very bad bronchitis.
These are the centers of your father and this
is the finger which denotes this center.
You telephone to him and find out."
He telephoned to him and the mother said exactly
the same centers, that he’s down with very
bad bronchitis.
This could be a cock and bull story.
The way Gregoire was telling you, he was trying
to establish my credibility to you, because
it is such an apologetic condition in which
I have come.
It‘s a very funny situation, I know that.
The other day I went to see a very influential
Indian man.
Of course, he knows me, because of my husband
maybe.
He knows that a person of that status may
not come to this level of cheating others,
whatever it is.
But still he told me that he can’t understand
how people are taking to these horrible gurus
and how these gurus came and cheated me also
and I helped them.
In Sahaja Yoga, it’s a spontaneous happening,
a living happening.
You are a living being and the force of God
is also living.
Just like a fruit comes out of a flower, just
like this living process takes place, you
become your Spirit.
We never think this thing is around us, every
day we see.
This is worked out by this all pervading Power.
We can’t do even with one flower.
We cannot transform even one flower into a
fruit.
We take it for granted.
We never know that all such living things
are done.
Now look at it.
There is a little bird, which lays the egg.
For what?
The eggs are kept in the nest.
The all pervading Power works it out in such
a way that the eggs grow and the bird hatches
them and from these eggs comes out a bird.
We have seen caterpillars turning into butterflies.
We never think how it happens.
We just take it for granted.
We enjoy their colors.
We never see how this transformation has taken
place and this transmutation has taken place.
In Sanskrit language a realized soul is called
as dwijaha, is the one who is born twice.
Of course, this is also another problem.
Last time I said you are to be born actually
again.
It is a living process.
The Kundalini has to move throughout the centers
and you have to feel the actualization of
your Realization, meaning that you must feel
the cool breeze coming out of your fontanelle
bone area.
Realization you have to feel.
It’s an actualization, not a vague belief,
I told them hundred times.
And they were taping me.
Some people told me, ”Mother, don’t allow
them to tape."
I said, “Let them tape! What’s the matter?
I am not running any enterprise."
They said, “No, they will use it for some
purpose."
I said, “Let them use it.
For what purpose they are going to use I don’t
understand."
I don’t understand these human laws.
I am very bad at it.
And human beings I am also worse.
These people met me the other day in Sydney
after so many years.
They have branded themselves as born again.
And they just self-certificated that we are
born again.
I said, ”But how?”
“But we are born again."
“But what is the proof that you are born
again, my children?
How do you believe you are born again?
There must be some proof of it.
“Oh, we are born again.
Finished."
Now, you cannot self-certify yourself.
If you do that, it is Ego.
Understand that.
If you are born again, you should be able
to feel the centers of other people, you should
be able to feel your own centers, you should
be able to judge yourself and cure yourself
and you could cure others.
Not only that, but you can raise their Kundalini
and give them Realization.
This is the minimum of minimums to them.
I mean an egg, if it is chanting, “I am
a bird,” does it become?
It’s an egg and an egg is an egg.
If it says, “Oh, I am
a bird."
It can’t fly.
It has to really fly.
If you tell the egg:
"Mrs egg, would you please fly?"
Some of the nursery rhymes are Humpty Dumpty
sat on the wall.
That’s what they are.
They believe that they are great people.
They sat on the wall and when they fell down,
all the King’s horses and all the King’s
men could not put them together again.
This is what it is,
this is a make believe, that we are born again.
But it’s of no use to you.
You are Seekers.
You are nothing but Seekers of Spirit.
Accept that situation, first of all.
Accept your Self.
These false certificates are not going to
help you, by any chance.
Again I go away, you find another Guru, get
after him, get after another, get after another
one.
Some of them just end up into a lunatic Asylum.
I don’t know what to do with them.
When this happens to you, physically you feel
all right.
I mean cancers can only be cured through your
Kundalini awakening.
I’ve been saying this for the last ten years.
I’ve also cured cancer automatically of
people as a by product.
All diseases get cured.-That is the minimum
of minimum that should happen to you.
After all, Realization is not some sort of
a cheap thing you can buy in the market like
a take away food.
It is your Spirit, which is an eternal Being,
which you achieve.
You achieve your absolute value.
You become that though it happens so spontaneously,
so easily that you can’t believe.
You have no self esteem.
You can’t believe it that you have really
got it in the beginning.
People just don’t believe it.
It is impossible, they can believe it
that this has happened.
And when they don’t believe it, they don’t
want to practice it any further.
It’s so surprising.
First you have to get the sprouting of Kundalini
and then you have to allow it to grow and
once you grow into it, then you are like a
tree.
As Gregoire says it’s true.
He was here in Santa Cruz, went to Berkeley,
there he met a very good Sahaja Yogi from
India and just came down to London.
That time I saw him and I said, “Look at
this Seeker coming down."
I went to receive him at the station and I
was surprised – he was so frantic, he was
so upset and I was surprised that the centers…
I know what he was.
He is a Seeker, I know that.
That had such love, and such feeling.
I said, “ Look at this my child.
Where is he lost?
What has happened to you?”
Now, we have to know what we are, what we
have to achieve and where we are to go.
That’s an important thing.
As I have told you, you must know what you
have to achieve, what you get.
In a very gross way I’ve told you.
Actually, it’s so dynamic, it is so fantastic
that if I tell you any more stories of it,
you’d say it’s really a cock and bull
story.
But there is God.
He’s there, no doubt and He is dynamic and
He is all powerful and that He is all Love
and that He loves you so much that he wants
you to enjoy His Kingdom.
It’s true, no doubt about it.
I am here to prove everything to you, not
to talk and give sermons and all that, but
to prove it to you.
And his Powers are so fantastic, at every
level how they work out is amazing.
You have to just become.
Becoming is the main thing.
Now, as far as I am concerned, I am Your Mother.
You have every right on me.
I shouldn’t say I am your guru because I
am only here to connect you to your Self and
you become your own guru, you
don't need any Guru anymore.
Once you are connected to the mains you become
your own guru.
You know this Warren Reeves, Dr.
Warren Reeves.
He came to me and I had to stick on to him
because he was all the time running away.
He has been to so many gurus who pampered
his ego –-”Oh, you are a great seeker,”
“You are already a realized soul."
All these things are sticking onto his head
and it was very difficult to get him together.
And also I do not work in the city.
I actually work in the villages of India where
really thousands of people have got realization.
We have seen six thousand people get their
Self realization at a time.
But Indians are wise people and they are the
people who do not indulge into extremes.
In their seeking also they are wise and they
know what to expect.
So, it’s easy for me to work out.
They are innocent people still not exposed
to the material things that you have.
Though you’ve denied it, but you can’t
help it.
Your brain is modern.
You may try to look like primitive people.
The brain is modern.
What can you do?
Think, think, think, think, think.
Just by changing your brain, you do not become
that.
This is the point we should know.
So, it’s easy there to work it out and in
the Indian villages you don’t even get sometimes
a car to move out.
You have to go in a bullock cart and there
is no bathroom, you have to go to the river.
It’s all right for a change or holiday,
but when you have to be with me three months
like that, it was too much for him.
But still he managed and now you will be amazed,
he has established seven centers in seven
cities in Australia.
If you ask him how many people he has given
realization, he will say, “I don’t remember."
So, one light which has been enlightened,
can enlighten another light.
But the first light has to be an enlightened
light.
Once you say that you are enlightened, everybody’s
ego starts coming up.
It’s very common with the Western people.
Every time I went to some place they said,
“Why you of all the things, Mother?”
I said, “It’s all right.
You come along, It’s a good idea.
I would like to retire."
I said, “My husband would pay a man who
can do my job.
It’s a thankless job to work for days and
nights together and he will be very happy
to do that for you."
This problem of becoming is not yours, is
mine for the time being.
When you become that, then it is yours.
Once I know how to swim I can save you.
If I do not know how to swim how can I make
you swim?
When you learn how to swim you can also save
other people.
It’s very simple.
But even if you say it is saving, people get
frightened.
No, it’s becoming.
It’s what you are.
To get to that is the point.
I would like to tell you what we are and what
is going to happen to us when we become realized
souls.
It’s a gross manifestation of the powers
I told you.
When you became human beings you got your
awareness in a different way than the animals
have, because for the animals, for example,
they do not understand the beauty of this
room.
They won’t.
They don’t understand anything that is filthy
or dirty, they have no smell power.
Somehow they’ve managed.
They can live under any circumstances without
smelling anything.
We don’t have to learn anything from animals.
We are on top of all the creation and we have
to assume our position.
Once you have assumed your position, you become
that and once you become that, then you will
be surprised to see how fantastic you are.
That is the discovery you have to have.
Within ourselves I think all of you got this
unique discovery so it’s easy for you to
see what I’m about to say.
You will be amazed this lecture which I gave
about ten years back in India to begin with
after there have been many lectures.
But if you have this is a good idea.
You can go home and see for yourself.
But you also have a little pamphlet.
On the back side is the complete picture of
the Kundalini.
Now, this is the God, the Primordial Being,
who has made you in His own image.
But still there’s the reflector, the human
being, which is not complete.
Within us lies this subtle mechanism, which
is called the tantra.
This is the real tantra, holy tantra, is an
auspicious thing, which gives us righteousness.
You see, when we think of the tantrikas, they
are the worst of all.
They make money,
they do all kinds of violence, they teach
all kinds of nonsensical things.
I mean they indulge into any kind of sex.
They use your women, they use your money,
they do all kinds of things.
This is the holy mechanism, this is the pure
mechanism, is the purity, is completely pure
Love, is not biased.
This mechanism exists within you and expresses
itself outside in the gross also to a great
extent.
It expresses itself, on the left-hand side,
as the power of your Desire (iccha shakti).
This expresses itself within us as our emotions,
as our psyche.
Gregoire has rightly said that Freud was quite
half-baked because he knew only one part of
the human being and that, too, was very little
of the psyche.
Because all the scientists see things from
outside in.
If you see a tree from outside, if there is
something wrong with the leaf, you try to
treat the leaf.
But how to treat the whole tree is through
the roots.
So you go to the roots of your being and these
are the roots.
One side of it is the Power of Desire and
it works out after the first center.
I’ll be telling you tomorrow morning about
these centers.
The another power is the power of action,
which enacts your Desire
whick works out your desire.
this yellow color.
This gives you your future.
You enter into your future by your planning,
by your thinking, for working out.
The left side gives you your past.
It goes on accumulating on the left-hand side
and the deeper you move on the left-hand side
there is the collective subconscious.
First the subconscious and then the collective
subconscious.
Now this is very important to know that when
we indulge too much into the left subconscious,
that is a very dangerous situation, as well
as if you move into your right-hand side is
the supra conscious and then to the collective
supraconscious, is also a very dangerous situation.
Moving into the left and the right is the
easy thing for human beings to do because
if you want to do something, if you try to
do something about it and if you are not spontaneous,
what happens?
That your sympathetic nervous system, which is
governed by this subtle energy, goes into
action and you either move into the left side
or into the right side.
For example, if you want to run, as these
days many people are just running, (You can
run once in a while, but all the time running
– what is the need?
Human beings are delicate things.
The way we go headlong into everything like
a bull in a china shop is not necessary.
The way you ruin yourself also, because you
think this body is your own, do what you like.
You must respect your body.
This is the Temple of God.) So, when you start
overdoing something on the left or the right
side, say some people are crying, weeping,
singing praise of death and all that, so have
it.
Some people say we must suffer.
Alright, then you suffer, have Hitler on top
of your head.
If you want more, you can have them, any number.
There are already so many coming to make you
suffer.
There is no need for you to suffer.
Somebody has suffered for you, once and for
all.
There is no need for you to suffer anymore.
You are just ready to enter into the Kingdom
of God.
If you try to go too much on the left-hand
side or too much on the right-hand side, you
feel that you have gone into a new world.
You have not.
For example, take a simple thing like LSD.
Now, what happens when you take LSD?
When you take LSD, you move to the right side.
You start seeing the light,
you start seeing the eyes and all that.
Is a movement of the right-hand side.
Actually, you put your Ego to the right-hand
side and you start seeing that and once you
see that you do not become anything, you just
see it.
Seeing it is not becoming, you have to become.
And once you start seeing it, you think you
have become a higher personality.
It’s absolutely wrong.
You are under the control of something else.
You are not yourself.
The last word on the collective supraconscious
was Hitler.
He got lost completely.
He was using tantrikas, these horrible people,
and he was using all that knowledge, so called,
how to use these forces.
The forces come to you through dead spirits
who are very powerful in their lifetime, and
those who are not, give up that idea of domination
and they are on this earth still all around.
The left-sided people are the people who indulge
into other kind of things like-alcohols and
ganjas and all these things, by which you
become sort of all the time crying, weeping,
this, that.
In that you see your past.
Is a good idea in a way, but a bad idea also
in a way, because you are in the present,
not in your past.
Past does not exist any more, it’s finished
now.
What exists is the present.
Either you are in the future or in the past
and when you go too much into it you get identified
and you think this is what is the Truth, which
is not.
I have to tell you that it is not.
What is the Truth is your Spirit.
That it is your evolutionary process has to, little bit
trigger it and that’s how you become.
By becoming that what happens to you?
You don’t start jumping like mad.
No, it’s not.
Anybody can jump.
Is it difficult to jump?
Some people who said that we went for a flying
course.
They paid 3000 Pounds to fly.
What is the need?
You don’t want to become birds or frogs,
do you?
And they were nothing but frogs jumping.
In my presence they were jumping like that.
I didn’t know how to control.
And they paid 3000 pounds for this.
The other day in a plane I had somebody from
that kind of a thing was sitting and he was
all the time doing like this because I was
sitting behind him.
I said, ”I think I better get out from there
and go out the back."
You are not in your own control.
You have to be your own master.
Now you must know this, that you should be
able to control yourself is the main point.
Like in a car, there are these two powers.
One is the brake and the other is the accelerator.
First, you don’t know how to drive.
You are sitting and first you are going into
a ditch, then sometimes you are getting out
trying to balance it, then you know how to
drive.
When do you know?
When you know.
If you ask me, “Mother, when do we know
how to drive?” When we know.
It is an amazingly simple thing.
So, now you have managed both these.
First, you’ve made accident and have done
all mistakes, doesn’t matter.
As long as you learn how to drive, finished.
First you have a driving license, then you
start arranging these two things to keep yourself
into balance.
You come into balance, still you are not the
master of the car, but you are master as far
as the mechanism is concerned.
So, there is a master who is sitting, of the
car and of you.
In the beginning you should be master of your
body, master of everything.
Then, what happens, that you become the master
of the car as well.
First you balance yourself in such a way that
you know how to master your body, your mind
and everything.
And then you become that by which you can
master other people also.
But mastery does not mean domination.
It’s Love.
It’s a wrong idea that a master is a person
who dominates.
It comes from where I don’t know.
Master is the one who loves, who really does.
He may just sometimes tell you don’t do
this because it’s wrong, the whole bad things
happening, he may tell you.
But he is a comforter.
Comforter, because you have felt no Love in
your life.
The real Love you have not felt.
You want some place where you can get that
Love.
He is a comforter, is the left side.
In our Sahaja Yoga language we call the Comforter
as Mahakali.
She is the Holy Ghost.
From that Comforter other aspects come up.
The second aspect is what you call the Councelor,
The one who tells you what is what, decodes
everything, tells you how to manage, how to
go ahead.
Like an instructor and you verify that.
The second one in our Sahaja Yoga is called
Mahasaraswati
And the third one is the Redeemer,the one
who gives you moksha,
through the Sushumna nadi, is called as Mahalaxmi.
These are the three powers which exist within
us.
The first manifests the left sympathetic,
the second one manifests the right sympathetic
and the third one gives you the parasympathetic
which controls these two centers, which coordinates,
cooperates and refills.
But it is still a limited amount of energy.
Some people tell me that they went to a person
and felt the energy.
What sort of an energy were you feeling?
Very much like shaking and all that.
No, that’s not good.
If you are not possessed you should not shake
before a person.
On the contrary you start feeling the cool
breeze in the hands.You feel completely relaxed.
How do you know?
What happens through Sahaja Yoga is the way,
is very good.
You should see for yourself.
Get three people – one from a lunatic asylum,
certified mad; get another one who is not
realized; get the third one who is realized.
They sit down.
Now you ask them to put their hands towards
you.
Now the person who is lunatic will be doing
like this.
Now if there a cancer patient, he will be
emitting tremendous heat, so much so that
you don’t need a heater, even in London
in December or January.
If there is somebody like that, you
don't need anything.
But supposing that person is just a normal,
balanced person, is in the center.
He starts feeling the cool breeze and the
realized soul starts feeling the whole thing
coming on.
This is what you have to judge with people
when they come.
You should know what happens to them.
If you are seeking reality, you must know
that you have to face yourself as you are
today.
You need not try to hide anything, because
there is nothing to be hidden from your mother.
I don’t care whatever you have done.
I just don’t bother.
It’s not necessary.
The first mantra in Sahaja Yoga to be said
is that Mother, I am not guilty.
You have to say that 16 times in your heart,
that Mother, I´m not guilty
This is the first mantra of Sahaja Yoga, because
in yourself whole things have crawled up into
a diffidence in life.
Even the Ego sometimes gets hurt.
When you do mistakes or anything, it gets
hurt and when it gets hurt you get diffident,
so it gets built up within you as diffident.
When you say, “Mother, I am not guilty,”
your self-esteem is established.
First day you’d better establish your self-esteem.
Within you lies this power of Kundalini.
I was very happy to know that people have
reached the conclusion that it is the Kundalini
awakening which is going to do the job.
It is a very good conclusion you have reached.
But any Dick, Tom and Harry cannot do it,
one should know that.
Saying it is a sprouting, it’s a living
process.
Now, logically you should approach the subject.
You are all very intelligent people, I can
see that.
You are not stupid people.
Living things, like sprouting the seed.
If you want to sprout a seed, can you pull
it out?
Or if you stand on your head, will it happen?
They are such sweet things.
“Hello.
Alright now, sit down for a while."
They are realized souls.
They are born realized.
So many children are born realized and if
you are not realized [UNCLEAR parents] you
are going to harm them.
You have to know what are they.
They know me better than you people do and
they are going to come up.
Wait for ten years before.
They are going to create that great, beautiful
mansion of Love for you.
So, this Kundalini is the power within us.
What power is this?
This is the power of Primordial Desire within
us to be one with the Divine, to be united
with the Divine and this is the Yoga.
All the rest of it is not.
Yoga is nothing, that as you are,
you are to be connected with the
Divine, is the Yoga.
All right?
If that is so, this desire is not yet manifested.
So, it is called as a sleeping Kundalini and
only the person who has that warmth of the
Mother Earth can do it, as simple as that.
Everyone who thinks that Kundalini is to be
awakened must know it is a spontaneous, living
happening, just like a sprouting of a seed.
You cannot just pull it out.
It cannot be done by any effort.
It’s spontaneous.
If it is evolutionary, logically we can find
out that we did nothing to become human beings
from amoeba stage.
We didn’t cut our tails to become human
beings, did we?
We didn’t do anything.
It has happened so spontaneously.
But where is the change in us, let’s see
again logically.
Not rationally, but logically.
Rationality could be quite mad.
Logically you should understand, what is the
difference we have got is in our awareness.
Something has to happen in awareness, not
in a way that you just start jumping or taking
out your clothes and doing nonsensical things.
It’s very easy.
In the bathroom everybody does it.
What’s so great?
But just understand.
You can see with your naked eye the pulsation
of the Kundalini.
Not in all.
If you are a first class instrument, it just
happens.
Like a jet it goes.
It’s a jet Kundalini in the jet age.
It has to happen to all of you.
Why some people said you have to do so much
and you have to do like this and you have
to do that and you have to cleanse yourself
and then only you’ll get realization.
Why is it so simple today?
The reason is the time has come.
In the beginning of a tree’s life one or
two flowers come in, but now the blossom time
has come, so many seekers I see before me,
just like flowers about to become the fruits.
There were never so much seekers before.
Whatever you can say against the modern times
this is the outcome of that.
Without this chaos there would have been not
so many.
This is the time that he predicted that many
saints will be born at this time.
[UNCLEAR] imagine thousands of years back
it was written.
When this Kali Yuga, this modern time, the
one who created the Kali, he was caught up
by somebody and he said, “Nala, what do
mean by torturing me and my wife like this.
I am going to kill you.
The Kali said, “Alright, you can kill me,
but you have to find out one thing about me.
You must know what I am and what I represent."
“What are you?
Just tell me."
He said: “When the modern times will come,”
we call it as Kali Yuga, “at this time,
these saints who are seeking God in the hills
and dales and in the Himalayas will be born
as ordinary householders and they are going
to receive the blessings.
It’s already promised."
If so, that happening has to take place.
But as soon as people came to know that people
are seeking, the market got jammed.
and you got into the trap.
It’s a very subtle method of making money
out of you.
Now, I think, most of them are getting a little
worried, because all their advertising and
all that is a little bit fading and they don’t
know how to find out new methods of advertising
to get ‘round you.
These people are not interested in Indian
villages.
They are interested in Los Angeles or in Santa
Cruz where they can extract money.
It is an enterprise.
You cannot sell God, can you?
You cannot organize it.
Some lady paid $4000 very recently and I heard
somebody told me that she went there, she
danced, she took out her clothes, became mad
and came back.
You pay to go to lunatic asylum or what?
But it helps you to go there because there’s
a fashion on.
Everybody is going, “Oh, I’ve been there
to that Guru."
It’s so maddening.
You must understand, you are the new forms
of the old ways.
In olden days, people who could donate for
a church were regarded as very religious.
Even now, I think, some of the Jews, they
have a diamond-jeweled bible and if they can
tithe there they show it nicely that they
have got one.
All these false ideas of God you’d better
give up, because you are not followers, you
are seekers.
Let them go on with that nonsense.
But you are seekers, so you take to the Truth
and you become that.
I think today, it’s quite a lot for you.
I would like you to ask me some questions,
but sensible questions and don’t be aggressive
with me.
I am very clever.
As they told him, “She’s a masterpiece
of camouflage."
It’s true, I am, so be careful.
If you have any real questions ask me.
If you are not a true seeker and you are just
trying to show off, you are cheating yourself.
Don’t try to show off.
“I read this book."
“I read that book."
“This happened."
”What do you think of this Guru?” Don’t
bring me to controversies.
It’s unnecessary.
If they were of any value, you would have
been a realized soul.
I can make out from you who was your Guru
the way they have ruined your Kundalini.
Some of the Kundalinis are so ruined.
I see them just like wounded snakes, tossing
their heads like this.
It is so bleedy.
You don’t know how much they’ve corrupted
you.
Don’t ask me about these cruel people.
If I start blasting them, you’ll be amazed
how they are.
I love you very much, but I don’t love them.
I am wrathful, very angry with them, because
they are devils, satanic.
If they wanted money, they could have smuggled.
They could have done something like that,
but they should not have ruined your Kundalini.
They had no business to do it.
They will go to hell, no doubt, but they’ll
be carrying so many with them, they know that.
They are trying to overpower.
They are Anti-Christ.
They think they can win over God.
Let them know that God’s Powers are so powerful
that they can all be destroyed like this in
one stroke.
The only thing why they are not destroyed
is because today they are in your brains.
Krishna has said,”Whenever there is the
fall of Dharma, fall of your values, your
virtues, whenever the saints suffer, I come
on this Earth to save the Saints and kill
the devils."
But the devils have gone into the Saints now.
It’s a problem, a dilemma for me.
What to do.
These devils have come into your brains.
They are to be taken out, first of all.
Just wait for me to finish.
Do not stick on to one question.
If you stick on, you’ll miss the whole point.
By questioning, you will not get Realization.
It’s not a mental activity.
It’s triggering beyond the mental activity.
This lecture is useless if you do not get
your Realization.
In the beginning of the Vedas it was written
that if you do not get the knowledge… Knowledge
doesn’t mean going mad.
It doesn’t mean hypnosis.
But if you do not feel the all pervading Power,
then these Vedas are useless.
In the same way my lecture and all mental
activities are useless if you do not get your
Realization.
That’s the main thing you must have.
All right?
May God bless you.
Now, ask me a question.
Seeker: What is the best approach we can take
to go to Laxmi?
Shri Mataji: I will tell you tomorrow about
Laxmi, where she is settled down.
That’s what we are going to do, all the
Goddess, not one.
All in one bundle.
Now what do you say to that?
Alright, good idea.
Seeker: Asks about how to deal with her worries.
Alright, doesn’t matter.
We are going to work it out.
Don’t worry about your personal things.
It’s all
going to work out en masse.
Don’t worry about your personal things,
just don´t worry.
There is nothing to worry
it is going to work out.
Is a working out I must say.
Yes, please.
Dr.
Warren: She is asking whether you said to
say, “Mother, I am not guilty”.
Shri Mataji: Yes, yes, please, within yourself.
Very important.
What is it?
Dr.
Warren:She is liking it!
Shri Mataji: Good, good.
May God bless you.
Don’t feel guilty at all.
Otherwise I would not come here.
The ones who have harmed you are guilty.
Seeker: What is your capacity and our capacity
to hate the devils.
Most religions preached that we should not
be angry.
Shri Mataji: You should not be angry, but
with Devils?
You run away from them.
Let me handle them.
You don´t worry.
You just don’t worry about them.
All right?
It’s my job.
First of all you love yourself, have self-esteem,
know that you are the temple of God, Then
you love by becoming realized, you become
collectively conscious.
Again the word becoming.
Then you start feeling the other within yourself.
Who is the other?
I am not helping you, you are part and parcel
of my being.
If I am helping my finger, am I helping you?
Then we see about the rest of the thing.
You don’t worry about them.
Seeker: Many of the people who come to my
clinic have activated their Kundalini too
early and I’m wondering how to help them.
Shri Mataji: They do not activate their Kundalini,
they do not.
All these things are just to activate the
sympathetic and it’s very dangerous.
You can get blisters, you can get all kinds
of problems.
You can get cancer also.
I get so many people like that.
I’ll make you the masters.
It’s Love.
It cannot harm.
It’s your Mother.
That’s the only Mother you have and you
are the only child.
How can your Kundalini trouble you?
She is just waiting for the moment to give
you realization.
She loves you the most of all.
And you cannot activate it, it just spontaneously
rises.
I was myself amazed to read some books on
Kundalini.
I said these people don’t know what Kundalini
is.
They tell lies
They’re liars.
They are cheats writing such big books about
Kundalini without knowing a word, without
having any authority.
You have to have Divine Authority, isn’t
it?
You cannot get it in a Theological college
or any place you go to.
You can not.
Its a Divine Authority you must have.
Seeker: Should we love our enemies as well?
Shri Mataji: First of all you love yourself
and your friends.
Then we can talk of enemies.
You have to know who are your enemies.
Actually, you don’t know who are your enemies.
First, we have to develop that discretion
power.
By your vibrations you will know who is who,
because once you are connected with the mains,
you start feeling it.
You can ask any question whichever is an absolute
question.
You can ask is there God?
You will start feeling a cool breeze coming
in.
Like a computer, you become connected with
the mains and you answer all these questions.
You develop your discretion and you will know
who are yours and who are not yours.
Before that you don’t know, you are so mixed
up.
Actually there are very few enemies that you
have, very few.
Should we now have it?
You’ve got that door open there.
Just get one of the doors open for some of
the enemies to fly out.
Dr.
Warren: If anyone has their shoes on, take
them off and simply put your hands out towards
Mataji as if asking for it.
Be humble about it.
Be open-minded.
If you’ve got a lot of questions…
Shri Mataji: Sit comfortably.
There is nothing to put yourself to stay.
Your neck should be bending neither forward
nor backward.
There is no effort to be put in.
Just sit comfortably.
Kundalini will rise by itself and you’ll
get your Realization.
You don’t have to do anything.
Just don’t put your concentration onto one
point.
Some people have a habit of concentrating
here, concentrating there.
All those people who have done this concentration
business or, what is that the another one,
putting the tongue back?
(kechari mudra).
Whatever you have done, all such people should
put their attention here (top of head).
There is the door, not here.
That’s all.
But rest of the people just keep your attention
absolutely loose.
Now, close your eyes.
Keep your eyes closed, because Kundalini has
to pass through Agnya chakra and if your eyes
are not closed, she won’t rise.
Put your hands towards me just like this.
All of you, please put your hands, because
in the hands you have those centers.
I would request you to take out if there is
anything heavy in your necks.
Please, take off.
It is better.
Also, if there is anything heavy or tight
on your waist.
You can loosen your belt a little bit.
Just put your hands towards me.
Close your eyes.
Please, put your right hand on your heart,
because Spirit resides in our heart.
Sit very comfortably without any strain on
your back.
That is very important.