So now we will be going for our further movement
and I may have to return back to Bombay.
I do not know how comfortable you were here,
but you wanted to be away from the maddening
crowd and I thought this would be the nice
place to be here though Dhumal was all the
time insisting that they should stay in some
Mangalkaryalay or something.
But I told him, “You don’t understand
them, they don’t enjoy much of all this
cement, concrete.”
They would always like to be in the company
of nature as long as they get some protection
from the sun and the rain and they want to
enjoy that kind of a collective living and
they’ll be very happy.
But still I don’t think he was very much
convinced about it, very hesitant.
Then again he came to Bombay, I again told
him, “Now believe Me, you have to have it
somewhere.
You just have a pendal for them, they’ll
be very happy, you just don’t worry about
other things.
They want to be with the nature because they
don’t get a chance like that.
They cannot take bath in a lake anywhere,
it’s a great chance for them to take a bath.”
They said the water is not so clean and maybe
that it is full of clay.
I said, “Clay is good for them, they’ll
like it, there’s …” And I see your skin,
it’s so much better, I see your skin, you
see all this you have suffered the sun burnt,
whatever you overdid in Ganapatipule, is now
being cleared out by this clay because the
clay is the one that soothes you.
Even if you can put some clay on your stomach,
it will take out all the heat from your stomach,
very good for liver this clay is.
So, I told them that you don’t understand
that this natural naturopathy that they can
have here, they cannot have it.
But he very, very reluctantly agreed thinking
that I’m really trying to be hard on you.
So, this is a mild sun here and it’s nice
and the atmosphere is very clear and clean,
plus you have got such a beautiful temple
of Ekadesha Rudra here which is such a nice
place we have found out.
So for a saint, you see, for a saintly person,
what does he need?
Because he’s so satisfied with everything.
Whatever he gets he’s satisfied.
But he will be more satisfied, he would be
much more enjoying when he’s with the nature.
I know that.
And, they are not still very happy the Rahuri
people that they think that this is no way
of putting up guests like this and all that,
still.
I just had to tell him that you see their
faces, how they look, they look so very happy,
so very relaxed, now what do you want?
What do you want more?
But now we must understand that one habit
that we have always, we have developed it
because we have been going out.
Our attention has been going out.
You see the one habit that we have in the
West, which I have noticed also, very common,
is, to be a daredevil for everything and to
go to the extreme.
You see there’s no …
[Shri Mataji asks a yogi] How do you say to
the bridle?
Bridle you say, the one that is used for the
horse?
Bridle.
The bridle is not there.
There’s no bridle, in our behavior.
We go to extremes in everything.
Whatever we do, we go to extremes.
There’s no bridle in our hands and this
is what, one has to get to the bridle.
It is not that, it’s like a kite which is
just moving here and there, it’s not that.
It’s a complete thrust, complete movement
with all will power, with all effort, to go
to something that is dangerous.
I personally think it’s a self-destructive
character which is built within us as a result
of our movement too much outward.
Because whatever moves in one direction has
to recoil back, it has a reaction.
Like the science has developed atomic bomb.
Ultimately you do develop a destructive temperament
and that is why I think in the west people
have no idea how to control the speed backwards.
It’s more the speed outward to dangerous
places they like it.
Nature is good.
In the nature it’s nice to be there.
But it does not mean that you should ask the
nature to hit you and kill you.
Now in Ganapatipule I was so sad to see those
boys who burnt themselves.
It was really very, very saddening to Me and
when I treated them, of course they got well
but you wont’ believe the whole of My stomach
here, [SHRI MATAJI PUTS HER HAND ON HER STOMACH]
the whole skin of My stomach was burnt, charred
and burnt and is now peeling out, just like
they had the problem, I never went to the
sea, I never stayed there.
So, this was the heat they were carrying.
Now people get, say, what you call, skin troubles,
skin cancers.
Still they want to do it.
Like the other lady who was so sick from Switzerland
is so sick, you see, I was really very worried
because she was very dangerously placed and
she is the one who had this problem and she
said, “I have an addiction with the sun.”
How can you be addicted to the sun?
Is just a mental idea.
And believe Me, it’s just a mental idea
that if you go in the sun your skin will be
all right.
It’s just a mental idea.
Have you seen anyone like that?
I mean what is the proof that if you go in
the sun your skin will improve, what is the
proof?
We Indians never, never go in the sun.
Never.
We never go in a windy place, never in a windy
place, we never go, say for example this skiing.
According to us skiing is a stupid job.
We would never do it.
Any Indian who does that is a stupid fellow
according to us.
Women will never do horse riding because it
affects the uterus.
The women don’t swim after sometime because
it affects the uterus and if it affects the
uterus, it affects the whole system because
uterus represents your Kundalini.
All wrong ideas you have got.
That’s why I see that in the West everybody
is sick.
They have this trouble or that trouble or
this or that.
Certain principles are to be borne in our
mind because we are saints and we are precious
things.
We are not like other Westerners, that we
can waster our life like this for some sort
of a stupid venture that we think of .
Can you imagine all Indians have much better
skin than you have.
All right.
Don’t they?
Do they ever go in the sun?
Never.
Have you seen any Indian sitting outside here
taking sunbath?
I mean the proof of the pudding is that despite
all that your skins are so bad.
Now how can your skin be good with the sun,
let us see.
Let us say, Let us take absolutely a chemical
reaction.
Now what happens that when the, the thing
falls upon our skin or upon our head, this
head has got a brain and the brain is made
of fat.
All right?
Now if you put the fat in the sun, what will
happen?
It will melt.
And that’s how people have melted brains.
The brains are not normal, they behave in
a way which I don’t understand why they
behave like this.
So first of all if your brain goes out, how
can your skin be all right?
Because the brain controls the skin.
It controls everything.
If your brain goes off, I’ve not met one
person who looks beautiful because he has
been in the sun.
On the contrary, you stay at home.
Preserve your skin by staying at home.
The second point is that a Sahaja Yogi should
not behave like other Westerners do that at
every holiday, they’re out.
They never sit in the house.
Gruhastha.
The one who stays in the house.
We are all Gruhasthas, householders, we are
married people.
As soon as you get a holiday you’re out.
Now you might give an explanation, “Because
you see our houses are like this and, we think
that our houses are just suffocating us.”
Have you seen the houses of the poor people
here?
Have you seen the houses of the labor in Bombay?
Nobody goes out for a holiday.
All My life I don’t think I’ve been ever
out for a holiday with My husband.
Only once we tried for two days and we were
back from Scotland all the way.
We just go for a wedding or a festival or
something like that.
If there’s some collective happening or
else you can go for a picnic, all of you together.
But you must sit down in the house and talk
to each other nicely, there should be some
rapport.
There’s no rapport between the children
and the parents, there’s no rapport between
the husband and the wife, no rapport between
the in-laws, other people, no rapport at all.
So you become people who are absolutely secluded,
shooting off this way, that way, that way.
Sit down and talk.
Now you see our children, now we talk that
our children should be disciplined.
The best way to discipline your child is to
make the child sit down for a while and talk
to the child properly.
Tell the child what he’s supposed to do.
You’ll find an Indian child goes to somebody’s
house just keeps quite.
But let an English child come.
He will break this, he’ll break that, give
me chocolates, give me this, I want this.
You take an Indian child, maybe a poor child
to a market, he’ll never ask for anything,
demand for anything.
Never.
Even if you give, he’ll say, “No, I won’t
have.”
He has that self-respect.
But if you take a child, any other child,
he’ll say, “Please buy me this, please
buy me that, please buy me that.”
Without any self-respect, without any discipline.
Now where does the discipline come up?
Now what we do, supposing a child is there,
we are going out, we tell the child, “Now
we are going out, and you have to be a self-respecting
child because,” supposing now you are talking
you can say, “You are a realized soul, you
are a Sahaja Yogi and you can’t behave like
a stupid fellow asking for this and that,”
and sit down quietly, make them sit down.
To begin with, you have to do lot of massaging
on their body.
Lots of massaging, everyday massage, massage,
massage the body so the nerves are all right.
Then, when you take them out or do anything,
before hand, tell them properly, build up
their personality of self-respect, of discipline.
But you yourself should be disciplined, now
you are sitting in the sun, say, for the whole
day and you tell your son, “Get inside the
house,” how will he?
A Sahaja Yogi should never go in the sun.
Take it from Me.
Never, never go in the sun.
Because this brain requires complete quietitude
and no sun activity is needed.
You should not even, when you sleep, there
should not be even a ray of sun.
Even I, when I sleep I want complete darkness.
Even a slightest ray of light is coming, which
people know very well, I cannot sleep, because
I must act.
So the reaction to this light is so much in
Me, maybe that I’m very sensitive to all
the elements but what about you?
You must avoid the sun’s light as much as
you can when you sleep and also should not
sit in the sun for such a long time.
Of course sitting in the sun helps you because
it gives you Vitamin D, by which, Vitamin
D if you take it you build up your bones better
but now I think your bones are quite built,
there’s no need to build your bones anymore.
But now by God’s grace you are getting soluble
calciums which you can eat and you can also
have Vitamin D and A if you want to.
What is the need of scorching this head?
Now, if you sit in the sun, then either you
will have a bald head or you will have a jungle
in the head.
One of the two thing’s depending on the
personality as you are.
Because your brain cannot bear it, your skin
cannot bear it.
After all we are not jungle people are we?
But you ask any jungle person also, he never
sits in the sun.
It’s only somebody has cooked it in your
head that you must sit in the sun.
If you go and see Eskimos who live in the
ice houses, they never bathe in the sun.
Have you ever seen them sunbathing?
Have you ever seen them?
Any picture, anywhere?
Then why this special type of stupidity is
there among other people because you have
lost that sense to know that you are maneuvered.
You see, how to befool you.
Now you must create some weaknesses for people,
if you don’t create a weakness how will
they prosper with their machineries?
So now, let’s befool them.
If you go to the seashore and you tan your
body, you look very beautiful?
First of all, you never, you look horrid,
horrid you look and secondly they will say
that your health will be all right so everybody
is going to the seashore, ending up with a
skin cancer.
Because your body revolts against it that’s
why you get skin cancer.
You get liver troubles, already you are liverish.
You are already thinking too much, why do
you want to have sun?
You’ve already too much sun within yourself.
So what is the reasoning for it?
I just don’t understand.
You must know that today we have the work
of the Sahasrara and the Sahasrara is the
brain.
We have to work on the brain and if you people
do not know how to use your brain properly,
I don’t know what am I going to do.
Moreover today, talking to some Indians, I
discovered some horrifying things which I
must tell you, which is horrifying as well
as laughed at They were telling Me that if
you take an English hen and an Indian hen,
there’s a tremendous big difference between
the two.
The hen that is Indian, if she sees another
hen being attacked she’ll make such a noise
that all the hen will join together and will
start making noises so that if there’s an
attack the master will come and try to remove
the attack.
But if it’s an English hen, she will just
watch another being eaten up you see and then
she’s eaten up also, she says, “All right
you eat me, doesn’t matter, I’ll take
second birth and come back.”
See they’ve no brains at all.
You see they have no brains, like say an English
bullock, they have English bullocks also.
I mean English means Western, they don’t
mean anything else but he’s Australian,
maybe anything, is English to us because we
had known only English so we say English.
But that’s what they say English but it
doesn’t mean anything, it means any Westerner
or any Australian or white skin person.
A bullock is there, he said, “Our bullocks
if you tell them.
‘go straight,’ they know; if you tell
them, ‘go left,’ they know; if you tell
them, ‘walk this way,’ they know;they
know everything.
But if you have any of these bullocks, they
don’t do anything.
You tell them go further, you teach them anything,
nothing, they will never learn any thing.
You tell them, they’ll go the way they want
to go.”
So very surprising, I said, “Really?”
“Yes” they said, “It is so, they are
for no good, they can just do what they want
to do.
They cannot understand what you’re talking,
they have no understanding about it.”
Imagine about the bulls.
And then think of it, in India, you see we
have everything walking on the street, we
have got the bullocks and we have got the
cows, we’ve got sometimes the hen, everything
goes on the road.
They know which side the thing is coming,
which side they have to move, there’s a
car coming.
He said, “Put one English cow, they’ll
be all finished on the road.”
I got such a fright you know when I heard
it.
I said, “They do not do sunbathing.
How do they get it?” then I was thinking
that the kind of the food you give them, there
must be some horrible hormones, they must
be spoiling their brains.
But we are very destructive, I must tell you.
Drugs, now we started taking to drugs, in
the name of God.
I mean Indians, you make them take drugs,
they’ll say tell another, I know what it
is.
And then our brains go off with drugs.
Brains are not normal, why we behave like
this I can only explain that they have taken
drugs, I’ve seen people who have taken drugs
I just don’t understand why, there’s no
logic into their behavior.
Just no logic, they just, like the brains
of a bullock, they behave the same way.
You just can’t explain why they behave.
They have taken drugs.
Now what is drug taking?
Is again self-destructive.
Because you want to destroy yourself that’s
why you’ve taken drugs.
Otherwise how many Indians you have known
who take drugs?
I’ve never even seen them.
And another thing, Dhumal told Me, I mean
he says his reading is he says that if a child
is educated in a vernacular school, I was
also educated in a vernacular school because
My father was very particular, “Nothing
doing, no English schools.”
And those who are educated in the English
schools, there’s such a difference, he say’s
he has his children educated in the English
school and he has his children educated in
a vernacular school.
The youngest one is in the vernacular school.
He says he knows about everything.
He’ll know how many cows are in the house,
he will look after parrots, he knows how the
parrot works out, how the things are, he’s
the youngest.
He knows about everything but other children
they just will stand.
If you tell them, they’ll give an explanation
and then they say, “So what?
So what?”
But if you tell him something, immediately
he will know what is to be done, he’ll just
get it done the way he wants to do it, in
the sense that it must be done.
But here the other way round.
If you tell a child from an English school,
he will do the way he wants to do and if you
tell him, “Why did you do this way?” he’ll
say, “What’s wrong?” or at the most
he’ll say, “I’m sorry.”
Finished.
I mean like Sahaja Yogis will pull their ears,
finished.
Even if he hit’s you, he’ll say, “Pull
my ear’s Mother, I’ve hit You.”
It’s like that.
It’s very funny thing, I said what’s wrong
with the language?
Why this English language makes people like
that?
I can’t understand.
Why?
I just didn’t understand.
“What’s wrong?”
Now this is not in any Indian language, you
see if you say, they’ll say, “What?
We didn’t understand, what are you saying,
‘What’s wrong?’”
I mean just, the whole, I think the language
itself has the disciplining in-built, it’s
a what you call Mardav, it builds up the personality.
Like if somebody tries to show off.
You see, immediately we’ll say, “You are
over wise.”
Ati Shahane.
And the saying is, “Ati Shahane tyanche
baila rikame.”
Those who try to show that they are very intelligent,
their bullocks have no work, means they’re
lazy lumps.
The whole language system is such.
They’re so practical I tell you, they’re
so practical.
And that is why, we came to India first of
all, we had some Sahaja Yogis with us when
we came here about twenty-five Sahaja Yogis
from England came and we all stayed here and
all these people looked after them and they
fed them and of course I mean, they had paid
no money, nothing they lived there.
Nobody even wrote a letter of thanks so they
all got worried and they wrote a letter to
Me saying that Mother what has happened, are
they all right or are they sick?
They have not written any letter to us.
So I called them, I said, “Did you write
any letters to them?”
“No”.
I said, “Why?”
“We know, we know, we did wrong, we know.”
“You know, then why did you not do it?”
“No but we know.”
Now what is an argument here?
Now you have come out of that, what I’m
giving you, the background.
You have come out of it, now you are Sahaja
Yogis, you are saints, so you have to be very
different.
You can’t be like them.
You have to understand.
Like some people have a habit of saying, “Ah,
Mother I’m so badly off.”
You ask them, “How are you?”
They’ll say [SHRI MATAJI SWAYS HER HAND
INDICATING ‘SO-SO’] like this, it’s
very common, so I look at their hands, what’s
it?
I don’t understand.
What does that [SHRI MATAJI SWAYS HER HAND
INDICATING ‘SO-SO’] mean?
Here people will feel ashamed to say.
Even if you are sick, even if you are dying.
If somebody will ask, “How are you?”
They will say, “I’m all right.
I’m all right.”
Nobody will do like this [SHRI MATAJI SWAYS
HER HAND INDICATING ‘SO-SO’] Means what?
You ask them “What’s your name?”
“Did you ask my name?”
“Of course I did, but why do you ask Me
again?”
Any question you ask, they will repeat it,
always.
I used to wonder why do they repeat?
And they didn’t get it in their heads or
what?
Now the thing is, that is what is the background
of this brain and don’t spoil it more by
this sun.
You have to do work of this Sahasrara, Sahasrara
which is the lotus, lotus of the Divine which
has got beautiful petals now enlightened by
your Kundalini.
They are the living petals, do not try to
play with it.
That’s why I say, don’t read funny books,
don’t see funny things, don’t talk to
funny people, don’t waste your energy in
worrying, in futuristic attitude, keep to
yourself.
Let this [SHRI MATAJI PUTS HER HAND ON HER
HEAD] grow because the roots are in the brain.
The tree of awareness grows downward but the
roots are in the brain and you have to go
to the roots now because you have done that
movement now you come back and for that you
have to know to look after your brain.
The other day I also said that I don’t know
why you people don’t put any oil whatsoever.
Why not put oil in the head, poor head needs
the oil always, at least on a Saturday, put
so much oil, rub it nicely and have a bath.
But people just don’t put any oil in their
head.
I mean you must oil, gear up your brain, don’t
you think so?
If you don’t put oil in any machine, it
will crack.
For this brain which is your special machine
after Sahaja Yoga is really a very special
one, you must try to put lot of oil in it.
Put some oil in the ears, put some oil in
the nose.
Now the modern theory of the doctors is don’t
put any oil or anything into the ears and
the noses of the children.
Rajesh’s brother had a child and they went
to of course to a latest Doctor from America.
And the child was crying, weeping, feeling
so horrible and his Brahmarandra, what you
call, the fontanel bone area was not filled
at all, it was all open.
I said, “What’s the matter with you people?”
They said the doctor has said, “Don’t
touch the oil.”
I said, “What?”
They said, “He’ll have allergy”.
I said, “Nothing of the kind, you bring
the oil.”
I got one full katori [KATORI MEANS BOWL IN
HINDI] of oil, rubbed it on his head, pushed
back that thing and I put it in nose, in ears,
the child slept like a log of wood.
Imagine how much the child must have suffered?
These stupid ideas come from where?
I don’t know, they don’t have any oil
these days, so what is their idea is to do,
some business must be behind it, I don’t
know what is going on.
I don’t know what they are going to run
by not giving any oil to the children.
They must be having some business with that
also.
Otherwise it is absolutely a stupid idea.
I just don’t understand that the child has
an allergy.
But how presumptuous to think like that!
Now why the child has an allergy.
Now let Me ask a question.
Why a child will have an allergy?
The doctors have to answer.
Or, of course you are all doctors so you should
say.
Can I have the answer?
Yogi: It could be an imbalance of heat and
cold in the body?
Shri Mataji: But why?
Say on the chakras.
You say on the chakras what will be catching.
If somebody has allergies, what does it catch?
Yogi: The Left Nabhi.
Shri Mataji: Correct.
Left Nabhi.
Left Nabhi will catch.
Now that means the mother.
Because the child is not yet married so it’s
the mother.
That means mother must be having a left Nabhi
herself and that’s why the child must catching
with that allergy, so instead of punishing
the child, why not cure the left Nabhi of
the mother and left Nabhi of the child?
Now what will you do if there’s a left Nabhi
of the child?
What we can do to help the child to get rid
of it?
Ah, very simple.
Anything that is left can be taken out on
the little flame.
Put your right hand on the left Nabhi of the
child and put your left hand to the flame
and finished.
Now in diagnosis you are easy but now for
medicines, now remember the certain principles
of medicines.
Very certain principles are there.
If it is left side, you have take it to the
fire or to the sun or to the flames, all right?
If it is a left side [could Shri Mataji have
meant “right”?] you have take it to the
water in general.
Any body suffering from right side, put him
in the water, finished.
Done.
Not in the sun of course.
Any disease, you bring it to this point.
It’s very simple.
Now let Me have some questions about certain
diseases.
Yogi: They’ve been asking Me for the last
three weeks.
Shri Mataji: Huh?
Yogi: They’ve been asking Me for the last
three weeks, so they must have it.
Shri Mataji: All right let’s have it, I
will see if I can answer.
Yes.
Yogi: Psoriasis, Mother?
Shri Mataji: Huh?
Yogi: Psoriasis.
Shri Mataji: Same thing.
Psoriasis is nothing else but left side problem.
Is a lethargic liver.
And gives you allergies.
For psoriasis, left hand towards the photograph
and right hand on the Mother Earth.
Putting hot water bottle on the stomach.
Or even giving bandhan to your liver with
the light is all right.
You must see, because psoriasis, now people
might think psoriasis means active liver or
inactive liver, you see it comes to that point.
But we have only two types: active or inactive.
Now whether psoriasis is inactive or active
you will know from one point that when the
liver is inactive you get the allergies, and
when it is active you get other problems like
what you call that in English, I don’t know,
nausea and also you get biliousness.
You don’t eat much, you thin down all these
problems are there.
Now what else?
Yogi: Eczema?
Shri Mataji: For eczema same thing.
Eczema is the same thing, is just like allergy,
eczema same thing.
But for eczema because it’s outward you
can use certain things like neem ka pata and
all that I’ve told you and so many things
can be used on top.
Yogi: Fungus?
Shri Mataji: Fungus, outside or inside?
Yogi: On the skin.
Shri Mataji: Is one of the worst thing is
fungus.
Same thing, but it’s the worst thing I should
say that it’s the left side again is the
attack is the left side fungus is all dead
and you have to use the left side towards
the photograph and right hand on the places
wherever you have the fungus, you may take
it out that way but don’t eat cheese, and
the fungousy cheese you are not supposed to
eat at all.
All the Sahaja Yogis should not eat any fungousy
cheese.
That blue one, with a crust one, all fungus
must to avoided, and also mushrooms if possible.
Yogi: Why does cow’s milk make allergies
and eczema worse?
Shri Mataji: What is…?
Yogi: Why does cow’s milk make allergies
and eczema worse?
Shri Mataji: Cow’s milk..
Yogi: Because it’s left side?
Shri Mataji: Left side.
Cow’s milk always give you the left side
because she’s the mother, and you should
not have her milk, because it’s left sided.
Whether it is cow’s milk or buffalo’s
milk, all will give allergies but if you have
animals which are smaller than you like if
you can drink like Mahatma Gandhi the goat’s
milk then you might not have the problem.
Yogi: We do completely around..
When we have diarrhea we drink milk.
Shri Mataji: Diarrhea you drink milk?
The amount of salads you eat, sometimes I
think this fodder will make us like buffalos
or what?
I just can’t touch them I tell you.
But I have to eat just to show that I appreciate.
Yogi: Bronchial Asthma.
Shri Mataji: Bronchial asthma is caused by
the combination of the right heart and the
left heart.
If the parents have been quarreling too much,
if they are divorced, if you never had the
security of the parent’s love, then you
get bronchial asthma, but if it is another
one just superficial one then it could be
from the father’s death or from the fatherhood
suffering but if father and motherhood both
have made you insecure or if both of them
have died then you get bronchial asthma.
Is a combination.
Yogi: Hypoglycemia.
Shri Mataji: What’s that?
Yogi: Low blood level.
Hypo-glycemia.
Shri Mataji: I know.
Low blood level.
That comes from over activity.
You should not think so much.
Agnya.
Too much of Agyna.
Agnya chakra.
Too much of agnya.
Surrender yourself to Christ, absolutely surrender
yourself to Christ, it will work out.
Yogi: Spondylitis.
Shri Mataji: Spondylitis is left Vishuddhi.
And right Vishuddhi could be also.
But mostly left Vishuddhi Spondylitis.
Combination also could be.
Yogi: Multiple Sclerosis.
Shri Mataji: Multiple Sclerosis is comes from
Mooladhara.
Mooladhara and Nabhi.
Left Nabhi and Mooladhara.
It’s more left sided.
Give the treatment of the left side.
Saying the name of Ganesha and of Gauri.
It will work out.
Yogi: Varicose veins Mother.
Shri Mataji: Huh?
Yogi: Varicose veins.
Shri Mataji: It comes from the people who
stand too much all the time and they work
very hard.
As soon as it starts it’s better to cure
them, you have to lie down everyday.
Those who stand everyday for more than say
three-four hours should lie down on bed and
do cycling.
[SHRI MATAJI MAKES CYCLING MOVEMENTS WITH
HER HANDS].
Everyday, that will help reduce the weight
maybe due to weight also.
Some people have weight, but those who stand,
I’ve seen those who stand for a long time
without the heels, if you use the heels you
might be better off.
With the heels the pressure is not so much
then it is distributed more to the lower of
those five chakras down below that might help.
But, best is to do exercise after you have
stood for a long time just lie down in the
bed and do cycling, and also massaging, slowly
massaging it downward.
Also it can work out with the ice treatment,
you can put some ice before massaging you
can put the ice on them and use very cold
oil and rub it, it will work out.
Yogi: Flu?
Flu?
Shri Mataji: That’s one thing is difficult.
Flu.
Now for flu, first of all this is again left-sided.
But we have got a very good medicine in India
I don’t know if you have that there is what
you call is the basil [IN HINDI IT IS CALLED
TULSI].
Basil leaves, you take lots of basil leaves
make a concoction, it’s called?
Yogi: Infusion.
Shri Mataji: Huh?
Shri Mataji: No.
Yogi: Boil it up in a pot.
Shri Mataji: Boil it up in a pot, make it
absolutely, the essence take it out quite
thick put tea in it or wateror just like the
way you want to make it like a tea and put
milk or whichever way you want but less milk
and sugar because the taste may not be so
good.
And then you drink it, before that you have
to prepare some what you call for dhuni?
You all know ajwain ka dhuni.
You see you know that.
So you take ajwain ka dhuni after that, that’s
all.
You do it three days you’ll be all right,
cleared out.
Yogi: Shri Mataji, psychosomatic diseases…?
Shri Mataji: What?
Yogi: He’s saying psychosomatic diseases
in particular, nervous break down comes from
where?
Right side or left side?
Shri Mataji: You see it’s a very funny word
psychosomatic means it’s also psycho and
it’s also somatic, so I don’t know which
one it is, if you say psycho somatic or somatic
psycho.
Yogi: You mean psychological diseases?
Shri Mataji: Nehi, nehi.
Psychosomatic is nervousness you see.
Nervousness can be caused by bad habits.
How?
Like if you are an air hostess you form a
bad habit, as soon as you see the airport
[SHRI MATAJI MOVES HER HAND AROUND HER STOMACH
INDICATING NERVOUSNESS].
Now those who travel too much.
As soon as they have to travel they go off
their heads.
Over doing anything, you see, you get nervous
feeling, it’s a matter of habit, you form
that habit so it happens.
So, I will not say it is due to some bhadha
or anything, but your nerves are too much
used in a particular way.
Then they just give in, they cannot work it
out anymore.
So then you must change that habit.
Supposing you are traveling too much by plane,
then travel by a ship, or travel by a train,
or by a bullock cart.
Or don’t travel, something like that, anything
that you over do too much that forms a kind
of a strain on your nerves.
So try to reduce that strain on your nerves.
Yogi: You recommended heels, what height?
Shri Mataji: No, no I didn’t say for all
of you.
I said for varicose veins.
Or specially for people who develop problems
on the heels.
There’s no height you just try whatever
you can say about one inch will do from one
inch onward, anything, not too much one inch
or lower, but you see if you develop some
sort of a bone on your heels or something
like that for that the heels are always better.
Little heels are better.
Baldness.
It’s not a disease.
But it comes out of many habits.
One of them is wearing the hat.
If you wear the hat too tight then the circulation
of the brain is spoiled and that’s when
you might get one.
Then also with the left Nabhi you might develop
a back bald head here if you have a left Nabhi
then their’s no circulation, it works out
that way.
And they say that if somebody has a bald head
he will get some money, he’s a moneyed man,
in India.
I don’t know why we believe in such a thing,
but we believe that if you have a bald head
means he’s a moneyed man, you see, the one
who does not have a bald head is not a moneyed
man, who doesn’t have a belly is not a dignified
man, according to Indian standards.
But bald head is caused by not using oil.
Or, by not using proper oil.
Oil should be used properly and the skull
must be actually the skull must be rubbed
not the skin so that if you rub it the skin
must move on the skull and then you won’t
have this problem.
Another is that if you use funny type of oils
with lots of fragrance and essences in it
then you might get grey hair.
And also ghee should never be used for rubbing
in the head but you can use it for the body
is good ghee or even the butter is good if
you are overactive, then, otherwise not, but
ghee should never be used or butter should
never be used for the hair.
Now you have two types of bald heads, as I
told you.
Some who start from here and some who start
from there.
[SHRI MATAJI POINTS TO THE FRONT OF HER HEAD
AND THEN TO THE BACK].
It’s a very interesting subject.
[YOGIS LAUGH TOO].
And, those who have both, could be.
Now I would say the one which starts from
here [SHRI MATAJI POINTS TO THE FRONT OF THE
HEAD] are the people who are the ones who
have got an Ekadesha problem also possibly.
With the Ekadesha problem it starts or who
are not very collective or something, it will
start receding back.
All right, those who start from here [SHRI
MATAJI POINTS TO THE BACK OF THE HEAD] are
the people who may not be good husbands, maybe
something wrong with their wives, maybe bad
wives, the husband-wife relationship is upsetting
then also this starts at the back or maybe
there’s some incompatibility between the
two or too much attachment to the wife or
too much attachment to the husband also you
start developing like that.
All these things are left Nabhi, so the left
Nabhi relationship you know is the Gruha Lakshmi
relationship, where you adore your wife so
much that she’s no more a Gruha Lakshmi
also is a wrong thing, these things start
with that.
And also could be, also could be with your
hectic life, if you are very hectic in your
life running up and down doing too much work
also it may start, you don’t listen to your
wife about it and you think you have to do
this work then also it might start it there
are so many reasons for the left Nabhi to
start, but the one that starts here [SHRI
MATAJI POINTS TO HER FOREHEAD AREA] starts
with the right Nabhi or we can say with the
Ekadesha more on this side.
So I don’t know in your case, Johan, what
should I blame.
I would say is a complete neglect, complete
neglect of your hair, no oiling at all that’s
what it is, I mean if you do not give water
to the plant it will die and then if you say
why is it caused, I mean if you don’t give
it water it’s the one that it eats, drinks
and lives on so oil is the one on which the
hair reside.
Yogi: In the west we get pain in the knees
when we sit on the ground, is there anyway
of avoiding it?
Shri Mataji: You see it is due to the Nabhi
you have.
Right or the left and no practice of sitting
down.
Now what you have to do that you have to learn
a certain what you call an exercise.
I’ve told people what is the exercise needed
for it then you’ll get used to it you’ll
start sitting on the ground all right without
feeling the pain on the knees.
It will help you in the long run very much.
There are certain exercises to be done.
But at least your children you make them sit
on the ground from now so that there’s no
problem for them.
Yogi: I noticed that a lot of ladies…
Shri Mataji: Here?
In the West?
Yogi: When I came to Paris, I noticed a lot
of ladies after sixty years old began to lose
hair.
Shri Mataji: But sixty years one should have
that otherwise they don’t look all right,
you see, in sixty years you should look like
a sixty year old, you see, otherwise it’s
very embarrassing.
For Me I must say I must also get some bald
head and some wrinkles and this and that.
Because, you see, once we were traveling and
we had some lady with us she’s six years
younger to Me and Modi was all the time trying
to help her, poor old lady, poor old lady,
I said what’s this nonsense, she’s six
years, younger to Me and you are just trying
to help her all the time.
What about Me?
Nobody’s bothered, they make Me sit for
hours together, they do this, do that.
Supposing if I looked old, you would have
said, “No, no Mother, you must be tired.”
Now the ladies develop that because they might
be dominating women – possibly, or maybe
they are neglecting their hair.
Yogi: Or drunkenness.
Shri Mataji: Huh?
Shri Mataji: Drunkenness, also could be they
might have taken drugs or maybe, in the west
anything is possible under the sun, you see,
or maybe, they’ve had some problems with
their mothers or something like that basically
must be there but I think mostly it is due
to neglect, complete neglect of the hair.
You see these hair styles, now you go to any
person who is doing this hair styling within
three years time we are bald, then they will
give a wig, that’s their business.
So going to these hair dressers and all that
you develop it.
What is the need to go to the hair dresser?
I don’t understand.
There’s no need, waste your time, waste
your money.
You look very nice without it.
Yogi: Is there a chance to get lost hair back?
Shri Mataji: Huh?
What she…?
Yogi: Is there a chance to get lost hair back?
Shri Mataji: Ah, you might.
Try.
If not by Sahaja Yoga, they say there is a
method.
They put something here there [SHRI MATAJI
POINTS TO THE TOP OF HER HEAD] and they plant
it and all those things they do.
If you do it then I’ll see to it that they
grow well.
Yogi: Why are diseases through generations
limited to seven generations?
Or any trouble, Mother, that comes through
the generations?
Shri Mataji: The problems are like this.
There’s only one center which covers all
the seven centers which is the Mooladhara.
Because it is the Omkara.
It is the Chaitanya.
If Mooladhara is insulted, say I said that
if there’s an incest relationship and the
family grows then it is seven generations.
But, if it is between a very holy relationship
like a mother and a son or something like
that then it is fourteen generations.
It’s complete insult of Shri Ganesh and
so many of these can come from there most
of it comes because Shri Ganesha gives you
the real strength.
Those who have insulted Shri Ganesha are always
delicate people physically, so you have to
reestablish your Shri Ganesh.
Yogi: …How to keep the body cool in summer?.
Shri Mataji: Uh?
Yogi: How to keep the body cool in summer?
Shri Mataji: To keep the body cool in summer
first of all you have to do is to take some
ice and rub it on your liver, keep the liver
cool, don’t think too much, don’t take
hot things like in the summer time so many
people eat those watermelons and things like
that.
They should be cooled down properly, like
even mangos in India must be cooled down and
then taken.
All such fruits should be cooled down and
then eaten.
Some people eat the mangos just from the tree,
that’s very wrong.
You have to cool it down for twenty-four hours
and then eat it.
This we knew all of us, but in modern times
I don’t know if people don’t know.
All these things add up.
Then reduce on meats and fish specially, you
should not eat fish in the summertime at all.
First of all it is spoiled, something wrong
with it or else it has phosphorous which ignites
you.
So avoid all these things, eat things which
are cool.
Now specially for India it is very easy because
we have got something called gool khand which
is made out of rose petals which is a very
good thing for cooling the liver, then cardamom,
then the candy sugar, sugar itself.
All these things will cool down your liver
and you’ll feel very good.
It’s the change in your diet is very important
during the summertime.
Yogi: Hemorrhoids, is it a Mooladhara problem?
Hemorrhoids?
Shri Mataji: Right side.
Right side Mooladhara.
Right side.
For that you have to keep yourself cool, again
get the cooling effects, all the cooling things
to be done and also a very good thing is to
eat the black dried grapes.
What do you call them?
Yogi: Raisins.
Shri Mataji: Raisins.
Black raisins, soak them in the night with
some orange juice and eat them, I mean soak
them in the morning eat them in the night
before sleeping.
That
will cool down, that’s very, very cooling
[HINDI] I’ve forgotten the name.
[MARATHI] For allergy the best is gheru, you
take all of you, you should take gheru those
who suffer from allergy and we get little
stone pieces round ones rub it on that and
take it with some water about seven times
and then eat it, is good for allergies, but
everybody should not only those who have allergies,
gheru is not good for people who have overactive
liver.
Now if you’re finished, huh..
Shri Mataji: Kya?
[IT MEANS “WHAT?”
IN HINDI]
Yogi: India has the biggest problem of leprosy
particularly Bihar and U.P., what is the reason?
Shri Mataji: It’s a kind of a, you know
it’s an infectious disease and now they
have found some sort of a thing for that leprosy,
is not only in India it was everywhere, but
you know the [HINDI] the ones what you call
them the parasites which create this leprosy
drink kerosene oil, petrol, they prosper in
petrol, do you know that?
Yogi: What is the treatment in Sahaja for
that?
Shri Mataji: For leprosy, you see, for any
infection as such it’s all left-sided.
One can work it out but as far as possible
keep out of it.
Infectious diseases you better not treat.
This is very dangerous, I will never advise
you because you shouldn’t waste your energy
on lepers now, leave them to Me.
Which is the easiest way to cure yourself?
Yogi: What about people who are born with
epilepsy?
Shri Mataji: Oh, epilepsy is curable, hundred
percent curable, it’s a left-sided problem,
epilepsy whether born or anything can be cured,
can be cured.
Yogi: [SAYS SOMETHING INAUDIBLE]
Huh?
Excessive?
Yogi: Excessive tooth decay?
Shri Mataji: Tooth decay?
You see for tooth decay the thing is you must
use your fingers to rub on your teeth you
see that’s the thing and also on your gums.
So what you have because you have got vibrations,
your right Vishuddhi’s quite all right,
it is due to right Vishuddhi, so what you
have to do is deficiency in Right Vishuddhi
gives you, rub it nicely with olive oil and
little salt, very good finely thinned out
salt and it will stop it everyday, everyday,
brushing is not sufficient.
Shri Mataji: One more, one more.
One more here.
What’s it?
Sit down, sit down.
Yogi: What is the reason for having your intestines
all on the left side?
Shri Mataji: All on the left side?
Nothing on the right.
Good idea.
Left side.
There’s no reason as such you see after
all think that God creates so many human beings.
Even I mean you tell about two hundred people
to do some work, one goes this way, another
goes that way, you don’t know what happens,
they go so helter-skelter.
Now in that sometimes it’s a freak it happens,
there are freaks, it makes no difference.
All right, what do you want?
What’d she say?
Yogi: Ulcerative colitis.
Shri Mataji: Ulcerative colitis comes by people
who have amebiosis maybe one of them could
be, is it there?
Hmm.
Yogi: Is there amebiosis?
Shri Mataji: Yeah, yes.
Could be due to that.
Or could be due to very hot food if you eat,
or if you drink too much and all these things
you see can be affecting, but mostly it is
due to amebiosis I’ve seen it and hot food,
you shouldn’t eat hot food, like some people
like very hot food and they get this trouble.
Yogi: Does anyone have a question that’s
a little more visionary?
A little less medical.
What about Hailey’s Comet appearing later
this year?
Shri Mataji: I’ve seen it.
This Mr. Hailey had seen it and he said this
will happen, that will happen and they say
so it’s a good sign, let’s see, you see
whatever maybe the stars, whatever may be
the things, unless and until human beings
become sensitive nothing can happen.
We have to be sensitive people to receive
the blessings of these things otherwise Hailey
may come, Mailey may come but we go on forever
to be.
If we are become sensitive then only it will
happen, first of all when there is ego what’s
it’s nothing is going to work out.
Ego has to go down and you have to feel everything,
the vibrations and everything of the atmosphere
of all the stars, then it will work out.
Otherwise, it has no effect.
Yogi: What is the proper attitude when we
take darshan from You?
I’ve never known how to approach You.
Shri Mataji: Oh, it’s rather embarrassing.
All right I’ll close My eyes and My face
and I’ll tell you [MARATHI].
Now.
Your question is nice.
Now supposing Christ appears before you and
you know He’s Christ, what will happen?
That should be the attitude at least minimum,
though Christ had to manage only one chakra
I have to manage seven.
If that attitude develops even thinking of
Me is sufficient, you have to just think of
Me your diseases will be cured.
That depth has to be there.
This is just one chakra seven times raised
to the power seven.
That’s what it is.
You have seen the miracles, you have seen
the photographs, you have seen thousands getting
Realization, none of them did it.
But also I’m Mahamaya.
But in your heart you should know whom you
are facing.
But mostly people get into the web of Mahamaya
very much that awe is so fulfilling, so penetrating,
so deep that one lives with that idea only
all the time, you don’t need anything with
that.
It’s a very great fortune, if I were you
I would have called Myself the most fortunate
person, but it’s the other way round, I
don’t know what to say then, though I must
say that I’m very fortunate because compared
to all of them I have so many of you here
who are Sahaja Yogis, so I’m very fortunate,
very happy about it, very happy, but still
to grow in that you have to know what it is.
Indians have senses, it goes easily into their
heads, they are very sensitive.
In the same way I hope you develop it in that
way, in that fashion, then life would be very
enjoyable.
All right now coming back to something practical.
I have to ask you have you made all the purchases
that are needed for your pujas in your various
countries?
Yogi: They are going to do some of it in Bombay,
on the day it’s available.
When the busses go back in each case.
Shri Mataji: Because all those who are going
Europeans, please raise your hands.
By the earlier.
Yogi: First bus.
Shri Mataji: First bus.
Yogi: Monday 7:15 the Egypt Airfly will leave
on the 17th morning.
Shri Mataji: Now there’s one good solution
also, I was saying that if you start very
early in the morning, next day you may reach
there for this work but the shops close very
fast.
Another one could be you make a list of things
that you want and send it over to Nima or
someone, and they’ll keep it ready for you
so you need not go to the shop to get it.
For example, if you want to buy a mukhoot,
you want to buy this and that, better give
her a list and they will keep it ready for
you.
As soon as you go you’ll get them, is a
better idea, don’t leave it to chances because
when you travel you see you don’t know the
car may not take you at the right time, the
shops maybe closed, being Sunday it’s going
to be difficult again, best is to make a list,
even Saturday is very difficult there, it’s
so crowded and all that.
So make a list of things that you want definitely,
and those otherwise you can try later on some
that you want to buy personally but actually
these things are so common and so understandable
you write it down whatever you want for your
puja.
Have you got any list?
Of say what one needs for the puja?
No all together what you want to buy?
Then make a list now, sit down and make a
list, now when you’ve made the list, I’ll
send somebody to Bombay who will purchase
all these things, keep ready for you, put
the price for you, you pay them and you take
them.
I don’t think you’ll have much chance
to go to any shop and I would advise don’t
go to any shop on a Saturday.
On the contrary, you just go to the airport,
rest there and take your things.
Yogi: They reach on Friday night, they have
all day Saturday and they go in the small
hours of Sunday morning.
Shri Mataji: Why do you want them to go on
Friday night?
Better let them go on Saturday morning.
Yogi: They choose that.
Shri Mataji: I see.
And what about you people?
Yogi: We’re going the next day.
We’ll leave on Saturday and the flights
not only until Tuesday or Wednesday.
Shri Mataji: All right.
Yogi: But if you suggest Mother that they
go on Saturday they’ll do it.
No, is better go earlier because in any case.
You know why I was saying that maybe you see
cars and this and that supposing it fails
or something better to be there one day earlier.
Try if you can get something because Saturday’s
such a crowded thing there, I don’t know.
Yogi: We’ll still make this common list
for the puja.
Shri Mataji: In any case you should.
Whatever you have is all right, if you don’t
have you better make it here, I mean you spend
so much time making the mookhut, what’s
the need?
You can get it here ready made, very good
ones, any amount, any type you want, if you
want to do it you can do it but normally there’s
no need.
Yogi: They don’t know what mookhut is Mother?
Shri Mataji: Huh?
Yogi: You better tell them what mookhut is.
Shri Mataji: Mookhut is the crown.
Yes.
All right, by all means you can see.
It’s done or not.
Yogi: [HINDI – Requesting Shri Mataji to
vibrate kumkum for Australia.]
Shri Mataji: Ha, Ha, please bring it.
[Individual conversations between Shri Mataji
and Yogi continues]
Shri Mataji: For the hair, coconut oil is
the best.
If before going, whatever silver you have
got you put it in your suitcase.
Find it also customs you just … [voice breaks
a bit] Please tell them frankly that these
are [Shri Mataji requests to increase the
volume of the microphone] … these are your
wedding presents, would be better if you wrap
it with some …
Shri Mataji tells a yogi specifically: It’s
not meant for you in any case, meant for married
people.
In case you are carrying the silver with you
then put it in your suitcases with a wrapper,
with the wishing of somebody like that for
your marriage.
You should say, “We got married.”
Or, somebody has to say, “We re-married.
It’s a present.”
And, they won’t say anything to you.
But in any case, they won’t see anything,
I hope so.
Next time when you come don’t bring any
nonsensical thing like the one you brought
last time.
First was My television set the way it was
ruined.
It’s all absurd ideas, I never do like that.
You need not try to avoid paying customs.
We have to pay where you have to pay.
So, whatever you are bringing, each person
should not bring more that five hundred rupees
worth, means about say, about twenty-five
pounds.
Secondly, that whenever you bring such things
like tapes you should divide them into different
people and then bring it.
Don’t bring them together.
Thirdly, whatever you bring you don’t send
it back without asking Me.
There’s no logic in it.
All the way you bring something here and why
do you send it back?
Again, this is the same brain I think which
I cannot explain.
Nobody can explain this.
Yen, who took them back?
[Yogi’s answer is inaudible]
Shri Mataji: Who is he?
From Bristol?
You know we have paid for that.
[Yogi’s answer is inaudible]
Shri Mataji: But why?
English originals, why did you send?
You see, you are made in-charge of that, have
you?
Who has made you in-charge?
Warren made you in-charge, did he?
Then, did you ask Warren?
You don’t know you have sent also in that,
I had saved some tapes which were the bhajan
tapes.
I saved them that time when I was giving.
I said, “Keep them for the villagers.”
I’m saying did you appoint him as the in-charge
of the tapes?
All right.
What, he didn’t do these tapes.
The tapes that he has sent back, he never
did it.
That’s done by Paul.
We have purchased them, gave it to Paul for
doing it.
Now, I saved these ones when I was giving
the presents to people.
I said, “Save these.”
Because I have to take them for distribution
for the villagers and these tapes were sent
back.
He never asked Me.
See, this is the trouble.
When you are in-charge, doesn’t mean you
can do things like that.
These are not your tapes that you sent them.
We paid for it, we got it done through Paul.
It has nothing to do with you.
You never did these tapes.
Nothing.
No, you did not.
I know.
Paul did it.
It was given to Paul, we paid for it, we asked
Paul to do it.
He did it.
These tapes are not done by you.
If you have done it I don’t know but as
far as I know, they are done by Paul.
And, I kept them back, I didn’t give them.
Yesterday, I was really crestfallen because
I had told them that I’ll give it to the
bhajan-mandals.
And, it was not there.
They asked Me, “Where are the tapes You
had promised us, Mother?”
[Yogi’s answer is inaudible]
Shri Mataji: I think you do not know because
I had kept about forty tapes or thirty tapes
which were of Indian bhajans separately with
that.
But what was the hurry?
If you have to send something, you can always
send it later.
[Yogi’s answer is inaudible]
Shri Mataji: How do you know?
You just sent the lot.
How do you know?
You didn’t see everything.
Definitely, they are gone but why do anything
without asking?
First of all, always do things with asking.
You shouldn’t behave arbitrarily, first
point.
Second point is that these things can be done
later.
What is the hurry?
Even Warren asks Me if he has to do something.
Is a very common thing I know with the Western
mind.
I’ve known that.
I’ll tell you people used to live in My
house, they would just walk off keeping the
door open, just walk off.
Where’s he gone?
God knows!
He’s walked off.
Very common.
He just walked off.
Where did he go?
I mean, even if we have to go the bathroom,
we’ll tell somebody, “I’m going to the
bathroom.”
That’s our habit.
No, it’s all right whatever it is but I’d
saved these.
Now, I cannot locate it because it’s not
there.
There was no need to send them back at all.
What was the hurry?
To whom are you committed?
If not to Me, at least to Warren.
Why they arranged these things?
I think something goes out there.
You better look after yourself.
You have to do sadhana.
You all must do sadhana.
There’s one more thing: is that by saying
I’m a Sahaja Yogi, by believing I’m a
Sahaja Yogi, you are not going to be helped.
You have to do your meditation sincerely.
You see, I know it’s not hypocrisy.
But also it is not all out sincere effort.
There’s something in between, the limbo
I would say.
That’s not the way.
We think we are Sahaja Yogis.
All right, then do it.
You have to everyday; all these Indian Sahaja
Yogis meditate everyday.
Everyday.
They are much more in a way evolved.
They have a much better background.
We have to fight all that.
Everyday, they cannot live without it.
All right?
Now, try to meditate, try to take out because
you have problems there.
That’s how you go off.
Now, just don’t do anything arbitrarily,
ask ten people.
I also ask you.
I don’t do anything arbitrarily.
Yesterday, when all the leaders were there,
I asked them what is to be done, isn’t it,
Warren?
Asked everyone.
I can do everything Myself, I don’t do that.
It’s a collective thing, you cannot do anything
like that.
All right, that’s one thing now.
Thank you very much.
Next time, don’t do anything.
It’s not only him, I’m telling all of
you.
Don’t do anything arbitrarily.
All right?
May God bless you!
Now, second is Felicity, come here.
Felicity, you sit down.
I have to tell you one thing.
In Sahaja Yoga, you have come here to achieve
an ascent.
You know you had lots of problems.
You have not come here to achieve any positions,
know that.
If you want to achieve positions, why don’t
you go to politics and spare us?
You become ministers, prime ministers, do
what you like.
Why do you want to start another center?
[Answer is inaudible]
Who is Danny?
Is he you leader?
Who is your leader?
Then, why did you listen to Danny?
Danny will do that.
He’s gone back, he’ll tell you, he’ll
try to break your organization.
Are you going to listen to him?
He will do like this.
You should have told him in all sense that
you better talk to Lori.
Now, don’t listen to Danny.
He’s already gone off his head.
Actually, he made a horrible thing which you
can’t imagine.
I mean, if I tell you, you’ll be shocked.
He made a deed.
He made the deed for the so-called registration
of the Vishwa Nirmala Dharma.
[Shri Mataji asks a Yogi] That one or the
other one also: Life Eternal Trust?
[Yogi’s answer inaudible]
You can say Life Eternal Trust and what he
did was that when I die he becomes the head.
He becomes the head of the whole of the world,
Mr. Danny.
That his great wife has achieved it.
And, when he [Shri Mataji points to one of
the Yogis sitting there] found it out, he
told Me, “Mother, what are You doing?”
I trusted him, he’s such a good man.
I don’t know how he got into this trap of
getting some sort of a power.
Can you do that?
You cannot.
Started it [Shri Mataji smiles and shows thumbs
up and gives bandhan, Yogis chant Shri Mataji
Nirmala Devi ki Jai]
[Conversations in Marathi]
You have to support Lori out and out.
I must get good report about you from her.
You know you had terrible problems, you know
that.
I must get very good report from her.
And, you must respect your leaders.
Don’t treat them as equals.
None of you are going to treat your leaders
as equals, you have to respect them and you
have to listen to them.
If something goes wrong with them, I will
remove them.
Don’t start arbitrary behavior.
This goes to this limit what Danny has done.
Do you want to become like that?
So don’t start any arbitrary behavior.
And, if you want to make Me unhappy, I have
nothing to say but I’ve tried to make you
happy by so many ways and so many methods
but if you want to make Me unhappy all the
time, what can I do?
I have to be unhappy.
You don’t want to make Me unhappy, isn’t
it Felicity?
All right, now go ahead and don’t do all
these things.
It hurts Me.
I mean, I just don’t understand.
You have been with Me for so many days and
this thing, I’ve loved you so much, just
can’t understand.
Why do you want to hurt Me?
All right, get up now.
Now for something nice, we should say it’s
done is done, finished.
You see, sometimes the ocean of forgiveness
gets so filled up that some of it like what
you call the tushar in Marathi we say.
I don’t know in English what is the word
is.
Some drops come out from that on the shore.
Try to love each other, try to be helpful
to each other, try to enjoy others – that’s
what you are here for.
Keep to your age, keep to your levels, keep
to your growth and also, you must understand
that respect if you give, you get the respect
also.
This is not the way one should behave in Sahaja
Yoga.
I’m trying to build up a new world.
You are doing God’s work.
Just find out have you got sufficiently enough
understanding what work you are taking.
Arbitrary behavior is absolutely cancerous
for Sahaja Yoga.
Anybody does that, you point it out to others,
“This is arbitrary.”
This has been done very much before also.
You know how the money was collected arbitrarily
by Patrick.
Terrible things happened and everybody supported
him, even Steve and everyone and people sent
him money without asking Me.
This is very sad.
You are all Sahaja Yogis of such a level and
you must come up to that level and see that
you are the people who are going to change
the whole world.
You are the foundation of that.
No arbitrary behavior should be there but
an understanding because you have to receive
so much.
Unless and until, you are respectful, you
cannot receive anything.
Whatever you have to do please ask your leaders.
Don’t do anything arbitrarily.
The leader may be younger than you, may be
older than you, may be now he is appointed,
you are an old Sahaja Yogi.
Doesn’t matter, I know whom to appoint,
I’ve appointed that person there.
All right.
I hope you will give Me joy and happiness
as I have always tried to give you.
May God bless you!
Now, the ladies have arrived and they want
to give bangles to the ladies.
They have brought the bangles for you.
The reason is tomorrow is a great day, what
we call the Sankrant.
Is a day when the Sun changes its meridian?
It moves from the South to the North, towards
the Cancer.
It moves towards the Cancer, you see.
And, that’s how tomorrow is a very great
day for us, fourteenth.
That day we say that that’s the day lots
of things happen.
So, San Krant.
Krant means revolution and San means holy.
So is a day of holy revolution.
Luckily we are here, we’ll be having a nice
puja, we’ll have an international puja also,
everything will be done tomorrow very nicely.
Now, one thing we have to do today that these
ladies have come to give bangles to you, to
all the ladies.
They have got all sizes.
They showed Me what sizes I should take.
I told them some of them should
be maximum.
[laughter] And, they’ve brought it.
So as many as you can have, please have it.
All right?
[applause]
[Marathi] We don’t offer them to men because
it is insulting.
When
the men don’t go for
a fight or they behave cowardly then women
offer their bangles to men that, “You better
wear them, sit at home and I’ll go on
the war.”
There’s a saying, “Bangadya bhara.”
Means to men if you say that
that means now you are a coward.
Means that in all languages.
It’s a sanctuary here, so many birds.
Have you seen those birds before or only they
have arrived today?
Just go
and have
a look.
We have everything by the kilos, you see.