I bow to all the seekers of truth. At the
very outset we have to know that truth is
what it is. We cannot change it, we cannot
transform it, we cannot describe it, we cannot
purchase it. It is, it has been and it will
be.
I’m so very happy to see so many seekers
of truth in Los Angeles. So whatever I’m
going to tell you today, you are not to take
Me for granted, nor you have to believe Me
blind-folded. We have had lots of problems
because of this kind of blind-folded faith.
But whatever I’m telling you, you have to
know that this is just a hypothesis I’m
putting forth. If it is proved, then you have
to believe in it as honest people because
it is for your benevolence, it is for the
benevolence of your family, it is for the
benevolence of this city, it is for the benevolence
of your country and it is for the benevolence
of the whole world.
It is important that now we have to think
about our benevolence. We have had lots of
fun, pleasures, all kinds of enterprises in
our life. But what do we seek in those enterprises
is joy, anand. Whatever you want to have,
you want to have it because you think by that
you will feel satisfied and you’ll have
joy. But it is not so. Today we want to have,
say, for example, a house, all right? Then
we want to have a car. All right, then we
want to have a helicopter, I think. Then it
goes on like that one to another. We are never
satisfied. If these desires were pure desires,
we should have been satisfied when we got
them.
Also economics says that in general wants
are not satiable. Now whatever you have been
told about this power which is residing in
our triangular bone called as sacrum, that
means the Greeks knew it was a sacred bone.
They called it sacrum. And this bone has this
power within us which is the pure desire and
what is the pure desire? That is the truth
about ourselves that you are not this body,
this mind, this ego, these conditionings,
this emotions, this intellect. You are not
that because you say my emotions, my ego,
but who is this “my”? So you are not that.
The truth is you are the pure Spirit. The
second truth is that there is a all-pervading
Divine power of love. This power of love does
all the living work. For example, now you
see beautiful flowers all over. We take them
for granted. We don’t even think that it’s
a miracle. Who runs our heart? If you ask
the doctors, they will say it is autonomous
nervous system. But who is this auto? So all
these living things are done by the Divine
power of love. I say to you this, you need
not believe it M. But tonight you are going
to feel it, you are going to feel it on your
finger tips this all-pervading power of Divine
love which is called as paramchaitanya in
Sanskrit language. In Koran it is called as
ruh, in the Bible it is called as the cool
breeze of the Holy Ghost and Patanjali has
called it as Ritambhara Pragya, which is rather
a tongue twister.
So this power exists. You see the result,
you see the result that living things are
happening. Now if you go to the science, it
has its own limitations. First of all, science
is amoral. You can destroy Hiroshima, is all
right with science after all. You can do whatever
you want to do because you think you have
mastered the matter, but that is not our job
is to destroy people all over the world. This
idea of destruction comes because we forget
that we do not know the absolute truth.
First we have to know the absolute truth,
then we’ll know where are we. What are we
doing? What we are supposed to do. You are
quite aware as to what is happening in the
world, especially in America about which I
am very much concerned. As you know, there
are sixty-five per cent people are expected
to be sick within ten years’ time. It’s
not only a sickness of the body but of the
mind and this destruction will one day create
such a vacuum that we’ll be all shocked
why we are born as human beings and why we
should be destroyed? After all, the Creator
has created us with such understanding, with
such love, He has evolved us to this position
and now why should we be destroyed?
The reason is: we must find out why are we
on this earth. We are on this earth to become
the Spirit, to be a channel of God’s love
and above all, to enter into the Kingdom of
God. When I say to you it sounds rather impractical
and people can’t believe it. It’s a fact.
It’s the truth, I’m telling you that the
time has come for all of you to become the
Spirit. It’s a special time. I call it a
Blossom Time. They call it the Last Judgment.
Some people call it as Qiyama. Even in Sanskrit
there are words, many words to describe it.
So now we have to be the Spirit, otherwise
we should see with our own eyes the destruction
of our fellow men and of ourselves. There’s
nothing in between. Either you become Spirit
or all kinds of destructions will start. You’ve
been already told about the centers that exist
within you. On the medical side, we can say
that they express themselves and manifest
themselves as plexuses, but also they act
on the left-hand side as shown there on our
mind. So we’ll take one center and I’ll
tell you what can happen to you. Of course,
Sahaja Yoga is a meta science. Whatever I’m
saying you can find out and you’ll discover
that whatever I’m saying is the truth.
This one chakra we’ll deal today because
I could feel what’s the problem of Los Angeles.
This center that we call as Swadishthana , the
yellow-colored one. It comes out of the third
center what we call the Nabhi chakra, the
solar plexus. But this one which manifests
aortic plexus moves all over your abdominal
viscera and gives energy to your liver, to
your pancreas, to your spleen, to your kidneys,
to your intestines one side. Another thing
important thing it does, about which I think
doctors don’t know, perhaps, is that it
transforms energy for the use of the gray
cells. The gray cells in the brain we use
when we are futuristic, we think too much,
read too much, when we are very mental.
This energy is used and for that this poor
center has to work very hard. Today’s life
as it is, you see, where it is so futuristic.
Not only that but we have become really very
mental people. We go on thinking, thinking,
thinking and this thinking is done by the
gray cells which require the energy. So this
poor center has to work for this only work
when you are a thinker. Now it has to do other
things also. So it neglects all other viscera.
(Mother talks aside.) So all others are neglected.
Now when the liver is neglected, it is a very,
very important, extremely important organ
in our body. It takes out all the poison from
our body as heat and pass it into blood. It
cleanses through this process. But when this
liver is neglected, it cannot do that work
which it has to do; then the heat starts accumulating
in the liver.
Such a person is quite a hot-tempered person,
very hot-tempered can be. When he tries to
control the temper, he gets even worse. That’s
not the only thing that happens. This heat
consumes all the fats and such a person starts
becoming extremely thin. He doesn’t like
food, he doesn’t like people. I mean his
attention becomes extremely disturbed and
he thinks no end of himself. He thinks that
all others are stupid fools; I’m the only
wisest person. If anybody thinks like that
then they should know they have a liver problem.
Now thus a thing called ego starts growing.
This is the white color into the brain crosses
over and you get a big balloon of ego.
That’s on one side, doesn’t matter. But
what happens to your body? This heat of the
liver then starts rising and when it goes
to the pancreas, you develop diabetes. Is
a very common disease of modern man is diabetes.
Now can you imagine in India we have villagers,
simple people. They don’t think so much,
you see. They earn, today, eat their food,
sleep off. Next morning they are again up.
They don’t have to insure anything, they
don’t have to worry about it. But they take
so much of sugar, sometimes four, five spoons,
big spoons. The spoon must stand straight
at right angle otherwise they think this is
not tea at all and they take it three, four
cups of tea. They never get diabetes.
It’s a wonderful thing, you know, that you
can have as much sweet as you like, you never
get diabetes. Now these villagers don’t
think but those who are sitting on their chair
planning, thinking of the future all the time,
they definitely get diabetes. Then what happens?
Then the another movement of the same heat
goes to spleen and now this is even worse.
Spleen is a speedometer. It keeps our speed.
Supposing we have eaten our food and then
we want to run, get a pain here, because it
supplies red blood corpuscles for emergencies.
If the spleen goes out of order with the heat
as well as the kind of life we have, a very
hectic life. First of all, what I see in America
is really terrible because they get up late,
in the night sleep late first of all and get
up late. Then early in the morning they have
to go to work, so they are in a hurry. They’ll
pull back their jeans and then I don’t know.
They don’t eat at all, they don’t even
brush, get into the car, start brushing and
then they have their food in the car, or call
it the breakfast, so-called breakfast. Here
it is all the cars are honking and you’re
getting late and there’s a jam, this that.
This poor spleen doesn’t know what to do,
because it’s such a hectic life. It doesn’t
know how to cope with such a hectic person
who sometimes needs this, sometimes needs
that, so it becomes hectic. But then it is
vulnerable to a very serious disease which
we call as blood cancer, leukemia. On the
contrary, if our life is a peaceful quiet
life, we nicely get up in the morning, have
our bath, don’t go for jogging, that’s
also another thing. Jogging is right-sided.
Jogging is all right for people who are lethargic,
you see. Indians would be better. But not
for Americans. Because this is the physical
as well as the mental side, right side. And
suddenly you get a shock or something happens.
Specially the newspapers. They believe in
just giving you shocks.
So in the morning you read something. “Oh,
what has happened?” And you get a shock.
Now you won’t believe the way they are describing
now the calamities in India are not so bad.
I’ve telephoned, I found out, it’s not
so bad. But why the newspaper are doing because
they love to give you shocks and you also
love them because they give you shocks, I
think. So in this shocking conditions this
poor spleen of yours cannot cope and that’s
how you get this horrible disease called blood
cancer.
Now I must tell you with Sahaja Yoga we have
completely cured blood cancer, completely
cured of many people. It’s a fact. Without
going to doctors, without going for diagnosis
because in the diagnosis only half people
die, but we know their trouble. They and we
know what they are suffering from and it can
be worked out. Just this Kundalini is to be
raised. She goes to this center and just pacifies,
enlightens it, nourishes it and the whole
thing changes. I’m not telling you a cock
and bull story. I really tell you. You should
know that it is all happening, it’s all
happening today, everywhere.
Then the third thing that happens is that
your kidneys get coagulated and you get kidney
trouble. Then you have to go for dialysis
and you end up as bankrupts. I mean they do
not cure you with dialysis. No, there’s
no cure with dialysis. But the only thing
that happens that you can become a bankrupt
and then die. Then it goes to intestines,
creates problem. You never feel hungry and
whatever you may eat, you get into constipation
of terrible dimensions and that leads to then
hernia and all kinds of diseases. So with
one center how many things you are suffering.
But that’s not the end of it. Then this
heat rises upward. There’s a center we call
it as right heart. Here you can see. When
this center is affected, you develop asthma.
Asthma is one hundred per cent curable in
Sahaja Yoga. We have a doctor who got his
MD. Now he’s in America for curing cancer,
curing asthma through Sahaja Yoga. Absolutely
curable. So with the intestines, with the
kidney, there are problems which seem, looks
like, people say, is incurable, but not. These
are the fundamentals we have, and if you have
to deal with the fundamentals, then the rest
of it falls into proper picture.
Like supposing now there’s a tree which
is sick. Now if you start treating the leaves,
you can’t cure. If you try to correct it
through its branches, you can’t cure. You
have to go deep down into the roots and the
sap that rises will cure it. In the same way,
these are the roots. This is the knowledge
of the roots I’m telling you. I see Los
Angeles every year is growing and growing
and growing. America is growing very fast,
no doubt. But when a tree of this civilization
is growing so fast we must find out about
our roots. And if you do not find out about
your roots how are you going to look after
this huge big civilization you have created
which is dry, which has no nourishment? So
we have to go to our roots.
Another problem is that if this knowledge
is coming from India, people have an objection.
It should come from America or from England.
Many people believe that Christ was born in
England. Is impossible to say that all right,
you have science, which we have learned; now
we have something. Why shouldn’t you learn,
if it is for your good? It’s only not I
am saying that. We had poets in London like
William Blake. He has said for these days
that the men of God will be born in those
days and they will become Divine and they
will have powers to make others Divine, said
by an Englishman. I don’t know if you read
C.S. Lewis or not. Another one, so many. There
was also one poet. He was Englishman who came
in here and lived here. I read them and I’m
surprised that this has already been predicted.
So some people start thinking about it and
they think, “Let’s go to religion.”
Nothing wrong with religion as such and nothing
wrong with the people who have created it,
but I must say people like Jesus Christ or
Mohammed Sahab were really very, very great
people, were very, very great people and they
were so much evolved. They were so much evolved
that they never understood human beings, what
sort of things they are dealing with. I’ll
give you an example. Fifth chapter Mathews,
Christ has said that: “If your one eye does
anything wrong, take it out. Otherwise, take
out the other one. If your one hand does something
wrong, then you cut it or cut both the hands.
If somebody slaps you on this side, you turn
the other side.” I have yet to see one Christian
who has cut his hands or taken out his eyes.
Is impossible. He thought you were such, we
were all such great…
I was born myself in a Christian religion
so I was shocked, how could these people follow
these rules and regulations which are beyond
human beings because they’ll have to take
out their eyes or they’ll have to cut their
hands? Then Mohammed Sahab thought that such
strictness was there for men, why not we have
something for women. So for women also, he
said, “All right. If a woman is not moral,
she should be put in the Mother Earth and
should be beaten with shoes or with stones.”
Now imagine: What about American ladies here?
It’s a dangerous situation.
So then came the another one called Sharia,
you see, it was actually given to the Jews
by Moses when he saw they were very decadent.
So he gave them this, this is in the Jeremiah,
who has written clearly that he said that
if you steal something, your hand should be
cut. All this Sharia was given to Jews, but
Jews were wise. They said, “Baba, we can’t
do this. No, no.” So the Muslims have taken
over and they are putting on their […?] I
have yet to come across one Muslim who can
be called as a real Muslim, or one Christian
who can be called as a real Christian. It’s
none of their mistakes, after all, they are
human beings and these laws and regulations
are for saints. If the saints do anything
wrong, then they should be punished. Not for
ordinary human beings, it’s too much.
But to us religion now has become a matter
of fighting. And then you see people, they
go on distributing. Now like the other day
a fellow came with a Gita to Me. He walked
up to Me. “You must buy this Gita.” I
said, “I have many already in the house.
But,” I said, “Why are you wearing this
dhoti here? It’s Chicago, is a very cold
place. You know, you should not wear this
dhoti.” He said, “My Guru has initiated
that I must wear a dhoti.” I said, “Do
you think by wearing a dhoti, you will go
to heaven? In India everybody wears a dhoti,
will theyl all go to heaven? Try to understand
now.” Now shaven his head completely . I
said, “Why do you shave your head?” He
said, “That’s what my Guru has told me
that if I have to be spiritual, I must shave
my head.” Kabira has said that if, by shaving
your head, if you can go to Heaven, then the
sheep is shaven every year, there won’t
be any place for you there!
All the saints who were real saints were full
of fun about all these things and they could
see that this is all stupidity. The way people
are trying to create this kind of fanaticism
is all stupidity. It is, then we feel disappointed.
Same about Hindus. Hindus, it is said that
in every human being there is a Spirit. Everybody
has the Spirit in the heart. Then how can
you have caste system? How can you have a
higher race and a lower race? There are so
many examples to show. For example, Shri Rama
ate the fruits from an old lady who had eaten
them before to see that they are not sour.
In India if somebody eats something you’ll
never eat that. But look at Shri Rama and
then He tells His wife, “Oh what fruits!
I’ve never eaten like that.” But the brother
was angry. The brother said, “Why should
she give you such fruits, it’s not proper.”
So the wife says, “Please give me some.
After all, I’m your wife.” Then she eats
something and says, “Wow! What fruits!”
Now the brother Lakshmana says, “Sister-in-law,
give me also little bit.” “No, you were
so angry, I will not give you.”
The whole story shows the love, the compassion,
the oneness, because of love. Krishna also
had food with a person called Vidura who was
a son of a maidservant. He wouldn’t go with
the king and eat food but He would eat with
this. Now why? Because he was a realized soul,
Vidura was. Every story of Christ or anything
you see is nothing but love. But if you are
bent upon taking something like Christ went
to a wedding and He made wine out of water.
That’s the simple thing. Now I can also
do that, not difficult. But that’s not the
wine. That is the taste of grape juice. For
wine it has to rot. Instantaneously who can
make wine? How can you make wine just by touching
water. You cannot. It has to rot. The more
rotten it is, the better it is, they say.
I’ve never tasted so I don’t know, but
smells horrible, I can tell you this much.
Now, so we don’t know what to do because
go to religion, there we find fanaticism.
We find people fighting in the name of God,
making big money out of, I don’t know but
I read a book about where it said the Vatican
printed one million, no, nine million dollars,
nine million dollars as counterfeits and distributed
through their own bank. How could any religious
man think of doing these things, I can’t
understand. First of all, they have to be
holy people. They have to be righteous people.
If they have interest in your purses, then
how can they be holy men? God doesn’t understand
money. It’s your headache. Banking is your
headache. How can you purchase God with money?
So I appeal to your intelligence, to your
wisdom, to know that this your American country
has fed so many false gurus so far without
even thinking what they are doing, without
even finding that they are just making money.
They are marketing some nonsense.
That’s another problem. When I came here
first nobody would listen to Me. I said, “Why?”
“Because you don’t take money, so what
is the credibility?" They can’t understand
anything without money. All right, doesn’t
matter. Now the situation seems to be better.
But the last thing that happens to you is,
very serious thing with this Swadishthan chakra,
is that you get a heart attack, a massive
heart attack, especially if you are young,
and you are playing, say, tennis and you are
drinking too much, you get a heart attack
which is very massive and which is always
fatal. Angina is different. But this massive
heart attack comes from this right-side problem.
Then this heat rises into the head and what
happens, you get paralysis of the right side,
minimum.
There are so many diseases out of one center
you can get. Then you go to some guru. He
puts something into your head, I don’t know
what they do. Then you get cancers, you get
incurable diseases, you get insomnia, all
kinds of things you get and ultimately you
realize, you have gone mad. I mean I don’t
know, a mad man doesn’t understand he’s
mad, but others know. But wisdom should be
there. When you choose a guru, you must know
anybody who wants money for spiritual work
cannot be a holy person, cannot.
So at this juncture you have to know that
when this Kundalini rises, first thing that
happens to us that our innocence starts manifesting.
Innocence is eternal, it is not temporary,
it is eternal. Whatever you may try to destroy
it, it is there and it starts manifesting
and then your eyes become innocent, absolutely
innocent, and very powerful and there’s
a glint of the spirituality in your eyes.
Such eyes are so powerful that even a glance
of such a person can settle down thousands.
With this innocent eyes you understand that
your attention has lost lust and greed completely
and you have become a very moral person, very
righteous.
Nobody has to tell you, don’t do this, don’t
do that, no. Just it happens. Now how? It’s
like this, if I have a snake in my hand, and
I’m a very obstinate person and you tell
me, “There’s a snake in your hand, please
leave it.” I’ll say, “No, there’s
no snake, it’s a rope.” Till it bites
me and I’ll go on saying, “It's a rope”.
But if there’s a little light, I’ll throw
it away. I’ll know this is wrong. As a result
of this happening, whatever is destroying
within you, you may think it should be given
up. You may not be knowing also that it is
destructive but you just drop it out. Overnight.
I must tell you I have known people who have
dropped drug addiction. Here such a problem
exists of drug addiction and can be completely
cured with Sahaja Yoga, I can assure you.
If this Kundalini rises, then not only drug
addiction but any kind of addiction drops
off.
Then you know all about your centers on your
fingertips. You know what’s wrong with you
on your fingertips. With this light you know
where lies your problem. This is self knowledge.
On your fingertips, means on your central
nervous system, in Sanskrit the word is bodh,
from where the word Buddha has come, or also
is Vida from where the word Veda has come.
You have to know the truth, not mentally,
but on your central nervous system, on your
fingertips. So you know the absolute truth.
Now there are many who came to me who never
believed in God. Atheists, they call themselves,
especially in Russia, say Russians. But they
took no time to get their realization. They
are such a clean slate, I tell you. They have
no conditionings, nothing. And you won’t
believe that we always have our program in
stadiums. We cannot have in halls. We’ve
got sixteen to eighteen thousand people in
one place. What is happened with them? Why
is it they are so sensitive? They have thrown
away all false gurus, one by one. They’re
not bothered. After all at least, I must say,
sixty per cent people in Russia are so sensitive
to spirituality, very sensitive. Most amazing
thing is that they jump into it without any
difficulty. I don’t know how they trust
Me so much but they do trust themselves first
and then do trust that they have got self-realization.
I don’t know if you have told them or not
that recently they had a conference of two
thousand scientists. Their scientists are
very highly qualified people where they invited
Me to speak to them. In the conference I was
the chief speaker and I was amazed. There
were also ten thousand other people. The subject
matter they gave Me, “Medicine and Self-knowledge.”
They all talked about morality, how important
it is to preserve the society, to preserve
the families, to preserve the whole society.
And they were such great surgeons, there was
one surgeon ninety-year old who had operated
on our prime minister Indira Gandhi, who is
still operating. He’s ninety years, and
the way he speaks you wouldn’t make out
that he’s of that age, and he has written
a book against alcoholism and immorality.
I can’t think such a subject can ever be
talked about here where your Hollywood is
so important. What harm they have done to
you, you don’t know. First of all, Mr. Freud,
who just was worshipped like Christ and he
has ruined the people and brought them to
the sex point only. He is from Austria and
when I told this in Austria, they were very
happy. They clapped, they said he’s brought
such shame to us. But here he was worshipped
and now the whole country has been so much
degraded by him. Now I read the book, “Freudian,
Fraudulent Freud”. There’s another book:
“Downfall of the Freudian Empire”. But
with that, how many have suffered? What has
happened? Families broken. What nonsense he
talked about. The mother, that your relationship
with mother is of a sexual nature. God knows
he must be having something like that. I told
this to an Indian, he said, “Thank God he
didn’t come to India, otherwise we would
have cut him into pieces and thrown him into
Arabic Sea.” How could you accept such an
unwise, nonsensical thing? Well, you did and
so many people who thought it was big experimentation,
this that. It is absolutely a myth, I tell
you. If you come to Sahaja Yoga, you will
know what is a psyche, how it gets affected,
where it is, how it works out the real knowledge
about psychology, you will know. This is psychology
or is it child science? I don’t understand.
It has nothing to do with reality, everything
imaginary. Jung, Jung was the one who got
realization and he did say that Freud was
wrong. He was the one who said it and who
talked of morality.
But I must tell you one story about Myself.
They invited Me to a conference of the Jungians.
It was International Jungians Conference.
Me, poor thing, was supposed to talk about
Jung and I told them where did Jung went wrong
because he said the consciousness is vertical.
No, he said it is horizontal which is not
so and that was the biggest mistake. But whatever
it is he talked of morality.
But next day the president, now he’s no
more, so I can tell you the story, came to
see Me. Eighty-five year old, shaking, you
know? He came to Me, said, “I have some
private work.” I said, “What is it?”
“I have a keep and my wife is dead. Can
you please help me to cajole this keep of
mine, to tell her that she should now marry
me?” "What's the age of your fiancé or
whatever you call it?" "Only about thirty-eight
years." I said, “Do you think I am supposed
to do all such work?” Now this is a Jungian
who is talking like this. If it was a Freudian,
I could have understood. I was shocked and
to come to Me for this kind of a nonsense.
I said I don’t know what’s wrong with
these people. They can’t even understand
that spirituality is holiness, auspiciousness,
is purity. Can’t understand how he came
to ask Me this question. I was so disappointed
that nine years I didn’t visit your country.
I said, “How can I talk to them?”
[“I have a keep” means to have a mistress,
Ed. ]
Today I have to tell you one thing. The time
has come for all of you to get your self-realization,
by which your attention becomes enlightened,
your health gets completely all right, your
mental processes are sensible, but above all
you stand in your present. We live in the
past or the future and all the time we are
thinking of past and future. We are jumping
on the cusp of past and future. With this
happening you become thoughtlessly aware because
these thoughts elongate. Thoughtlessly, but
aware. And this thoughtless awareness is the
time which is reality in which you grow spiritually.
Then you get your inspirations. All your potential
qualities starts manifesting.
You’ll be amazed in India we have had many
great writers, very great, we should say,
poets, very great musicians who are now world
famous. All of them came to Sahaja Yoga. They
were nothing. Even Miss India that was this
time Miss Universe. She is a Sahaja Yogini,
and she came to Me, she said, “Mother, is
it all right if I go for this beauty contest?”
I said, “What’s wrong? You go.” “I
don’t want to wear funny dresses.” I said,
“But you wear, after all, swimming dress,
it’s all right.” She, she was not such
a beautiful girl. She asked Me, “Mother,
I’m going just now for Miss India.” I
said, “You’ll be also Miss Universe. Take
it from Me.” She became.
Because what is the speciality? It’s not
only the face, it’s not only the features
or anything, but it is the inner beauty, it’s
the balance, it’s the poise, it’s the
wisdom, all these things put together make
a personality. Not only just your face, how
you look. That’s not important. See, look
at Mahatma Gandhi, how he looked like. I don’t
know I have seen him, I have lived with him
in my childhood. Such a bony structure, but
even Samson would have been afraid of him,
he was like that. Such a power of truth and
honesty in his heart. It’s not that his
face was very impressive, but the inner power
which was within him. I know of another prime
minister very well Lal Bahadur Shastri. I’m
talking about him because both were born on
the same date of 2nd of October. Another person,
tremendously powerful, very short man. So
powerful he was and his realization of such
a high degree. He could easily make out who
[BREAK IN RECORDING] Of course, he respected
Me very much. I used to be very shy,because
he would not even sit before Me
on the chair. Is what we call self-realization.
In Sanskrit an egg is called as Dwijaha, the
bird is called Dwijaha and a human being,
when he is realized, also called as Dwijaha,
means born twice. So first it’s an egg,
then it becomes a bird. There are two different
things. In the same way, first we are a human
beings then we are realized souls. This is
the new age, this is the new race which has
come up. Is nothing, just put a brand here,
one, like any other twice-born, like any other
person you are behaving. Why? What is twice,
twice-born? Or I am a Christian, and a Hindu,
and a Muslim or anything. It’s just a brand
because anybody can commit any murder, any
sin, anything.
So this transformation is your responsibility.
You have to take to this transformation, and
you have to change people. If you have to
save your country, now learn this: that you
can do it. You can easily do it. Is very simple
because is all built in within you. Now what
do we do? Just put a seed in the Mother Earth
and it sprouts by itself. How? Because the
seed has a built-in quality to sprout and
the Mother has a built-in quality to make
it sprout. In the same way, you all have this
power, this glory is within you, just it has
to happen. It sprouts and then you have to
grow.
I don’t know how people trust Me so much.
I am an Indian after all. I could be an immigrant,
or whatever. I could be anything. But they
trust Me somehow. But later on, they do not
trust themselves and they do not grow. It’s
a very sad thing, not in Russia, I must tell
you, not in Russia. There’s a joke. We had
a seminar of thousands of people in Russia
and there was one American Sahaja Yogi and
a Russian Sahaja Yogi asked him: “How many
do you have Sahaja Yogis in America?” So
he said, “To be precise, it is fifty-six.”
So this Sahaja Yogi from Taliatti says, “Oh
my God, you are fifty-six thousand? We have
only twenty-one thousand here in Taliatti.”
They can’t understand. They think Americans
are very bright, very smart people. There
must be at least 56,000. Americans are known
to be very intelligent, very smart. So they’re
taking to Coca Cola culture now. Russians,
forty per cent, because they think Americans,
after all, you know, they take Coca Cola,
they go to McDonald. They’re very smart
people. They’re ruling all over the world
and all your junk which doesn’t sell here
goes there and they are really trying to look
like Americans, you know.
Whatever it is. Why I’m trying to say this,
is the whole world is looking at you. They
follow you. This Hollywood doesn’t understand
its own responsibility. The whole world is
following you and the way they speak also
English is very surprising is just like American
English. I take about two days to understand
that. But now in Russia they are speaking
the same English as you speak and it’s a
difficult situation. So, you have to understand
the second responsibility that, as citizens
of this great country, you have to lead the
whole world into righteousness, into morality,
into constructive beautiful life. You have
to enter in the Kingdom of God and settle
there, whatever may be your race, whatever
may be your religion, or all these nonsensical
differences.
But it’s very important and you’ll be
surprised, the first country I visited was
America. I would say, first I went to Iran
because my brother was there but after that
I came to America and I was surprised. How
do they take to falsehood so easily? Even
Indians who come here become stupid. I don’t
know. Really. You won’t believe, this there’s
a gentleman who is organizing the marriage
of Rama and Sita. I mean they were married
long time back. But he’s organizing it in
every place. Los Angeles one marriage, one
in New York, one in Philadelphia. All like
that he is organizing. And here there were
ten thousand people who attended that wedding.
The boy, means Rama, was ten-year old and
the girl was eight-year old. So this kind
of nonsense, even Indians, they would not
do this in India. No, everybody will laugh
at them.
The another example if I give, you’ll be
shocked. There’s a lady, Maharani of Dhrangadhra
. She’s another mad woman and she has lost
her husband. So she has got one man, she dressed
him up as a lady, and she calls him as “the
goddess” she worships. I was shocked at
the whole thing that they are doing. So I
said, “But you don’t have anybody who
follows you.” “No, no, we have many in
Los Angeles.” Can you imagine? This there
is another one now who makes the pendulum
move. The people who are lynched by him, I
met them in Washington. They told me, “Mother,
we have sold out our houses. Now we don’t
know what to do. We have taken out our children
from good schools. We have no money.” I
said, “ So why?” "There was this gentleman
from the TM, you see. Pradeep Chopra is the
name." Pradeep, to have such a nice name,
I don’t know who gave him this name. What
his mother must have thought. So he said that,
“Now, I can control the minds of others,
I’ll teach you how.” So he calls somebody.
“Stand here” and he gives you a pendulum
in his hand. Now he says, “See, now he’ll
move the pendulum.” He moves the pendulum
and people have given up their houses, this,
that, to this man. So I said, “How can you
come and tell Me this now? Have you come on
this earth to move the pendulums?” I mean,
this kind of stupidity, can’t understand.
Then they said you can levitate three or four
feet like this. Already you have jams on the
road. Why do you want to have such people
moving their three feet? Such stupid things
they accept, such stupid things. But the fellow
of TM, the one who was their very big master,
he got epilepsy, so he came to me. By that
time, he had become bankrupt. He told Me:
“I went to America and my guru told me,
your money is so much involved, so you have
to tell then, I came without any visa, without
any passport.” His name is Peter Pierce.
“And you have to tell them I can walk into
the wall, through the wall." "Then?" I said.
"I told them and they all believed me.”
“They all believed you?” “Yes.” “Professors,
mathematicians, everybody believed you?”
“Yes.” How can they believe such nonsensical
things?
There is a saying by Guru Nanaka, “Satguru
wahi, jo sahib mili hai.” “The one who
is the real master is the one who makes you
meet God, who makes you Divine.” And this
is what you should expect. It looks difficult,
is the easiest thing to be Divine. You don’t
have to jump, you don’t have to waste money.
Nothing of the kind. It’s all built in within
you. Just have your awakening and enjoy. You
don’t have to do anything like running away
from your homes, going to Himalayas, standing
on your heads. Nothing needed. No austerities.
You are already ready for it. You have done
all this in your last lives. Now please don’t
do all these things. You just get your Self-realization.
So you become collectively conscious. You
can feel on your fingertips vibrations of
another person, whether dead, living, or historical
whatever it is. You can know. You know the
absolute truth on your fingertips. But above
all, because you become collectively conscious,
that is, a microcosm becomes the macrocosm,
because a drop becomes the ocean. Who is the
other? You become the part and parcel of one.
So when it happens to you, it is very amazing
how you realize what powers you have. You
can give realization to people, you can cure
them, you can enjoy yourself. You never get
bored. So many powers you have which starts
expressing and when they start expressing,
you’re amazed at yourself. This is what
you must expect and not moving of a pendulum.
I’m sure today I’m not talking to stupid
people. Sahaja Yoga is not meant for idiotic
people, I must tell you. The kind of idiocity
that has come I can’t understand, because
I used to worship Abraham Lincoln, used to
worship and he gave us such a great thing
like democracy and how can this democracy
be a demonocracy? There are seekers, but misled.
Above all that happens to you, the highest
is that you jump into the ocean of joy…you
just become joy. Joy is singular. Happiness
and unhappiness are the two sides of one coin.
But joy is singular that you become the witness
the whole thing like a drama. It’s fun and
you get out of your problems and that’s
how you know how to solve them.
And above all, the bliss is there to help
you. You’ll be amazed how things work out.
Meticulously in every way, even money-wise.
There was a girl, lady from Toronto. She wanted
to travel with me, come here. She’s very
good, but she thought she hasn’t got sufficient
money and next day she got a check of $4,000
because she had paid some money somewhere
a long time back. This is just a very, very
minimum. But the greatest thing is that you
become your own master. You know what chakras
are there, you know what you are doing. You
know everything. It is not just like standing
and moving a pendulum nonsense but it is you
know what’s wrong with anyone. Then you
don’t talk about his face, about his dress,
how he walks but you talk about his centers,
what centers are there and you can cure. All
this is your own.
Last of all I have to tell you this Kundalini
is the power of pure desire and she is your
individual mother. She knows everything about
you. It’s all tape-recorded. So you don’t
have to start judging yourself. She knows
you and She is anxious to give you self-realization.
She takes up all the trouble on Herself and
gives you this beautiful thing which you call
as self-realization and then you realize that
you are endowed with the power of Divine love.
You become extremely dynamic; at the same
time you are extremely compassionate. You
enjoy your virtues, you enjoy your love, you
enjoy others, you enjoy everything. Such a
state is not difficult. Only thing you must
understand that you are here to become the
Spirit. In this time try to say whatever is
possible. I’m going tonight to New York.
They always put me like a shuttlecock from
one place to another. So I have to go. But
I’m very happy I saw so many of you here.
I hope you’ll be all responsible and will
look after your realization.
Now I would request you that it cannot be
forced on you, it cannot be, because I respect
your freedom. You have freedom. This is the
Last Judgment: If you want to go to Heaven,
you are welcome, if you want to go to hell,
you are welcome. I cannot force on you. So
those who do not want to come for this or
do not want to have it, I cannot force, so
I would request you, those who do not want
to have, can leave the hall. Would be better
for others and those who want to have it are
welcome and I’m sure you all will have it.
No doubt about it. No doubt. It will take
hardly ten minutes for you to get your realization,
ten minutes. But you have to be little patient
and you have to also know that it is your
pure desire that is going to give you. Just
your pure desire. I’ve already told you
that Kundalini knows everything about you
and you don’t have to judge yourself.
So there are three conditions, very simple,
very, very simple. The first one is that you
are not to feel guilty at all. Your Kundalini
knows everything. Why should you feel guilty?
Leave it to Her. You don’t judge yourself
and please don’t feel guilty. You don’t
know if you feel guilty, this center here,
catches, and if this center goes out of order,
you develop angina which is a horrible disease
of the heart. You develop spondylitis and
also lethargic organs. Only by one this center
of yours, and it is always there when you
feel guilty. If you have done anything wrong
in the past, you should have dealt with it
that time. What’s the use of carrying it
here all the time? Also is conditioning. For
small, small things people start feeling guilty,
specially with this Catholic Church, Christian
churches. You have to know that we are sinners,
we are not. We are human beings and human
beings can commit mistakes. You are not gods
and at this juncture, if you have guilt, how
will the Kundalini rise? If you are really
guilty, you would have been in jail, isn’t
it? I don’t know with this law here, if
people can go to jail even if they have done
something wrong, I have no idea. I, somehow
or other, I’m very apprehensive about the
LA laws you see. They say it’s very funny.
All right, whatever it is. Now God’s laws
are extremely pure and He loves you. He doesn’t
want you, to put you into any trouble. He
loves you and loves you very much and He wants
you to enter into His kingdom to enjoy. Now
you’re just ready to get it. So the first
condition is that you are not to feel guilty
at all. I assure you, you have done nothing
wrong. Is it possible to forgive yourself?
Thank you.
The second condition is even easier. If you
understand, logically. If, I mean, the second
condition is that you have to forgive everyone,
even without thinking about them. Just to
say, “I forgive every one of them,” finished.
Is very difficult but logically, I’ll tell
you, whether you forgive or don’t forgive,
what do you do? Do nothing. But if you don’t
forgive, then you play into wrong hands and
torture yourself while the person who has
tortured you, is very happy. You go on torturing
yourself because you can’t forgive. So just
you have to say, “I forgive everyone.”
Don’t think about them also because that
will give you a headache. Best is to forgive
everyone. Once you forgive, then the Divine
takes over and works it out. So now please
forgive everyone. Is there any problem? All
right.
The third condition is very simple is that
you have to take out your shoes. That’s
all. You won’t believe, in London first
time I said, “Take out your shoes,” half
of them walked out. It’s difficult.
All right. So first of all we’ll show you
what we have to do to nourish our centers.
Only for tonight, only for tonight. You don’t
have to do it. Later on, as I told you that
our centers are here and all this is happening
in a collective way. It’s not single person
doing something at home. So you have to go
there. They’ll give you every instruction,
everything, every book, whatever you want.
Free, absolutely free. But you must desire
to grow and it will work out.
Some people get it immediately in such a big
way and then they think they’re on top of
the world, but no. You have to grow and you
have to know everything about yourself. You
have to know about Sahaja Yoga completely
in a full way. You have to be a master and
I tell you hardly it takes one month to be.
You people are very intelligent and everything.
Just put your attention, it will work out.
All right.
So now we have to put our left hand on our
lap just. (Mother speaks aside to someone
in Hindi.) Just now. Left hand on your left
lap, comfortably. We are not to go to Himalayas,
do anything of the kind. We have to be comfortable,
that’s one thing. Here sitting down, you’ll
get your realization. Left hand towards the
photograph, we put here, because they have
objection for that, but now you put towards
Me, left hand towards Me which is symbolically
saying that you want your self-realization
because the left side is the power of desire,
mundane desire. So you’re desirous, so you
are putting the hand towards Me, left hand,
that’s all. Now with the right hand, we
have to nourish our centers on the left-hand
side. Now they will show you how to do.
First we put our right hand on the heart.
In the heart resides the Spirit which is the
reflection of God Almighty. If you become
the Spirit then you become your own master.
So you take your hand on the upper portion
of your abdomen on the left-hand side and
this is the center of your mastery which is
created by all the prophets. You will know
about it, everything. Everything will be told
to you. You have to put both your feet apart
from each other because these are also two
powers on left and right.
Now please take your hand in the lower portion
of your abdomen on the left-hand side. This
is the center for pure, Divine knowledge.
Don’t get disturbed with this, it’s very
simple, is the center for the pure, Divine
knowledge to work out. Now you take your hand
back to the upper portion of your abdomen,
press it which is the center of mastery. Now
please take your right hand on top of your
heart which is the center of the pure Spirit.
Now please take your right hand in the corner
of your neck and shoulder and turn your head
to your right. Now this is the center I told
you about that when you feel guilty, this
goes out of order and at this juncture you
must keep this center open by not feeling
guilty at all.
Now you raise your right hand on top of your
forehead across and put down your head. This
is the center where you have to forgive everyone.
This center is extremely constricted and if
you don’t forgive, it won’t open. All
your life you’ve tortured yourself and if
you don’t forgive now, you’ll have to
miss this great opportunity of getting your
self-realization.
Now take back your right hand on the back
side of your head and push back your head.
Here, without feeling guilty, without counting
your mistakes, just for your satisfaction,
you have to ask forgiveness from the all-pervading
Divine power of love. That we’ll do later
after closing eyes, but I’m just telling
you how to do it.
Now stretch your palm. This is the last center,
very important. Stretch your palm and put
the center of your palm on top of the fontanelle
bone area. Now please put down your head.
They forget this. Please put down your head
and push back your fingers as far as possible.
Just push back, so there’s a good pressure
on the scalp. Now please move your hand in
such a way that the scalp moves, clockwise,
seven times. Do it very slowly. Put down your
head, put down your heads. Please put down
your heads. You must put down your head otherwise
it doesn’t work out better. Put down your
head. Now push back your fingers. Pushing
back your fingers is important. Push back
your fingers outward, so that there’s a
pressure on the scalp. Now move it slowly
seven times, clockwise. Don’t hold your
head, push back your fingers. Please push
back your fingers. That’s it. That’s all
we have to do.
Now, again, we put our feet apart from each
other. Put the left hand on your left lap
and put the right hand on the heart. Now please
close your eyes and please don’t open them
till I tell you. You can take out your spectacles,
if you like. Now when you put your hand on
your heart, you have to ask Me a question,
very fundamental question about yourself:
You can call Me Mother, or Shri Mataji. Here,
you please ask Me a question, in your heart,
three times. “Mother, am I the Spirit?”
Ask this question three times in your heart.
I’ve told you that if you become the Spirit,
you become your own master. So please take
your right hand in the upper portion of your
abdomen on the left-hand side and press it
hard and here you have to ask another fundamental
question about yourself. Three times, please
ask in your heart: “Mother, am I my own
master? Mother, am I my own master?”
I have told you that I respect your freedom
so I cannot force pure, Divine knowledge on
you. You have to ask for it. So please take
your right hand in the lower portion of your
abdomen on the left-hand side and here you
have to say six times because this center
has got six petals. You have to ask, please
ask six times: “Mother, please give Me pure,
Divine knowledge.” As soon as you ask for
pure, Divine knowledge, Kundalini starts rising
upward. So we have to nourish our upper centers
with our full self-confidence.
So now please raise your right hand in the
upper portion of your abdomen on the left
hand side and here you have to say ten times:
“Mother, I am my own master.” Please say
it ten times: “Mother, I am my own master.”
At the very outset I told you that you are
not this body, this mind, these emotions,
this intellect, these conditionings, this
ego, but you are the pure Spirit. So now raise
your right hand on top of your heart and here
please say twelve times with full self-confidence:
“Mother, I am the pure Spirit. Mother, I
am the pure Spirit.” This all-pervading
power of Divine love is the ocean of knowledge.
It is the ocean of blessings, it is the ocean
of compassion, but above all, it is the ocean
of forgiveness and whatever mistakes you might
commit will be completely dissolved by the
power of this ocean of forgiveness.
So please forgive yourself and put your right
hand in the corner of your neck and your shoulder
and turn your head to your right. Here you
have to say sixteen times: “Mother, I am
not guilty at all.” Please say with full
self-confidence, sixteen times: “Mother,
I am not guilty at all.” I have already
told you whether you forgive or don’t forgive,
you don’t do anything. But if you don’t
forgive, then you play into wrong hands and
torture yourself. Specially at this time if
you do not forgive, this center of agnya won’t
open and the Kundalini won’t be able to
break through. So I request you again and
again, just forgive everyone.
So now raise your right hand on top of your
forehead across and please put down your head.
Here you have to say, from your heart, not
how many times: “Mother, I forgive everyone
in general.” Please say it from your heart.
Now without feeling guilty, without counting
mistakes, just for your satisfaction, you
have to ask forgiveness from the all-pervading
Divine power. So please take your right hand
back side of your head and push back your
head as far as possible. Here now you have
to say again from the heart, not how many
times: “Oh, Divine power, if I’ve done
anything wrong knowingly or unknowingly, please
forgive me. Oh, Divine power, if I have done
anything wrong, knowingly or unknowingly,
please forgive me.”
Now the last center. Please stretch your palm
fully. Now carefully put the center of your
palm on top of the fontanelle bone area which
was a soft bone in your childhood. Now please
bend your head as much as you can. Now remember
to stretch back your fingers so there is a
good pressure on your scalp. Here again, I
respect your freedom. I cannot force self-realization
on you. So you have to say seven times, moving
the scalp seven times, you have to say: “Mother,
please give me my self-realization. Mother,
please give me my self-realization.” Now
move the scalp seven times clockwise slowly.
(Mother blows into the microphone.)
Now please take down your hand. Open your
eyes, slowly. Now please put both the hands
towards Me like this and try not to think.
Now bend your head and see with your left
hand, right hand towards Me, the left hand,
you feel if there is a hot or a cold breeze,
like vibrations, coming out of your fontanelle
bone area. Please put down your head. Now
please don’t put the hand on top but little
away. Some people get it further away. So
please move your hand and see for yourself
if there’s a cool or hot breeze, like vibrations,
coming out of your fontanelle bone area.
Now if they’re not coming, you should say:
“Mother, please come through my head. Mother,
please come through my head.” Please say
thrice. Umm. Now please put the left hand
like this, and with the right hand try to
see if there’s a cool breeze or a hot breeze
like vibration coming from your fontanelle
bone area. Now if you have not forgiven you,
or if are not yourself, or if you are not
forgiving others, it will be hot. But now
try to forgive. Forgive yourself and forgive
others. It will cool down, I’m sure it will
cool down.
Now once more only, please put your right
hand towards me and again put down the head
and with the left hand, please try to see
if there’s a cool or hot breeze like vibrations
coming out of your fontanelle bone area. This
is the actualization of baptism. This is what
is the Brahmarandhra Bheda that they call
it. Now it’s done. Don’t doubt. Now please
raise both the hands towards the sky and push
back your head and ask any one of these questions,
three questions, three times. First one is:
“Mother, is this the cool breeze of the
holy Ghost?” Or, you can ask: “Mother,
is this the all-pervading power of Divine
love?” Or you can ask: “Mother, is this
the paramchaitanya or ruh?” Ask any one
of these questions three times.
Take down your hands. Such cool is coming
from you to Me now. Now don’t doubt that
it’s air-conditioning or nothing is not:
air-conditioning is not in your head, is coming
out of your head. So don’t doubt yourself.
All those who have felt cool breeze or hot
breeze on your fingertips, on your palms or
through your fontanelle bone area, please
raise both your hands. Aah! All Americans
have got it! Aah!
I bow to you, all saints. I bow to you. (To
one person) You didn’t feel, sir? What’s
the matter with you? You didn’t feel it,
the cool breeze? No? You’re the only person.
Why? Just put your hands; it will work out.
Just put both the feet apart. Now? Are you
a doctor? [Mother asks a yogi to work on him.]
Anybody can see that. [I.e., see the vibrations,
Ed.] It’s all right. Now all those who have
not felt, are there any? One, two, three,
four. (This one, two. Three, four is not in
the cassette)