I again see today some new faces
who have come here,
and I have to explain again today,
for the first time to them,
what is Sahaja Yoga,
which has been promised in various scriptures
that you have to get your Second Birth.
You have to be born again.
It is said. Christ has said too,
the same thing.
But people have not been able to ponder
on this subject: what does that mean – our Second Birth?
Are we not already born as human beings?
We are born
but the human beings, which are born,
are told that you are to be 'born again.'
Now what are we going to do?
So they asked, "Are we to enter
into our mother's womb again?
And are to be born again?"
He said, :You'll be born of the
Holy Ghost, of the Holy Spirit."
The Holy Ghost that He talked
about is the Kundalini within us.
She is the part of the Holy Ghost,
or you can say the reflection of the Holy Ghost,
which exists as all-pervading power.
Actually the all-pervading power of Divine Love
is the love of Holy Ghost or Her aura.
This is reflected within us, as the power of desire
as shown in the picture in
the triangular bone of sacrum
and coils itself in three and a half rounds.
If you could ask the child to play there,
it would be better. Whose child is this?
Children don't understand all, they
need not understand. They are all right.
They're realised. They're enjoying themselves.
This force, which is called as residual force,
is the desire of God,
which resides within us in a dormant way.
We actually do not know what is the desire of God.
We have our own conclusions,
our own conceptions,
our own ideas that I am doing the work of God.
But you are not yet connected with God,
how can you do the work of God?
There is no way of really establishing
any actual rapport with God,
and how can you say that you are related to God
or you are doing the work of God?
It’s all right that God is looking after you,
He is managing you,
He has given you this life, is correct.
But there is no way of finding God
in your conscious mind.
It's just your mental activity
maybe your ego,
which says, "I am God."
Some people say, "I like it!"
But why do you like it?
Because I think, I like it.
Then, why, whatever you think is your own.
It is not God’s,
how do you say, with such cock-sure attitude
that you are connected with God?
Then they will start discussing about it.
They sit down and talk about it
Yesterday only we had a very funny visitor in Paris
and he started it like a tape record
and he just started telling Me what he thinks.
But your thinking is your own imagination.
There is no actual experience in it.
There is no actuality.
I said, "This is fanaticism."
When you start thinking about something
and accept it as real, then it is fanaticism,
of any kind.
You can be a football fanatic.
You think that a particular person must win.
It becomes sort of your thinking.
Then that person must win, if he does not win
then you are going to kill everybody else.
If you go a little further with it,
you think that you are a great benevolent person.
Then whatever you think,
you feel that this is the thing
that is going to bring benevolence to people.
but what is the proof?
That what you think is the thing wanted by God.
All your thinking
is based either on your conditioning,
whatever you have read,
if you are born a Christian all your thinking
will be Christian thinking means church's
thinking not God's thinking.
If you are a Hindu, you will think like a Hindu
of a temple or some sort of a Guru
or somebody who has taught you something.
If you are a Muslim you might become Khomeini
anything is possible!
Are we going in the same direction
with our thinking?
Or are we related to God?
First, relationship with God must be established.
That is extremely important
before we talk of God
because all our thinking is our conditioning
or else our imagination.
There are some people who met Me
they said they have met God.
I said, "Really?  How, how does he look like?"
"Oh, I met him on the street."
I said, "Very good."
And somebody says, "I am Christ."
Somebody says, "I am Krishna."
But what is the proof?
I mean, supposing I say this is gold.
Then gold has a density.
You can find out whether it is gold or silver
or something but you cannot just go on saying,
“I think it is gold." So it becomes gold, can it?
In the same way our faith,
because we think we have a belief in it,
is mythical – as far as you are concerned,
as far as anybody else is concerned.
Unless and until you give the proof of God,
nobody is going to believe in God any further,
I can tell you this much.
And this is the reason
another mythical stuff is coming up
is that there is no God.
This is another myth.
Either to believe that you are connected with God
is equally mythical as to say there is no God.
Because if you have not met Him
how do you say, there is not? There may be,
may not be – is a better situation.
Just to denounce Him that there is no God,
is another myth.
We some how or other managed to live with a myth.
It’s very comfortable to live with myth.
It’s a comfortable life; we do not want to
give up our comforts.
As just now, I was telling someone
that a little shell contains a little oyster in it.
Now, the oyster doesn’t want to get out of the shell.
It’s quite comfortable.
And a little bit of a sand comes in
and it sat troubling the comfort of the oyster.
So, oyster takes out his saliva
goes round it, makes it softer,
puts it there, curls up a little bit of its body
and says, “Now I am comfortable now I'm
very satisfied, it’s all right.
The shell is the thing for me."
And that’s how we go on living with the shell
avoiding understanding
that this shell is not the thing we are seeking.
So, one has to get out of that
comfortable feeling one has.
If you have a house, very nice!
I’ve got children, very nice!
I’ve got a wife, I’ve got a car. It's all right.
I am very comfortable, I am very satisfied.
But then, certain calamities come in.
You are faced with them.
Problems come in
and then you think,
"I never waited for this.
It was most unexpected."
There are another set of people,
who think – who ‘think’, again!
that they have to search God.
And that’s how they jump into sea.
They jump into fire,
they jump into water,
they jump into all kinds of things
without understanding what danger it entails.
So one side we have a comfortably coiled up
an oyster and another is an oyster
which is burnt up
which is either drowned or something.
So what should a human being do?
He should be comfortable,
but all the time he should think that
“I have not yet met God, I must meet.
I have to watch and see,
I have to understand."
Oyster in the shell
is better sometimes
than the oyster, which is completely fried out.
But the oyster in the shell
will die its own death.
But there is a possibility about the oyster
which has come out that he might meet
something.
Because he is a seeker
God also looks after him,
God also wants to help.
If he could listen to his own unconscious,
he could work it out.
Sahaja Yoga is not a new thing.
Sahaja means ‘spontaneous’.
Everything that happens in life is spontaneous.
From amoeba to this stage, you have come
spontaneously, 'Sahaja,' born with you.
It is within you!
Gradually, as a seed sprouts into a flower
and then the fragrance starts emitting out
from the flower,
in the same way it is all built in you.
You don’t have to go anywhere, it is between
your own thinking
and your desiring, it resides.
You desire something
and you don’t think about it
that is the best way you can do.
We have two capacities within us,
one is to desire. With this left side,
the deep blue coloured channel within us,
the desire.
It manifests outside
as left sympathetic nervous system,
which is our emotional side,
which is responsible for collecting all our past,
all our experiences, all our conditioning.
This is the psyche about which
the psychologists are worried.
So, we desire.
And the right side one, the yellow coloured line
represents the power by which we maintain
our physical being
and ultimately we start thinking.
Between these two resides
the power of our evolution.
So we have left side and right side
sympathetic nervous system,
manifested in the gross, and in the centre
is the parasympathetic.
Parasympathetic is a system
which shows how much we have evolved so far.
How much we have achieved so far up to
human level.
Only human beings think that
they have to achieve God, not animals.
They have reached that state that they think
that they have to achieve God,
they desire that they have to achieve God.
There is a gap between their achievement
and there is the desire.
This is to be crossed.
But their desire cannot work it out,
only their desire can call for the help from God,
and the God’s desire is within you
in this triangular bone lying dormant.
This God’s desire is called as Kundalini.
That God’s desire has to rise within you,
and it is He who has to give you the Second Birth
or you can say that the She, the Mother,
has to give you the Second Birth.
This is the Holy Ghost
about which Christ could not talk
to those mad people who really crucified Him.
They were mad that they thought that Christ
was blasphemous.
Just think of it!
And today we have churches and people,
and this and that.
When He lived nobody accepted Him,
nobody recognised Him
When He came, they talked of Moses,
Abraham.
It is very nice to handle Christ,
better talk about them, so that  we don't have
to face reality.
Because if they had recognised Christ
then Christ would have said, "All right
if you are recognising Me, then get your
Realisation
and understand yourself.”
They where not prepared for this.
Only twelve people somehow – you see
managed to be there, somehow.
They would not accept Him either.
Till He was resurrected
then they accepted Him, in a way.
And then, what are you going to do
but to create a myth around it.
And to say that, “Of course,
we believed in Christ.”
Now what, which Christ did you believe in?
Because that Christ, whom you had to face
you did not face.
And now you live in imaginary world,
you have your own paradise about it.
Where does He live within us?
Has He created any position within us?
Is there any meaning to His life,
which has left a permanent mark within us
Was He one of the
mile-stones within us?
If so – where does He reside within us?
How can we be connected to him?
Nobody made any exploration about it.
Again the comfortable shell started.
It has happened not once,
thousands of years it has been happening,
whenever an Incarnation came on this Earth
that’s how they behaved.
When Rama came they said,
“We believe in Parashurama”,
when Krishna came they said,
"We believe in Rama."
Same thing with Christ, with everyone.
But you better now recognise
and know yourself, and face it once for all,
the time has come.
How long are you going to live with your myths?
The time has come.
It has nothing to do with
East, West or North and South.
Most amazing is that in the West,
people are afraid that this is Eastern knowledge.
The other day only one lady who is a Realised Soul,
her son is a Realised Soul.
They said their teacher was very anxious
about my son, because he said, "Why are you
giving this Eastern knowledge to him?"
How can it be Eastern? It is universal knowledge
I said, "Why don't you go and ask the teacher
was Christ born in England or in America?
His cross is even, you can find it
on the airport of London.
Because I think that Christ was an Englishman.
So it’s all right, he has to – poor thing
has to become an Englishman. What to do?
This knowledge cannot be limited to Indians
or to English or to anyone.
It is God’s knowledge, it is for everyone of you
it is your right to know.
All of you have got Kundalini.
You can see with your naked eyes its pulsation;
you can see its rising.
You can see its piercing through,
you can feel it, it throbbing here.
You can see the piercing.
You can see, when it pierces through,
how you become actually collectively conscious.
You do become.
It’s a fact! And how can you avoid fact?
And why should you avoid?
Because reality is so beautiful,
why should we be afraid of facing the reality,
which is so beautiful.
There was a gentleman in Paris
who got his Realisation and two days he was
just laughing out of joy and he said,
“I’ve never laughed all my life
as I have laughed now” and just out of joy
he was laughing;
so joyous. He said, "Mother let me laugh now
and enjoy myself, I'm really living."
Actually he told me that he never believed
in God, to begin with.
He thought he was a very rational being.
I said, rational beings are still half,
because they are dealing with something
so limited, is rationality.
We have to cross these barriers of rationality,
and something is already within you,
God has placed within you because it is his
desire that you should know Him,
that His power should flow through you
and that you should be the citizen of His kingdom,
that He is your generous Father and He's
and He has made all these arrangements for you.
Now, 75% people sitting here are Realised Souls.
I’m so very happy, because I struggled
with six of them for four years.
It is such a remarkable thing
but it is very, very hard for people to believe
that you have to get an experience of God,
you have to feel Him within yourself.
As an actualisation, you have to
feel Him in your conscious mind.
Because if religion gets organised
you also get beliefs organised.
Then, whatever they say becomes perfect;
blind leading the blind.
You cannot organise God, you cannot.
He will organise.
You cannot conceive Him.
He has to conceive you.
His Grace must come on you.
You have to ask for his Grace.
He has already placed His desire within you.
And this desire resides as Kundalini.
You have heard so much about
Kundalini before also, I believe.
Maybe you must have read some horrible books,
which are shown, to Me,
that this Kundalini gives you jerks,
and you start jumping and you start making
noises and things like that.
At the very outset, I must tell you
that it is the desire of God, which is your Mother.
And this Mother is your own Mother
You do not have
any other Mother but this Mother
and She does not have any child but you.
Do you think such a Mother
who has been waiting to give you this rebirth
would be in any way troublesome to you?
Even your physical mother bore all the pains
upon herself to give you birth.
Then why should this Mother try to trouble you?
Then people asked Me, "Then how did
these people talk of these things?
I mean you can talk of anything
if you want to befool people.
If you want to befool people, can’t you?
I mean, if you indulge into such a thing you
can. You can get possessed by somebody
also, that you start writing all these nonsensical things.
So many mythical things have been written
apart from that, those who write that Kundalini
gives you jerks and all that
maybe the people, who were something like
villagers coming and touching the electricity
at a wrong point and getting a shock and maligning
the electricity, maybe the unauthorised people,
who did not know anything about Kundalini.
For Kundalini can only be awakened by an authorised
person who is authorised by God.
not by theological college or by any Pandit
or by any Ayurveda school or anything.
Christ never went to any theological college.
It cannot be done by any such person
who says he will read books and raise the Kundalini.
It’s not the mechanism that works out that way.
You cannot even sprout a seed by reading.
Can you?
You have done nothing living by reading.
How can you raise Kundalini by reading?
This is in your every day-to-day life we really
lack sometimes common sense.
We go and read something,
we think by reading something we are going
to go to God,
or we then sit down and discuss about it.
You cannot do anything by this reading, which
is just a dead thing!
All your arguments, everything is dead.
It is not yet enlightened; otherwise every word
could be living.
That’s the Mantra.
The word that is living is the Mantra.
These holy words,
if spoken by a person who is not enlightened
has no meaning at all.
If it is spoken by a person, who is enlightened,
because enlightenment
means he is related to God
and he can address to God
like you get connected.
All right, if it is done, done, nothing to worry.
Nothing to feel bad, if some people have been
very fanatically involved into it,
it doesn’t matter.
Makes no difference at all today, I feel.
All kinds of things, whatever are done are done
in the past, finished.
We have to get our Realisation.
We have to actualise ourselves.
This is the main point.
We are seeking ourselves.
Unless and until you realise yourself
you don’t have to even believe in Me,
but you should not deny Me.
I would not like anybody to believe in Me, blindly,
because blind people cannot get it.
But you should not be also closed
because closed people also cannot get it.
When you get it then you must believe,
that is what is called as 'Shraddha.'
In Sanskrit language, there two things are;
one is blind faith and another is Shraddha,
that is faith, pure faith.
But in English we have to use an adjective
that blind faith and faith.
But people are so confused that they forget
the adjective of blind,
and they think my faith is... If your faith is that
one has to accept it.
But your faith should be such that it is based
on the truth.
Then you become an enlightened person.
After all God has made us into human beings,
He has given us this nose, eyes, everything.
We have done nothing about it.
And if He has made us for a purpose, He is going
to connect us, He is going to do it.
It’s His job
If He does not do it, He will have no meaning,
His creation will have no meaning.
It is His job!
And besides that somebody else wants to do
it for you, why should you worry?
Once you get it, you can do it, too.
Like one light enlightened can
enlighten another light, you can do it.
Today I wanted to talk a little bit,
because 75 % are Sahaja Yogis, who are Realised
Souls and who know Sahaja Yoga, they have
given Realisation to so many, they have cured
people and I mean they are just there.
And I was very happy that in Paris so many
of them achieved their Nirvikalpa,
which is... we call as the Doubtless Awareness.
The first state is the Thoughtless Awareness.
Awareness means, 'Enlightened
Awareness,' you can say,
'Samadhi' is the one where your awareness
becomes enlightened.
The first state is of Thoughtless Awareness.
And then you jump into your Realisation,
but still the state is not established.
You mature then as Doubtless Awareness,
and this Doubtless Awareness is a state, is not
a thing. “Now I have no doubts about Sahaja
Yoga”, that’s not the way. It's a state,
where the rhythm of these vibrations,
or the rhythm of these radiations
achieve a certain depth and a rhythm,
which then you yourself start seeing that these
doubts are something separate and you build
up your own reserve against them. It's not
mental state, it is the state of the being.
You can say a seed becoming a fruit
and maturing,
or you can say a flower becoming a fruit
and then the fruit maturing.
In this way, first you get your Self Realisation
and you get your Thoughtless Awareness.
And then you get your Doubtless Awareness.
But people who are not complicated so much,
uncomplicated people, simple people,
PART OF SHRI MATAJI'S TALK IS MISSING
chakras are alright,  or not you start verifying it
through your brain.
You go round and round and round.
That's why the first thing you get is...
your attention gets enlightened.
You put your attention to someone and you
know about that person on your fingers.
You can feel their centres and then you know
through decoding what centres.
Supposing somebody is having a heart-attack
or something you can feel it on this finger,
a heat, or a kind of a spasm,
sometimes and sometimes numbness.
If a person is going to die, you feel a numbness
in all your fingers. There are many things
which decode it. Apart from physical
you have got also emotional problems
which can be found out. The left side suggest
the emotional problem and the right side
the physical and the mental problem.
If a person is egoistical,
if his ego is hurt, anyway if there's a problem
with his ego somehow or other
in any way, then you get this
finger catching very much.
But after getting Realisation, you
don't feel bad if somebody says,
“Mother, my Agnya here is catching.”
All right, you say it, you don’t feel bad about it.
You say, "All right, clear it out!"
This centre is that of Christ.
Even many people who call themselves Christians
have the same Agnya as the Jews
have and as the Muslims have.
One because they are unauthorised
that’s why Christ is angry, another
because they are criticising Christ.
Both ways it is just the same.
Christ wants, or anyone of them, they want
that you should realise them, you should feel
them, you should know them.
Today specially for the Sahaja Yogis I
wanted to discuss the right side very much,
because so far, we have not dealt with it very
much. Normally we got people who were
on the left side, on the emotional problem.
The right side is called also as Prana Shakti,
means the vital power of life.
And the left side is called as Mana Shakti.
Now this Prana Shakti,
which is on the right-hand side...
What's happened?
There's some noise somewhere.
The Prana Shakti within us
comes to us through five elements.
The five elements are, as you know,
is, one of them is the earth,
then we have got the water,
then we have got the air,
then we have got the light
and then we have got the ether.
These five elements are there.
Out of these five elements our body is made.
These five elements create five cocoons around
us. And that’s how we have got five auras within us.
These five auras can be
detected by some machines
because these machines are
able to detect only the right side
as they deal with matter.
The whole of the matter is created by these five
energies and they have also a casual energy behind
it. And these casual energies actually make that.
For example: the causal
energy of earth is fragrance.
From the fragrance earth is created.
Now, within us all these five centres
that you see
these are, these five up to
here, are made of five elements.
The body of those centres are made of
only the body part, I am saying
– of those five elements.
And the Deities residing in those centres
are also born from those five elements.
Because they were born of a particular element,
they concentrated more on that and maintained
the knowledge more limited to that area,
which dealt with that particular element.
For example, we can say the green thing is the
one that represents the water, water element.
This centre in the stomach is
the water element within us.
It is called as Nabhi Chakra
and around it is called as the
Bhavasaghara, you can say the Void
or you can say the Gap, or whatever you may say,
the whole world as such, within us.
So the people who were born on
this centre, around this centre,
were born out of water element.
In this Bhavasaghra, Bhavasaghra
means the ocean of this world
were born, through this ocean of the world,
were born all the Primordial Masters
one after another,
we can say Abraham, Moses,
we had Janaka, we had Adi Nath and Socrates
and so many others like that
Nanaka
and also very recently we
had about hundred years back
a very great saint born in India known as Sainath.
They all represent the same
element, that is the water element,
being responsible or being born out of that
they are anxious to maintain water element as the
one which is within us for sustaining ourselves.
We are sustained by water so they
help us to sustain ourselves.
They are the sustainers, they tell us
how to sustain, as a human being.
And all of them have tried to establish religion
within us. A religion doesn’t mean outside,
but the religion as a man, means the capacity
of a man or you can say, the quality of a man.
What a human being should be like,
what is the way to know if
he is a human being or not
which is described in the Ten Commandments.
Now the way they have said it is all
misinterpreted and all wrong things have come.
But one thing is definite, that they have never talked of fanaticism.
They are against fanaticism.
They are against alcoholism, because
alcohol spoils the water element very much.
If you see the effect of alcohol on
water in the blood of human beings
you will be amazed how
the neutral position of hydrogen
and oxygen are over time
is absolutely imbalanced by alcohol.
And water cannot absorb any heat from the liver,
which sorts out all your poisons.
And that's how people get bad livers and bad troubles
and then people would say, "What's wrong?"
There is nothing wrong as such,
because even nothing wrong in that.
“What’s wrong according to the theory
of wrong and right of human beings,
I think nothing is wrong. You can kill
yourself. You can jump from anything.
You can do whatever you like.
There is nothing wrong. If you break this, if you
break that, if you break anybody, do anything,
there is nothing wrong what’s wrong with it?
But there is fundamentally wrong is
that you are created for a purpose.
You have not created yourself.
God has created you with such difficulties.
He has taken you out of
so many evolutionary processes
and brought you to this stage
and now you have no business to
kill yourself and destroy yourself.
This is wrong is that you are destroying
yourself, you are destroying your community
you are destroying others or
you are destroying yourself.
If you are destroying yourself also because
you are on your own, you think, "What’s wrong?"
You are a part and parcel of the whole.
You are a cell in the whole and
being created to know the whole
and if you destroy yourself you
are destroying the whole as well.
You become malignant. You become cancerous
and that’s why it’s all wrong.
In anyway if you destroy others or destroy
yourself you have no right to do that.
God has given you freedom, no doubt.
By creating ego and superego within
yourself with these activities,
you become separated from the whole.
And then you think you are Mr Such and Such.
And then you stand and say, “I
believe in this, and I believe in...,"
actually who are you? You are made by God.
You are His own child.
Still you are a child.
It's like a baby saying, "I believe in it, I believe in it."
You have not known the whole so far.
How can you say that?
You have to grow!
And when you grow, your
freedom is complete,
absolute.
But the ideas about this freedom are such
that you are fighting your own innocence
you are fighting your own sustenance.
And this sustenance was completely supported
protected by these great
incarnations of Primordial Masters.
That’s why they talked against alcohol.
Christ did not talk about alcohol, all
right – because He was at another point,
but He did not say that you take alcohol, never.
People said that He drank wine
but wine means grape juice in that country,
it doesn’t mean alcohol.
How can Christ say, you drink wine,
which is fermented,
which will go against your awareness?
Just think of it!
It goes against your awareness, isn’t it?
Your awareness is to be enlightened,
He came on this earth to enlighten that awareness,
do you think He will say that you get foggy with it?
Does it not fog your attention and your awareness,
is a fact.
But He wants to do something else
because He came as Divine Power itself.
He was the embodiment of Pranava
not Prana – all powers put together.
He was the embodiment of OM itself, the Brahma.
That’s why He came to prove
what Krishna has said,
that it cannot be killed by anyone.
It cannot be blown off,
it cannot be destroyed.
His body was made out of that,
and that’s why He could be resurrected.
All these things are knowledgeable
only if you are a realised soul,
otherwise you cannot understand this.
Because you have not yet gone into the depth
of your own understanding,
you are still children as I say,
you have to be born again,
and then you can find out for these vibrations.
You have to ask just a question,
“Was Christ embodied with Pranava,
or the OM, or the Brahma?
Or was He made of Brahma itself?”
You will get the cool breeze.
and that is the sign that He was.
It is much deeper but the whole
knowledge exists as experience to you.
The whole of it, it is an experience within us.
And one has to get that experience of oneself,
which is knowledge itself
and then everything trickles down
just like actual thing within us,
as we see white as white and red as red.
Animals do not see perhaps,
but human beings do see.
Thus, our awareness is enlightened.
I will be talking to other Sahaja Yogis in
the Ashram about the right side later on
because we have new people, and
they are to be looked after.
And I think, next time when I
meet, I don’t know when, maybe...
No, in the Ashram firstly. Thursday evening I think, then
I'll talk to you because Friday I've got to fly out.
Thursday evening I will
be there most probably.
So just now, let’s have the
experience for the new ones,
and for the others also to deepen themselves.
May God bless you.
All of you should put your
hands just like this, before Me,
and close your eyes, just close your eyes!
Put the hands like this, you
see and just close your eyes.
You have to close your eyes because
the Kundalini, when She rises
on the Agnya Chakra
the dilatation of the pupil takes place
and if your eyes are open the dilatation doesn’t take place.
When people mesmerize they keep your eyes
open, because they put you on the sides.
I will tell one day how they mesmerise, also.
First you will feel that there is no thought
in your mind, if you watch your thoughts.
Then the Kundalini rises about
Agnya, you get Thoughtless Awareness.
When it pierces the fontenel bone area, I mean
when you get your baptism by your Kundalini,
then you feel the kind of a cool
breeze coming towards you from me;
or a kind of a radiation of cool breeze
coming. From all over you might feel it.
On your hands! Through
your fingers! It works!
All of you should put your
hands towards me. Please!
That's important.
I mean even to put your hands is hard to
request, that means how egotistical you are.
You've come here for getting your Realisation
and don't even want to put your hands towards me.
All such people should leave.
Getting cool breeze?
Great!
Close you eyes and enjoy yourself.
Best is to enjoy, this is the greatest
moment you've been waiting for.
Close you eyes!
Enjoy yourself!