no no you see to begin with see it has
something to do with your nervous
alright so if your nervous system is
disturbed you may not feel at all what
the nervous system best thing is to do
massage somebody should massage their
back hands also I have told many times
that you rub your hands vibrated olive
oil quite a lot and drop these things so
if they become self could be within
sensitivity but if they can feel the
catches in this in the body that means
they're all right only that we should is
not all right rub the thing all the
machine work on we should be clear it
out and for we should be if you can use
say butter could rub on the here and rub
all these muscles listen with that all
these things will work out for your hand
but supposing you are there's no cool
breeze coming out of the head possibly
then the realization is not yet
established see other people should say
whether there's a cool breeze coming
because the person who is not realized
may not feeling supposing he does not
feel it and you feel it then he's
realized to only think his chakras are
to be cleared it's a different different
category of things then there are some
people whose Kundalini has not risen
there still sahaja yogi like that maybe
I don't know if there are any those
people who are unmarried for long they
are very difficult because they never
feel the cool things in that quite a lot
like that but it is not so they are
realized Souls in any case they may not
feel it but they realized so to see
because it kind of a soft as a kind of a
balance is developed after marriage
which is not there and that's how some
people don't feel
there are various reasons some people
who are oriented war they should turn
their left to the right
many at times they should find out from
the hands you see one hand is bigger one
hand is smaller that means the left side
if it is smaller that means you have to
raise left over that you see from the
size of the hands and all that you can
see putting one hand towards the
photograph another hand outside work it
out in so many ways because you have
permutations and combinations of certain
mistakes but that doesn't mean you
develop this left it should be by any
chance because that's the worst thing
that can happen if you develop the left
Rashidi then it's a very difficult
situation now
for this kind of a thing I think I will
give you a complete lecture on one day
complete as to see what permutations and
combinations of different chakras can
feel all right
but symptoms are outside the symptoms
are mostly outside there's no need to
from a personality to see what it is
since that is a very problem with a
problem with people that they don't feel
the vibration some people just don't
really how many there are like that
who never feel any vibration never
friend no you never your felt it
sometime
[Music]
which was good the answer what work you
are doing in Russia all right you had a
left side catch all right you can see
clearly a right hand is very shining the
left there is a problem you see this
these fingers are not so shiny as the
things are you had a left side problem
if you remember it all right so that's
fighting in the ashram the vibrations
are fighting that's why I feel hot
there's something wrong it will correct
it will happen please put your right
hand always up and left I'm tall so it
will correct