Pranava Mardini Ki!
Jai Shri Mataji!
I’m sorry what has happened yesterday, but
I think the war has begun between the evil
and good, and after all the good prevails.
In these modern times, evil used to prevail
on good but now in this Kruta Yuga the evil
will be completely conquered by good, and
not only that, but good will spread all over.
The evil has the capacity to go to extremes
and then to fall out of the evolutionary process
completely.
Because they are blind they cannot see the
good that’s why they are evil.
If they could see the good they would give
up their evil.
In our country which is a country of yoga,
especially Maharastra which is the country
of the saints, I was amazed to hear what people
are up to.
One of the real source of this nonsense seems
to be Rajneesh, the horrible fellow, because
he has made an exhibition here absolutely
denouncing all the deities and saying all
kinds of dirty things, and I think the chief
minister of this place is also hand in glove
with him and they are all trying to prove
that there is no God, there is no spirituality.
They want to establish that science is everything.
We have no heritage of science in India, we
have the heritage of spirituality.
I mean nobody is known as such a great scientist
in this country.
Nobody has made any special inventions and
the way people are organising it in the name
of science, there is hardly anyone who has
done anything of science.
So it’s the evil which has taken this new
form of talking about science and denouncing
God.
Of course in the West also the same thing
has happened to a great extent but not to
that extent.
They have not discarded everything that was
spiritual.
But here they have gone headlong, those few
people who are there, very very few, but they
are there.
So it’s a very bad growth in this country,
it won’t survive I know, it cannot survive
because this country is so full of spirituality.
In the West, because people took to science,
they have lost all culture of society.
There is no culture of society.
The etiquettes are limited to fork and spoon
or how you wish each other.
There is no other culture.
It’s so outside, there is nothing deep in
it because they have taken absolutely to the
modern or we can say that is the industrial
evolution of the people, they have taken to
all that and have lost contact with reality.
The culture of any country can only survive
on spirituality.
Science cannot talk of this and it has so
many limitations that it cannot even answer
simple few questions that are facing them.
Above all they have no idea what is love,
they have no idea what is the all pervading
power.
Now you all have felt it, and you know what
it is, and you know how to use it.
So under these circumstances I find that those
people who are mediocres in Sahaja Yoga cannot
help much for establishing goodness.
You have to be very clean within yourself,
you have to be very powerful within yourself
and you have to be extremely sensitive.
So, we are not to waste our energy, our attention
onto superficial and nonsensical things.
We have to get out of it and we have to become
people who are detached, detached from any
things which create problems.
If you take a detached view of everything
you will have a kind of a life that will nourish
your society which is now sick, is a sick
society, is a decadent society.
And for that decadent society you need people
who are very morally strong, who are tremendously
pure and who know everything about Sahaja
Yoga.
The mediocrity in Sahaja Yoga is very common
in the West, very common.
And so much involved into their personal problems
that I cannot understand how will they rise
above this nonsensical, personal viewpoint
of view.
So, one has to realise that the whole tree
that has grown outside so much due to industrial
revolution has to seek its own nourishment
from spirituality which is in India.
No doubt.
Spirituality without development has no meaning.
Spirituality has to have development outside
otherwise it is lost in the Mother Earth.
It has to sprout and it has to show results,
which we are showing no doubt, in so many
ways Indian Sahaja Yogis are trying to show
that, though they are rather slow about that
point.
So it’s something funny that in the West
people are rather slow, Sahaja Yogis are rather
slow about their spirituality, and in India
people are rather slow about their manifestation
outside.
Unless and until we really do some dedicated
effort it’s not going to work out.
So I hope as we have circulated letters that
we have come here not for fun but for dedication
and for our ascent and it’s a pilgrimage.
Talking loose, talking about small things,
quarrelling with each other is out of question
of course, but domination, terrible domination
of falsehood, just to think that you are leaders,
or why is he leader, shows that we are not
yet worthy.
So the worthiness of a ship is very important
if it has to fight the turbulence of the sea.
If it cannot fight the turbulence of the sea
then it is definitely not seaworthy and it
is absolutely useless because it cannot go
across.
In the same way if you have to be something,
you have to work it out in such a manner that
you really become worthy of crossing this
ocean of illusion and that many could cross
with you.
As in India they have started at every place,
at every home, at every family, a center.
If they invite people, they talk about nothing
but Sahaja Yoga.
Now you can go all out to talk about it, I
give you permission to tell them that I have
come, there’s nothing to hide.
And you have to go and open the doors of many
churches and many temples and many organisations
and tell them that I am there.
Now the time has come, you can see it so clearly,
it’s so obvious.
First I used to say I would not go to the
newspapers, this not good that’s not good,
let us work it out.
But it has come now so much, that I have to
say things and I am going to say them, very
openly, I am going to say them.
But I want all of you to be such that nobody
should point out a finger at you to say, “Oh,
this is a Sahaja Yogi and how this Sahaja
Yogi is behaving."
If somebody is stupid and not working it out
is better to get rid of such a person.
Or else help that person and tell him that
“you have to come out, you can’t be here,
we don’t want mediocre people here.
We want some very extraordinarily, pure people.“
The purity is the main point which we have
to have.
Once you are pure you don’t have to worry,
then I look after you.
But the purity of mind, purity of heart and
the purity of your attention, these three
things are very important.
When it works out, you’ll be surprised,
collectivity will grow in no time.
Is a tendency among Sahaja Yogis also, still,
to go back to the same materialism and to
try to have your own house, your family, your
children, this sort of a nonsense.
We have to be in the ashrams, we have to work
it out, we have to work it out very beautifully
that we all live very happily in the ashram.
But I find still people cannot work it out
that way.
They are more concerned about their jobs,
concerned about their things.
Once you live in the ashram I’ll see that
you get everything.
But if you do not want to have the blessings
of God, how can anybody help you?
So tremendous sacrifice is needed.
Of course as you know in Sahaja Yoga I don’t
need any money from you at all, but sacrifice
is very important, and sacrifice of nonsensical
ideas that you have.
In every way we have to show that we Sahaja
Yogis: the way you dress up, the way you live,
the way you think, the way you behave, the
way you have relationships with each other
and the way you lead your married life and
the way you look at your children.
Unless and until you have purity the light
of love will not shine, the light of love
will not shine.You have to absorb the light
of love within yourself, but you cannot unless
and until you are a pure personality.
And that pure personality has to develop by
your meditation, by working hard, it’s a
question of few years.
In 10 years we can change the whole world,
in 10 years!
But you have to be really very dedicated.(applause)
It is you who has to change, not Me.
You have to work it out, not Me.
I have done my level best but within 10 years
it should be possible that every Sahaja Yogi
should become a tremendous force of Sahaja
Yoga.
So please try to avoid all those who are mediocres.
If you find mediocrity, the leaders must go
all out to correct them, all out to tell them
off.
Don’t tolerate.
You don’t have to be very mild on this point,
you have to tell them frankly that “See
now you are an extremely mediocre person for
Sahaja Yoga, is not meant for mediocres, is
not meant for foolish people, is not meant
for stupid people, it’s meant for something
who are ready to sacrifice anything for the
sake of truth.“
These people are saying that “Why don’t
you go the way of science?”
I say “Why don’t you go the way of truth?”
Take to truth.
Science is not truth.
Today it might appear, tomorrow it disappears.
Today you may think it is correct but every
hypothesis is challenged, every law is challenged,
that’s no law.
You have to use Sahaja Yoga in every practical
life everywhere.
But in no way you have to be fanatic about
it.
Like I have seen some people start giving
vibrations or they start moving their hands
for bandhans, even if I am sitting they are
doing like that.
There is no stupidity about it, it has to
be very dignified, decent and decorous.
But for that we need really people of quality
and a complete obedience is needed I must
say.
I have told Indian people that time that they
must have a proper case done for them, they
just didn’t listen to Me that time, they
said “Mother, why do you want, you’ll
be in trouble”, and all that.
If they had listened to Me there would have
been no trouble today.
But you must listen to Me what I say, don’t
give Me explanations, don’t give Me logic,
but I know everything you know that.
I know everything.
Now we have something good for you is the
list of the marriages.
But marriage is not such an important thing
that you think about.
It’s not such an important thing for you
that you dedicate all your attention to that.
It’s just by the way, because you have to
have a marriage, that’s why.
There’s no need even to have sometimes.
But you have to have it, and then letters
after letters about your marriages, about
your children, I just don’t want to read
that.
Nothing about Sahaja Yoga.
If you are detached, whatever may be the quality
of your wife, you will not fall, whatever
may be the quality of your husband, you will
not fall.
So one has to be little concerned that: What
are we doing?
What have we achieved?
What are we going to give to the world?
For Me, you are My instruments.
I don’t have to ask anybody else.
You are My instruments and you have to work
it out.
You are not for Me useless people, I worked
very hard with you, very hard.
So please don’t waste My energies also and
try to become very good Sahaja Yogis in every
way that is possible, in every way you should
be dedicated, in every way try to be something
of very great qualities.
Now you have seen how people have becoming
violent and there is a violence on.
Of course, this may not continue but it’s
one of the signs that we have to be prepared
to be very strong people, very strong, and
that will work out I’m sure.
They threw about 400 stones at least, maybe
more according to the police report and very
few people were hurt.
What does that mean?
That there is somebody who is avoiding all
these troubles.
Regarding our tour further, now I have decided
we will not go to Atith because the commissioner,
the ESP, has told Me that it is better not
to go, that these people are very bad that
they are criminals.
So now until the election comes in they will
be behaving like this manner.
After the election of course they will be
put down.
So you should go by the understanding of the
time and directly to Sangli, so we’ll go
to Sangli, we will have a puja there, you
can do shopping whatever you like and then
from there will be going to Ganapatipule.
But it’s not fun, it’s not fun.
It is our development.
Otherwise you will be coming to India, going
back the same empty handed.
I want you everyone to be extremely active
in your own sphere of life, to talk about
Sahaja Yoga.
You must wear my badges, you must wear my
rings, you must wear my necklaces so that
people ask you “Who is this?”
Then you should say, “She is the Holy Ghost”,
you can say!
“We think she is the Holy Ghost”.
Let us see what happens.
So, it’s a serious thing that I felt that
I have to talk to you and that we have to
be very, very careful about how we look at
ourselves.
We have to be aware, we have to be aware about
ourselves and what is happening.
I’ve been telling you this many a times,
we have to be aware as to what we are and
what is happening.
But if your jobs are important, everything
else is important how are you going to work
out Sahaja Yoga?
So there has to be awareness and with your
awareness the light will spread.
But it’s not silent, you have to talk about
it.
Eloquence is needed, it has to be eloquent,
all your light has to talk, the light has
to say, the light has to express and has to
be very confidently done.
Let us see now after going from this tour
how far people establish new things.
So far, what My own opinion is that there
are 50% of Sahaja Yogis in the West are still
quite mediocre and 25% of them are just there
to take advantage.
If they can get something free they would
like to do it.
25% people are like that.
It’s very sad but it is so.
But I must say Indians are poor people but
they will not do anything, they will never
take anything free from Me, nothing.
They will not, they are very self respecting.
And that is what we have to develop, that
self respect.
Like I have seen I had a house in Hounslow,
everybody went there and stayed there free.
Now we have a house there in Shuddy Camp where
everybody who has no job goes and stays there.
It’s such a nonsensical thing.
So I’m even afraid to start any ashram in
London because same thing will start.
If they can take advantage they would like
to be there.
Even a spoon they would like to carry like
that.
It’s a shameless thing for a Sahaja Yogi
to behave like that I think.
We have to have full self respect and we must
understand that we have to sacrifice, to do
something about it.
Because this is the last leg I would say when
I will be talking to you about all these things
in the beautiful atmosphere here on the bank
of Krishna river.
We have to understand that the river flows,
it makes a sound, it makes a sound to show
that she/it exists.
But we are not only rivers, we are all the
mountains, rivers, everything of the universe
we are, and our manifestation is like a big
zero as if the Mother Earth has been emptied
out.
It is time that we should watch ourselves,
see ourselves, what’s wrong with us.
Very important.
I had to say this once again and again, but
I don’t like to say these things because
I love you so much and I care for you so much
and you people also love Me, but loving Me
is not sufficient, you have to love yourself
and respect yourself.
Only yourself is going to work out.
As Shivaji Maharaj said “You must develop
the religion of your Spirit”.
That’s what we have to do, is to develop
the religion of our Spirit.
And once it happens we can get the whole world
completely emancipated.
This is our work and if we fail then it is
the responsibility of Sahaja Yogis and nobody
else.
So for everyone I have to tell you that I
don’t have to please you, you have to please
me.
For a small thing people react, for a small
thing they feel bad.
If I don’t smile at somebody they feel bad.
In little, little things they feel bad and
they react.
If I say anything, they react.
So how can anything go into you?
If it is such a convexity, how will you absorb
it?
It is important that we should try to absorb
with humility, with understanding.
Now you are Sahaja Yogis, you know I am Adi
Shakti, you have had photographs, you have
known that I am Adi Shakti – but how much
are we absorbing?
How much we are taking within ourselves?
This work is much more than any one of the
incarnations had to do, is much more than
Christ, is much more than Rama, much more
than Shri Krishna’s.
So create such great people among you, because
I have the power, only thing, you have to
have the absorption power, the acceptability.
But if you run after something very cheapish
and something very frivolous, it’s impossible.
You have to ask for your depth and you have
to take in whatever is emitting from My being.
I hope now you all will take it up seriously,
do your meditation every morning whatever
maybe the time.
Every morning you have to do the meditation
and we have to see that we finish our work
in the night and then we do little meditation
and then sleep off.
Without meditation you cannot grow and that’s
why everything doing you have to know that
you have to get up in the morning, do your
meditation and then you can take to your work.
Daytime if you want you can rest for a while.
Now we are in such a place that we have time
to rest for a while, but morning time you
have to get up whatever time you sleep.
You have to conquer your sleep a little bit,
it gives you lot of lethargy.
Last night I don’t think I slept before
3 o’clock or something like that and then
the whole day I’ve been busy writing reports,
this, that.
If I can manage at this age, at your age you
should be able to manage something like that.
We have no time to sleep, we have no time
to discuss, argue or to eat our food.
We have only time to meditate, that’s all.
I wish all of you absorb My saying and understand
it without reacting to it.
Please do not react.
Don’t think “Mother is trying to chastise
you”.
No, I’m trying to help you to grow, this
is the way you grow sometimes very fast.
So it’s just your growth I am worried about
and nothing else.
May God bless you all.
I was very happy the way you were singing
all the songs and the way you expressed yourselves.