Today we are here, all of us, to celebrate
a four day festival called as Diwali.
Diwali comes from the word ‘dipali’; ‘dipali’
in Sanskrit.
The word ‘deepa’ means ‘the lights’,
and ‘ali’ means the ‘line’, the ‘rows’.
Now, there are many things that have happened
during these four days and that’s how it
is celebrated with such a great enthusiasm.
The first thing is the day of the Lakshmi’s
birth.
That is the thirteenth day of the moon, “dhanteras’
they call it.
[Which] is the real day when Lakshmi was born
out of the sea; that’s why She is called
as Miriam or Maryam.
The word ‘Marie’ or ‘Marine’, also
comes from the word ‘sea’.
So, She’s born out of the sea, She’s created
out of the sea.
And the wealth of the sea, so far, thank God,
human beings have not yet exploited.
But they may, one day, start doing that also.
And a lot of wealth is still there, so when
people start getting worried about exhausting
the Mother Earth, we must know that sea is
much more than the Earth is, so nothing is
exhausted.
Still there is such a lot in reserve for you,
and one should not worry as to the supply
of wealth that can come from the sea.
Now, this Lakshmi is the goddess who stands
on the lotus.
She represents all the well-being, the wealth,
the glory of wealth, the decoration of wealth;
whichever is auspicious.
Whatever is not auspicious is not wealth according
to Sahaja Yoga, or according to any scripture.
It is not wealth at all.
So She is a lady who stands on a lotus: showing
that a person, who has got wealth, has to
be a person who doesn’t assert his pressures
on people, who doesn’t push people around,
who doesn’t pressurise.
And then She’s a lady, She’s a mother.
So wealth, is the first opening to our seeking.
But when you start seeking the wealth, you
realise that the superficial wealth that you
are seeking is not sufficient, is not going
to give you complete joy.
So you start seeking the deeper wealth.
As I said that: on the Mother Earth you have
exploited all that is possible [but] still
there, deep down in the sea, a lot of wealth
is still there.
So then the seeking moves towards the deeper
seeking.
So the same Lakshmi becomes Mahalakshmi.
When you start expanding yourself to higher
and deeper, valuable things then this Lakshmi
doesn’t lure you much: She’s just there
for your glory, but not for your satisfaction.
The wealth is there for distribution only.
You enjoy the…there’s no word for ‘dhan’
[in English] I think?
Yogi: Generosity.
Shri Mataji: Oh, “generosity’!
But generosity is different.
But what I’m saying [is] generous fondness.
It’s a fondness that you should be generous.
Sometimes it’s a very great
happiness and joy that you feel — that is
the greatest — when you are generous, when
you give away.
That’s a fondness, that’s a kind of a
human expression of one’s own being: that
you want to be generous.
And this generosity only can come when Mahalakshmi
principle is born in you.
But at Lakshmi principle also She stands like
this; Her hand is like this one: as giving.
And the other is like this.
So miserliness is not a sign of wealth.
I mean, if you are miserly that means you
are not wealthy.
If you are really wealthy, why will you be
miserly?
This simple question is there.
That means if you are really wealthy, you
will just give away.
If you cannot give away, then you are poor,
you are a beggar.
[If] you are still hankering after that, that
means you are still a beggar, and you are
hankering for it.
So [with] this left hand She is giving all
the time, and with the right hand She protects
people.
She gives protection to people.
The wealth must give protection to people,
in the way [that] it must look after the well
being of others, not your own self-indulgence:
like having all the best things to yourself
while others are starving.
That’s not a sign of a wealthy man.
A wealthy man is a person who knows that,
unless and until he shares his things with
others, he is not going to be happy, ultimately.
For the time being he may be.
People live with imbalances, they live with
wrong ideas.
But ultimately they have to correct it.
If they do not correct this, there are problems.
Then there’s upheaval, lots of changes come
in.
People start seeing that, “Oh, this doesn’t
work out, that doesn’t work out."
The children run away from the houses, the
family goes into problems.
All sorts of things happen, and then they
realise, “This is the reason: I have been
very miserly.
I have not been generous.
I have not been using money for the sake of
others."
Now, after coming to Sahaja Yoga, you become
a Divine person.
Definitely you become Divine.
You are now a Divine personality, you are
not a human personality.
So you have to give up all that is human within
you, then only you will be fully Divine.
But it’s very difficult.
That’s [what] the problem is: that it is
very difficult to really accept that you are
Divine, and that you have to take to Divine
policies and Divine attitudes, and Divine
temperament.
Now, the Divine temperament is generous.
It is not bothered, as to what happens next.
It’s not bothered, because it is connected
with the Source.
If you give one you will get a hundred.
It is sure about it.
And to a Divine person, worldly things have
no meaning, if they cannot give pleasures
to others.
A person who is very self-indulgent, always
bothered about himself, is not a Divine person
at all.
In no way he’s Divine.
It’s very common.
It’s human.
Everybody does that.
Everybody is self-preserving.
But after Sahaja Yoga, you do not start all
this nonsense again; you give it up.
And who looks after you?
Who looks after your self-preservation?
Is God Almighty.
You are now completely dedicated to Him, and
He looks after you.
You don’t have to worry as to how to look
after yourself, how to do this, how to do
that.
It is His work.
The more you go on worrying about yourself,
the worse it will be.
The moment you give it up, it is looked after.
Many Sahaja Yogis must have experienced this
in their lifetime: that when they try to give
it up, they get all the help from God; but
whenever they try to assert, and worry about
their well-being and things like that, then
there is a problem.
You don’t know from where the help comes
in.
And we have had so many examples, so many
so-called miracles, where people wanted to
do something, and suddenly they got the money
from somewhere they least expected.
So for a Divine person, the attitude should
be of giving and of protection: protect.
Now, we are very good at protecting our bhoots,
and protecting others who are bhoots.
You see, the sympathies always go to bhoots,
because they have a way of creating a sympathetic
attitude in your heart.
So you start looking after that person because
that person looks so much miserable.
You have to protect the saints.
You have to protect the principle of God,
the Divinity in others, and not the bhoots.
You are not here to care for all the bhoots
of the world.
So the idea of Lakshmi must be understood
in a proper way.
In Sahaja Yoga it’s a very different thing
from all other people know about; like charity.
Like, people say now, “We must be charitable,
start a charitable organisation."
In that, you look after this kind of people,
that kind of people.
We are not bothered.
That’s not [what] you are given Realisation
for: to look after every sort of a person.
You are here to look after all the saints
and all born-realised children.
And you are not to bother about people who
do not matter to God and Divine.
When they came to Realisation, if they get
Realisation, if they become saints, all right.
But you don’t worry about every Dick, Tom
and Harry, on the street: “Oh Mother, he’s
so miserable!” and this and that.
So the charity must be understood in a Divine
light.
And the Divine light will give you discretion,
to understand whom to be charitable [to].
You have to be charitable to your brothers
and sisters.
You have to be kind to them.
Now you will say: “What about worrying about,
Mother, people who are starving?
Who are this?”
That’s not your headache!
Why should you do their jobs?
You are all good at doing others’ jobs.
For example, you are driving in the car: “Oh,
look at this!
There should have been this properly done!
That they should have done properly!” but
that’s not your job!Why should you waste
your energy in finding out what the others
should have done?
You should do what you have to do.
And don’t waste your energy in these things.
You see, [in] all these charitable institutions,
I have seen [that] those people who work there
are very difficult for Realisation.
This is the proof of the pudding.
Because to whom to do the charity?
If there is no other person, you do not do
charity to anyone!
I mean, sitting down here, I can do charities
to people, so-called, which are not charities,
they are part and parcel of my being.
I just do it, because they are part and parcel
of my being.
I don’t have to go all out to sacrifice
something to do charity, because that’s
nothing but ego pampering and ego-oriented:
“Oh, I have helped this man, and how dare
he say such a thing!”
So this is one quality of the Divine, one
should know, that It is generous.
It is generous to a fault, to a fault.
It is generous because It is generous.
It is not bothered.
It doesn’t reason out Itself: “Why should
I be generous?”
It is generous because It is; because it’s
the whim, it’s a fondness.
The fondness of generosity is such, as you
have fondness, say, people have fondness to
drink, for example let’s say.
That’s not fondness, that’s a habit, I
think.
But you can say some fondness people have.
What kind of a fondness you have, without
forming a habit, I don’t know.
Because you always have a habit and then you
form the fondness.
But supposing you just have a fondness.
For example, you are fond of, say, good food,
let us take it.
Now, if you have fondness of good food, then
you will just do it because you are fond of
it.
Now if somebody says, “Why are you fond
of good food?”
You said, “I am just fond – finished!
Who are you to ask me such a question?”
If somebody is fond of generosity, he will
be generous whether you like it or not.
And it is sometimes, to a reasonable man,
may look to be a bit too much.
The greatest generosity a human being can
do is to forgive.
I mean, it’s not generosity to others but
to yourself.
If you forgive others you are generous to
yourself.
First of all be generous to yourself, that
is you forgive everybody else.
If you forgive everybody else, then you are
not tortured by them; you spare yourself from
their tortures.
This is a generosity towards yourself.
Towards yourself, the greatest generosity
is that you do not bear any malice or bitterness
about anyone.
But clear-cut ideas that, “He’s like this
and he is like this."
Just a clear-cut idea, but no reaction out
of it.
If somebody is a man, say, he’s bhootish:
all right he’s a bhootish fellow, we know
he’s a bhootish, keep yourself in bandhan,
but don’t have a reaction out of that.
Then you have really forgiven everyone.
Forgiveness gives you a big kavacha; is a
big bandhan, is a big protection, we can say,
a shield, from all kinds of evil that other’s
can put on you.
Just forgive them, and then you see what happens
to them.
You just try this trick: just forgive, and
see what happens to others who try to torture
you.
Of course, the Divine never wants to torture
anyone; that is definite.
It never wants to torture.
It is extremely generous, It likes to forgive.
It enjoys Its forgiveness, It really enjoys.
Generosity is to be enjoyed in the same way
forgiveness is to be enjoyed.
It’s very enjoyable.
When you forgive others it’s the most enjoyable
thing, that you see the play, you become the
witness.
So the Mahalakshmi tattwa, when it develops
into you: first of all you have to forgive
if somebody has borrowed money from you and
has not returned — it doesn’t matter.
It’s difficult for people to forgive people
who borrow money and don’t give.
(laughter) And beyond that is also another
problem I have seen (laughing) that: if you
lend some money to somebody, then run away
from that person.
Because even to give is easier, but [to] take
is even worse.
A person who takes money from you, will never
forgive you all your life, because you have
lent money to him!
So, one has to understand that, when you become
Divine, you just give.
You just give.
This is Mahalakshmi tattwa.
Mahalakshmi tattwa is that you give.
Don’t worry about what is the result, how
others react to it, what happens to it, what
is the ultimate result, and what you achieve
out of it, and how the person has taken.
Just give!
That is Mahalakshmi tattwa.
But when I say give, also you must use discretion.
That is the part we always forget.
Sahaja Yoga must teach you discretion, that
is the Divine truth.
Divine is the most discreet thing.
Now, when I say, “Give,” I know people
will just start running on the street, finding
out somebody where you can give something!
You don’t have to run about to find out
somebody that you should give something to
someone: there’s no need.
It’s just flowing.
Whenever the chance is, just try to give:
material things, something kind words, sweetness,
comfort.
But never give one thing, which I sometimes
do by mistake: never give advice! (laughter)
That’s a very dangerous thing.
You can give bandhan, you can beat the person
at his back with shoes.
But never give an advice in words.
That is one of the principles of Sahaja Yoga,
for the time being.
Because giving advice, you know what it means.
You may have a boxed nose or something!
It’s a very dangerous thing.
So best is, on that part I would say, as far
as advice is concerned: you have so many ways
and methods of handling a situation.
So better not speak about it, just handle
it in complete silence.
Whatever you have to do about a person, just
handle him without talking to that person.
The more you try to convince the person, the
worse he will get.
Because they are not Divine.
They haven’t reached that Divinity.
They are a special type of people who cannot
become Divine, and do not break your necks
with them.
Also don’t give advice to other Sahaja yogis.
Everybody at this stage thinks that they know
all about Sahaja Yoga.
It’s all right, good idea!
Very good idea!
But never try to tell them what they should
do, what is good for them, unless and until
they come and ask.
Now, this Mahalakshmi tattwa, when it grows
into collectivity: what happens [is] that
you learn that you have to just give, and
you don’t worry about the receiving.
As Krishna has said, “Karmanye vadhikaraste
phaleshou Ma kadachana” (meaning) “Our
job is to do the karmas (the work) and we
are not to worry about the phalas (fruits)."
Just try to give whatever is possible to everyone:
vibrations, Realisation.
I know it is wasted so many times — you
give Realisation and it is wasted.
It’s like the seeds that are thrown on the
rocks.
Yes, I know, it is.
So many times I have wasted thousands of them,
but doesn’t matter, you give them.
It is not [that] you are giving them for their
sake, but for your sake.
It is for your satisfaction you are doing
it, for your fondness you are doing it.
So just try to give Realisation to everyone,
anyone who asks for it.
But, as Christ has rightly said that, “Don’t
throw pearls before the swines."
I mean, I shouldn’t use this word today,
on such an auspicious day, but doesn’t matter.
So, this, He has said it.
Now, this kind of people, who are they?
They are the people who don’t deserve it.
So there is no need to give Realisation to
every person you come across [or] talk to
everyone.
Gradually you will meet such people who will
ask for Sahaja Yoga, for Realisation: you’ll
give it to them.
Gradually those pigs, or what you call them,
whatever Christ has called them, they will
evolve, I am sure, one day, and they’ll
come to you.
So, let us try on the first level, where there
are genuine seekers of a high level, and you
will be amazed how they are sorted out.
You see, there isn’t much space in the Kingdom
of God, to be very frank.
And we should not worry if we don’t have
many people over there.
For us, it is a responsibility we must have
all the population of this world going up
there: is a wrong idea.
That’s not needed at all.
We should not crowd them there.
Here only, we can’t sit all of us you see,
we’ll have to have a bigger place.
So we should not bother so much as to the
quantity, that the quantity is not much.
Of course we should try our level best to
pass the message; Because they should not
say that, “We didn’t get the message."
To pass the message is all right.
But we need not in any way force people or
ask them to come to Sahaja Yoga or make them
Sahaja Yogis.
It’s a difficult thing.
The more you will try, the worse they will
be.
They will be so troublesome that it’s going
to be an impossible task.
So in your generosity you must have discretion:
how far to go with people, how far to work
it out.
This is the Mahalakshmi tattwa which comes
to you as a result of Shri Ganesha, who blesses
you with wisdom as to how to be generous with
others, where to give, what to give.
The discretion starts working.
You don’t have to think about it, it just
works out.
It will just work out.
Discretion in Sahaja Yoga doesn’t mean,
at all, thinking or rationally coming to a
conclusion, but it means that it just works
out that way: in the sense that you feel it
in your vibratory awareness.
Once such a discretion is developed, you will
be amazed that those who are not to enter
into the Kingdom of God will just shun it,
will not come close to you.
And it’s better for us, less headache, you
see.
Because they think that we need them, while
they don’t know [that] they need Realisation,
not we.
We have got our Realisation.
So this is about generosity, today, I wanted
to tell you; about being generous to Sahaja
Yogis.
Now, I’m not going to tell you that you
go on giving presents to Sahaja Yogis and
all that, because, as you know that, these
material things have no value except they
have symbolic value.
And symbolically if you work for them, and
if symbolically if you try to express yourself,
it is going to work out much better than in
a material way: that it should be so expensive,
it should be so much.
That’s not good.
Symbolically you should work out material
gifts and things among yourselves.
But the main thing one should understand [is]
that collectivity will only grow when you
do not, by any of your attitude or behaviour,
suggest that others are lower than you or
others are higher than you.
For example, you see something straight, you
see quite far away; I see much more than what
you can see.
It’s a fact.
You know that.
But I don’t tell you.
I just say, “I don’t know, maybe try this,
try that."
I keep quiet.
I just try to play about.
I say, “All right.
Let’s see."
I’ll consult you, I’ll consult him, everybody
I’ll consult: “All right, try this."
Or I’ll do all these tricks, because I don’t
want you to feel that, “Mother knows everything,
so why should I know?”
First of all you can say that.
Or you may say that, “Mother knows so much,
and I know nothing.
I can never reach Her."
So, what you have to do is to make another
person see as much as you see.
How will you do that?
By being with him all the time, by being in
such a relationship that the other doesn’t
feel the oppression: oppression of that personality,
as if that person [thinks], “Oh, he is so
great, he is so great, he knows so many things,
and he’s so evolved.
What are we?
We are nothing!”
If you develop such an attitude towards a
person, then the other person can also develop
another attitude, just the other way round.
That he’ll oppose such a person, he’ll
stand out, he’ll be angry all the time.
At the slightest pretext, he’ll be off and
he’ll feel hurt and he’ll be miserable.
All these things can come up.
So it is not going to help you, nor the other
person.
But to tell another person, if you want to
raise that person higher, the best thing is
to make him your friend, your dearest person,
and let him see as much as you can see, together.
Then the vision is broader.
It’s not that one person sees something
more and others do not see, and the person
who can see, thinks no end of himself.
You should behave in such a manner as if you
don’t know anything, it’s better.
You should see me, how I behave.
I don’t tell you anything, I just say, “All
right, go ahead.
Whatever you think proper, do it."
Then you come round and you say, “Mother
but it happened like this, and you had told
us this way!”
So I say, “I told you, all right, but I
didn’t say, “All right, this is going
to happen!’
” But it happens.
So it’s better that you should also develop
that kind of an attitude that, all of us have
to go together.
There’s nobody who can just pull out oneself
ahead.
We all have to go together, even me.
Even if I maybe anything, what does it matter?
What does it matter if God is great?
So what?
He may be great in His own play.
But what do we gain out of Him is the point
that, His greatness should be seen through
us.
If we cannot move up to that point, what’s
the use of His greatness?
It’s better that He’s away.
He’s too great for us.
So He has to come down.
He has to come down to this level to make
everybody feel that they are part and parcel
of His own ignorance.
He may be the most knowledgeable person, so
what?
You have to take the cover of the ignorance
upon yourself and go on slowly exposing yourself.
In the same way, if you can do it with other
Sahaja Yogis.
Then only you could be good leaders, and you
have been really generous with a full discretion.
So today’s day is, as I told you, the thirteenth
day is the Goddess.
Dhanteras it is called as.
That is the day of the Gruha Lakshmi; She
came as Gruha Lakshmi.
In the household, the lady is the one who
is the symbol of that Lakshmi, to begin with.
Because she’s the one who looks after your
food, looks after your comfort, she protects
you, she nourishes you, she gives you joy.
And the women who cannot do that are not Gruhalakshmis.
They are not the…’housewife’ is a very
poor word for that.
They are the Gruhalakshmis; means they are
the goddesses of the family.
So, the other day we were in America.
I told the girls, I said, “Let us wait.
And what we can do: it’s all right, I am
the Mother; you can give me food if you want.
But I don’t mind, give the boys first, and
then the girls should eat."
And one of them got very angry with me.
She said, “Mother what is this?
They are dominating us!”
If somebody eats before or later, what is
the domination?
I mean, in any case you are going to eat before
or after!
I don’t understand the portion of domination.
But you are privileged!
You are privileged that you can look after
so many people!
What is so wrong in it?
You see the whole atmosphere is so funny that
if the men eat first, then women should feel
that we are put down.
It’s absurd, because it’s a privilege:
you are like a mother.
You are the person who has to look after them,
and you have to feed them.
It’s a privilege that a Gruhalakshmi should
do that: look after everybody, give them food
to eat and treat them just like their protégés
you can say, something like that.
It’s such a privilege.
It’s a sign of complete maturity.
Even little, little girls, you have seen,
if they are brought up properly, otherwise
they can be horrifying.
But normally little girls are very generous,
more generous than men are.
And they always try to make you very happy.
They have great sense.
If somebody is sitting down they’ll come
and give you food and look after you.
I mean, I have seen my all three granddaughters,
do that.
Even once a washerwoman came in the house.
They said, “You must sit on the sofa."
She said, “But no, I can’t.
I can’t sit on the sofa."
“No, you must sit on the sofa!” they said.
They opened the fan for her and they brought
all the things that were in the kitchen for
her to eat, now, and they brought some plate
and this and that.
And the elder one, I told her, “What do
you want to be?”
She said, “I can only be a nurse or an air
hostess."
I said, “Why?
Air hostess and nurse, why?”
“Because these are the only two professions
where one can give, isn’t it, food."
I mean it’s a privilege.
Other professions you can’t do this great
job, this noble job, of giving food.
“So that’s why I want to be either the
nurse or the air hostess."
And they play, I have seen these girls play,
“Now I’m the air hostess, now.
You must eat this!”
They bring food in small, little things.
They make their own things, “Now I’m the
air hostess,” and they’ll bring it.
Now, there may not be any food in it, maybe
some stones they have put, or whatever it
is.
“You must eat!
You must look after yourself!
You are thinning down.
You’d better."
Like that: so sweet.
And then they’ll bring some pillows, “Now
you must lie down."
Like the air hostesses they are working, you
see, “Ah, are you feeling cold?
Would you like to have a blanket or something?”
I said, “What game is this?”
“Now we are air hostesses!” (laughter)
It’s such a privilege, an innocent privilege.
And that’s what, if we develop, this nonsense
of a right that, “We are higher, they are
lower,” all this nonsense will go away.
Who is higher and lower?
Like some hairs are here and some are here;
are they higher or lower?
You can’t do without this or this!
It is an absurd idea that has come into our
heads that we are higher or lower.
So a gruhalakshmi is the one who has to be
a noble woman, has to be an example in the
family.
Like, if a housewife herself is a drunkard,
marries ten times, what will happen to her
children?
Just think of it, such a woman.
A woman who has no sense of chastity, no sense
of auspiciousness, no sense of protection
for them, what can she talk?
Who is she?
What does it matter?
I mean what comfort can anybody give to a
housewife?
She is the one who is the source of comfort;
what comfort can you give her?
To her the greatest comfort is that you eat
your food properly, you sleep well, you keep
well; that is the greatest comfort.
So this is what one has to know: that gruhalakshmi
is the woman in the family, she is the gruhalakshmi.
But the man should not be a wolf also.
A gruhalakshmi cannot marry a wolf, you must
understand.
If the man is a wolf, then he doesn’t deserve
to have a gruhalakshmi, but he can have a
she-wolf as his wife; that’s a good idea.
Then they can fight, quarrel, have all kinds
of divorces, this thing.
But it’s the responsibility of the gruhalakshmi,
to begin with I must tell you.
To keep the balance it is her duty.
It is not the duty of the other people in
the family.
It is she who keeps.
She doesn’t give up at any cost.
Of course, if he’s a wolf: all right, he
can go to the forest.
She’s not bothered.
But the men must understand [that] the more
you start respecting the housewife, the gruhalakshmi,
in the family, the more there is respect,
the more there will be settling of these women
in their proper places, becoming proud of
their houses and families and their own set
up that they have put in.
They’ll feel they’ll have a meaning, and
the whole society will change.
But if the men run after dirty women and cheap
and street women, then the same housewives
can take to that.
So that is very important, that they must
be respected, because they are gruhalakshmis.
That is one thing.
The second thing is, they are also rajalakshmis.
Rajalakshmis are the goddesses who are looking
after the country.
Like England has a Rajalakshmi too.
Now, we say, we can say, the princess now
(Princess Diana) is, she’s a rajalakshmi.
She is a woman with dignity.
She carries herself with that bashful sweetness
and all that, she’s a rajalakshmi.
Our Queen is very good too.
But, we can say, other people in the same
family are funny.
They belong to Royal family [but] they haven’t
got that strength of character to belong to
that.
They have all the privileges, but they think
they have all the rights, but no duties.
And as that also the rajalakshmi can be very
funny.
Like in this country there has been curses
on curses, because of seven queens were murdered
in this country.
I mean, I can’t think of any country where
even one queen can be murdered by the king.
This country has a very funny curse of these
seven women who were killed like this.
I mean, what sort of women they must have
been, and what sort of queens they must have
been?
I mean, there’s nothing of a rajalakshmi.
A rajalakshmi is a dignified woman.
She is the one who is the glory of the country.
She has to be a glorious woman.
She has to be a woman with all the attributes
of a queen.
And that is the Rajalakshmi: is the, is the
queen, or the goddess, that is the queen;
and She resides in every country.
Every country has a Gruhalakshmi, and if that
is insulted, then the people suffer.
They will suffer in so many ways, like they
will have money problems, they’ll have financial
problems, they’ll have also have problems
of society; all kinds.
Because whatever the queen does, whatever
the king does, it is done by others; but specially
the queen.
Most of the fashions in England have come
because the queen started it.
So whatever she does, she’s so important
and she has to have that idea in her that
she’s the goddess.
She has to represent that goddess which resides
in every country.
So that is the Rajalakshmi.
Now, in countries where there is no [monarch],
in democratic countries, then all right, then
the first lady of the country should behave.
Not like the American lady (Jackie Kennedy)
who married a tycoon somewhere, an old man,
and is now a photographer!
What is this?
So cheap, it is so cheap!
She doesn’t deserve to be there.
There’s no dignity about her.
She’s competing herself with cheap street
women.
She should know that she is the first lady.
In the countries where there is even, say,
not democracy, and other sorts of governments
are there, there is also a first lady.
And why now these first ladies also have become
competitors and they compete there with their
husbands and try.
Wherever they have tried such a trick: Even
Bandaranaike tried these things; she failed.
Anywhere they tried to outwit their husbands
by this, they will failed, because God is
not with them.
They are there because they are first ladies,
and they should take all pride within themselves.
Even if they feel they are a little bit let
down by people, not respected.
But if she respects herself, nobody can be
disrespectful to her.
She should keep her respect and everybody
will respect her.
But just to punish people, if she has to behave
like this, that means she has no value of
her own.
So the first thing that one, Lakshmi, gives
you [is] the value system.
Your value system is corrected.
You evaluate yourself properly.
Like, you know the value of this and value
of that and value of this.
But the value system for a divine person is
not based on the amount of money or amount
of matter it has, but it depends on what vibrations
it has.
So the whole evaluation system changes when
you get into Divine temperament, that you
start seeing things.
What is precious is what has the maximum vibrations.
Whatever has vibrations is the precious thing
for a realised-soul, and not what is not Divine.
What is not Divine, we have nothing to do
with.
But you will be amazed, whatever is Divine
is all very precious, also, otherwise.
Like the paintings, which are done with Divinity
—means the realised-souls have done — are
today very expensive.
May not be in those days, but now, today.
Actually all the truth comes up gradually,
and people can see that clearly, that there
is something special about these things.
So your value system changes as your Mahalakshmi
essence starts growing and manifesting.
You stand absolutely open, and you find that
new things, new ideas, a new valuation of
everything starts coming to you.
Once this happens to you, know that you are
growing.
You must know how to judge whether you are
growing or not.
And that is how you will know that you are
growing in the right direction, if your value
system is improving.
Today’s day is the Lakshmi’s day.
I bless you with all the Lakshmi’s powers.
And specially the discretion to improve your
value system: what is more valuable to you,
what is the most valuable thing to you; you
must try to revise that.
Then there is, after this day, when they worship
the first day is, they say that, that is the
day when Diwali was celebrated when Rama was
made the king.
He killed Ravana on Dashera.
And [it was] on this day that Rama was crowned,
and that’s why they celebrate it.
Now, Rama is the person — at that time He
was crowned — He represents the Benevolent
King.
And the benevolence of a king is being crowned.
So that’s why they celebrate Diwali.
But we have a special significance of Diwali,
it’s a very special significance, I think:
that the light, that we see here, you will
see it always goes upward.
The fire is the element that always goes upward.
It’s always against the gravity, and it
is against all that pulls you down.
And the light of the Spirit is also like that,
it always takes you upward.
And the person who is a realised-soul is called
as an enlightened person, because he has the
light.
And the light has a capacity to give you a
full idea, to see what is what, to relate
to each other, to find out the distances,
and the differences, and to discriminate.
So the light represents discrimination.
And when you are enlightened, the Spirit is
enlightened: in the sense [that] Spirit is
the light, but which starts expressing itself
in the atmosphere, manifesting in the attention
of yours.
Now, what we have done, in Sahaja Yoga, is
nothing but this is Diwali.
First one light was enlightened, then that
light enlightened another light, and now we
have so many lights.
This is the Diwali that I have.
I enjoy this Diwali [more] than anything else.
Now some lights are really sometimes flickering,
I know that.
Doesn’t matter.
Some lights are afraid of the wind that might
affect it, so I have to look after them.
In India you see this part is called as ‘achal
of the mother’, you see, where she keeps
her child hidden.
And this is where she looks after the candle
also, the light that she has kindled.
And very carefully she looks after it and
tries to see again and again if it is burning
or not.
And when she is sure that it is burning nicely,
then she puts it on a higher place where it
burns; not for itself but for others.
It enlightens others and enlightens the path
of the people who are going in the darkness.
So, for us, Sahaja Yoga today, is a Mahayoga,
because it is the Deepavali.
It’s not only one deepa of your Mother burning,
but it’s so many lights all over the world.
You know they have taken their light and they
are burning.
Even small children are giving Realisation.
It has spread to the villages now, and is
spreading slowly as the Diwali.
And every day we celebrate Diwali we have
more and more lights.
And I am sure these lights are going to grow.
Those people, who still have flickering lights,
have problems, they always have problems,
and they must know that their light is to
be brought in properly, into proper shape.
They must put all attention to put their lights
in order.
If your lights are ordered there cannot be
a problem, there cannot be a problem.
So the correction is also a Divine quality
in you, which should work inward, by which
you correct yourself.
And the other day I was explaining how you
don’t have to think.
It’s very simple.
It’s a machinery, which is a Divine machinery,
which you have found out now, within yourself.
Now at this time when you have got a machinery,
you don’t have to think about it.
Because the machinery that is Divine, is just
like any other machinery.
For example, you know the machinery of the
car, you don’t have to think.
You don’t think, “I have to put a brake,”
you just put it.
When you are a master driver, you just do
it, you don’t think.
Do you think?
If you start thinking, you will kill so many
people by that thinking!
So in the same way, if you have mastered this
machinery: if you know which one to move,
how to move, how to work it out, if you have
mastered it you don’t think about it and
it just works.
And that is what it is and we have to understand
that, after developing Mahalakshmi tattwa,
which is the main tattwa, which is the evolutionary
principle by which you have evolved.
It’s the ultimate, the Sushumna, the central
path, which is the most important.
If the Sushumna is not all right, then you
cannot do anything, because there is the flow,
there is the opening, which is important,
which makes you wider, which makes you deeper,
which makes you greater.
That is the path of Sushumna which must be
always kept open.
You must try to keep it open: by balancing
yourself, by this generous attitude, and by
seeing everything through your discretion.
Keep it open.
Keep your Sushumna open.
And that is the path of Mahalakshmi.
If you keep your Sushumna open there will
be no physical problems, no emotional problems,
and of course no spiritual problems.
That is how one has to understand today’s
Mahalakshmi tattwa.
Now at this position when you reach, you see:
this position is very important at Mahalakshmi’s
principle, is that it gives you the witness
state, no doubt.
But as I have told you before, just after
this first day’s puja of the Lakshmi, when
Rama was crowned, next day they have the second
day.
And on this second day, you see the thirteenth
day, as I told you, is the day when the Lakshmi
was born.
Fourteenth day is a horrible thing, which
I do not want to tell you much about, because
that is the day the Goddess had to fight all
the horrible rakshasas.
So I don’t want to talk about it much because
you know all that.
That is the fourteenth day.
Then the fifteenth day is the day when the
moon is absolutely missing from everything.
It’s absolute darkness, where you put these
lights to suggest that: there are lights now,
let Lakshmi come within us.
So there is no spot that should be left which
is dark.
So everywhere the Lakshmi resides, and give
us the glory of Her blessings.
Then it is the night when you have the dark
night, as you call it, amavasya.
Then the first night after that, is the first
moon that the, you say the new moon.
[When] the new moon comes up, the first day,
is the day when the New Year starts for Shalivahana.
As you know, Shalivahanas are my ancestors,
or whatever you call it, the same Dynasty.
That is the day.
That day, they take a shawl, shawl of the
Mother, like this, and put this water carrier
on top, to suggest the Aquarius time.
The Aquarius time has started according to
them.
They put that on top of that, and put it,
like a flag, on top of their houses to suggest
now the Aquarius time is there.
With the Mother’s shawl they made the flag.
And on top of the flag is the water carrier,
is put upside down to suggest that the Aquarius
time has started, that the time of Kundalini
has started, and that this awakening has to
take place.
That’s the first day of the year they start.
Then after that, the second day is..so it
is five days actually; but why I said four
days celebration is because one day is a horrid
day in between.
But also there’s a celebration because,
after killing all these rakshasas, there were
Diwali.
Many a times these things happened, and every
time She killed all these rakshasas they celebrated
it by putting lights all around.
So after that is the second day, is very important,
which is here: is the brother and sister’s
special day, where the sister invites the
brother to her house for food.
And if he’s a small boy she will give him
a bath.
Even if he is a big boy he sits with all his
clothes on and she puts water on him and puts
something, very fragrant things, on his body
and gives him a bath nicely and gives him
a protection.
It’s a purity of relationship between
a sister and a brother.
And then the brother gives her something as
a present at that time.
And he may give anything: it’s just symbolic.
It’s the love and affection of a brother
and sister [which] is expressed at that time.
It’s very important.
And then the sister, actually gives him a
bandhan, with actual light, which we call
as the aarti they do for the brother.
And that’s how they try to give a big protection
to their brother.
So this is the day, they call it in Marathi
‘Bhaubeej’ or ‘Bhaiyadweej’: that
is the dwitya, the second day of the moon.
That is done in India.
Now it has significance because it is very
important that our relationship as a brother
and a sister must be strengthened, must be
purified, must be looked after.
In India, even if somebody calls you a sister
or a brother, then he is a sister or a brother.
It’s a very difficult situation.
If somebody calls you a sister, then you have
to accept that situation.
And if you accept that situation, all your
life you have to carry on that relationship
of that nobility.
Whether he may be your brother or not, doesn’t
matter.
She may your sister or not, does not matter.
But once you have said she is your sister,
then all that purity is there, all her chastity
is to be protected, and she is to be looked
after.
So this is how it is.
These are the five days they celebrate.
In short I have told you, how we Sahaja yogis
should understand, these five days are days
of real festival for us because we have overcome
death now, we have overcome that degradation
that would have followed after it.
Now we are people who are victorious.
So this is to celebrate our victory over evil,
our victory over our weaknesses, and our victory
towards the goal of our achievement — that
is full Self-realisation.
And that’s how it’s a great day of celebration,
and may God bless you all.
And in this jubilation I join you all, and
I am very happy that we are so many today
in this country, and a day will come when
we, our righteousness and our greatness will
definitely enhance the path of darkness with
this light, and improve the conditions, to
such an extent that people won’t believe
that they were living in this wretched world,
and today they are in such a beautiful world.
They won’t believe.
It will happen.
As it has happened within yourself it will
happen without.
And that’s what is the day I am waiting
for, when such things will happen.
And all these things we are doing here, leading
a very righteous and a good life now, with
forgiveness for others and with all the generosity:
it will became a universal truth for people.
And when this will become a universal happening,
and when people will universally accept Sahaja
Yoga, then will be the real days of Diwali’s
celebration.
May God bless you all.
So I must say, for Christmas I won’t be
here.
I’ll be in India.
It’s nice way, you know, because I’ll
escape all your presents! (laughter) You gave
me so many presents last time that it was
too much for me.
Of course if you say that, I gave you, because
that’s of course is nothing great because,
you see, if you give to one person, it is
too much to carry.
They say you have to have a shipload.
And if one person gives to so many, it’s
not such a difficult thing, isn’t it.
But if everybody gives to one person it’s
too much.
And if one person gives to many it’s very
good because the load is lessened on everyone
and also shared, of that one person.
So my giving was a better thing than your
giving to me, because I was really thinking
of taking a ship, to put all the nice presents
you gave me.
So, do you have any questions?
So, now, just, this is your ring.
Kay, here’s the ring.
Simon, come along!
So, you see, today’s puja is more sort of
asking for the expansion, expansion of your
Sushumna; more that.
So as it is, when we are doing this puja,
first of all you must develop a mood of forgiving
others, and forgiving yourself also; just
that mood, first of all, to improve your Sushumna
further to grow, first of all.
So there’s a mantra for that, “Ya Devi
Sarvabhuteshu kshama rupena samsthitah."
All right?
And, “Shanti ripen samstitah."
All these mantras, if you say, all of you,
if you say these mantras: one you can say
and they can repeat you.
And then that will definitely improve.
These are all mantras for the Sushumna.
I think you people don’t have any machine,
a grinding machine in the thing.
So I had better pay for that machine.
Because I would like to give some present
to the ashram.
And what do you call that machine for grinding
something?
Yogi: A grinder, Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji: Become something greater and
higher.
That’s the point is.