[Music]
[Applause]
this pure spirit within us is the
reflection of God Almighty Sadashiva
it's like the Sun that falls in the
water and gives a clear reflection or
else it falls on the stone it doesn't
give any reflection at all if you have
say the mirror the Sun will not only
fall on the mirror but will reflect back
its light in the same way in the human
beings the reflection of God Almighty is
expressed in a way your personality is
if your personality is clean and clear
innocent then that reflection could be
like a mirror
thus the saintly people they reflect God
Almighty in the proper manner in the
sense that their own identification with
wrong things is no more when there is no
such identification and when a person is
absolutely the pure spirit then the
reflection of God reflects into us
luckily you all have got your
self-realization that means the
reflection of God my Almighty is already
working into your attention the
attention is enlightened by the power of
the Spirit so when you are in sahaja
yoga you have cleansed out yourself your
Kundalini has also cleansed and now you
have pure personalities that's why this
reflection is clearer and clearer and
people see it see it on your face see it
in your body they see it in your work in
your behavior in everywhere it is
difficult for people to really believe
in themselves that they could be the
reflection of God Almighty they have
some sort of a complexes about
themselves I think that they cannot
understand how they have suddenly become
the reflection of God Almighty
but they have a capacity and they can
become the reflection of God Almighty
for which they have to have faith in
themselves faith in their ascent to
believe that we have become that you
must have confidence in sahaja yoga and
confidence in yourself that you are on
the right path and that you are now
saved and nobody can attack you because
you have the complete protection of the
divine with the proper understanding
that you are the pure spirit if you
believe in that then you will be
surprised that you will be very
confident about what you are doing we
have now sahaja Yogi's all over but what
I find among sahaja Yogi's is this that
some of the sahaja Yogi's grow very fast
steadily strongly they achieve their
principle of Shiva that the first
achievement shows that from inside they
start getting detached now detachment is
not mental it's not mental it is not
that we have to take to some sort of a
sannyasa or you have to go to Himalayas
give up our families and all that but
the detachment is within oneself when
that detachment starts working the first
sign is that we become Joy's we become
happy now if you ask anyone why are you
unhappy
he'll talk about this why maybe his
house maybe his children maybe
his country maybe society whatever it is
so he gets absolutely upset or maybe
very unhappy to see things happening
around him now he is a realized soul
this unhappiness is not going to help
what is needed is now to know that you
can correct all these eats of the
society of the family of the whole
country by transforming others not by
feeling bad but while doing that the
main thing that you should have is a
complete detachment now how to achieve
detachment is the point to understand
yourself you should introspect try to
find out - what thing am i attached why
am i miserable for whom am I worried why
should I worry you should discover about
yourself what's wrong with you which
side is catching is it right or left
side it's meditation you can find out
are you attached to money are you
attached to business are you attached to
your family are you attached to your
country in a way which is not such or to
your culture which is not such then try
to get rid of this attachment by
meditation this attachment will show on
your fingertips and you have to see for
yourself what centers you are catching
in which way are you in problem and then
you can clarify it very simply by taking
a very simple search treatment
I think here we fail that once we get
attached to something we don't even
think we are getting in time you think
we're doing very great thing because now
we love this person love that person she
was qualities the compassion part that
is no compassion of any kind to be
attached to any such things is no
compassion in you cannot have compassion
of Shiva because that compassion is very
few it is like as I have told you many
times it's like the SAP in the tree
which rises and goes to various parts of
this tree and then either it's
evaporates or goes down into mother
earth it's not attached if it gets
attached to one flower or to one leaf or
to one fruit then the whole tree will
suffer and also the flower will
discipline in meditating on your heart
on the Shiva tattva
the principle of Shiva you can
definitely detach and then the joy will
be the maximum you can have interest you
should have interest but in that
interest there should be enlightenment
that you cannot get attached what you
know is much higher much greater and
much more joy giving now these
attachments people think that is very
joy-giving it's a very wrong idea the
joy comes from your own source of your
spirit whether your husband is good
whether your children are good or bad
whatever they are they cannot give you
John it's only you can enjoy yourself
and this is why one becomes very
forgiving
when nobody can harm you then whom are
you going to be angry with that is
another great quality of Sadashiva is
that is extremely forgiving he goes up
to a point
till he destroys the whole work of
auditioning but otherwise he's very very
forgiving and he also is very balanced
about it what I find that in the whole
atmosphere of today in the modern times
there's a big struggle going on which is
not she was culture
she was culture is they I should say the
Sahaj culture if you are sahaja Yogi's
if you have compassionate understanding
of others feelings and also you should
have readiness to look after not only
sahaja Yogi's also non sahaja yoga then
your compassion will become effective
you should have also collective
meditation in your ashrams
will be a good idea if you can try
collective meditation will be nice but
you don't have to give vibrations
training you don't have to look after
the chakras of others you just bother
yourself what's wrong with you and now
whatever is the solution for your ascent
if you put because the responsibility of
the whole world rests on sahaja Yogi's
this you know that there's no way out
without sahaja yoga to save humanity
from all kinds of problems sahaja yoga
has come on this earth
so it is your responsibility to keep
yourself in proper shape as far as
sahaja Yoga is concerned get rid of your
left and get rid of your right and then
to spread sahaja yoga not by bombastic
words or aggressiveness but with love
and compassion I am sure we have done a
lot we have achieved a lot but there are
still some points here and there which
is a very unpleasant task for me to
correct them or whatever it is I have to
say that is working and everybody should
look at themselves and feel happy from
where they have come here and how far we
have to may God bless you
Oh