a month that I told
that you must have a puja arranged
the Sunday the full moon day and he
asked me what should I call is it a guru
puja or is it which are four Mahalakshmi
Ganesha's puja I told him call it a
group tutor and he asked me later on
much later when I was going to India but
why not also have this pool over here
today is a very important day
because for a long time back when Christ
was just a child
we read from the scripture and declared
to the multitude that he was the Advent
the Incarnation he is the Saviour
they believe that a savior is going to
come today long time back on a Sunday he
says he declares that he was to say this
but why today is this Advent and a
he had to leave vanish for a very very
short time so at a very young age he had
to declare that he was the Adventist
that is remarkable to see that before
this no incarnation said publicly that
they were incarnation
ramaa of course had forgotten that she
was an incarnation in a way they were he
made himself to forget Kate is my upon
himself to become a complete human being
maria de buzos sama and shri krishna
also only told one person Arjuna just
before he was start what
if Dom never said that he was
incarnation though he was the
incarnation of primordial matter the
Tatra himself never said that he was
seeing causation of the bimodal master
with all these three forces acting
through innocence came on this earth to
guide Moses never said that no they knew
he was great he had overpowered nature
but he never said that he was being
at the time of Christ
one felt it was necessary to say
otherwise people won't understand if at
that time they had recognised Christ
they would having no problem
but still human beings had to evolved
further somebody had to cross the agya
chakra in the veritas to go through that
door that's why Christ came on this
earth
it is most surprising that in this tree
of life when the roots give out the
chute and the chute gives out the
branches and the branches give out the
leaves and the flowers also blossom out
of the same free those who know the
roots do not want to another shoot those
who know the chute do not want to
recognize the flowers this is typical
human nature
I never said about myself because it was
felt that shown beings have not achieved
another dimension of evil even worse
than at the time of Christ may you blame
anything you can call it natural
revolution because you are away from the
nature whatever you may call it but
human beings had locked all contact with
reality they were identified with
artificial icky and to accept such a
great reality is going to meet him
possible for them that's why I never
said a word about myself till of course
some of the things told about me today
some of the possessed people also told
about me and also people started
wondering but how the most difficult
thing of Kundalini awakening takes place
with that speed in the presence of Mata
there was a temple in India and nobody
knew about it but they found that the
ships which went near a particular
spoils but we're drawn towards the shore
and it was difficult to fly them back
and there to put double forces to take
out of that attraction and they did not
know that there was some thing that was
acting they thought there was something
wrong with the depth of the sea but
invariably it happened to many ships
then they wanted to find out after all
what is happening to those ships while
all the ships suddenly start getting
attracted towards the shore so they
tried to find out and when they went
into the jungle they found a big temple
and on top of the temple was kept a huge
mass of magnet
so through rational understanding people
reach the point that Mataji has to be
something exceptional because nowhere in
the scripture written down anywhere that
such an incarnation came on this earth
whose we are ground even thought can
raise the Kundalini
many saints who are away from the
madding crowd sitting in the jungles on
the himalaya all know about it
because their awareness is at a point
where they understand
they understand much more than you do
because you are still children newly
born they are grown up
but today is the day I declare that I am
the one you have to save the demand
I think here I am the one who is
auditions we the mother of all the
mothers who is the primordial mother
we Shakti the desire of God who has
incarnated on this earth to give meaning
to it sir
through this creation to human being and
I am sure through my love and patience
and my powers I am going to achieve it
I was the one who was born again and
again but now in my complete form and
complete power I have come on this earth
not only for salvation of humanity not
only for their emancipation but for
granting them between them of seven the
joy the Bliss that your father wants to
get to Apollo
these words are to be kept within the
bounds of sahaja Yogi's only for the
time being
and today is the day of guru puja not my
puja but your ku jazz blues I anoint all
of you as gurus and today I will tell
you what I have been told upon you and
what great powers you already have
among you there are people who are still
not being able to recognize
my announcement we'll work it out within
them recognition without recognition you
cannot see the play without saying you
cannot have confidence within yourself
without confidence you cannot become
guru without becoming guru you cannot
help others and without helping others
you are not going to be in any way happy
so to break the chain is very easy but
to build the chain one after another is
what you have to do
this is what you were all wanting to be
so be confident and be joyous and be
happy but all my powers will protect you
my love will nourish you
and my nature will fill you with peace
and joy
in God