Today, we have gathered here to worship Shri
Lakshmi.
In Diwali, in India, they worship Lakshmi
because a great rakshasa called Narakasura
was killed. Also that Lakshmi came out of
the sea, at the same time, long time back.
I mean, I should say, this is like Her different
appearances on the same XXX. Lakshmi is the
Goddess which gives us wealth, gives us prosperity.
She is very blissful, no doubt. She gives
you protection and also She is very humble
because She stands on the lotus. She is very
light, means doesn’t put Her pressure on
anyone. These are symbols of Shri Lakshmi,
but also She is a part of Mahamaya in the
modern times. When people get Lakshmi, the
money, they don’t understand that She is
their Mother and She is to be respected. When
this kind of perverse idea of Shri Lakshmi
comes in such countries, such people meet
their last end and destruction of the worst
type. So this Lakshmi has to be used with
a big balance, like standing on a lotus and
not get into the pond, where there are all
kinds of creatures to eat you all. You have
to stand on the lotus, that means that you
are above all the lures of this Maya. Also
in Sanskrit languages, we call Lakshmi as
the Maya. If somebody gets lot of money, they
will say: "You got lot of Maya."
Now, this Maya plays the tricks. If money,
prosperity was the salvation, then, there
would have been no problem in this world because
those people who have money always get ruined.
If they are not ruined, their children, their
grandchildren get ruined. This principle of
Lakshmi within us is very dubious and the
allurement is so much that people see somebody
having a good car these days, they say: "Oh,
what a man he is..." In any case, he’s not
going to give you the car. If somebody is
having lots of, what you can call, palaces
or buildings, people start admiring! This
is Kali Yuga. They start admiring: "See this
man, he is so rich!" Even clothes: people
see you wearing clothes which are very good
tailored, might be from some designers, say.
They think knowing of that man. For example
in England, there is another befouling place
called "Saville Row." So if you want to buy
one suit, you have to pay sometimes 3000 pounds.
Now, people are so stupid that now if they
wear a suit from "Saville Row", they put the
brand outside, "Saville Row." All such thorough
foolery is going on all over the world. The
clothes have no meaning, their life style
has no meaning. Ultimately they end up in
Swiss bank.
The Lakshmi Tattwa of Swiss bank is also now
showing its teeth, and if you read what’s
happening to them, I mean, they are shaking,
they don’t know. They went to this limit
that they took the teeth, golden teeth of
the Jews! I mean, it’s going to far! All
this thorough foolery has been going on. They
have military services. Why? Who’s going
to conquer that country? Even Napoleon didn’t
do that. And they have made big caves to keep
their weapons there. Who’s going to attack
them? Stupid people... Suffering from ego.
But the attack has come and this attack is
so serious that they might be completely shattered
and destroyed. Now, who falls for this kind
of thing, you should see, are the people who
are crooks, who are dishonest, who are absolutely
adharmic. They can be Mafia, XXX or they can
be some thugs, some black marketers, some
smugglers. So, going against the Lakshmi principle,
are so many done these days. One fellow who
was thrown out of Sahaja Yoga, because he
was trying to be very dominating and all that,
he said: "That’s better." I said: "Why?"
He’s doing now smuggling, making money out
of smuggling and he has become very rich,
according to him; but it comes to an end and
a very tragic, bad end. Money is such a lure
for human beings that it kills all sense of
decency of higher values, everything. A brother,
say, who is very nice and good fellow, if
he gets money out of proportion by doing hanky-panky,
he neglects his mother, father, brothers,
sisters, everything. So I would say, then
it comes to that point that Lakshmiji becomes
a bhoot then and all Her blessings becomes
a sort of a challenge to your dignity.
Now, certain countries, like America which
is the area for Shri Krishna, because He is
Kubera, they have no money as such. I’ve
seen they are all poor, they are all indebted.
So many Indians went to America and they can’t
come to India now. "Why?" "We are indebted."
"Why are you indebted?" "Oh, we get everything
free, now, you see, the bank gives us loan,
we can have the best life style." So they
will have three Mercedes. Is nothing! "Three
Mercedes is nothing. You should have Rolls
Royce’s, we should have this." "For what?
What do you get out of it?" Now of course,
little bit they are shaken out with the stock
exchange and all that nonsense they have started,
all these jokes and all these very big kind
of loggerheads. All now are coming out. So,
this is no Lakshmi, because Lakshmi must give
you dignity, prosperity and respect. I think
Americans understood about it, so they become
philanthropist, means they are giving money
to people. To whom did they give money? All
the names these people took from South Africa
were all the money given by the philanthropist
of America. What has happened to their wisdom?
That 16-year old boy, he went there and then
all ages went there and made a very big money.
All this money making proposition...
So what is the matter if there is a blessing
of Lakshmi? Why a man who gets the blessing
of Lakshmi becomes so funny, so stupid and
ultimately ends up his life that people are
not there even to pick up his dead body?
What is the difference between money and Lakshmi?
She gives you money, alright, agreed, but
when She is giving the money, what happens
to that money which comes to you? It’s a
very subtle thing one should understand. In
India if you give 100 rupees to a servant,
immediately he’ll go to drink somewhere.
First, idea will come, what he should do,
he’ll go for a drink. Of the hard one, I
mean; your moorka is nowhere near that, such
hard one they make in India, you know. It
is called as Hatbhatti, made with hands. So
in 100 rupees, they are willing to go. I mean,
that means any money you give to them, it
spoils their life completely. Lakshmi has
been given, alright, so what happen to this
Lakshmi? She changes Her form and Her form
is so bad that you are completely ruined with
that.
So, now we have to understand what is the
way we can use the Lakshmi. Supposing I get
money, supposing. Then I will go to the market,
say, and I’ll see something nice: "Ahh!
This is very good for this Sahaja Yogi." Or
I will say: "This will be very handy for our
ashram." Immediately the mind starts working
in a very socialistic way, I should say. Not
individualistic. For example, I went to Rajasthan
and I saw such a lot of sand, just like a
big desert, big dunes, everything. And people
starving. So I said: "How to get money to
these people?" So, I said: "Let Me start a
factory, factory with the unbreakable glass,
which they make only in France." They make
it very cheap and regarded as a very cheap
thing, not in India. In India, if you go to
some elite’s house, they’ll offer you
tea in these unbreakable things, they think
it’s very elite, you know, it depends on
what you think about. And very proud of it.
So, I said, if you make these things in India,
these poor people, you know, because there
is so much sand and sand is needed by trucks,
so I will utilise this to make this beautiful
factory here and then give them some support
to live well.
Now, when I went to one place called Warana.
You all had come also once. There’s a gentleman
who was a disciple of Gandhiji and he has
organised this Warana company for distributing
milk. It became so very rich, so very rich,
it’s a co-operative, so he started giving
money to all the co-operative people, those
who were labour there. Now, this labour had
never seen that money, so he came to Me, touched
My feet and said: "Mother, You tell me now,
what should I do: I’m so unhappy with the
development of this Warana, because there
are prostitutes who arrived from Bombay, there
are all kinds of hard deals which have come
from Bombay and these people are smoking like
hell, they are taking drugs..." "Hey?" "Yes!
Wherever there is money, the drug goes there
and the children are becoming absolutely useless,
they don’t want to study, they even slap
their parents." So he said: "This was not
Gandhiji’s ideal, now what has happened?"
He says: "This is a curse of money." And he
was crying.
Now, how can Lakshmi become a curse? It does!
It is in the Nabhi. What a central position
it has and when this Nabhi starts working,
it is a very remarkable thing that you feel
gobbling the food all the time with this Nabhi.
You go on eating, go on eating like mad and
then some bhoot comes in to eat also with
you inside the Nabhi. Then you can eat so
much that no human beings can eat like that,
except for the people who are rich. Then you
start a big science or what you can call etiquette.
I don’t want to hurt anybody, I mean, if
you are eating well I don’t mind, eat well.
But the fuss part is, because today is Diwali,
I’m trying to tell you all these interesting
stories.
I went many times for dinner with French diplomats.
My goodness!! Now, Me and My husband don’t
drink, so forty five minutes they were only
discussing what they will have today. Then
they remember, yesterday they had that, the
day before, they had that, so there should
be variety. So, then they came down to something,
not all of them drinking the same, different,
different. So, they came to some point: "Alright,
we’ll have this." But some people asked
for something which was not available. So
they said: "You have to have it!" And they
shouted at them. My goodness! They took forty
five minutes to decide what they are going
to eat. It’s regarded as French etiquette,
I think, and we took chief guest Myself and
My husband. Looking at this man and looking
at that woman, did not know what to do with
those etiquette. We were thinking, now better
go.
Then came to food. They are so particular:
"I like this and I like that." They are worst
than Indians, I think, and they took at least,
at least eighty minutes to decide what they
will eat. Ultimately, they found something
nice, each different and the restaurant people
were trying to pamper their ego: "Oh, what
a thing you have chosen, this is the....Wah,
wah, wah..." So they started serving. The
cheese was smelling so awful, I tell you.
We couldn’t bare it, you know, both of us,
so My husband told them: "Today is our fasting
day for both of us." He said: "Why is it a
fasting day?" He says: "In India, we have,
you know, fasting like this, sometimes we
have to fast; today is our..." But I told
him: "Here, one day you are saying today is
our fasting, but we have to go to so many
dinners, what will you do?" He says: "Everywhere,
better to say that we are fasting." Such a
horrible cheese they brought and they started
boasting that they have 200 types of cheese,
200 types of the smelly ones. "From where
did you get?" They said: "This is French perfection!"
I said: "What is this French perfection?"
But then, you know, tears came into My eyes.
C.P. said: "Why are you crying?" "Not crying,
but I think what will happen to these people
with their cheese, where will they go? Even
if they go to hell, people will throw them
away with the smell of the cheese."
Then I read how this cheese came in. So they
said that there was a big snow fall and they
had put some big, big containers in a cave
of milk and people forgot about it. Snow fall
was there for 20 days, whatever it was, and
they just forgot about it. So, after one year,
they got the smell, you see, coming out of
it; so they went and saw the cheese being
formed, can you imagine? This is the beginning
of the hell. Actually, one should never eat
anything that is kept overnight, normally.
But now they have got fridge, so you can keep
it for 2 days, 3 days at the most. Like on
the ship they keep it. But this I couldn’t
understand that this cheese which they told
Me is very old. I said: "Really?" And they
sell it by that, what old it is. And their
wines, if they are, say, 200 years old it
is 200 times more expensive. So, it’s such
a bhootish thing to eat all that. So, when
the Lakshmi goes into the hands of bhoots
on a very less level, I should say, these
days, then it goes into the heads of people
who want to exploit money, exploit poor people,
exploit countries which are downtrodden, go
on like this, collecting money, you know,
looting, looting, looting.
When English came to India, we did know, they
used to take brides. On Diwali day if you
went there without any present they say: "Oh,
baksheesh, you must give some presents." And
what they liked was our country liqueur, I
never knew this, but later on I came to know
because My husband became a collector of XXX
and there where bottles of country liqueurs
kept in that house, with that house was itself
more than hundred year old. Long time back
it was kept but still, some of them, you see
and we could have sent them to England to
sell, I mean, it would have been a good idea.
So, the older it is, it’s better. This Lakshmi
I think becomes old and dies and there is
alakshmi. Alakshmi means when you have money
and you don’t have the qualities of a person
who should have money. In that quality of
Alakshmi, you become very miserly, you don’t
want even to help your brothers and sisters,
you don’t want to give any money to anyone
and even if you give it, you give it to false
gurus and wrong things. This is up to, we
can say, is Alakshmi.
The behaviour becomes very arrogant, so arrogant
that you behave like horses you know, people
look like horses: they walk like horses, but
I don’t know if horses have ego. If you
see these people, you just don’t understand
what has gone wrong with them. There is one
gentleman who started an aeroplane business,
aeroplane business in India. I won’t take
his name but say some Majidya or something
like that and my granddaughter met him with
my grandson-in-law and they were walking like
this, talking like this, you see, they can’t
understand these two persons; so, they came
and talk to them who you are and all that
and then they said: "We are this Majidya."
So, my granddaughter said: "Who is Majidya?"
"My goodness!", they fell from heavens, "You
don’t know who are Majidyas, do you read
newspapers or not?" Then her husband came
in, he said: "I do." "Now what do you want
to say? We are Majidyas!" He said: "Who are
Majidyas?" "You don’t know? What sort of
business you do, what is this..." Such stupid
things they did that these children felt that
there is no use having any business; if business
means this kind of behaviour, very indecent,
very arrogant, they don’t know how to relate
to people, they don’t know! And after some
time, I heard that their business was completely
finished, was a flop, they call it a flop.
So now, we have to realise that this Lakshmi,
how it takes us to wrong things. Firstly,
She makes you very egoistical. Somehow, if
a man has money, he starts behaving like that.
One cannot understand how a person who was
normal, suddenly becomes like this, starts
talking like this. He might earn money, even,
in the horse races.
Around the Lakshmi is the valence of Dharma.
There is around the Lakshmi, is the Dharma
and this Dharma if you cross, that’s the
best place where they can cross the Dharma.
Then, you can do whatever you like. This adharmi
which is irreligious, which is hideous, you
have to just cross that limit of that Dharma.
We have to just deviate from Dharma.
Now, as I said many a times that ten valences
human beings have got, but apart from that,
there are many Dharmas which are surrounding
everything, like angels. Like first Dharma
is your love for humanity, is the first Dharma
but if you say from that end when you start,
it starts with 3 Dharmas, is the Dharma of
the woman, how she should live, how she should
get married, how she should look after her
children, what should be her behaviour, all
is three Dharmas. And then is Patni Dharma,
is the wife, wife Dharma, what should be her
Dharma. In her Dharma she looks nice. If she
gives up her Dharma then she is a prostitute.
So, then is Pati Dharma: how should be a husband,
how he should behave towards his family, how
should he pay attention towards his wife,
about the whole entire family, the whole,
you can say parivar, as they call it, all
the relations. That is his Dharma but beyond
that is the Dharma of Satya Dharma: how much
he sticks to truth, then the Dharma for creativity.
In creativity as you know very well these
days, with money people are standing on their
heads or I don’t know what they are doing
because the amount of nonsense they are producing
all over the world in the name of modernism
is no way is Kala Dharma, no way.
Then we have also politics, Rajkaran Dharma.
This also Dharma is there, now taking bribes,
I mean the kind of things that are going on,
corruption, all kinds of things that are going
on, competition, fighting and all that. They
are falling from their Dharma of Rajkaran.
Education, same thing; we call it Shiksha
Dharma.
All such things are Dharmas; there is a kind
of a principle which we have to keep, otherwise
you can topple down from the lotus and that’s
what happens. Now we have also Rashtra Dharma.
The Rashtra Dharma is that your country, there
is a Dharma of your Rashtra. When you have
to fight for your country, you should, but
you should not be aggressive on other countries,
it’s not right to dominate other countries
nor you should bring bad name to your country.
It’s very important! Sahaja Yogis have all
this intact, absolutely, because you are standing
on the lotuses already. You don’t have this
problem, normally no. Once in a while there
are people who behave like that but mostly
Sahaja yogis don’t fall into these traps,
that’s why their Lakshmi Tattwa will definitely
improve. They’ll have little problems here
and there but without problems if you get
Lakshmi, you will not value for it. So, with
little problems, you get the Lakshmi. But
Lakshmi doesn’t give you all this imbalance.
Such a man has to be extremely balanced because
beyond that is the step of Mahalakshmi where
your seeking starts, where you become a seeker.
You go beyond Lakshmi principle and this Mahalakshmi
principle starts coming into it.
I would say the Western countries this consumerism
has started and it’s such a funny one. In
America, one lady was married to an Indian
and he used to tell Me how this consumerism
works. I said: "How?" He said: "I gave my
wife money to buy two shirts for me because
I had no shirts. So, she went and bought five
skirts. So, I said: "You have so many skirts,
why did you buy the skirts?" "Because in this
money I could buy five skirts instead of two
shirts, so I bought five skirts." So he said:
"I can’t wear skirts!" "So, how I should
correct her?" he said. I said: "You do one
thing, tell her you want to buy some skirts
for her and go and buy five shirts, then she
will realise that if the money was given to
her for one purpose should be used for that."
This is a very subtle principle which I follow
because I don’t understand money. So, what
I do, whatever money I get I put packets:
this is for this, this is for this, this is
for this, into packets. But I don’t understand,
you know and I don’t write accounts. I’m
very bad about all that. Somebody else does
that. Now, if I spend some money from one
pocket for some emergency, then I again fill
it back, it’s written there: so much is
there, so much is there. So, the money is
available at the right time for whatever I
want to do and the money is in the packet.
It is not in sort of an open thing that I
can just want to buy a Mercedes, I want to
buy a Rolls Royce, no nothing doing, it is
for something, some purpose and there is no
need. So, when you go to the shop and you
see something, you won’t buy because that
money is not kept for that particular thing.
For Sahaja Yogis it is very easy to handle
their money with respect. So, you go to any
shop, you won’t buy anything.
But My nature also is spontaneous. So, I went
to Frankfurt, changing. They said: "Mother,
there is a very nice watch shop." I just thought
I’m going to get three son-in-laws and what
am I going to give them? So, I went to that
shop and I found such beautiful, beautiful
things but I have not kept any money for the
watch, but I said I must buy. One of the watches
turned out to be a very unique one, I must
tell you, which is no more available. Because
of My eyes, I saw this something unique and
My son-in-law is so... I mean, over wealth,
so... quite rich, he has no problems, but
he said: "This watch you cannot get it." Then
an article came about that particular watch.
So he has kept it with him. You see, have
something that it should have a value behind
it. That is the Dharma part. Value behind
it; what is the value? When you want to buy
something just don’t buy because you are
mad, I mean instead of shirts you buy skirts,
not that way. But anything that has an artistic
value or some special value, then you should
buy that.
Now this sari I’m wearing, it has a special
value. Why? Not that it is made with hands
is a very beautiful design it has, no. This
was made in place called Paithan which was
the capital of a kingdom which belongs to
My forefathers: Shalivanas and these saris
were made there, Paithan and they used to
sell it to people. Now they have becoming
expensive, in those days they were cheaper.
Now, it has that value; they are very honest,
very religious, they are called Shalivanas
because they used to give shawls to the Goddess.
They spread their kingdom very much and also
there is a calendar in their name but the
kind of life they led: they were just very
generous people and they have made beautiful
temples, beautiful places for people to rest
near the river. I mean, so many beautiful
things they have done. Apart from that Rama
and Sita, when they went to Dandakaranya,
they went to this place and you have the place
where Sita took Her bath, Her bathing place.
There is a little river flowing there. How
it was covered from all the side and how the
light was coming, so beautiful. But whatever
Rama had done they redecorated it with the
Rajput style. Then also there was a very beautiful
temple, I saw that they have made. Also, I
don’t know how, there was some water flowing
and there was Shri Mahadeva, a big thing Pinda
and also there was a Parvati statue. So old
as that, I don’t know if it was put by Rama
or by My own, you can call them great, great,
great grandfathers, but the beauty about that
place that it shows that Sita used to worship
Mahadeva. The water was flowing, somehow by
nature inside, up there in a stream and She
used to take the water and put it on that
pond. How deep these people were; those who
built that temple, such a beautiful temple
they have made. You see, so many temples are
built like this in India by people who had
money and they believed that if you spend
your money in this kind of work, you are blessed.
I bought a land, near the river Nira; that’s
My own name: Nira and this land I just bought
it just like that without thinking and what
they told that their guru, Shalivanas guru
was Shandilya and this place belonged to him
long time back which was an ashram of Shandilya,
exactly the same. And that land I bought,
very surprisingly. Then in the newspaper,
it came out everything about that land and
this land was the place where a great devotee
of Shri Vishnu: Pralada was playing. You must
have heard about Pralad. His mother had a
husband, long time, Hiranyakashapur was her
husband, horrible rakshasa, so she ran away
from there and who help her was Indra. He
brought this lady to the place of guru Shandilya
and Shandilya told him, Indra, that: "You
don’t put any effort for her, I’ll look
after her. And the child that is going to
be born to this lady is going to get the avatar
of Narasimha." You know Narasimha is the man
and the lion. He said: "How can that be?"
He said: "It is so." So Indra left her there.
The child was born. Till five years that child
used to play in that land which I bought.
But I didn’t know about it. I just saw it;
I was surprised. But when the child grew up,
up to five years he had to go back to his
father. I don’t know how many of you read
about Pralada? Raise your hand, I would like
to know, let me see...who was killed and I
mean his father was trying to kill him and
torture him but he had certain boons. So Shri
Vishnu appeared as Narasimha, means the lion
and the human form. And then He killed this
Hiranyakashapur, the father.
Now, imagine how much it was that thousands
years back, this must have happened and I
should purchase that land and there is a very
good temple built about 300 years back by
Maharashtrians. So, the story is that Pralada
came into the dream of the people who wanted
to built the temple and told them that: "I
already made a statue of Narasimha along the
river Nira." Imagine the name of the river
is also mine. "And if you can walk along the
banks of Nira river very close to the temple,
I’ve made the statue in sand." "It’s a
miracle!" So, they went there and they saw
that statue. They brought it back and installed
it in that temple. And it is still there,
made of sand. Also they say there’s a kind
of a river or a water flow, very small one,
just like the finger flows down from the top,
God knows how. So, now see the value, the
value of money which was collected to built
this temple had such an old value. So, the
value is not money. This, one should understand
what is the value of the thing you want to
give something to others, then the feelings
you have in your heart is the value and that
value is the real Lakshmi. When you are, say,
building a house, the plans you make, the
things you do, what is the idea behind and
what you are trying to express through that
house is the value of that house.
Once you understand that, you have to buy
with this Lakshmi or you have to use this
Lakshmi for certain value and not for showing
off or for money. This superficialness that
we have about money itself is like an ordinary
glass. But if you put behind the glass the
mercury you can see the value. So, when you
start buying something, what is the purpose?
Why are you buying? This will determine the
value. Like the last time I came to Portugal
and I said we’ll go and buy some terra-cotta.
But they are very expensive. I said this is
the price, but I wanted to buy terra-cotta
from Portugal because it’s very rigid. So,
we went to one factory and the factory was
quite far away. None of them could find out,
but I told them: "It’s here only, just go
and see!" And then we bought the terra-cotta.
But on our way, I told: "Stop, stop here,
stop!" So, they stopped; there was a shop.
I had to buy some things for Sahaja Yogis
in India and also for some people in Cabella.
And that shop had such beautiful cottons.
There were some Sahaja Yogis from here who
saw that. Such beautiful clothes. I bought
a lot of it. I said: "Thank God, the problem
presents are finished now for India." So joy
giving it was. Everybody was surprised: "Why
suddenly in a place where never have been
Mother there, suddenly She finds?" It has
a value because I wanted to buy some things
for Indians to be given as presents. So, if
a Lakshmi is say, this much, once you add
to it a value it becomes so.
The sign of a person who is Lakshmi Pati is
this: he should have a house like a lotus
in the hands of the Goddess, he should protect
people who are depending on him and from the
left hand, he should give. This is the image
of the Lakshmi. This is what the Lakshmi is
within you. If you have this four things in
balance without conditioning, without ego,
then you are a Sahaja Yogi. Otherwise, you
are not. On a Diwali day, you have to promise
ourselves that whatever we are going to get
now, as Lakshmi principle or as a Lakshmi’s
prasad, should be used in getting things which
has value and thus you will learn that you
have used your Lakshmi very well and with
that, your Mahalakshmi principle will become
very strong; you’ll become very strong by
which you will ascend very fast.
Today is the day for us to celebrate the Lakshmi
Puja but Lakshmi Puja doesn’t mean that
you worship money. Money as it is, is the
most dangerous thing and I think it is the
hidden weapon of Lakshmi Devi. See, if you
try to misuse Her, She goes on punching you.
With one punch, if you don’t realise then
She gives you another punch. Like that, then
She might little bit twist you to suggest.
She’ll try everything to convince you that
what you are doing is nonsense. Ultimately,
She sees your destruction completely. So,
Lakshmi, though She is the One who is the
giver of boons, giver of everything, you should
not be mislead by Her Mahamaya character.
I’m your Mother, so I better tell you to
be very careful! Thank you very much.