the second very important point is of
complete integration within and without
within unless and until today's
integration we cannot bring forth the
outside integration the complete
integration within comes by dedicating
yourself to your own improvement first
and foremost is time must be given for
your development it's not to show me or
not to show anyone it is between you and
yourself
let's work hard to cleanse yourself easy
to live comfortably with all the
horrible chakras within us
but it is easier also and the best most
enjoyable is to have very clean chakras
well it comes first of all is insulated
first of all is complete sincerity are
we sincere to ourselves sometimes it is
misunderstood people think if you have
to be sincere to ourselves we should
deny sahaja yoga sahaja Yoga is the
union between you and God and the
sincerity must be full must be complete
any kind of insincerity which comes into
you is extremely detrimental
so you must know that as your mother has
sincerity about you you must also have
sincerity about yourself
then you will start enjoying sahaja yoga
that is very important to create
integration within you because efreeti
sincerity it comes from your heart if it
is coming from your heart then your body
your mind your intelligence everything
will work hard to fulfill it but if it
is not coming from your heart it is
going to be a superficial thing so you
try to feel it from your heart that's
what it means sincerity do not depend on
anyone your wife husband children
nothing mother father it's your own
so you have to work in such a way that
you get complete integration and the
driving force towards integration is a
very simple one is sensitive
thus you will know that automatically
you are getting integrated the another
factor is important is patience you must
have patience with others because if you
do not have patience your sincerity will
start doubting itself so you must have
patience and to get patience you must
know what you have been so far and where
are you when you will know what you were
you will have patience with others
tremendous patience and by having
patience with other your sincerity with
me all the time complete by your
sincerity you will be completely
integrating so we come to the point of
sincerity now let us go deeper into how
the sincerity is to be maintained
first of all we have to make some
determinations on calhfa's
of visas then we have to act by finding
out how do we get in sincere on what
points you have good at analyzing you
can find it how do you get you get in
sincere on what price you get uses what
are the corrective points keep a control
on your mind to see how does it become
insolence you will be amazed
that is simple to be sincere than to be
using so if the easiest thing is to be
sincere than to be deceiving because you
don't have to think to be sincere you
don't have to think if you have to be
insensitive to think plan out and to
find out methods all the loopholes and
escapes by which you have to run away if
you have to be captive of your sincerity
you don't have to worry about it and
then sincerity itself is rewarding this
principle must be written down in your
hearts that sincerity itself is rewarded
you don't have to go to anybody else to
ask for the reward of sincerity
sincerity itself rewards you
and that's why you start enjoying your
own sincerity if you start seeing all
these things as a witness that how your
sincerity has made you so beautiful so
dignified and how you have started
rising in yourself esteem it will be
amazed how sincerity itself is a big
force which will manifest its living
dynamism in you and you'll be a
Transformers these transform
transformation within you he is going to
change the whole world people are going
to see that you are no more a confused
person you are not a person who is
doubting and neither you are a person
whose affinity you are not a blind
person and you are a person which
undertand aware and you can see things
better than others so Devine is only
interested in such people as I have told
you before that Devine is more
interested in a little worm which is
alert and aware than in a palace of a
king which is that the more alert you
become the more divine takes interest
but this alert net is nothing but the
enlightenment of your sincerity
you'll be amazed how sincerity is the
thing that means you're loyal to
yourself you have to be loyal and not
destroy the loyalty to yourself is
sincerity and that is how I have managed
sahaja yoga but sincerity is by nature I
don't have to strive for it I cannot get
out of it while if I am your idea you
should try to invite my nature within
yourself and then you will be amazed how
you are connected then we all move like
one wave one being one personality that
is the achievement of the Sur started
sincerity of purpose brought in action
not theory and philosophy but in an
active sincerity in every way and
patience all these things will bring
forth the complete integration within
try to become sincere and sincere and
sincerely enjoy your sister
I bless you all with yourself