I bow to all the seekers of truth.
It has to be understood that truth what we
know through our mental capacity is not the
truth, because mind itself is a myth.
We have created it.
As we have created computers.
we have created our myth also through our
conditioning and through our ego.
Beyond it is the reality.
So if you have to know the absolute truth
something has to happen.
We have to evolve into a higher realm of existence
of consciousness.
You have been already told about the subtle
system that you have.
You all have it.
You are the owner of it and you have every
right to achieve that state of consciousness
which in the Zen system call it “Satori”.
In every system they have something they call
it some name, like the Islam calls it “Wali”,
some called it “Sufi”.
In the realm of reality, when we are not,
we have problems, because we fight for unreal
things, you think of unreal thing as real
and accept.
For example, when they English lost the match.
I mean one party has to win, either this or
that.
But they were so much identified with it,
which was falsehood.
They were not playing, there were not players
that they were English, alright.
But there was no war going on.
See the myth about it is this, that we get
identified with things which are themselves
not real.
And all these problems that we see of anger,
which is violence after all, or the attachments
we have, identifications we have, then the
lust and greed and all kinds of problems that
we see in every country is due to our imperfection.
It is due to our ignorance about reality while
reality is beautiful.
And we have to enter into that realm that
is what is seeking for.
The other day I was reading a book of a boy,
who was an athlete and who went through the
Zen system of training and it was so hard
and hazardous that I thought very few would
accept such a situation, very few.
Might have been in those days, there were
seekers of that quality that they worked it
out.
But now there is system available for you.
The knowledge that they gave you about the
subtle system we have is a fact, but if it
is a fact or not you should first verify don’t
just believe me or believe what he has said.
You should verify if it there within us this
subtle system of our ascent.
I knew about this since my childhood, but
I did not know how to explain to people because
I found people have no idea about it even
in India.
Traditionally, in India we had three types
of seekers.
One was through Vedas.
Even the first stanza of Veda says that, “If
you do not know yourself by reading or by
chanting these mantras it is useless”.
Then the second seeking, second style of seeking
was that of bhakti, is you to sing the name
of God, or you can pray to God.
Even great people like Gyanadeva did not know
want to do.
So they also said it is better to do bhakti,
bhakti of God because the time had not come
perhaps to give self-realization or may be
the people were not prepared to get it.
But in the center we had another great movement
which is called as Nath, Nathpanthis.
They say it came from Shiva, but whatever
it is; it came from Adinath and these people
and got diverted into many types.
But those who remained in the middle, one
of them was we should say was called Gahininath
and his disciple was Nivrutinath the elder
brother of Gyanadeva.
It is amazing if you read anything about them
they know all about chakras, they know all
about these all three channels.
Everything they new thousands of years back.
Then somehow or other they didn’t tell people.
They kept the knowledge to themselves.
I can’t say why they did it but they did.
Ultimately, Gyanadeva took permission of his
Guru Nivrutinath and said that let me tell
you, at least let me tell others, you allow
me because people should know what works it
out.
So he wrote about Kundalini.
But if you read these ancient books, you will
be amazed that the whole thing was described
in those books how you get your realization
and how then you have those centers which
are to be enlightened, what problems come
in.
But the method they employed for achieving
it was really hazardous.
I don’t know why they had to do it but they
did it.
They were all unmarried people and very strict
with themselves and they had to lead a life
very secluded from the society.
This was really a very difficult time of ascent
they had.
When I read about them I really feel very
extremely sad that all these great people
who were seeking had to go through such horrible
strenuous turmoil for days together and then
some of them got realisation.
But you are lucky people I should say to be
born at this time.
This is a special time, very special time,
which is described in all the books, all the
scriptures as the last judgment.
Now, if you start deciding about it through
your mental capacity you cannot achieve anything,
because you have only two agencies: one is
your conditioning, another is your ego.
So one has to rely on the natural gifts that
we have, is that of this Kundalini and she
is your individual mother; she does not want
to torture you, she does not want in any way
to give you any pains, whatsoever.
Also, there are some books written that Kundalini
means it is a something horrible and it can
kill you, it will do all these things.
All these years, now I have been working on
it, I have never seen anybody getting into
trouble.
But if you are in trouble you get out of it.
So, all these myths were created for Kundalini
also later on so that people should not take
to reality.
But all this knowledge was somehow lost, though
Gyanadeva had mentioned in his book that in
the sixth chapter he said that one should
seek through the awakening of Kundalini.
But people said no, this is no good, we are
not going to have it; because when those people
who organized the religion, become in charge
of the religion - actually you cannot organize,
you cannot organize religion - and once they
start organizing it you see they put there
own norms on people who are seeking.
So they said no this is something is not allowed
because they could not raise the Kundalini
may be.
But in the sixteenth century in India, suddenly
so many realized souls were born, saints were
born.
Perhaps they might have been Nathpanthis who
had died before may be, they have taken the
birth, so many of them, and they started understanding
each other because they were one with reality.
Everybody was feeling the same thing about
each other.
There are many examples of that.
First of all I would say, Namadeva in Maharastra.
He was a tailor and he went to see one pitcher
- who make pitchers you see, potter you can
call it – and, when he went and saw this
fellow standing and trampling over the clay,
he just stood up and the sentence he said
is so remarkable.
He said,” I came here to see the formless
- that is the vibrations or Chaitnaya they
call it - but I see it in you in person.
It is in person I see it”.
This kind of appreciation is only possible
between people who are realised souls because
they understand each other.
Those who don’t understand you see have
different, different ideas, different, different
things.
Now they say that we must have peace.
How can you have peace?
One is going to the right direction, another
is going to the left direction, another is
going in middle some where hanging.
Everybody think they are right.
Whatever they are doing is right.
But what is the outcome of it.
Nobody is peaceful within.
They are fighting for things which has no
meaning at all in life.
They are many people who are fighting in the
name of God, I mean this is the worse someone
can do stupid thing.
How can you kill each other in the name of
God, how can you?
But this happening is accepted and not only
but it is regarded as religion.
Like this whole world is full of violent people.
You should say minimum disturbed people: families
are disturbed, children are disturbed, the
whole mother earth is shaking and everybody
is disturbed.
By saying that you should have peace you cannot
have.
By talking about you cannot have.
Because I have seen some people who got peace
awards, there is no peace within.
Only by transformation of human beings, by
evolving them, taking them into this realm
of peaceful existence of reality you can bring
peace.
Everybody wants peace but even if you want
you should genuinely ask for it.
If you are going to decide it mentally you
cannot.
Mentally everybody differs, everybody has
opinion for everything.
Like they will say, now they have come here.
I mean the modern mind is like this.
It always tries to runaway from the truth,
always.
If you, I will give simple example, if I tell
somebody to please telephone to such and such
gentlemen, immediately the other person will
say, “He may not be there.
He might have gone to his office.”
Today is Sunday how can he go to his office.
“Alright, then he might be...”
I said, “Why don’t you telephone first,
why do you react?
First telephone, finds if the person is there
or not.”
But that is not possible because the mind
is all the time wobbling, giving answers and
reacting.
Whatever you do, there is reaction.
It can also say now why so many flowers, I
never asked them but they did put it also.
I don’t know whom to be blamed, who is the
victim.
But they might say so.
They can have objection to everything.
But one thing is that why don’t you understand
that you are not at peace, at peace with your
self.
Unless and until you yourself at piece, you
cannot find faults with others.
You cannot judge others.
Why are you not at peace with your self?
(This is the thing one should understand)
Because you are not integrated.
Your mind, which is I have told you what it
is, says something then your heart says something
and then your liver says something.
There is no integration in your understanding
of any problem.
Once you are completely integrated then you
feel the peace.
But the best thing that happens I have seen
with Kundalini awakening is this.
We are all the time thinking, thinking, thinking,
and thinking so much.
Some people really have told me that to cut
our throat but stop this thinking.
Specially in modem time we think so much more
for everything.
I think without thinking we will be lost and
in this ocean of thinking, we are so frightened
with the waves, as if you are in the ocean
and there are waves around you and you are
very much frightened of them.
But supposing by any chance you get in to
a boat then you can watch these waves which
were frightening you and enjoy them; but supposing
you become an expert swimmer you can jump
down and save many.
In the same way it happens.
When Kundalini rises these waves that we have
of our thoughts which rises and falls, rises
and falls, and we are all the time jumping
on the cusp of the thoughts, either in the
past or in the future.
We cannot be in the present.
So when she rises, she elongates those thoughts.
There is a space in between that in the present
and in the present we don’t think but we
are aware, much more aware then we were ever.
We are in the center, we are in the center
and there it is our peace.
So we have to rise up to that point.
Now - as he has told you about all these centers
- when the Kundalini passes through them she
nourishes all of them.
These centers are responsible for our physical
mental, emotional, also our spiritual being.
So she nourishes them, integrates them and
ultimately pierces through our fontanel bone
area and connects us to this all pervading
power of divine love.
All the scriptures have described about this
thing.
they call it by different names, as I have
told you that they call it “Ruh”, they
call it “cool breeze of the Holy Ghost”,
they call it as the “all pervading power
of divine love”, all kinds of names like
“Param Chaitnya” as “Nirakar” they
call it “Alakh niranjan”.
All kinds of names they have given to this
all pervading power because you can see it,
you can see it and you can feel it after realisation.
You can feel it, it exist.
For the first time you feel it.
You see these flowers you take them for granted
how beautiful they are.
But it is a miracle, just think it, how beautifully
this mother earth has created for you all
these.
That means she is living organism.
She understands what to produce out of what
to do.?
Who does all this?
What is this energy?
This is the energy of divine Love.
When I say “Love”, I mean compassion,
it is the compassion.
It is a thing we don’t understand that how
can compassion be the truth.
But on a little lower level we can understand
it.
If you love somebody then you know everything
about that person.
Take it that way.
Compassion is real intelligence.
Which gives you the, I mean, enlightened compassion,
the complete idea of the totality, it does
not talk of one here and one there but of
the totality it has.
Through its intelligence it understands what
is benevolent for the global peace, what is
benevolent for an individual problem.
It understands everything, because it hasn’t
got any angularities.
It is so pure.
And this purity, which is compassion, which
is pure intelligence.
And once you enter into that realm you don’t
have to read anything.
You become just very knowledgeable, yourself
very knowledgeable.
So many powers you have within yourself, of
which you are not at all aware they all start
manifesting.
I have known people, ordinary artist coming
to Sahajayoga become now world famous artist.
Ordinary people who could not even come up
on the stage have become great orators.
All these qualities which make you so special
just start prospering and also manifesting
itself.
But that’s not, that’s like you see mother
giving chocolate for children, that is not
the main thing.
The main thing is that you reach a point that
you feel you don’t have to achieve any thing.
You have achieved everything.
All that hankering after achievement and all
that is finished.
Then you enjoy everything.
Your existence you enjoy.
You enjoy each and everything that you see.
This enjoyment cannot be described.
But it is to be experienced and to be felt.
I must say In England I worked the most because
somehow my husband is posted here and lot
of time and the country which I had worked
very hard is England, no doubt.
And I had an advantage of this English language
which I could speak also.
But I have seen that, once English take to
something, they will take it seriously.
But to take them to something is difficult,
because too much of mental activity.
We have to go humbly beyond this.
Because they will say, I don’t like this,
I did not like this I don’t want this.
That is not the thing.
Who are you?
Do you know who you are?
I want this, I believe, our politicians will
always say I believe, now who are you?
Do you know who you are? Mohammad Sahib has
said, “Unless and until you know yourself
you can not know God Almighty.
So why talk of God?
First know yourself.
That’s why Buddha never talked of God.
He said better not talk of God First know
yourself, because, you haven’t got yet,
the capacity to understand God.
First of all you must know yourself.
And to know yourself is quite easy now days.
I am amazed the way it worked in so many nations,
the way people have taken to Sahajayoga and
the way it is spreading, I am amazed; this
is the special time and a special blessing
where you are born when it was to happen.
But, still it’s a judgment; again I will
say it’s a judgment.
Nobody can force you.
You have to judge yourself whether you want
it or not.
There cannot be any forcing.
But you see, this countries also, European
countries I have some ideas, they think it
is a cult.
I mean I can not understand how can there
be a cult when where there are no weapons
used, there is no money taken, there is nothing
as such peace such joy, such friendship among
so many nations its established.
If it is cult alright, does not matter.
I wish there were some more like that!
This mind all the time criticizing, finding
fault, this and that.
But what have you got so far.
As a Mother, I will say you have to be selfish.
Just know that you have to know yourself and
that is what will give you everything that
you want.
Actually the wants also change.
It is very surprising how after Sahaja yoga
people change.
Of course there are one or two here and there
who are not so good.
But they will be, they will be, they have
certain hankering, something hanging in there
minds I think.
But most of them come up so fast.
I am really amazed, how these things are happening
in the western countries.
India, of course, no problem, because they
have the heritage, they have the knowledge
they know everything, they know what they
have to get.
But here in England, I was really amazed,
how it has worked out.
So seekers are born every where, I see now
this seeking is so deep and so much maddening
for people.
Of course many people have made money out
of it.
That’s where I can’t understand.
They have made marketing thing, you cannot
market, you see, this is your evolutionary
process.
How much money do we go give to mother earth
for giving us these flowers?
It is natural process of evolution, which
has to take place in simple words it is “Sahaja”.
Sahaja means spontaneous.
It’s born with you.
It is a great chance of becoming sahaja yogis.
“Yoga” means the union with the Divine.
You get powers, it is not just to say I am
twice born have some sort of sign board; but
you become.
Is the becoming is the point.
You really become and in that becoming you
get powers, you can raise the Kundalini of
others you can cure people.
I mean so many things happen.
The greatest thing happens is that such a
person become extremely peaceful, wise and
enjoyable.
As Namadeva enjoyed, Gora Kumbhar they enjoyed
each other.
Then Namdeva went to Punjab where Guru Nanaka:
he saw another realized soul, immediately
he recognized, and he said “It is so nice
you come to Punjab, now you better learn Punjabi
language and write beautiful poetry as you
done it in Marathi language.”
So there is such a big book written in Punjabi
language by this great poet.
You too had great poets here, there is Lewis,
then we have William Blake.
William Blake was unknown to us in India.
They never, they thought he’d be a mad man
or what I don’t know.
After coming to London only I could discuss
something about him such a great man, such
a great poet.
But they had to write it in this poetry, because
if they were saying something, they would
have been murdered or killed, I don’t know
what would have happened.
So they wrote it in poetry when people couldn’t
understand much.
They have [not clear] way for us.
They have created this path.
For them the greatest thing is that it is
working out because they are all together.
First so many came, trying this, and else
you see build the path.
Now, it iss complete, not only that, but also
the temple is ready for you to enter in.
The whole work of this great people has helped
us.
They were never against each other, Never.
When they talk different religions I can’t
understand specially, when Moses, Abraham,
were described by Christ.
How come the Jews fighting Christians, I can’t
understand?
Not only but also Mohammed sahib described
about Christ, his mother, much more with greater
respect than in the Bible.
So how can this people fight among themselves?
It is to be seen clearly in their books only,
they find the books so authentic it is in
the book written down that they followed all
these great people.
So there cannot be any devising thing that
is a religion.
Religion cannot divide.
Actually religion is within ourselves.
And when you get your realization you suddenly
become very righteous, suddenly.
I have see in this England only, people taking
drugs and all that overnight gave up, overnight.
It is remarkable how in the light of the spirit
they saw what is wrong with them, what is
destructive and they just gave it up.
Such beautiful people have come up.
You won’t believe that these were the people
who lost all hopes about themselves and how
now they have become such beautiful beings,
I am very proud of them.
This lecture of mine should not upset you
in any way.
If I have said something that makes you feel
little nervous or any thing, you should not
worry.
Because your Kundalini is all the time there
and innocence cannot be destroyed.
Of course some clouds come over it but there
is the deity of innocence sitting within you
and it holds everything works out without
any problem.
Only thing you have to desire for it and asked
for it.
As I said it can not be forced.
I respect your freedom, and in your freedom
you need to receive your self realisation.
It cannot be forced, it cannot be argued,
nothing of the kind; because it is natural
process as I said, is a natural process, and
for the natural process how can you argue
it.
So, I would request you, first of all, that
those who do not want to have Self Realization
should leave the hall.
Because it will take hardly 10 minutes, hardly
10 minutes.
But those who don’t want should leave the
hall, would be nice, very amicably, I will
be thankful.
[Pause for some minute]
One thing I have to tell you that there are
mainly two problems with human beings where
Kundalini stops: one of them when you feel
guilty.
When somebody tells you, you are sinner or
something like that, such an idea crops into
your head, and you think you are sinner and
they are afraid.
Many people have told me, “We are afraid
of you.”
I said “Why?”Because you have sinned…
that’s why I am here, why you should be
afraid.
So first thing is that I love you all and
you all should love yourself.
Because you all are human beings and at the
epitome of the evolution.
So please give up the idea of feeling guilty.
Alright, you have done something wrong, accept
it.
That is finished now that is past and I am
talking about present.
That is finished.
As far as this moment is concerned, it is
doesn’t exist.
So, don’t think of what you have done wrong
or what you have been worried about and all
the time thinking.
Also our modern life is so much, full of norms
that even a little thing you do like, even
if you put the spoon on this side to that
side, you feel guilty.
Oh I did like that.
If you were really guilty, you would have
been in jail not here.
You should have very pleasant attitude towards
yourself and not to feel guilty.
That is what I am requesting you again and
again don’t feel guilty.
Then the second thing is why I say so.
Because this center [left Vishuddhi] here
left side catches.
It goes into very big jeopardy, into very
big problem and this center can give you spondylitis
to minimum, or angina or all your organs become
very lethargic.
So why carry this guilt with you?
So give up the guilt.
The second simple thing is that please forgive
everyone, in general.
Don’t think about them.
If you don’t forgive then you go on thinking,
“Oh my goodness he troubled me” like this
and the person who has troubled you is quite
happy while you are just troubling yourself.
By that you catch on the Agyna which is in
the center of this optic chiasm like this.
And it is so close and so constricted, that
if you want forgive it want open and how will
the Kundalini pass through?
So just forgive all of them and don’t think
about to whom you have to forgive.
Just say in general, I forgive everyone.
Many people say it is difficult, it’s a
myth.
You forgive or you don’t forgive what do
you do, do nothing.
But when you don’t forgive then the all
problems start.
So better forgive everyone.
Without even thinking that you have to forgive
this person or that person.
It is headache even to think about them so
better not.
This center is very important, specially for
Christians.
You know that how forgiveness was [not clear]
that Christ has manifested and requested all
of you to forgive.
The third thing I have to request is that
have full faith in yourself that you are all
going to get your self realisation.
Please have this faith in yourself.
If you have that faith it will workout.
In no way condemn yourself or say that how
could I get it.
In Genoa it happened, it was not such a big
hall but quite a big hall and everybody got
realisation.
And for at least half of they were stunt they
couldn’t believe that they were feeling
the cool breeze of Holy Ghost, they just could
not believe it, for a half a minute.
Then they looked very happy and joyous and
started smiling and clapping.
So it is going to happen to you all.
I promise, but have just faith in yourself.
You all can get it.
Another thing I have to request is if you
can take out your shoes, this mother earth
helps us a lot.