face yourself
for becoming
and then
the preparation is done
to become something
and on the whole when you know that it
is your ego and superego
which are loading you up
you have to scan them out with vibrato
awareness
now there are two
types of
attention we have to pay
first is a constant attention
that is a routine of a sahaja yogi
and the second one is the emergency
attention
i've been saying that all the sahaja
yogis must start
writing their diaries
one with every day's experiences
if you know that you have to write a
diary you'll keep your mind alert
and another one whenever you get any
special idea
of the past or of the future also to jot
it down so like that you should have two
dice
for your constant attention you have to
fix up your mind
on certain facts the first one as i said
that
if you keep a diary
then you will know that you have to
remember what important things have
happened
so your attention will be alert and
you'll be looking out for such points
where what is the thing you see
and you'll be amazed if you make your
attention alert
what new things come to you
very brilliant ideas
and the miracles of life and the
miracles of
god's beauty and his auspiciousness his
greatness his kindness his blessings how
they work out if you start writing every
day
even two lines about it
it will make your mind constantly
involved with it
that's a human style of doing things
also you can mention in the diary
what happened did you could you do your
meditation did you get your time for
meditation
a little bit as if you are
appearing for some sort of a examination
or something you
prepare a little note like that did i
get up in the morning did i
then any special thought or any special
movement
in the center or left or right also
should be mentioned so that
you keep a watch on your mind it's a
very good thing to maintain a diary
also you will see progressively how your
ideas are changing
how new priorities are settling down how
you give more importance
to real things and very little to unreal
things
i think this is a very very practical
side of human beings
that one should have a diary same
diaries after sometimes
will become historical things and people
would like to see
what you all have written not to be
hypocritical about it or deceptive about
it
but quite truthful and understanding
you should jot down few lies just before
sleeping
now we have to see that we have
problems for superego and ego
now superego is the left side as
darkness
tamagura and our past
those who have left side problems should
think of the future
use them balance if they think of the
future
for example a person
who is lethargic should take to working
put your mind into working for the
future planning what to do where to go
how to do that will keep you
away from drag up the
left side and
gradually then you can balance yourself
also
now the right side
of a person when it is activated very
much
he has to balance it
not with the left side but with the
center
that is a person who is very hardworking
must develop a witness statement
you try to do a work any work
indulge into work in thoughtless
awareness
as a witness whatever work you are doing
you just say that i am not doing it
this you can do it after realization
become thoughtlessly aware
and start doing your work
so the compensation of the left side is
done by movement to the right
and of the right side movement in the
center left side is the tamaguna
right side is the rajoguna the center is
the septum
still these are three good eyes that's
not the state
which you have to achieve about this
i'll tell you tomorrow more
how to go further
after scanning out which side is weak
you should plan out your style of life
for example if you are extremely
lethargic you cannot get up in the
morning
you feel very sleepy in the night you do
not feel alerted then start planning
as to what will you do how will you get
up even puja is a good idea
home is a good idea do something like
that you see so that
you have to do something what you call
the kriya is the action
get into the action some sort of action
you're going to
in sahaja yoga as well as in your daily
life
you'll be able to change that mood and
come to the right side
and then you go to the move your
movement should be towards the
satyaguna is to watch everything
now at this point where you are in the
center
you have to see
how much you are misidentified
so supposing you are at the first stage
of left side then you will just
do dreaming oh this person is so much
identified that one is so much
identified as if you are the best
is human nature you see well that person
is like that he's like that
this is very bad in the society that is
going bad in the society
it's better then we can also go to this
limitless to that guru is very bad
and that one is another mad gap like
that this is all day dreaming going on
how far it is affecting you how far you
are improving by that is not
it's just you see thinking analyzing it
it's insane this stuff
sitting down and just analyzing it's
amazing stuff
the second thing could be
when you come to the second side of it
is the kriya
then what happens when you start doing
it
then at least your attention is on what
you are doing
it's not allowed to drift into something
and which goes into any nonsense and can
i mean then you don't know from where
the funny thoughts are coming
so you start doing something you can go
and plant some trees or you can go and
plant some
flowers or if you want you can do some
cooking you can do some work
take to work that will help you
any work but while doing the work
the problem will be you'll develop ego
that's why when you are developing the
ego
you have to tell yourself you are not
doing mister
this you are not doing this is not doing
you are not doing
if you go on suggesting to yourself mr
ego will not come
and then many things you see which
normally trouble you and trouble others
like
you have cleaned the room all right then
somebody comes and spoils it you get
angry with that person
naturally because you think you have
done
first of all you don't clean the room if
you clean the room then you'll be
prepared it will be dirty otherwise you
do clean
now if it is dirty well and good if it
is not directed well and good
this type of attitude you should take
to jump onto saturn on sattva guna you
start accepting it you become extremely
mild
you become a mild personality then
at that time you do not discuss as to
oh i don't like it this was wrong this
should not have been all these things do
not come to you in saturn
you start seeing it that time you see
that all right doesn't matter it's done
it's time on the contrary you feel hurt
if you are a satyaguni that
by any suggestion you have suggested
your ego
can you get that point you feel ashamed
of your ego i mean to say
if you are a sabzi for example even to
say that this is my car
you will feel shy that's a sattvuli
style
or even to say why did you spoil my
carpet i mean in india nobody will say
i can tell you this regarded bad manners
absolute bad manners
if anybody comes to your house and the
carpet is well they sell it doesn't
matter
even it is brought i don't know let it
be auto burnt
they'll never say that you're burnt by
carpet or done anything to my
is regarded bad manners like here you
see
somebody sleeping somebody makes the
noise
the person who is sleeping will never
say that you are making noise
let me get it he'll just get up and ask
do you need anything
that's difficult for people here to
understand because ego is
just sitting on there but these bad
manners
there you will find when you will go to
india you'll find this these are bad
manners
to say that or to say oh i feel very
comfortable
i mean to say i feel comfortable is bad
manners i mean they never say
i like it so what
all these words are not to be said if
you are in satragoni then you just don't
say
you say do you like it is it comfortable
would like to have this before attention
goes from your side
you understand that
that is the style one has to develop
then you are a satwa guri
otherwise you are still on ego trip you
see whatever you may say
i don't like that i don't i who are you
first of all ask the question who are
you
if god says i don't like you i can
understand the reasons
but for you to say i don't like it after
all how did you come on this earth
how did you get a human birth
how did you get all these things nothing
like that
who am i
i am nothing everybody who thinks i am
something he should know
that he is nothing makes no difference
to god whether he exists or does not
exist you see
he's not he's just
so this point if you understand that
even if you do something any work you do
or anything you are doing
you are just doing it because you want
to do it
that is how you come on to satyaguna
but normally it doesn't happen it
happens the other way around for example
a person
is say
doing something by any chance
he feels hurt or he thinks that whatever
he's done is no good
people don't appreciate or maybe he
might think that
oh it's not up to the point or whatever
it is
then the reaction for him is not that he
does not like to rise to satyaguna but
he rises
he goes back to them
all right i'll not do it i'll sleep over
it let them do it
why should i do it
so the training that you have to have
through your rajaguna
goes the waste it's just a training
period
that you have you are doing something
now in the training period you have to
learn only how to
come in the center for example now
water is required for you to swim if
there is no water you cannot say
all right in the same way rajoguna is
required for you
to come to satyukra
if you do not do any work you cannot
come to satoku
so you are just working just to train
yourself
to be a witness now do you follow that
point
you are not doing it because you like
particular thing you are used to
particular thing because you want to be
this
this is not the way it is
you are just doing it to learn how to be
patient
to practice your patience
to see how much patient you are
once you start doing it you'll be amazed
that you will never feel the burden of
the work
but it never happens most of the people
if they find their work is not effective
they'll go back to tamagona
there are many attitudes say is working
then he thinks why should i do all the
work
others are not doing she'll go back to
their states
but those who are not working will not
think that this person is working let me
also work
it's other way around you see
this can be an attitude of some people
that if this person
is working let him work
this is even a meaner stuff avoid just
you go to a restaurant and somebody
takes out the purse others start looking
this side that's what you mean
i mean everybody should come forward
and once you are paid you played it
finished then you just don't start
counting
why did i pick once you try
or any work has to be done go forward
with it do it with your heart
don't worry if others have not done it
just do it for its pleasure and the
pleasure only you will get
well you will do it with the
understanding that it's a training
period you are better trained than the
other one is
you are at a higher class than the other
one so we have to
be at a higher class
for that this is just a training on
and that's how we can really
put our preparation into practice into
all details
to see how we work out our ego
and superego today in the morning i have
told you that
your intellect must
imbibe this within itself all right and
now i'm telling
you that your action
action that you do must
be every time branded by you as
just your training
any action you do sometimes you have to
drive for miles together
you're trying your patience you see them
doing everything say they have to do go
for
say helicopter or say if they have to
drop from the
what you call them drop down
parachutes or helicopter you take away
or whatever it is
you go on doing it again and again isn't
it
you practice it again you drop many
times you break your legs you break your
hands you do this and do that
then you become a master you understand
my point
driving same way till you become a
master you go on in the same way
you are doing this work just to master
your patience
and that your love
is your love how much you love really
if you really love someone you are never
tired of working
you are never upset with working but if
you don't love
you start counting how much money how
much work
how many hours how much to be paid
all artificiality comes because there is
no love involved in you
whatever you don't want to do you don't
do it
to begin with to begin with you just
don't do what you don't like
to begin with but once you have mastered
that
then you have to master it that you do
something that you don't like
like meeting some buddhist for example
you don't want to meet
you want to run but you go little nearer
you see then develop a immunity for
these buddhis
after some time will not cast
you have to develop the immunity isn't
it otherwise one person comes and
everybody's head goes out
it's not the fellow improving you all go
out
so all these things are all these events
are for your
training your immunity
your immunity is to be trained
and when it is so when we are training
ourselves we should take it as a job
but the attitude should be extremely
positive
extremely positive and
all that is should be expressed in your
notebook whether you got dejected
or you got upset and disgusted you want
to run away from it all sorts of things
it's just a training to your mind
whatever is the situation wherever one
has to live
whatever one has to do
you should do whatever may be the
circumstances conditions
you'll be amazed you will not even know
what you have eaten in the morning what
you have it means
whether you are eaten or not you will
not
you will not fuss about it
do not worry about it you will not think
about it
but this being
the a is to reach the satavura
every other thing becomes 0. the
greatest
hurdle comes to sahaja yogis i've seen
when they start organizing
they start organizing something now
somebody wants something
so they'll run up to get the thing for
that person
now just have said that you must look
after the needs of others
but if i'm sitting here and there's a
lecture on then you better be
just listening to me you see this also
is
that how to have your prayers at this
time one
something working on you
this is the first thing you have to do
not that at this time you go
and cook
you have known the story of two sisters
attending on christ
all right so at this time
what is your first job is to try
to be more exposed to me
so that automatically you go into your
subtotal
this is the best but if i am not there
and when you are alone or when we are
with other sahaja yogis
you must now compete in rising higher
and higher
from tamaguna to rajaguna and from
rajaguna to sato
but actually by realization you have
gone beyond
these three ones you have gone beyond it
actually that is what has happened
but like clouds they cover you again and
again
and when the sky is covered with those
clouds
you cannot see the sun you cannot see
the moon you cannot see the stars
so we have to know how these clouds are
coming into us
and that's how we go into our complete
analysis
how these clouds are coming to us we
find out about our
different chakras what are the chakras
we are catching
here comes the another constant
attention
towards our channel are our vibrations
all right or not
why are we getting our vibrations
if not what chakra am i catching what
must be the catch
i must raise my kundalini see for myself
where is the catch
do i do my meditation or not if i do it
am i doing it just dozingly or
am i really in it am i
really feeling it or not am i alert or
not
all this is to be assiduously
sincerely absolutely truthfully should
be worked out
because it is a process between
yourselves
see it's a very funny it is so funny
relationship
that it is satisfied with happening
you have to be satisfied with yourself
there's nobody mataji is not concerned
nobody is concerned it is you
are concerned with yourself
you