Oh
we show very very happy diwali to see
all of you here is itself such a joy for
me that you all have taken to sahaja
yoga in such a beautiful way it is your
own self is your spirit is your own but
to take to self is difficult it's only
your desire something which is
meaningful frame and that's how you have
got your self-realization it cannot be
forced as you oh very well it has to
work out only with your desire only
with your surrender
no use talking about no use convincing
about what works out is your desire
simple as that the power of desire
within you work sat out there are many
who are not here who have got their
realization all over the world I
remember all of them and all of you
should remember them today is a nice day
when we can think of all those who are
enlightened in this world that's the
reality was the Enlightenment of human
beings it's not Colonel it's not some
love as human beings if they are
enlightened then there is no problem
anymore left the problems come with the
people who are not invited because they
are in the darkness they are groping in
the darkness and some of them are don't
know also that they are company
completely ignorant of realities once
you come to sahaja yoga and enlighten
yourself you've seen that light in that
light what is good what is bad to begin
with and then you grow into it
beautifully just like these flowers who
are all the time happy all the time
giving you joy in the same way when you
are enlightened with that light you
don't see anything
you got everything within you keep the
lights on the another thing you can do
is with your light you can and write
another people like we have done here we
had enlightened one can deal with that
we haven't written none of them so you
all can do it because you have got that
light within it that's right you can
enlighten others and they can feel their
joy of their spirit is something to be
seen now like so many lights you helped
in the same way you are the lights for
the whole world it's not sufficient that
you have got the light but also you have
to give light to others you have to
enlighten others just like these colors
once you start doing that you will
realize what you have got and then
introspect yourself and you will behave
in a matter manner that behaves a saint
could be a sage without proclaiming it
inside your being you just develop that
beautiful extremely beautiful
improvement that is joy
you don't want to give any false ideas
about risk because whatever is the truth
is with there is no need to tell
something untruth about yours people
will realize that you are realized Souls
they will just feel your subtle nature
your reality whether you come from India
or you count from England or from
America you all have that ocean of love
and knowledge be sure that this all
there only you first enjoy your own
ocean of love first you enjoy that and
then you can enjoy in others I don't
have to tell you that you love each
other or anything you just love you just
understand you just spread your right
among yourself sometimes you get
frustrated with other people in your
country maybe in your city maybe in your
village that the people who are not yet
a lighter but best thing is to work it
out you have to work it out
no I had first wanted very old lady one
who got a realization and then you all
are here in the same way you all can
also do the job of realization for that
you don't need any calculations you
don't need any Thanksgiving it just
there and it works out what do you do
for a light just see you just put near
the candle and you get the night in the
same way it is your enlightenment is
such that it will give light to
thousands and thousands of people all
over them as you know there are many
countries who we have to steal approach
but we will do that just locate and find
out where do you have to go and where
you have to work firstly you are capable
of giving realization you are have
confidence that you can give realization
to people for which you don't need any
help single person can do it thousands
and read it is very important for the
diwali of the whole world that we should
give realization to people very
important
now the in sahaja yoga many people are
such who are little frustrated with them
skills especially with their past forget
the past past is not important what is
important is present at this present
moment what have you to do you don't
have to worry about the past that I have
done this have done that was done is
finished now you look out for the future
what can you do for the future and some
or other with the light you see your
path you get rid of all the darkness and
you know how far to go how to beat
people and how to spread sorry it's
something you have already within you
but you have to first of all establish
your connection with it if you have
established your connection with that
ocean that will happen you can
definitely work it out work it out in
such a beautiful manner and will be
somewhere amazed how you will be
successful the success that you get out
of all this ignorance you are amazed at
it but you have the light with the light
you do remove all the darkness doesn't
have to think about it just removes
because we have but if you don't have
the light then no use talking about it
no use doing it because
it does give any success on the contrary
it's a failure failure of the worst type
and can be very dangerous for people we
have had very funny experiences also in
the search but I think they all are
learning one by one thus this should not
have been done that was wrong now what
blinds you we should find out in this
country it's such a money oriented
country America we shall spread all over
the world and being money-oriented you
do get enamored you do feel that you
must make money out of sahaja yoga there
are some who do not think like that but
they are still running after making
money there is no need at all for you to
make money or to find for yourself a
kind of a security in one your security
is in great within you so all these
outside things which are absolutely
unnecessary should not blindly now if
you have the light you can see clearly
and this help of divine you see that
very clearly in your life and you're
surprised how the divine has helped you
out
points I get letters from people who say
mother thank you very much I got rid of
my problem I got rid of mine enemies all
kinds of thing well I have done nothing
it's your light which has removed the
darkness if you are ignorant then only
the light can remove the darkness of
your ignorance actually we don't know
how much there is the power of the light
as you can see here every light is
giving such a lot of not only energy but
also complete picture so thus you can
make up for example you can make out of
somebody that rely so long it's a not
necessary that you have to go near that
person or take any special care or
anything you will just know that this
person is realized soul or not I've had
many such experiences where I found that
people don't know is realized very
surprising if you know who is a realized
soul then half of your problem is over
now the second one is the problem of how
to convince that fellow what he is
capable of I find that problem also with
circles they are capable
a very great book all over the world
they can find out so many things which
are normally normal people cannot find
out but sahaja Yogi's can immediately
find out what sort of a person you're
facing this is the difference that means
you know the truth truth about everyone
truth about the whole situation truth
about who is just boosting or just
making up a story or some sort of a
hypocrisy it's not difficult because now
you have the site you can see with your
light what's wrong what's good with
others such a blessing it is for you
that you cannot be cheated because also
you are looked after by the divine
guided all the time by the river have
faith that you have faith in the divine
that's very important as you have faith
in a cannibal have faith that the divine
will give you a light will guide your
path to take you to the right place to
do the right thing I mean so many of
these experiences are with you I need
not tell you how much people have
written to me how they found things
working out
despite all that we are collecting we
are nice to each other we don't tell
lies we don't try to destroy anyone that
means we are much above all human
feelings and this is only because of the
light you can see where you are
faltering it it's just you see for
yourself for that I think meditation is
the most important thing is every day
should do meditation those who do not do
meditation not capable of falling down
because meditation is like putting oil
into the love those who do not meditate
think they can do without it or sand
instead they have to meditate morning
and him the problem is everything comes
from Andy so simple that they don't
understand that meditation is very
important typical not you but there are
many I know who get realization don't
meditate and their style is different
their nature is different meditation is
such a soothing such a beautiful way of
connection with the divine that all your
problems get solved in that meditative
mood
if you are not meditating you are not
following meditation then maybe your
light will go down it won't give
sufficient is importantly wearing to
find out about yourself about others in
the medication how to do meditation many
people ask don't do anything to just go
into thoughtless already try to go to
the thoughtless awareness if you can get
into that condition of thoughtless
awareness you can your job because
that's the point where you are the truth
with the reality with a joy with
everything that is so condom when you
meditate try not to not to make some
sort of a function out of it no
meditation is something silencing
yourself silencing your thoughts and
going to that deep ocean which is within
yourself but supposing you don't do that
if you don't breathe it eight I can make
out immediately those who are meditating
and those work it's not difficult for me
those who do not meditate are always
hesitated they are confused they can't
honest
and that's why meditation is the most
important thing in self just like a
light burns the electricity flowing in a
treadle concern or by because of the
tunnels in the same way meditation is a
continuous availability of the divine
force that will reduce all your
operations not only that but takes out
all the negative thoughts it takes out
all the discouraging thing and when you
are meditating like that thoughtless
awareness then he'll be amazed how you
are ahead from within and without it's a
terrible power that works is thoughtless
awareness so those who do not meditate
cannot go very much far with that
wantage of sahaja yoga once you try to
meditate and go up to the point of
thoughtless oil so what happens to you
if you are in thoughtless awareness what
happens to you is that you get
the confidence complete confidence talk
to you later you know you have that have
seen children coming from our school in
the rosh hashanah extremely confident
and extremely humble and i asked them
what do you do he said they said / we
meditate we meditate in the school in
the evening and that meditation helps
imagine the small children can say that
so why not you also understand that
meditation will give you security it
will give you a real enlightenment and a
complete connection with the divine
without the connection of the divine
most elusive green sahaja yoga
I know the people who are meditating who
have gone down into their being and who
are very developed also I know people
one little supervision your depth is in
thoughtless awareness is a very
important point which you should reach
looking at anything if you are
thoughtlessly aware then you really
become reflective about just works out
that way I don't know how far you can
remain in that condition but even for a
second you can achieve it star achieving
it more than I have talked so much about
meditation before but today when I see
all these candles burning I think they
are all meditative they are all in
meditation and that's how their work in
the same way sahaja Yogi's who meditate
I know and those who don't I know and if
they have problems I know why the
problems are their main thing is your
connection with the divine is only
possible when you meditate and become
thoughtlessly aware that's the point
where you mind works it helps
it comes to your help in such great that
you don't know how we have achieved it
so thoughtless awareness in the first
point all of you should achieve very
important after that we can achieve
something else but the first step is
thought the Sun it is very important to
become thoughtlessly aware because then
there are no thoughts coming from the
left or right from the present or the
future just in the present you are there
it's something you all have it's not
that me I am saying that to you but all
of you have this but steady yourself you
have to steady yourself at thoughtless
awareness how long that's not the point
the point is once you touched it you
will go on touching it many people
meditate but their thought process is
going on they are not thoughtlessly
silent now this is the one point which
is very important if you have to grow
you should be absolutely in connection
with the divine through thoughtless
awareness you don't have to bring you
don't have to call anyone nothing it
just works because it is within you all
these thoughts are bombarding from both
the sides in your mind these thoughts
that are coming to you have no meaning
with you they do not substantiate
yourself you
ocean and you have to get into that
state of thoughtless awareness it is
always described in all the great books
but not so clearly I am Telling I don't
say that some of you do not get
thoughtless awareness so they are good
for nothing no but please try you can
all get into that state of thoughtless
awareness even for a second if you get
it is a very good idea then you go on
increasing that second I think this is a
reflecting mind when you look at
something you can become thoughtlessly
aware and then if mind effects to the
depth of what you see that's how you all
will become really very creative sahaja
Yogi's would I find that this state of
thoughtless awareness is not established
by many which is not good today on this
day of diwali i would say that you
enlighten yourself we thought this
awareness it is not difficult is within
you because thoughts are coming from
this side and that side and they are not
the waves of your brain no just your own
reactions but in case you meditate in
the real sense of the world then you
will get in
to that thoughtless awareness which is a
very important point and all these
nonsensical thoughts which are of no use
to you will disappear they won't be
there and then your growth is possible
and you grow very many people are here
who will save the mother we don't get
that straight try try that I don't
believe you cannot get it all of you can
get that thought that I can eat it and
you will get in that you don't have to
discard anything you don't have to see
anything just go into meditation and
you'll be amazed how little work of
course you are many was there most of
you but still they would say increase
that thoughtless awareness that area
today is very important because of this
day of the valley the valley is supposed
to be enlightenment II but enlightenment
within is how much you are in
thoughtless alone under everything works
out because you are the ocean of it you
have it within yourself only you have to
tap it if you don't have it then in the
world you have to just tap it and you'll
be amazed that you are a source of such
on
source or such happiness I should say
source of really frightening so today's
message is that while meditating go into
thoughtless awareness no thought is
important because it's your own creation
but if you have to become with the
divine creation you have to get to that
state of thoughtless awareness minimum
of me once that comes to you gradually
it will grow and you will be amazed how
you will be able to grow into sahaja
yoga in a very big way thank you very
much
ah
Harsha by the pollution of you
ha
Oh
thumb
ah
Oh
you
I did tell me
who toppled
Oh
me
bhutan
a good time
me
Oh
how long is all
we love my only love
I
I love
recognized
Oh
you
my god
I
my
stop
Oh
on my god
not there
my god
they are