... yang mengekspresikan dirinya dalam jumlah besar
keluar dari pusat-pusat halus.
Sisi kiri tubuh halus kita adalah kolom biru
adalah jiwa kita. Itu emosi kita. Ini masa lalu kita.
Ini adalah bagian dari kita
adalah pengkondisian kita dan menciptakan apa yang kita sebut superego kita,
mekanisme respons kami, mekanisme refleks kami.
Ini ingatan kita.
Sisi kanan adalah proyeksi kami.
Itu berkaitan dengan perencanaan kami. Itu berhubungan dengan kami
berpikir, berpikir, berpikir.
Dan tentu saja itu berkaitan dengan ego kita.
Ini adalah mekanisme yang kita gunakan untuk mencapai kesimpulan rasional.
Ini melalui sisi kanan yang kita analisis
dan menghitung dan mencapai tertentu,
sering tidak logis tetapi kesimpulan rasional.
Jadi kita harus berhati-hati terhadap ketidakseimbangan ini
jangan mengekspresikan diri dalam diri kita untuk sebagian besar,
sementara kecenderungannya adalah bahwa sementara kita akan melakukannya
bergerak terlalu jauh ke sisi kiri
atau terlalu jauh ke sisi kanan dan sebagainya
bergerak melampaui alam bawah sadar pribadi kita sendiri
atau supra-kesadaran pribadi kita sendiri
ke suatu area yang
benar-benar menipu dan cukup sering berbahaya
yang disebut alam bawah sadar kolektif
kesadaran kolektif yang ada
diduduki oleh roh orang mati
yang bisa dan memang memiliki kita.
Ini berkisar dari zona berbahaya
yang memberi kita masalah seperti alkoholisme, kanker,
segala macam kompleks kekuasaan
contoh utama Hitler.
Jadi kita harus sangat berhati-hati
dari sikap berkecimpung dan [DILATANTE?] ini terhadap pencarian kami.
Saya telah berurusan dengan orang sakit dalam kehidupan profesional saya
dan saya telah melihat begitu banyak pencari yang sudah
tidak hanya pergi ke guru-guru palsu ini
dan telah rusak
dan kembali menjadi lebih buruk bagi ziarah spiritual.
Tetapi saya telah melihat banyak orang lain yang memiliki
sama-sama rusak meskipun mungkin tidak begitu
secara terbuka dan jelas
bentuk pencarian lain yang lebih diterima secara sosial
seperti kursus-kursus ini dalam clairvoyance,
seperti gerakan gereja karismatik di mana
ada penguasaan spiritual yang jelas,
seperti di misalnya
memanggil roh-roh di gereja spiritualis, seperti
duduk di trans dalam lingkaran dan sebagainya.
Kita harus berhati-hati terhadap semua bidang ini juga
dan saya berkata kita harus sangat berhati-hati terhadap penyembuhan
karena yang mungkin penyembuhan mungkin
kekuatan tubuh yang sangat, sangat sibuk atau
Semangat berorientasi ego yang menggunakan tubuh kita
untuk mencapai perjalanan ego sendiri melalui kita.
Ingat kamu
orang yang menjadi tuan rumah harus memiliki ego yang agak besar juga
menjadi tuan rumah yang dapat diterima untuk tubuh yang sibuk itu.
Tapi sudahlah.
Ini sering terjadi.
Itu telah terjadi pada saya dan saya secara terbuka mengakuinya.
Sejak mendapatkan Realisasi diri saya
Saya mendapatkan kekuatan yang jauh lebih halus,
tetapi jauh lebih banyak yang merangkul dan itu adalah kekuatan Tuhan.
Kekuatan yang mencintai, koordinat itu, keseimbangan itu,
yang melarutkan segala negativitas.
Bukan dengan beberapa trik penumpangan tangan
dan Anda mulai gemetar dan berkeringat
dan beberapa bantuan sementara terjadi di
tubuh fisik.
Tidak mungkin misalnya saya menonton selama dua tahun
penyembuh Pilipino,
dimana dengan segala macam monster yang mereka mainkan dengan tisu
dan mereka menggunakan roh
yang dematerialisasi jaringan dan rematerialisasi jaringan.
Ini omong kosong yang berbahaya
dan sering mengganggu kemajuan spiritual
pasien dan tentu saja orang yang melakukan pekerjaan itu.
Jadi berhati-hatilah terhadap semua area yang agak pinggiran ini,
zona bahaya ini di bidang pencarian spiritual
dan ambil ke Sahaja Yoga karena di sini Anda mendapatkan kekuatan Anda sendiri.
Dan kekuatan itu sangat sangat halus, sangat sangat manis.
Dan mereka sama sekali tidak terkait dengan kepemilikan roh.
Aku sedikit berkutat dengan semangat karena
mungkin Ibu malam ini akan berbicara tentang chakra itu di mana
ini adalah masalah, Chakra Swadhistan.
Jadi dalam pencarian kami sangat berhati-hati.
Berhati-hatilah bahwa Anda memiliki kekuatan Anda sendiri,
bahwa Anda memegang kendali, bahwa Anda menjadi tuan.
Inilah yang direalisasikan oleh Self-realization.
memberi Anda sukacita dari Roh.
Ini memberi Anda kontak itu dengan Yang Ilahi
dan Anda mengembangkannya.
Anda menemukan bahwa penyakit fisik Anda menjadi lebih baik.
Anda menemukan bahwa Anda dapat memberi realisasi kepada orang lain.
Anda menemukan bahwa Anda bisa menjadi dokter Anda sendiri
dan dokter kepada orang lain
dan Anda dapat menikmati manisnya kolektivitas
benar-benar memiliki saudara dan saudari.
Tidak membicarakannya tetapi menjadi
bagian yang sangat indah dari peradaban spiritual yang muncul
yang telah dijanjikan dalam semua tulisan suci.
Jika Mataji adalah orang yang bisa melakukan pekerjaan itu,
jika Dia adalah orang yang bisa, dengan kekuatan dan cinta-Nya,
angkat kundalini ini,
cukup rendah hati untuk menerimanya.
Setidaknya bawa sebagai hipotesis.
Biarkan itu berkembang dalam diri Anda.
Dia menyarankan setidaknya untuk delapan hari.
Temukan.
Kembangkan itu. Menyelesaikannya.
Kenali kekuatan Anda sendiri.
Manuver itu.
Biarkan diri Anda
menikmati memberi realisasi kepada orang lain
dan akhirnya tahu bahwa Anda adalah Roh.
Inilah apa itu. Itu yang Anda cari.
Namun saya tidak bisa meyakinkan Anda.
Anda harus mencari tahu sendiri.
Bahkan Anda tidak perlu percaya apa pun yang saya katakan.
Apa yang harus Anda lakukan adalah Anda harus menetapkan getaran Anda.
Anda harus membangun kebangkitan kundalini Anda
Sedemikian rupa sehingga Anda sebenarnya
buktikan sendiri bahwa apa yang saya katakan adalah kebenaran.
Sekali lagi, para wanita dan pria adalah kesenangan saya
untuk memperkenalkan kepada Anda
Yang Mulia Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi.
Mungkin ketika kru film sedang menyelesaikan pekerjaan mereka
Saya hanya bisa membiasakan Anda dengan chakra
chakra karena pusat-pusat ini mungkin sedikit asing bagi Anda
dalam hal nama jadi
Chakra Mooladhara ini terletak
di area yang berada di dasar tulang belakang. Disini.
Itu berkaitan dengan area-area tulang belakang tubuh seperti itu
sebagai kelenjar prostat. Itu berhubungan dengan seks dan organ seks kita
dan memasok energi di area tubuh itu.
Ini juga terkait dengan pleksus sakral dan coccygeal
dalam tubuh kotor.
Dan itulah pusat yang harus dibangunkan.
Itu pusatnya
harus memulai pekerjaan memberi Anda Self-realisasi karena
disini digulung di sakrum adalah kundalini.
Perhatikan bagaimana itu di atas.
Ibu akan menjelaskan sebentar lagi
titik yang sangat penting
bahwa pusat ini berada di atas Mooladhara Chakra
karena itu pusat kekudusan.
Ini adalah pusat Bunda Suci di dalam dirimu.
Itu adalah pusat Roh Kudus di dalam Anda.
Jadi sekali lagi, para hadirin dengan sedikit pemahaman itu,
Mataji Nirmala Devi.
Saya tunduk pada semua pencari kebenaran.
Seperti yang saya katakan kemarin kepada Anda bahwa kebenaran adalah apa adanya.
Ini akan menjadi apa yang akan terjadi.
Anda tidak dapat mengubah kebenaran untuk adaptasi Anda
atau untuk proyeksi mental Anda
atau untuk kenyamanan Anda sendiri.
Itu akan tetap apa pun itu.
Titik kebenaran pertama adalah
bahwa itu membangun dirinya sendiri
kendati semua jenis agensi
atau semua jenis kekuatan yang anti-dewa.
Kedua adalah bahwa itu melayani para pencari yang jujur.
Ini seperti akar kecil yang keluar dari benih,
berjalan berputar-putar, memperbaiki dirinya sendiri ke sumbernya.
Yang ketiga adalah bahwa hal itu dapat menghancurkan beberapa ide Anda.
Itu mungkin mengacaukan sebagian keyakinan Anda.
Tetapi ketika tampaknya itu adalah suatu sukacita yang besar
itu benar-benar Anda hilang
di lautan kenikmatan itu.
Anda melupakan semua yang hilang.
Anda senang bahwa Anda telah kehilangan perahu kotor itu.
Itu tergantung dan semua yang Anda miliki
dan sekarang kamu telah menjadi satu dengan lautan kegembiraan.
Kebenaran adalah Roh Anda.
Itu abadi. Itu adalah ekspresi Tuhan di dalam diri Anda.
Karena kami belum bisa mencapainya
bahwa dalam kesadaran kita,
kita terganggu, kesal,
merasa kadang-kadang seolah-olah kita adalah orang-orang yang hancur.
Tetapi Roh tidak bisa dihancurkan.
Itu tidak bisa dikeringkan.
Itu tidak bisa dibunuh.
Ini membangkitkan Anda,
memenuhi Anda dengan semua berkat dari Yang Ilahi.
Itulah koneksi yang harus Anda dapatkan.
Setiap instrumen yang dibuat
jika tidak terhubung ke listrik tidak ada artinya.
Dengan cara yang sama Anda dibuat dengan sangat indah,
sangat mulia dan lembut.
Itu satu-satunya hal yang harus Anda lakukan agar bisa dimasukkan ke listrik.
Dan sukacita menjadi diri sendiri adalah fantastis.
Jadi poin kedua yang saya katakan adalah itu
itu bisa dihancurkan - keyakinan Anda.
Dan itulah mengapa saya harus memberi tahu Anda bahwa ketika Anda mendengarkan Saya,
kamu tidak boleh kesal.
Itu sama sekali tidak membuat Anda kesal.
Saya tidak punya apa-apa dari Anda, tidak ada apa-apa.
Ini adalah milik Anda sendiri di dalam Anda
dan Anda harus menghapus semua belenggu,
semua ketidaktahuan yang kuat
dan hanya mendapatkan kebenaran seperti apa adanya dan sebagaimana yang termanifestasi.
Manifestasi dari kebenaran Roh
berada di luar pemahaman manusia
dalam arti bahwa itu adalah kejadian.
Itu terjadi pada Anda bahwa Anda menjadi Roh.
Dan sesuatu yang harus terjadi
tidak dapat dipahami dengan otak yang terbatas ini
karena saya berbicara tentang sesuatu yang tidak terbatas.
Jadi kamu harus
bersiaplah untuk terpicu ke ruang angkasa
yang tidak terbatas.
Ini terjadi pasti ajaib dan spontan.
Ini adalah kejadian terbesar
bahwa manusia bisa pernah memikirkannya.
Ini dijelaskan secara singkat
dalam banyak ayat Alquran.
Cukup jelas dinyatakan oleh Kristus bahwa Anda harus dilahirkan kembali.
Tapi peramal India telah melihatnya
sangat jelas segala sesuatu yang berhasil.
Mereka tidak memiliki agama apa pun.
Mereka tidak mengikuti organisasi apa pun. Mereka adalah peramal.
Dan mereka semua telah melihat bagaimana cara kerjanya.
Pengetahuan yang kukatakan padamu bukan hari ini.
Tetapi bahkan 14.000 tahun yang lalu Markandeya, seorang penyair besar di India,
telah menulis tentang hal itu.
Tentu saja saya membawanya ke standar modern untuk menjelaskan kepada Anda.
Tetapi ketika Anda membaca Markandeya Anda akan kagum
setelah menyadari bahwa dari bukunya Anda akan mendapatkan getaran.
Baru sekitar seratus tahun yang lalu
William Blake, seorang penyair besar Inggris,
telah menulis semuanya tentang Sahaja Yoga
bagaimana itu bekerja.
Dia telah menulis bahwa orang-orang Tuhan akan menjadi nabi
dan para nabi ini akan memiliki kekuatan untuk menjadikan yang lain nabi.
Jelas [dia atau Dia?] Telah mengatakannya.
Tapi saya bertanya-tanya berapa banyak orang yang membaca [dia atau Dia?] Untuk mengerti
apa yang diharapkan bahwa Anda harus menjadi nabi.
Jika orang berkata, "Saya seorang nabi." Baiklah jadi apa.
Tidak ada bedanya bagi Anda jika saya seorang nabi.
Tetapi Anda harus menjadi nabi.
Itulah yang [dia atau Dia?] Katakan dengan jelas.
Dia telah dengan jelas mengatakan begitu banyak hal yang luar biasa
kami telah menemukan bahkan tempat kami telah mendapatkan ashram kami.
Bahkan tempat tinggalku
[Dia atau Dia] telah dengan sangat jelas menyatakan alamat yang tepat dari tempat itu.
Apa yang seorang pelihat Inggris miliki
dan kemudian akhirnya [dia atau Dia?] kata Yerusalem.
Inggris akan menjadi Yerusalem tidak ada yang percaya
tiga ratus tahun yang lalu
atau bahkan dua ratus tahun ke belakang, bahkan kembali seratus tahun ke belakang.
Bahkan kemarin itu mungkin
bahwa bahasa Inggris akan mewakili Yerusalem.
Tempat ziarah
di mana orang akan pergi untuk berziarah.
Tetapi hari ini saya akan mengatakan itu menjadi.
Itu terjadi di Inggris dan harus terjadi di Australia juga
karena saya katakan Australia memiliki tempat khusus, tempat yang sangat istimewa.
Dalam kosmos alam semesta ini
Australia adalah pusat besar ini, pusat pertama Mooladhara.
Dan buktinya adalah Aires Rock
yang memiliki warna yang sama dengan bentuk yang sama.
Wajah dewa juga sama dengan batang di depan.
Australia menunjukkan kepolosan.
Saya bertanya-tanya berapa banyak yang telah menahan ketidakbersalahan mereka.
Mereka tidak bersalah sejak lahir.
Dengan cara Tuhan memberkati Anda.
Pria yang tidak bersalah adalah pria yang paling bijaksana. Adalah orang yang paling bijak.
Dan dia sangat mudah mengambil kebijaksanaan.
Hanya hal kepercayaan diri harus ada dan harga diri
tentang dirimu.
Ini adalah dua hal yang akan muncul
kepolosan itu di dalam dirimu
yang harus membantu seluruh dunia untuk datang.
Saya memiliki harapan besar dari Australia
karena Tuhan telah menciptakannya dengan tujuan yang sangat besar.
Jadi seperti yang dia katakan padamu hari ini
tentang ketiga hal yang kita miliki
Saya akan memberi Anda permutasi dan kombinasi ini
bagaimana mereka bekerja di dalam diri kita.
Jadi tolong dengarkan dengan pengertian
bahwa apa pun tidak cocok denganmu,
ide-ide Anda, Anda tidak perlu repot-repot.
. Saya yakin kami akan dapat membuktikannya kepada Anda bahwa ini benar.
Sekarang kekuatan pertama yang ada di dalam diri kita adalah kekuatan hasrat.
Kekuatan keinginan adalah yang ada
tetapi tidak jelas.
Inilah kekuatan yang memberi kita emosi
atau kekuatan jiwa kita, begitu mereka menyebutnya.
Ini adalah kekuatan yang diciptakan oleh aktivitasnya
di atas kepalamu,
lebih banyak di sisi kanan,
sebuah institusi yang disebut sebagai superego.
Berarti semua kondisi Anda disimpan di sana.
Ini berfungsi untuk memori Anda. Untuk masa lalumu.
Dan di luar itu terletak daerah -
di luar sisi kiri terletak area bawah sadar kolektif
karena ini terlihat setelah alam bawah sadar Anda.
Dan di luar itu adalah alam bawah sadar kolektif.
Berarti area yang dibangun dalam diri kita sejak penciptaan.
Mati lengkap ada di sisi kiri.
Di sisi kanan
ada kekuatan lain yang berfungsi
jadi kami menyebutnya kekuatan tindakan
dimana kita bertindak
untuk ekspresi fisik kita
dan untuk ekspresi mental kita.
Dengan mana kita berpikir untuk masa depan.
Dengan mana kami merencanakan hal-hal.
Dengan mana kita merasionalisasi dan membuat kantong lain seperti balon
yang disebut sebagai ego sebagai produk sampingan
dari kegiatan pusat ini.
Di luar ini terletak area lain yang merupakan supra-sadar
dan kemudian arti supra-sadar kolektif semua itu adalah masa depan.
Jadi orang-orang yang sangat futuristik,
sangat ambisius,
yang mencoba mendominasi orang lain
seperti Hitler yang bisa Anda hubungi
akan berada di area supakribadi kolektif.
Di tengahnya ada kekuatan lain di dalam diri kita.
Itu sebabnya Buddha selalu berkata tetap di pusat.
Jalani kehidupan yang moderat dan bukan yang ekstrem.
Kekuatan pusat ini adalah kekuatan
yang memberi kita kesadaran manusia kita.
Itu membawa kita dari amuba hewan kecil kecil
ke tingkat manusia ini.
Jadi itu adalah kekuatan evolusi kita di dalam diri kita.
Para ilmuwan tidak pernah memikirkan satu hal pun.
Mengapa kita menjadi manusia?
Apa kebutuhan untuk menjadikan kita manusia? Untuk tujuan apa
alam jika mereka tidak percaya pada Tuhan telah menciptakan manusia?
Jadi kekuatan evolusioner ini bekerja pada sistem yang disebut dharma
berarti yang ditopang.
Juga Anda bisa menyebut agama batin dalam diri kita.
Agama karbon adalah empat valensi.
Karbon memiliki empat valensi
dan panggung karbon berada di pusat pertama dalam manusia
di mana karbon adalah hal yang tidak bersalah.
Semua binatang tidak bersalah.
Semua materi tidak bersalah.
Jika saya meletakkan tangan saya di api itu akan terbakar.
Jika saya tidak meletakkan tangan saya di sana, itu tidak akan terbakar. Itu tidak bersalah.
Berarti tidak melakukan dosa apa pun karena tidak memiliki konsep dosa.
Hanya manusia yang memiliki konsep dosa
melalui ego mereka dan itulah mengapa mereka berpikir mereka melakukan dosa.
Sampai kamu adalah manusia
Anda akan selalu merasa bahwa Anda melakukan dosa
atau Anda akan berpikir bahwa orang lain melakukan dosa.
Entah Anda akan menyerang orang lain
atau Anda akan melakukan agresi terhadap diri Anda sendiri.
Jadi kita punya dua tipe orang di dalam kita.
Khususnya orang-orang yang melakukan agresi,
yang lain yang memberi agresi.
Orang-orang sisi kiri adalah orang-orang yang melakukan agresi.
Orang-orang sisi kanan adalah orang-orang yang memberikan agresi.
Itu tidak berarti orang yang melakukan agresi adalah orang yang sangat baik
atau orang yang memberi agresi adalah orang yang sangat jahat.
MenurutKu, keduanya sama-sama.
Karena jika Anda merepotkan orang lain Anda agresif.
Tetapi jika Anda menyiksa diri sendiri, Anda agresif terhadap diri sendiri.
Dan Anda tidak punya urusan untuk menyiksa diri sendiri
karena tubuh ini tidak diciptakan oleh Anda.
Itu diciptakan oleh Tuhan.
Dan manusia ini diciptakan sangat indah dengan cinta seperti itu
oleh pembuat konten itu untuk suatu tujuan
dan Anda tidak memiliki bisnis untuk dihancurkan karena ego Anda
atau karena superego Anda.
Sekarang kita punya dua jenis orang
seperti yang saya katakan kepada Anda orang-orang sisi kiri dan kanan.
Dan ada banyak orang yang berada di tengah
yang menjalani kehidupan moderasi
pemahaman
bahwa kehidupan harus diselesaikan dengan cara yang Anda dapatkan kepada Tuhan.
Bahwa Anda mendapatkan Roh Anda.
Mereka mungkin tidak percaya pada Tuhan.
Itu tidak perlu. Mereka mungkin tidak pergi ke gereja.
Mereka mungkin tidak pergi ke kuil.
Mereka mungkin tidak melakukan semua hal ini tetapi di dalam diri mereka sendiri
mereka adalah orang-orang yang moderat. Mereka adalah orang baik.
Mereka adalah orang-orang yang saleh.
Mereka adalah orang-orang yang memimpin kehidupan yang baik
tidak agresif atau melakukan agresi.
Mereka berdiri di samping mereka yang diserang
dan mereka [ABHOR atau APPAL?] orang-orang yang agresif.
Dan mereka memberi tahu orang-orang yang diserang
bahwa Anda tidak boleh melakukan agresi apa pun.
Mereka adalah orang-orang yang ada di pusat.
Sekarang pada tahap ini kita harus menggabungkan ketiga tipe orang ini.
Salah satunya adalah tamo guni karena mereka menyebutnya di sisi kiri.
Sisi kanan adalah rajo guni.
Dan di tengah adalah orang yang tetap sebagai [SATWA?] Guni.
Sekarang orang pusat
sangat penting dari sudut pandang Sahaja Yoga
karena dia mendapatkan realisasinya tanpa kesulitan
dan dia mencapainya, memahaminya, dan menerimanya
tanpa kesulitan. Setelah itu terjadi, itu hanya tumbuh.
Orang-orang yang sangat rumit
baik dengan lebih dari emosi atau aktivitas mental
adalah orang-orang yang akan dibawa ke pusat.
Dan begitu perhatian mereka datang ke pusat
maka jauh lebih mudah untuk mencerahkan mereka.
Sekarang kundalini ini adalah kekuatan di dalam Anda dari Roh Kudus.
Roh Kudus adalah kuasa Allah yang melingkupi semuanya.
Kekuatan Tuhan yang terpisah dari Tuhan.
Tuhan Yang Maha Kuasa Bapa menyaksikan karya ini
kekuatan yang merupakan milik-Nya.
Sekarang Anda dapat melihat bahwa kuasa Allah ini terbagi menjadi empat.
Tiga dari mereka seperti yang saya katakan. Yang keempat adalah kundalini.
Suatu hari saya mengatakan kepada Anda kundalini adalah keinginan murni di dalam
yang mungkin tidak Anda sadari.
Apakah keinginan paling murni di dalam dirimu.
Dan keinginan murni ini adalah menjadi satu dengan Yang Ilahi.
Dan keinginan ini mutlak
menunggu sesaat ketika seseorang bisa membangunkannya
dan berikan kelahiran kedua kepada anak tunggal-Nya.
Setiap orang memiliki ibu individual.
Kundalini ini terlihat setelah.
yang dia beri Anda nurani.
Dialah yang membimbing Anda.
Dialah yang menyelamatkanmu dari hal-hal yang sulit.
Dialah yang juga menyehatkan parasimpatis Anda
yang berada di pusat yang diekspresikan di pusat
yang mengkoordinasi dan mengontrol sistem saraf simpatik
yang kiri dan kanan
sistem saraf simpatis dalam tubuh manusia.
Sekarang para dokter tidak mengerti ini
jadi mereka tidak mengerti bagaimana membedakannya
antara masalah psikosomatis,
antara masalah fisik,
antara masalah mental,
dan masalah yang dapat kita sebut ketidakseimbangan.
Dan dalam kebingungan itu sebagian besar penyakitnya
dinyatakan sebagai tidak tersembuhkan.
Sekarang untuk memahami seberapa dalam
semua masalah ini
kita harus tahu bahwa sejauh ini kita belum mencapai kedalamannya
di mana kita bisa mengerti itu
semua masalah yang kita hadapi di masyarakat kita,
dalam politik kita,
dalam ekonomi kita,
atau di kehidupan sehari-hari kita,
di keluarga kami, dengan anak-anak kami,
punya akar di bawah di dalam diri kita sendiri
dan jika kita bisa menyembuhkan akar itu
kita benar-benar dapat mengubah seluruh dunia.
Wajah seluruh dunia.
Dan emansipasi seluruh umat manusia
ada di tangan orang-orang hari ini
yang ingin terlebih dahulu koreksi instrumen mereka
dan dengan itu, koreksi orang lain.
Kali ini telah dijelaskan sebelumnya sebagai waktu kebangkitan
oleh Muhammad.
waktu penghakiman oleh banyak orang lain.
Dalam Alkitab itu dijelaskan pada saat penghakiman.
Di Kapel Sistine jika Anda telah melihat
gambaran lengkap tentang penghakiman terakhir ditunjukkan dengan sangat indah.
Dan Chakra Agnya yang ada disana
[PRESIDED or RESIDED?] oleh Kristus Sendiri
benar-benar ditampilkan di sana.
Michelangelo sendiri adalah jiwa yang sadar
dan dia bisa melihat semua hal ini dengan sangat jelas.
letakkan dalam gambar yang indah.
Saya berharap Anda dapat memiliki kesempatan untuk melihatnya
setelah realisasimu
dan Anda akan terkejut bahwa dia telah menunjukkan
bagaimana Kristus akan memilih pada akhirnya.
Sekarang pada saat ini kita harus melihat ketiga chakra ini
ditambah tiga
saluran yang kita miliki di dalam diri kita sendiri.
Jadi kombinasi dari ini kita harus melihat bagaimana mereka berhasil.
Sekarang chakra pertama jika Anda perhatikan hanya terhubung ke satu sisi.
Itu adalah jiwa.
Jadi ketika kita mulai melakukan seks melalui aktivitas mental kita,
itu tidak menyenangkan.
Itu tidak pada tempatnya.
Membaca tentang seks, memikirkan tentang seks,
mengerjakannya melalui pemahaman seks melalui otak
sama sekali tidak berguna karena otak tidak dapat memahami seks.
Kami berbicara banyak tentang seks tetapi orang-orang tidak suka seks yang bisa saya lihat
karena jika Anda benar-benar mencapai kesenangan seks dalam diri Anda,
setelah beberapa waktu Anda hanya menjadi di atas seks.
Anda matang menjadi kepribadian yang lengkap
kebebasan ada dari seks untuk Anda.
Anda benar-benar kuat.
Anda tidak menjadi impoten.
Tetapi seluruh gerakan energi lengkap Anda
berjalan menuju hatimu dan bukan ke arah seksmu.
Ini adalah jenis lain dari
dunia saya terkadang datang ke Barat
di mana saya terkejut bahwa orang-orang percaya bahwa seks memainkan peran
dalam evolusi mereka.
Di India tidak ada yang akan mempercayai ini.
Bahkan jika Anda memberi tahu mereka Freud atau siapa pun
mereka akan bilang dia pasti gila.
Mereka tidak akan percaya karena secara tradisional
itu terbukti. Lihat semua negara tradisional - China sama.
Saya sudah bicara dengan orang Mesir, Cina, dan India.
Mereka memiliki pandangan yang sama tentang seks
dan mereka hanya tertawa pada orang lain
apa yang mereka lakukan di mana mereka bertele-tele?
Mengapa kamu membuang-buang energi mereka?
Mereka tidak bisa mengerti
ada apa dengan orang-orang ini mereka telah pergi dari kepala mereka.
Tetapi jika Anda pergi ke negara yang baru lahir
mereka lebih baik
karena juga satu alasan
yang terkadang tradisi
dapat menjepit Anda ke hal-hal tertentu yang tidak bisa begitu membantu.
Tetapi mereka yang [FAULT?] Dengan pendapat mereka bahkan sekarang
lebih baik karena Anda bisa memberi tahu mereka
bahwa seks tidak berperan dalam evolusi Anda.
Sekarang Anda dapat melihat bahwa itu terletak di bawah kundalini.
Pusat ini menjaga semua ekskresi
telah mendapat empat kelopak
karena kami punya empat plexus, sub-pleksus.
Kami punya empat sub-plexus untuk kami
pleksus mayor yang disebut pleksus panggul dalam diri kita.
Jadi di gores pleksus panggul
mewakili di bruto pusat halus Mooladhara ini.
Jadi orang-orang yang terlalu memikirkan seks,
belajar seks,
dan terlalu mengganggu otak mereka
sedang mengalami pornografi tanpa sukacita bersama mereka.
Itu benar-benar tidak menyenangkan, tidak masuk akal
dan menciptakan masalah terbesar bagi masyarakat.
Pertama kali ketika saya pergi ke luar negeri
di luar negeri saya [MEMULAI?] orang-orang melihat setiap wanita
melihat setiap pria.
Gila aku melihat ada apa dengan mereka.
Temperamen yang sangat tidak stabil.
Anda tahu sepanjang waktu melihat setiap wanita
melihat setiap pria.
Anda tidak dapat melewatkan satu pun.
Anda lihat, bahkan jika ada seorang wanita [UNCLEAR] terjadi
Memutar leher Anda ke atas dan yang lain jatuh ke bawah.
Dan kemudian Anda mengatakan Anda merindukan seseorang.
Di sana kita harus terus mencari.
Dan seperti orang gila, kamu tahu mereka semua akan pergi
Saya berkata, "Ada apa?"
Apakah mereka berusia delapan puluh tahun,
berusia enam tahun, atau sepuluh tahun, atau bahkan
mereka benar-benar akan melompat ke kuburan.
Masih di kuburan mereka mungkin memutar kepala mereka.
Itu bodoh dan itu kebodohan.
Apa yang kita dapatkan dari itu?
Tapi matanya sekarang lemah
karena setelah Sahaja Yoga ketika mereka datang kepada saya
mereka memberi tahu saya, "Ibu bahkan sekarang kita tidak bisa memperbaiki mata kita."
Ada sesuatu.
Suatu kali seorang yogi sahaja berdiri di sebelah saya.
Tiba-tiba dia menoleh.
Saya berkata, "Apa yang terjadi?"
Dia berkata, "Ada seorang wanita yang berdiri di belakang saya."
Jadi saya berkata, "Bagaimana Anda tertarik padanya?"
Pasti ada semacam itu
hal di belakang kepala Anda dan itulah yang ada di sini.
Bahwa Mooladhara diekspresikan di belakang
di sini di titik yang menonjol keluar dari Anda
otak dan tulang. Itu intinya adalah Mooladhara.
bagaimana efeknya pada mata. Karena terus bergoyang-goyang.
Ada dua jenis efek Mooladhara
Salah satunya adalah sisi kanan sisi kiri yang lain.
Jika Anda terlalu banyak orang yang sembelit
jika Anda menderita konstipasi terlalu banyak
Anda adalah pria yang sangat ketat.
Bahkan Anda tidak akan melihat istri Anda, orang semacam itu.
Ada yang ekstrem lainnya di sana.
Seorang biarawati atau pendeta atau semacam itu.
Hanya dipaksa selibat
dan kehidupan yang sangat disiplin. Orang-orang seperti itu bisa mendapatkan Hak Mooladhara.
Mooladhara Kiri - orang-orang yang mengerti siapa
sama sekali tidak menghormati kesucian mereka sama sekali.
Ini adalah dua tipe ekstrim yang Anda lalui
karena kiri dan kanan.
Tetapi sisi kiri
Mooladhara jauh lebih berbahaya daripada sisi kanan.
Karena paling banyak seseorang bisa mengalami konstipasi atau masalah
semua kekeringan ini di dalam tubuh dari sisi kanan.
Tapi sisi kiri Mooladhara
mereka yang tanpa pandang bulu menggunakan cakra mereka
untuk kehidupan yang sangat bermoral, permisif dan semua itu
masuk ke zona berbahaya.
Sudah alam telah menunjukkan itu.
Alam menunjukkan itu.
Enam puluh lima persen orang muda di Amerika adalah
entah impoten atau menderita yang mengerikan
[INFLUX atau PENGARUH?] Penyakit mengerikan mutlak yang tidak bisa disembuhkan.
Anda harus mengetahui bahwa pelaut ketika mereka melakukan perjalanan
mereka harus mengambil suntikan di setiap pelabuhan.
Karena mereka seharusnya menuruti itu
tetapi sekarang ini adalah demokrasi, jadi semua orang sama.
"Demonokrasi" Aku akan menyebutnya.
"Karena para raja seperti ini,
kita seharusnya menjadi. Mengapa apa yang salah?"
Tetapi Anda akan kagum jika pusat ini dimanjakan
penyakit apa yang bisa Anda dapatkan adalah salah satunya adalah mellitus ini.
Bukan hanya tetapi jika seseorang memiliki penyakit ini
wanita atau pria manapun yang tinggal dengan orang seperti itu
dapat menghubungi penyakit mengerikan pada saat itu karena pusat ini.
Itulah sebabnya mengapa Kristus mengatakan bahwa, "Ada tertulis di dalam Alkitab,
'Engkau tidak akan melakukan perzinahan.' "
Saya berkata, "Engkau tidak akan memiliki mata perzinahan."
Sampai sejauh itu Dia pergi.
Kemurnian mata hilang.
Dan itulah Dia
menunjukkan untuk waktu hari ini pada saat ini bahwa ini akan terjadi.
Jadi itu menciptakan begitu banyak masalah dalam kehidupan pernikahan itu sendiri.
Sekarang kita melihat kombinasi cara kerjanya.
Jika Anda adalah pervert seksual sisi kiri
Anda masuk ke semua jenis omong kosong.
Pertama-tama Anda kembangkan
hubungan lucu yang tidak bisa saya pahami.
Segala macam hubungan lucu.
Saya diberitahu kemarin ada beberapa
homoseksual yang memiliki beberapa untuk melawan Aku
tapi aku tidak pernah menyebutkan apapun tentang seks jadi dia lari.
Tapi itu adalah kebiasaan seks yang tidak menyenangkan.
Ini tidak menyenangkan.
Selain itu tidak wajar.
Ini memberi masalah bagi mereka berdua
dan mereka sedang dalam masalah
untuk penyakit yang sangat serius dalam waktu sepuluh tahun, semua dari mereka akan menderita
baik dari kanker atau dari mellitus. Ambillah dari Aku.
Dalam waktu sepuluh tahun.
Biarkan mereka bertarung, pergi ke pengadilan, dapatkan hak mereka untuk menjadi [SAMA atau SIN ?. -aku pikir sama].
Saya tidak memiliki apapun untuk dikatakan.
Mereka semua akan terlalu menderita.
Ini seperti Anda pergi ke pemerintah dan meminta yang benar
untuk mendapatkan penyakit atau kegilaan.
Mereka akan menjadi gila
karena jika pusat ini keluar, kamu menjadi gila.
Anda menjadi orang gila.
Tidak heran itu
Anda menemukan lebih banyak orang gila di barat daripada di India.
Kita mungkin orang miskin. Setidaknya kita memiliki kebijaksanaan.
Kami secara tradisional tahu bahwa inilah yang terjadi.
Saya tidak bisa mengerti bagaimana orang-orang mengambil hal-hal ini dengan mudah
dan memintanya dan pergi ke masalah.
Jadi semua penyakit ini seperti kanker bahkan mellitus,
kanker di wilayah bawah.
Semua ini dapat disebabkan oleh orang-orang sesat ini.
Terlepas dari penyimpangan ini
terlalu banyak indulgensi ke semua jenis wanita
dan segala macam prostitusi dan ketidaksopanan adalah dekadensi.
Merupakan dekadensi menyeluruh dari masyarakat.
Bagaimana kita berharap memiliki anak yang baik?
Bagaimana Anda berharap memiliki hubungan yang baik dengan istri Anda?
Di keluarga Anda, Anda tidak memiliki sarang di sana.
Anda akan hidup dengan [WILD WIND?].
Seperti [ANGIN ANGIN] sendiri.
Bayangkan di India ketika mereka mengatakan itu,
"Baiklah. Jika Anda memiliki orang asing yang datang ke rumah Anda
hati-hati. Dia mungkin lari dengan barang-barang Anda. "
Baiklah tidak masalah.
Tetapi sekarang di Inggris, orang India berkata, "Jangan izinkan apapun
Orang barat datang dan tinggal di rumah Anda.
Dia akan lari dengan istrimu. "
Maksud saya mereka benar-benar menghilangkan akar keluarga.
Anda masuk dalam masyarakat. saya menemukan
semua wanita dan pria sangat kesal
atau agresif karena merasa tidak aman.
Sangat tidak aman satu sama lain.
Mereka tidak tahu apa yang para wanita ini rencanakan.
Wanita itu tidak tahu apa yang diinginkan pria itu.
Mereka sangat tidak aman.
Jika Anda bepergian ke luar negeri, Anda bertemu seseorang
dia mengatakan hal-hal seperti, "Tentu saja suamiku tidak akan seperti itu
seorang pria yang sangat baik, mengapa saya harus menjadi wanita yang baik?
Kenapa aku harus menjadi wanita yang baik?
Jika itu suamiku tidak akan melakukan itu
lalu mengapa saya harus mencoba menjadi orang baik? "
Dan kompetisi itu ada di dalamnya.
Segala macam hal lucu terjadi atas nama kesenangan.
Ini adalah perusahaan yang paling tidak menyenangkan yang Anda ikuti.
Seorang pria pulang ke rumah.
Saya melihat ini di Inggris pertama kali dan saya terkejut.
Kami tinggal di daerah yang benar-benar sangat elit
tuan dan wanita tinggal di sana.
Dan kami punya tetangga
katakan empat puluh delapan tahun atau sesuatu.
Dan putranya yang tinggal di asrama membawa teman lain
yang jauh lebih muda darinya.
Dan wanita ini kawin lari dengannya.
Bodoh Aku bilang itu kebodohan wanita tua ini.
Mereka menjual rumah karena dia punya hak.
Bahkan hukum Anda harus mengerti apa yang mereka lakukan.
Dia menjual rumah. Mereka memiliki tiga anak perempuan.
Tiga anak perempuan ada di jalanan seperti pelacur sekarang.
Ayah tidak punya kendali.
Dia disebut menikah dengan wanita lain.
Itu tidak masuk akal.
Ini bukan cara masyarakat akan berhasil.
Pasti ada yang salah dengan kita
karena kita tidak mengerti kesucian itu
adalah hal terhebat yang dimiliki manusia.
Kekuatan yang dimiliki seseorang adalah kesuciannya
dan seorang wanita.
Orang-orang bertanya kepada saya tentang Mahatma Gandhi.
Maksud saya dia adalah pria yang sangat suci, istrinya begitu suci.
Maksud saya, kami punya banyak orang seperti India itu
kecuali orang kota berbeda.
Tetapi di desa-desa mereka tidak berpikir
dari hal-hal ini, dan mereka hidup dengan sangat normal.
Sementara itu semacam a
rasa rendah diri dimasukkan ke semua orang.
tanda rasa rendah diri saja
bahwa Anda ingin menarik setiap pria dan wanita di jalan.
Jika kamu benar-benar baik
mengapa Anda khawatir tentang menarik semua orang yang Anda lihat?
Dan iklan.
Hal lain adalah, orang-orang berpikir demikian
ketika seorang wanita tampan Anda harus memilikinya.
Ini tidak masuk akal lagi.
Bagaimana kabarmu? Silakan lihat di cermin.
Mengapa setiap pria menginginkan wanita cantik
dan mengapa setiap wanita cantik menginginkan pria yang cantik?
Saya tidak bisa mengerti.
Tetapi hanya dua, tiga orang dapat menikah di dunia ini.
Karena yang lain hanya melihat mereka terperangah.
Tetapi apa yang Anda miliki mengapa tidak Anda nikmati?
Suatu hal yang sederhana seperti itu.
Anda punya istri. Anda punya suami.
Mengapa tidak menikmatinya?
Ingin menikmati istri orang lain?
Jangan mengingini istri tetanggamu.
Perilaku ini harus diubah
Tetapi Anda tidak dapat mengubahnya dalam semalam. Aku mengerti itu.
Satu-satunya cara adalah Anda harus naik.
Ketika Anda menjadi Roh ada kelahiran kedua
semuanya terhapus.
Saya telah melihat banyak homoseksual - mereka bisa menjadi bijaksana.
Banyak pelacur telah menjadi wanita yang sangat bijaksana.
Tapi itulah yang terjadi pada Mary Magdalena
ketika dia datang kepada Kristus.
Inilah yang harus dilakukan oleh kemurnian adalah memurnikan Anda
dan memberi Anda sukacita hidup yang maksimal.
Dari kehidupan pernikahan Anda tidak memiliki sukacita.
Anda selalu bertarung untuk sesuatu,
pada hal-hal materi, ini dan itu dan itu.
Tetapi jika pemahaman bawaan antara keduanya dibuat.
Hanya orang yang mengambil obat-obatan itu
mungkin tidak berkelahi karena mereka telah menjadi kubis sekarang.
Jika Anda tidak memiliki kekuatan untuk bertarung dan jika Anda tidak berkelahi,
apa yang begitu hebat?
Untuk memperkuat masyarakat Anda dengan sumber sukacita yang nyata
Anda harus mendirikan pusat ini
yang bisa dilakukan orang Australia lebih cepat daripada siapa pun
karena sekarang saya punya murid dari dua belas negara
dan yang terbaik di antara mereka dalam hal ini adalah orang Australia.
Semalam mereka berubah orang. Semalam. Orang-orang yang luar biasa.
Tetapi bagi pikiran barat itu bukanlah hal yang serius
karena mereka tidak dapat menemukannya.
Mereka tidak dapat menghubungkannya dengan penyakit yang menyebabkannya.
Itu adalah kebenaran yang begitu terbuka
orang yang menikmati kebiasaan buruk ini berkembang
penyakit yang sangat buruk
even some of the leprosies among the kind of leprosies
are developed by that.
But the modern diseases are even worse.
I met a gentleman who has mellitus.
And his wife was a mad woman.
But he liked her despite her madness and all that.
He should have put her in a lunatic asylum.
And he developed this from the Left Mooladhara.
Now to cure these people is very easy.
You have to just raise the kundalini
and the kundalini can enlighten that center
and your innocence can come back.
Your chastity will show its result.
Your face will change.
People I have seen after realization become twenty years younger
immediately
because of this center
which is bestowed upon by the deity of Shri Ganesha
who is the embodiment of eternal childhood.
And this Shri Ganesha later on takes His birth
at the higher chakra called Agnya
as our Lord Jesus Christ.
That I'll tell you tomorrow about Jesus Christ who He was,
how He came on this Earth
and what are the reference to Him
in the ancient scriptures of India.
So the center of Mooladhara - the lesser the better.
I think it is for you to understand
that chastity plays a very important part.
If the person has got this problem
then the kundalini does rise no doubt.
It rises but is again sucked back.
Even the people who are too much on the right hand side
always think too much and work very hard
and earning money for their wives find their wives run away.
Because they are very hard people to live with.
They are very hot tempered, irritable, and aggressive.
So here the man earns everything for the wife
and there he finds the wife has run away by the time he comes home.
So this chakra is the basis of our lives.
Chastity is the basis of our life.
You must have heard that women in India - thousands of them
put up a pyre and burnt themselves off
called as [JEOPARD?]
because they thought that the Muslim invaders will come
and molest their chastity.
Because traditionally they have realized that chastity
is the power of a woman.
Same of the man.
Of course men don't believe in chastity at all.
You see, they think they are not men if they are chaste.
such a man who has no chastity is not at all a man.
Not at all a man. He's something in between.
Anyone who has chastity
chastity can see from the way he talks with his confidence with his
complete understanding of the whole thing.
Such person surpasses everybody else.
And even after the death of such a licentious man
he may be the biggest man, people talk about him.
You cannot adore a man of that kind.
"Oh it's all right he was great
but he had this nonsense business with him.
He was going about with such and such actress."
You don't respect such a man because I have not seen anyone
putting up statues of people who were great because of
their unchaste behavior. I haven't seen anyone.
Or because he was a great homosexual you put up a
big statue of him. A great homosexual.
I mean you may do it later on.
I don't know to what extent one can go
with this madness what wrong
I have not seen anyone putting up a perverted man.
All right put a statue of him and garland him.
I've not seen even the silliest of silly respecting such a people.
There's a clan in India called as
[ZARCOMES?]. They are of a right type.
They too worship a goddess who is a very strict goddess.
They too want to ask her for blessing that they should not
be like this in next life whatever they have done in previous life.
That's why they have become like this.
Now next life at least should be good.
So they try to worship a goddess which is a very strict goddess.
They give all punishments to us but don't give us this life.
So this is the basis that we have
and we have to ascend to the spirit.
Now the another chakra we have is the Swadhisthana Chakra.
As you can see that it is connected to the right side.
But it moves to the right and left.
It is like a lotus with a stem
which moves in that area that is shown the green part
which is [UNCLEAR].
And here the attention resides.
Human attention resides here.
This center comes out of the third center which you see there
as the green one
called as the center of your seeking.
The first one I told you is the center of innocence.
The second one of creativity.
And the third one of seeking.
This is the most important center
within us because of seeking we have become human beings.
First we were seeking
only food, then a shelter, then a society.
Then of course money, possessions, politics, power.
Ultimately you become subtler and subtler because
is trial and error method.
You try this. Get fed up.
Next life you come you become something else.
That life you try something. You become something else.
That's how the human beings work it out
ultimately come to a point that there is no sense in all these
pursuits. Lupakan.
There must be something beyond
and that's the real place where you have to arrive.
That it is the Spirit we are seeking.
In all these things there was nothing but a just a mirage
of joy.
There is no joy in all these things
so we should give up this mirage and take to reality.
That is the Spirit within us.
In this seeking we have two types of people again
the left sided and the right sided.
The left sided people think that
if they have their own family - mostly Indians are like that.
They believe in the family system to such an extent
that they can sell their country sometimes
for their own children's sake, for their sons.
Thus, they have no sense of collectivity in them.
When it comes to such a
close [UNCLEAR] feeling for your own family
that if your son - even if he's a murderer
still he's your own son.
So in relation to the whole you must think of your family.
The left sided people can be also extremely emotional type.
So all their creativity goes to the emotional side
like they become poets
sing the song of [LAMENTATION?],
anguish, sufferings, all kinds of sufferings they have.
This is not a very kind thing to do
to make others cry you see.
There are some poets who make you so much cry
that they'll take out your eyes and wash it and put it back.
To that extent they are horribly sadistic
like Lord Byron, horrible fellow.
He wrote this so many things.
He himself led a most licentious and a horrid life.
He was an aggressive man.
He did all that to aggress others, torture others.
And here he's writing the poetry of how man suffers.
Just imagine
what a dishonest and a cheat he was to talk like this.
He was such an arrogant man
that he went to Portugal.
There's a beautiful place called Sintra there.
Beautiful place.
So he says that
Sintra is too beautiful to be wasted on Portuguese.
As if he is the most beautiful man ever,
meaning that all this beauty should flow to this horrible person.
This creates an imaginary you see
an [UNCLEAR] to suffer.
I've met many like that.
They are poetically suffering. See.
They enjoy all the songs of suffering
and then they become themselves tragic.
Such people cannot give joy to anyone.
I mean people run away
from such people. They think he is a person who is a mourner.
In India you see we pay these mourners.
If somebody dies and has no mourners they can be paid.
And they are brought for crying and weeping
and saying all these things you see
there are people paid for it in India. Imagine.
I mean we use them for this purpose.
Artificially they can mourn somebody's death
and earn some money out of it.
But such kind of miserable people
are such a
blot on the name of God
who has given you so much.
Count your blessings.
Count your blessings one by one.
First of all that
you are not under the control of the nature, the parsha.
You are a free human being.
So many things He has given you
and still you are weeping and crying
and saying that we have to suffer.
who believe in suffering will get it.
You want suffering? Then have it.
They get it.
And these people can really go so much with it
about the suffering part
that recently I met one group in Spain.
And I said, "What are you doing about your seeking?"
They said, "We are going to Gobi Desert."
I said, "For what?"
"There's the Shambhala is there."
I said, "What is that Shambhala?"
"It's the God's heaven in Gobi Desert. And there's a gentleman
who is going to take us to the Gobi Desert
and we are going to walk in the center of Gobi Desert."
I said, "Very nice."
"And we are paying so much money for that."
Now in that Gobi desert
you can't get even a drop of water.
You pay lot of money
to go to that Gobi Desert,
walk across, and die there.
And this man gets all the money you know befooling [HERE?].
"But then we must suffer."
Untuk apa?
Why you want to suffer?
Christ has suffered for you enough.
If Christ is awakened within you
He will take up everything upon Himself.
He'll really wash all your sins
and you can get your realization.
That's how it works so quick.
If you know how to enlightened Him within yourself
then it works out.
Still the Christians are even continuing with ideas
leave alone the Jews.
Christians are just the same.
And they enjoy you see this kind of suffering upon themselves.
Is all imaginary.
Like we went to France in Paris.
"We are all miserable people le miserable."
And they told Me,
"Don't tell them Mother that you are happy, you know.
They'll not like it.
You better tell that you are the most miserable."
Le miserable.
All miserables sitting there.
I said, "What miserable they are."
Every third lamppost you'll find a pub
and every seventh lamppost you'll find a prostitute.
This is the miserable thing they have.
Do miserable people do all these things?
Just sitting outside for the last doomsday,
the calamity. They'll have it
if they want to have it.
But God has not created you to be miserable at all.
No, not at all.
He has created you to be very happy and joyous
to enjoy the beauties of His bounties.
We are really letting Him down
and it's really such a miserable thing. Supposing now
you want to invite somebody to your house.
Your own son is coming. You are so excited about him.
You are so anxious that your son after such a long time
such a long journey
is coming as a glorious man to your house
and then he's weeping saying, "I'm miserable."
So those people who indulge into the left side of the Swadhisthana
so much
suffer
because they enter into an area called
collective subconscious
and this is the area which the other day doctors pointed out.
they were studied the cancer disease they said
a vulnerable person who is vulnerable to cancer
the one who's an extreme temperament person.
A person who is extremely hard working can be vulnerable also.
But is triggered, is triggered by
a protein which they call as protein 58
or protein 52
which enters into the being,
which triggers it, and this protein one
is coming from the area called as
according to them we call it
collective conscious. Collective subconscious.
But they call it the area built in within us since the creation.
I mean they say something else. We make it clearer that's all.
And cancer is caused by that.
Invariably I have seen those people who have come to Me from cancer
have been the people who got it from left side.
You wanted to suffer? All right have cancer. Enjoy it.
But there was a journalist who came to see Me in America
and I told him that you should not suffer.
So he folded everything. He said, "I'm going back".
He said, "It is my right to suffer."
Imagine. I said, "Now what to say to this man?"
I said, "All right then go ahead with it.
When you are fed up with it you come to Me.
But just now you have a right to suffer. Do what you like."
If somebody wants to hit himself
with a bamboo or something
and you say, "Why do you want to hit yourself?"
Say, "It's a right, my right to hit myself."
I said, "All right hit." But you have no right
because you cannot create yourself.
You have no right to torture yourself.
You have no right to make yourself miserable.
You have to make yourself happy people,
joyous people,
blissful people so that God feels
you have received blessings.
That He may be placed
through His own creation that is the epitome, the human beings.
That's the best way you should please God by saying,
"Father we are very happy people.
Don't worry about us. We are so thankful to You."
So that's how the joy killers come to us from the left side.
The right side is the people who kill others' joy.
Spoil sports as you call them in a very mild way.
They are the ones who are aggressive.
They cannot see anybody being peaceful.
Even countries can be like that.
Collectively they can do like this.
If they see any country is peaceful, they'll attack.
"Why is he peaceful?
We must attack and capture that country."
The people who cannot bear the joy of other people
become aggressive and try to aggress them.
There are people who just get sometimes jealous.
Sometimes just for aggression they become aggressive.
I have no reason sometimes
the way people suddenly shoot up like Jack in the Box
and start talking in such an aggressive manner
you don't understand why should we aggress.
is no need to aggress at all.
But they go on aggressing people.
Then they may form
a thing like as a German state
that we are a superior race, a sense of superiority.
All your racialism comes from this nonsense of a aggression.
I mean I can't understand Western people.
For example they're so particular about their race being preserved
because they think they are white skin.
But they go to the sea, make it black. Mengapa?
I mean either you are white skin or you have black. One of the two.
So they are so confused.
They think they are not beautiful
because they are white skin, light skin.
So if you are not so beautiful
then why do you think you are above the world?
Racialism is something so much
a mental projection, absolutely a mental projection
and with this mental projection we gather so much of
curses of [THE OTHER WORLD?].
I'll give you an example. We went to China.
And Chinese are so much against British I was surprised.
So much against. The worst are British according to them.
They had seven aggressors.
I said, "Why?"
Because they gave them dopes you see.
And if you ask the British of that time they will say that,
"Because they deserved it.
We gave them. See, what's wrong?"
But when I told them that
Britishers are taking drugs and all that. "Nice for them.
Let them all take it.
That's what they deserve.
They're drunkards. Let them have the drugs."
Nobody will have the sympathy with people who are aggressors.
If you think you are a great [RACE?], go ahead with it.
And the more [RACE?] is going toward the doom.
You must know you must learn from others also.
People have learned from you politics, economics.
I don't know what you've made out of it.
If you think you have done very good, well,
Saya tidak memiliki apapun untuk dikatakan.
Also other things they have learned from you.
English language I have learned.
And why do you call everybody a lower
developed thing? You are a developed country.
What have you developed?
Atom bombs to kill yourself?
All kinds of aggressiveness.
You go to other country with a Bible in the hand and another
a pistol in the your hand or a rifle in your hand to kill others.
This aggression comes from mental projection that we have
that we are great you see puffed up.
The best for that is Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall.
That's the one it is.
Is that the Humpty Dumpty's.
I tell you all [RIGHTS? HEIGHTS?].
All [RIGHTS? HEIGHTS?] are so sensible.
And they said the Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall
and Humpty Dumpty had a big fall.
And all the king's horses and men could not put them together again.
That's what it is a Humpty Dumpty a big ego like a balloon.
They'll float like as if something
you see like angels in the world
while when they'll reach
the kingdom of God, God will say, "What business you had to hate
any part of this creation.
Who are you I don't know."
Because in collectivity you are so poor in this respect.
So we have to understand
that God has created all of us.
We have to have variety.
It looks nice
that you wear another dress. I wear another dress.
I have another face. You have another face.
Unless and until there are variety in the nature
it doesn't look nice. You'll be bored stiff.
I mean people get bored stiff I tell you
when I've seen these people when they come to India
they want to go to villages
because in the city they said there are many white skin people.
You want to see something else than this.
This variety is an important of the beauty that God has created
out of which if you think the white skin is higher.
Tomorrow the black skin people will say the black skin is higher.
Possibly.
But the another thing is working out is this
very subtle which you do not understand.
The people whom you have aggressed are
crawling into your young people.
They are the one who are aggressing you now
as gurus
draining out your money in a very subtle way.
They are dominating all your young generation
which is tomorrow's nation.
They are giving them drugs and things and they are just making them
into cabbages
a very subtle way
because they are left sided people they know how to do it.
The aggression is not apparent. The aggression is at least better
better that you can see it apparently
but this is a very subtle aggression that is crawling in.
And it's going into your minds working here,
and you are losing contact with yourself.
Every action has a reaction but this reaction is very wrong for me
because I have come at a time when thousands of my
children, the seekers of God have been born.
This is the time when they have to got their realization
and at this time these people are so powerful because
of your fear now.
The person who aggresses also has a fear.
The children might develop a fear that we should not aggress.
And they become so mild that they take aggression from others.
And that's what is happening to your children
when your grandparents aggressed others.
They now want to take all the aggression from the other.
That is also a wrong thing.
So this is what is happening to our society today.
I would say to sum it
we'll say that the people in the West
are committing a sin against the Mother
and in the East in India against the Father.
And how they commit that I'll tell you in the third center.
The third center is of the seeking.
The third center that belongs to the seeking
a very important one
because it gives you seeking in all kinds of things.
Money
kekuasaan
love
and ultimately God.
Now when you are going against
the current of a [UNCLEAR]
sideways if you are moving
then the problems are created.
That people who are seeking power outside
must know that the power lies within yourself.
As I told someone the other day
that I am the greatest capitalist and the greatest communist
because I have all the powers within Myself
and I cannot live without sharing it with others.
I am a very happily married woman.
I have a very nice family.
Everything I have in life
that one could think to be a very successfully married woman.
That's what I am.
But I can't
enjoy anything without sharing this inner joy with you all.
This is the real politics of God.
Not an artificial politics where we believe
in communism, but in heart we are capitalist.
And while we believe in capitalism, in heart we are communist.
We are suffering because of that.
There's no integration.
All this what you see artificially
is all real there because whatever is artificial
comes from some real source.
If there is one artificial flower means there are
real flowers and
you can create many artificial flowers
but it has to have some background.
All these ideas that human beings have about economics also
is very artificial to possess things
to possess many things.
To possess human beings also is there, possessiveness.
But you must know possession is the greatest headache.
Logically you can understand.
I don't possess this instrument, thank God.
So I'm not worried about it. I'm using it nicely
because it is higher or whatever it is.
It's not mine. I am not to be [UNCLEAR].
Otherwise I'll have to insure it.
I'll have to look after it. Big headache.
It's better to see other people,
other people's palaces than to have for yourself.
It's a headache you see.
The owner of the palace if you go and see
has all the wrinkles which you can count one by one.
A very sad man sitting there miserable
and they point it out he's the owner of this palace
while others who are seeing it are enjoying it
and the fellow is sitting miserable
because he has problems of duty
he has problem of income tax,
he has problem of how to maintain it.
But you don't possess anything. It's a myth.
It's a myth.
We don't take anything with us.
Only we take our realization.
But it's not a mental thing, that I can tell you.
You cannot detach yourself for any one of these things
unless and until you get your realization
because attachment is there
as a result of ignorance.
Unless and until there is light
you cannot give up.
Mentally you cannot do it.
But the possessiveness on India is that
they think they should somehow hook or crook make money.
Not all, but many.
At least the people at the helm of affairs feel like that.
That means they have no faith in God.
Shri Krishna has said, "Yogakshemam vahamyaham."
When you will get your yoga
when you'll get your union
I'll look after your kshema, means your wellbeing.
Shri Krishna was in India
and this is what India believe in.
When God is going to look after us when we get yoga,
why not get to yoga straightforward?
I could understand that we had to fight for our freedom.
Tidak apa-apa.
But after that fight
now what do you have to have is yoga.
First take to your yoga and He looks after you
because this is the principle of wealth also
of your wellbeing.
Those who come to Sahaja Yoga
somehow get their debts paid.
They get out of all the financial entanglements.
They get sufficient money to live well
but not too much because that's an extreme.
They live gloriously.
They become generous people.
Despite affluence I find people have no sense of generosity.
They are saving money.
Morning till evening saving so many pounds.
Spend so much save so much.
The advertisement goes like that.
We spend so much and you save so much,
and people are looking out for us how they can save money.
Save for what?
Untuk apa?
To go to a pub?
We have strikes, things like that.
Australia is another one very much interested
by this strikes business.
We are suffering because of that.
I can see that clearly.
That's happening in England also same thing.
The reason is
you do not know why you want to save money
why do you want to have more money.
Is this bottomless pit
which you have to fill with alcohol.
Alcohol is the curse of the West.
That is the curse of the West.
But human nature is so funny
that they see a man falling down on the ground
and enter into the same pub
to come back and fall on the other side.
Perhaps they think the other side is missing so let's fill it up.
It's so stupid to see.
I mean I was living in a place near the church.
to be the biggest church of England
in Catholic Church
and the only activity I saw there in the morning was
itu
beer. Big, big barrels of beer coming in
and empty ones going out. Itu saja.
No other entry no other exit.
Only that much.
From the back side from the sideways
I saw this was the only thing going on
and these priests are supposed to be godly people.
It is so absurd you can't imagine.
In Russia I went and they took me
to a church. You see they had a Church of Orthodox.
You too have here. I've seen Orthodox Church.
And the fellow of the head of the church
us that today that this is our fasting day so we can't eat meat
but he drank so much
that he become a drunk, you see.
And we didn't know where to look.
He got drunk completely.
He was supposed to see us out because we are VIP's
and there were three officers and then they started laughing.
They said, "This is what Christianity is."
I said "Why, why this?"
He said, "You know what happend
that Russians thought that they must also have a religion,
after all everybody has a religion."
They sent for someone.
So the Muslims came in and they said,
In Islam you can marry four times
but you cannot have alcohol."
They said, "This won't work out for such Russians.
This is all right go out."
So then they said, "Let's call Catholics."
So they called Catholics
and the Catholics said that, "You can
have alcohol quite all right as much as you like."
I don't know why they got this idea that they can have alcohol.
[aside]
"You must take a vow
that you will not marry another woman,
and that there is no divorce." They said, "This won't work out."
But Orthodox Church was like our gurus.
Said, "Do what you like.
We are not bothered as long as you give your purse to us."
And that's how Orthodox Church came. Can you believe it?
This is the plight of the churches, of the temples now.
I asked a little boy who
was taking drugs, a Western boy.
I said, "From where do you get?"
He said, "From the temples of India."
Can you imagine the temples.
While you people think that all that is Indian is great, you see.
Temples are great.
Even lamas are another institution by themselves.
You think lamas are great people. We had a big
argument on that.
These lamas extracted blood out of that Tibet.
You won't believe.
If you see a Tibetan he's just
any blood, without any flesh in him.
And these people lived in big [GLASS?] place
you see with the golden cups
with golden plates.
And one of them came to Sweden and he told these people that,
"If I come I must have a marble floor."
What was he going to do with a marble floor? God only knows.
Poor things. They starved themselves.
These young people don't have so much money in the West.
And made a marble floor for this great man to come in.
He would sit seven feet high
and what did he do there
is to go just to bow 1001 times on that
cold marble while they're sitting nicely on a very cozy place.
And they got all kinds of diseases as with that.
This is what it is. This is so called [UNCLEAR].
Now one has to understand
that religion is for your balance.
Balance is for your ascent.
And the ascent is the one you have to achieve.
And if you cannot achieve your ascent
through any method then you give it up completely
because it would be something like
not arriving at a point
nor completing what you are.
You are not complete unless and until you become the Spirit.
And this is the biggest problem today is to bring to people
this simple fact. Sangat sederhana
that Spirit is within you and can be enlightened
spontaneously
without any effort
without reading about it because it's so [WHITE OR WIDE?].
Just like your own heart beating.
You cannot believe in a person who can be genuinely [BENEFACTOR?].
Even some of them said, "Must be suspicious.
She doesn't take any money." They can't believe it.
How can I charge for my love?
What can you pay?
Can you value it in money?
Can you imagine it in anything that exists?
This joy is boundless.
Is your own.
Is just waiting
to open its door. The flood
of that joy is going to come into your life.
But once you have got realization as Dr. Warren has said,
"Be careful that you establish yourself."
Individually every person can give realization
to thousands. There's one Indian who's just a farmer
has given realization to at least to ten thousand people
whom I never met before.
Of course he can't give en masse
but still from one to another to another to another like that
he has given ten thousand people,
and he's a miraculous man.
It is very easy to mock at these things and to make fun of this.
It's a sign of superficiality.
Kamu hebat.
You are fantastic.
I'm requesting you as a mother
that just recognize yourself.
Have your self esteem
and don't worry as to what I've said.
Whatever you have done is all forgiven once for all.
At this moment you have to be absolutely
beautifully placed as the most innocent people ever [UNCLEAR].
No guilt of any kind.
No guilt at all.
Yesterday some people came there. Later I suffered here.
I got the pain here.
I suffered so much with this idea of guilt.
Is all your own mental projection.
So without any guilt you are going to get your realization today.
I hope it works out with all of you.
If it does not - tomorrow, day after.
I'm going to tell you about the other chakras
tomorrow and then about realization, about the Spirit.
Then we want to have a
as they call it which is a very funny word I find
workshop as if you are all machines and I have
to do some hammer to make your heads.
But I've seen it's a blossom time
and some gardening we are going to do.
And we are going to invite you to some place on Sunday.
Come and have lunch with us
and we'll have very relaxed time
and we'll enjoy this [FEELING or BEING?] within us.
May God bless you.
Unnecessary waste of time.
We'll just
have the realization.
Now a very simple thing has to be done.
Just take out your shoes
because the Mother Earth is going to help us. Just take out.
Also take out your spectacles because your eyesight might be helped.
As I said before not feel guilty at all.
Not at all guilty.
First of all before closing your eyes you have to tell yourself,
"I am not at all guilty."
Thrice you must tell yourself assertively that,
"Mother I am not at all guilty
of anything."
Because I am talking of God
who is so anxious to give you this.
Who is the ocean of love.
Who is the ocean of forgiveness.
You should sit with relaxed mind.
Put your hands towards Me just like this.
Simple way like this just put on your lap.
Seperti itu.
You can keep it on the ground. [UNCLEAR].
You can keep it here, down below. Iya nih.
Be comfortable.
Be comfortable if you have a
very strong on your neck you can little bit reduce it
if it is tightening or in any way hot for you.
Anything
whichever thing which way you are comfortable is the best way.
Kamu.
Now with a cheerful mind you have to [LISTEN TO ME
Not to be angry with yourself.
In no way be angry with yourself.
So put both the hands
on your lap and close your eyes.
Just close your eyes.
So as a result of the kundalini awakening
what happens
that first of all that you start
feeling the cool breeze coming out of your head. Is
Is the real baptism.
That's the first thing that should happen
that the cool breeze starts coming out of your head.
Please don't open your eyes.
Please just don't open your eyes
because if you open your eyes
kundalini won't rise above Agnya Chakra.
So just keep your eyes shut.
It will help a lot.
Not to bend your neck too much
to put back, but be straight.
Be straight and parallel. Be comfortable.
Put both the hands straight on the Mother Earth
away from each other. Not touching each other.
Now the first center that I told you about
is the center of your chastity of your wisdom.
So you have to say, "Mother please
awaken the innocence within me."
Just to say that because this is your right.
cannot force you.
You have to ask. This is your freedom.
If you do not want it I cannot do it.
You have to ask that, "Please awaken my innocence within me
and my desire to be one
with the Divine should be intense."
"Please awaken my kundalini,
this desire within me,
and make me that all the technique of Divine love."
That is called as shuddha vidya is the pure knowledge
of the technique.
You have to ask. That's the problem is
because human beings have been given something
which cannot be taken away.
Not to feel guilty at all
is again I said every time
don't feel guilty.
Don't say how can I do it. What will -
It's all within you. It's just waiting.
The whole instrument is there.
Just I have to connect it. You just help me.
By not feeling guilty at all
because your guilt has no meaning at all
to the ocean of love
it's not even a speck. It can be washed off in no time
so you just don't stick onto your guilt.
Now left hand is your power of desire
and right hand is your power of action.
So keep the left hand as it is towards Me
so the desire is steadied there
and use the right hand first of all on your heart.
Put your right hand on the heart.
In the heart resides
the Spirit, the reflection of God Almighty.
So you have to say, "Mother make me the Spirit."
Now you have to become the master.
Master of all these trigunas,
the three powers I've told you.
Like you have got in a car
the break and accelerator.
You have these three powers within you
by which
you first of all you make mistakes these two powers
and then you become the third power
which is the automatic driving power.
You learn it.
Just becomes part and parcel of you. Don't think about it.
And then the master is sitting behind the car.
You become that.
When you become the master you start seeing the driver in you
you and all these powers within you
and handle them
just like a master handles his own vehicle
you handle it and you just don't get into tantrums and
you do all kinds of things which are not
within your reach within your control.
That's how you become the master.
So to become the master you put your right hand
your stomach on the left hand side.
Right hand
on the left hand side of your stomach.
Right hand on the left hand side of your stomach.
Right hand on the left hand side of your stomach
left hand towards Me.
Now you have to say, "Mother make me my own master."
Say it thrice.
Kemudian
now you have to say, "Mother I am my own master."
Put your left hand towards Me please.
Left hand should be towards Me, yes.
Open, open. Not closed hand.
Now say, "Mother make me my own master."
You have to be your own master.
You are not to be guided by any master or anyone.
It's your Spirit which is going to guide you.
Just say ten times, "I am my own master."
Now raise the same hand
higher to the Spirit to your heart
and now say 10 times, "Mother I am the Spirit."
Ten times.
Just right hand. Don't move left hand. Only move right hand.
Left hand you keep all the time stretched.
hand you move to the heart and say ten times,
"Mother I am the Spirit."
Sekarang.
Put the right hand on the left hand side of your neck.
Left hand side of your neck on the Vishuddhi Chakra.
The Left Vishuddhi.
We are working on the left throughout.
So you say, "Mother
I am not guilty."
sixteen times as a punishment.
Just say, "Mother I am not guilty."
Sixteen times.
This will cure lots of your problems
of guilt, of diffidence.
You cannot be guilty because you are the Spirit.
The Spirit cannot be guilty.
Now put your right hand again.
Left hand being there where it is. On your forehead across.
On your forehead across
at the center of our Lord Jesus Christ
and say, "Mother I forgive everyone."
With your full heart you should say, "Mother I forgive everyone."
Because if you don't forgive you are working under a myth
because you are not troubling the person.
The person is troubling you.
Just say, "Mother I forgive everyone."
Some people say it is difficult. It is the easiest thing.
Just your mental projection it is.
Now put this right hand on top of your head.
You'll find it's little hot.
The heat is coming out of your body.
Just put it on top of your head. Kepala.
The heat is coming out. Press it.
The palm of the hand should be pressed in the center.
find there is a heat. Press it.
At this point you have to have to ask for your realization again
because I cannot force it on you.
So you have to say, "Mother I want my realization.
Please give me my realization.
I'm a seeker of truth.
Please give me my realization, Mother."
Now raise your hand and see if there is a cool breeze coming out.
You can change your hand. Put your right hand towards Me
and put the left hand and see if there's a cool breeze coming out.
Right hand towards Me not closed but open, open hand.
[FIRST TIME?]
which is doing all the living work,
everything around us.
Now put down your hands please
and see if you are feeling now in your hands.
Just see if you are feeling in your hands also.
feel very relaxed.
[COULD BRING?] peace, bliss of God
and kingdom of God on this Earth.
Please raise the hands who have felt the cool breeze in their hands
All of you have felt it.
Itu keren.
Very great.
So many of you have felt.
May God bless you.
You need not think about it.
Only thing I will tell you how to fix your kundalini better
because you see it's like fixing
it into a plug properly otherwise it can be loose a little bit.
So Warren will tell you how to do it. Just tell.
WARREN: Just put your left hand near the kundalini at this point.
SHRI MATAJI: Put the left hand
towards your kundalini, little in front.
WARREN: And the right hand in front
and you come around in that fashion.
SHRI MATAJI: First higher, forward, lower, backwards.
Like that.
You have to move. This is the left hand which moves steady
and the right hand moves round and round like that clockwise.
Now you go on moving it.
WARREN: You raise it.
SHRI MATAJI: Raise it - your kundalini. Go up.
Take it up. Push back your hands.
them loose.
Push it up. [MAKE IT A BIT?]. Twist
on top of your head
and now give it a knot.
This is first time. This is for the first power.
For the second power again
put your hand in front of your kundalini but do it properly.
Higher, in front, lower and backwards again.
Start doing it. Raise it.
Go high
and push your back your hands
and just give it a big twist again.
Now for third power you have to do it thrice. Three knots.
Don't put down your hands but just do it three times.
Again let's do it.
are raising your own kundalini.
Go up again. Push back your hands. Give fast twist.
Keep your hands there. Give it a knot.
Again twist your hand
and give it a knot.
and now give it a big knot.
Now see for yourself if your hands are working better.
These are the hands that are going to speak
as told by Muhammad Sahab
that at the time of your resurrection your hands will speak.
Now you can see that in the hands he has shown the chakras,
the fingertips.
All these I will tell you.
Today's three chakras I'll tell you where they are.
Left side is left side. Right side is right side
and the center side is here.
And the three chakras we have.
The first chakras is this one on the left hand side.
This is right hand side first chakra.
And the second chakra we have are these.
One on the left hand side, right hand side.
And the third chakra are these.
Both the left hand side and right hand side.
Now what you feel
if there's something wrong with these chakras within yourself
you will feel a little burning
or maybe little numbness
maybe some heaviness.
What all these things indicate I'll tell you tomorrow.
And on other people also you can feel
but just now you don't try with other people
because it's like a sprouting of a seed which is very delicate.
You have to look after it.
Tomorrow and day after we'll work it out.
You establish yourself fully in Sahaja Yoga.
You have to become a guru, a complete guru of your own.
May God bless you.
WARREN: As Mother said there will be a workshop on Sunday.
We'll give the address tomorrow night, Friday night
SHRI MATAJI: You tell them just now.
WARREN: and you are all invited.
Mother will work it out.
Dan
the whole day free because we're happy to show you
all the aspects of Kundalini and the chakras.
Bring your lunch along.
It should be a good day.
Tomorrow evening Mother will speak about the Heart Chakra,
the center of security within us.
The Vishuddhi Chakra which is the center
in which we are able to witness the drama of life
and get our self esteem.
And the Agnya Chakra which is the center of Christ which relates to
the principle of the Spirit,
the quality of forgiveness.
And then finally the Sahasrara Chakra which is the center
which Mataji Herself has opened in this incarnation.
So the two successive lectures are going to deal with those centers.
Thank you very much and good evening.