So today in the city of Vancouver, we have
gathered here to pray for, the country of
Canada, and also for the Canadian people.
Also we have to know that, there are lots
of negative forces working, and there has
to be some puja to be done, to the Mahakali
Force.
And so I thought today: ‘Let’s have the
puja for Mahakali’.
So Mahakali Puja is the same as you do the
Devi’s Puja, but first the Mahakali Force
came on this Earth.
Adi Shakti came as Mahakali and created Shri
Ganesha.
Then She ascended as Mahasaraswati, and with
that Force She created the whole universe.
In that She created this world, in a very
beautiful manner, with great arrangements
and organizing and on that were born human
beings because the temperature and all that
was made very congenial for human beings.
So this climate has also played a big part
on the temperament of the people, on the seeking
of the people.
Like in India we can say, the climate is very
congenial for meditation.
It is been a traditional country from ancient
times, but from the very beginning we have
had seers who were seeking the Truth, in the
jungles.
The reason is this that, in India its climate
is so good that you can live in a jungle,
no problem.
So it was easy for them to get rid of all
the superficialities of life and to take seriously
– go to the jungles, dedicate themselves,
for finding out the Truth.
And thus they found out the Truth, that it
is the Kundalini which is the Force within
us which gives us Realization.
But this group, then scattered in different
places and they formed schools, were called,
or universities, called as gotras, and in
these schools were sent children from the
age of five years.
Till five years they lived with their parents
and then these children were sent there and
they were given all the education about day-to-day
life.
Their education system was very different.
By their education they made the children
very aware about everything, concentration,
and a complete celibacy because all the people
in a gotra could not marry.
Even today supposing I belong to one gotra,
I cannot marry a person in the same gotra.
So it is so much maintained even today.
Like in the university you cannot marry each
other.
So the children were kept like brothers and
sisters and they felt it all the time, brothers
and sisters feeling.
In the same way, you see, it has worked out
in many ways that the mooladhara chakra was
established very strongly in India, and that’s
why, though we had many other countries like
China, we had old China was there and also
Egypt, then we had Greece and also Rome.
All these countries did not pay much attention
to their mooladhara chakra and this mooladhara
was created by the Mahakali Power.
Mahakali created Shri Ganesha to emit holiness,
auspiciousness, wisdom, Divine wisdom; and
Her establishment of Shri Ganesha is also
within us on the mooladhara chakra.
But, if we do not pay attention to our mooladhara
chakra, then our powers become very weak and
we start catching from negativity much more.
Those who have good mooladharas do not catch,
so fast.
But we catch, we are harmed more by people
who are negative because they know that we
have bad mooladharas and they can affect us.
Now all the gurus and all those false gurus
came to western countries because they knew
they can affect much more here, than in India.
Like Rajneesh, nobody would accept such a
man.
Freud, nobody would accept such a person.
But here already Freud has done the necessary
harm to people and they were prepared to become,
vulnerable to these people, and on that background
these people came here and started acting
and they have been very successful.
All of them have been found out to be very
loose character and they are being exposed
and it’s nice that whatever is negative,
whatever is false gets exposed.
But still one has to remember that if we have
a strong mooladhara then Mahakali Power is
the strongest within us, because as I told
you, first She created Shri Ganesha, so all
Her Power are actually expressed in Aumkara
which is Shri Ganesh; and this Shri Ganesh
Power within us represents the complete love
of Mahakali and all Her Powers of destroying
the evil forces.
They go hand-in-hand we should say like, every
light has its glory around it, or glow around
it; in the same way the light of Mahakali
has the glow, as chaitanya, which is actually
nothing but Aumkara and Shri Ganesha.
Now Shri Ganesha has aspects, as I have told
them, that if you see the carbon from the
left, you see on the right side Aumkara, Aum,
written like that.
If you see from right to the left, you see
it as swastika.
If you see from down below upward, then you
see it as a cross.
And now they have verified it, they have experimented,
and the scientists have found out and have
now declared that it is so.
So that aspect of Aumkara which is within
us is the right side.
But the left side is the swastika.
And the swastika is a very, very sensitive
instrument that if you use it on the right
side then of course it is all right, it works
for construction; but if you use it for left
side, I mean in the anti-clock manner, then
it is destructive.
So swastika, when it is moving in its right
direction, clockwise in front and anti-clockwise
at the back, if it is moving in the right
direction, all negativity is thrown out on
the periphery, and absolutely they cannot
enter in.
But if it is moved on the left-hand side then
anybody can enter in.
So it is, even if you move a swastika, see
now, create a kind of a opening.
If you make a swastika and see, it opens out.
But if you move it this way, there’s no
opening.
It goes on closing, one on another.
So by moving it left side, it starts opening
itself to these negative forces.
This is exactly what has happened in the West,
that they had their mooladhara moving on the
left-hand side, the anti-clockwise.
They went against their own principle of morality,
absolutely against Christ, and managed to
get all these bhoots into themselves.
Now Sahaja Yoga has one problem, in the West,
that people don’t want to hear that you
should be moral.
They find it very difficult.
If you tell them you have to be moral they
think we are fundamentalist or something like
that.
But it’s a fundamental thing that we have
to be moral people.
Now they are seeing the results of it, that
they have got AIDS, they have got all these
diseases, all these troubles; from that they
are learning that our mooladhara should be
all right, otherwise all these problems can
come.
But still they don’t want to accept it,
that they have done mistakes.
So this is another ego problem that they think:
‘Oh they are very much glorified and they
should be glorified, they did something new’.
I mean if you go and cut your nose, you don’t
glorify such people.
But something like that has happened and this,
kind of a nonsense is still stabilized, and
people don’t think much against it.
But the sufferings are so much, that whatever
you may try the sufferings are there, and
they have to accept that they have gone wrong,
and they have done such a wrong thing, and
that’s what they deserve.
But whatever it is, despite all their - you
can say the foolhardiness or tomfoolery, whatever
you may call it, they are to be saved, and
something has to be done for them because,
after all they are all seekers and they deserve
to be saved.
But with ego they don’t understand their
own benevolence.
To them benevolence is that their ego should
be satisfied.
So Sahaja Yoga is not like this that you just
put some spirit into somebody and the person
feels absolutely elated for a time being and
then is finished, but it is something that
has to grow, it’s a living process, it grows
within us, it takes time, and sometimes people
get frustrated with it.
But we should not.
We should know we are the foundations and
this is the most important work we are doing
in the history of spirituality.
So far, such work has not been done before.
So, this is such a big thing that we are doing
and we should be very satisfied with ourselves,
and should be confident, because this requires
people of quality.
Not necessarily you should be well-educated,
you should be highly placed; though to impress
people might be this might help, but still,
if you are deep people you can work out, in
no time.
If the soil is not good, then the tree has
to go deep down.
In the same way, when the atmosphere is not
good, we have to go deep down.
But one should never feel frustrated; one
should never feel upset, because even if you
are one person you are a Saint, and a Saint
brings all the luck, all the auspiciousness
to that country, so there’s nothing to feel
in any way desperate or unhappy about it.
But try to develop your depth by meditation
and by collective sitting down and talking
to each other.
I’m sure this will work out and this Force
of Mahakali will manifest.
After this puja I am sure something tremendous
should happen.
As it is you know that all these false gurus
have been exposed and are put on the shelves
now, most of them.
Some of them have died, some of them exposed
some - has happened.
Gradually they will all disappear.
We don’t have to worry about them.
We have to worry about ourselves that negativity
should not fall into us, and the negativity
that falls into Sahaja Yogis is the frustration.
They feel: ‘We are very few, others are
so many, why should we so few?’
I mean it’s all right.
That has to be that way, doesn’t matter.
And to have more people is not so important
as we should have quality.
We should have very good quality people who
are deep, who understand Sahaja Yoga, who
know it very well, because even if you have
too many and they don’t know anything about
Sahaja Yoga, they are useless.
So not only that you should have this love
of God’s Divine Nature but also knowledge
about Sahaja Yoga.
Both things are the same, actually if you
love someone you know about that person, everything.
When such a thing will happen all over the
world that, so many countries will accept
Sahaja Yoga, and so many will start talking
openly about it, on a very high level, then
even the countries which have not been able
to achieve much results, or we can say cities,
will suddenly jump up.
I have great hopes from Toronto.
Toronto will come up very well I think and
I’m sure tonight also, we’ll have lots
of people who will be sticking on.
Because no use having thousand people and
ultimately two turn up, that sort of thing,
common experience.
So this would be a better idea.
And today’s prayer should be, in our hearts,
that let us get very powerful Ganesha Shakti,
let us get that.
And second should be that this Shakti should
destroy all that is negativity.
Even not to be collective itself is a negativity.
All these collectivity problems, or all these
negativity problems must be destroyed by this
Mahakali Power which will manifest through
us.
May God bless you.
So now there should be washing….[HINDI]