Today we are celebrating Sahastrara day. Perhaps
we have not realised what a day it must have
been. Without opening the Sahastrara, God
Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth,
and all talk about Divinity was a myth. People
believed in it but it was just a belief. And
the science, as it was put forward, was about
to obliterate all the value system, all the
proof of God Almighty.
If you see in the history, one after another,
when science established itself, the people
who are so-called in charge of the helm of
affairs in religion, in different religions
tried to cope with the findings of science.
They tried to show that: “All right, if
it is said this much – is in the Bible,
and if it is wrong we should correct it.”
Especially Augustine did that. And it started
looking as if it’s all a stupidity this,
these scriptures were just mythical. At least
the Koran itself, though, had lots of things
which were describing the biology of today.
They could not believe that human beings were
specially created by God. They thought it
was a matter of chance that one after another
the animals acquired a situation by which
they became human beings. Thus all the time
Divinity was challenged and there was no way
of giving a proof of whatever is said in the
Bible or in the Koran or in the Gita or in
the Upanishadas or in the Torah. Any one of
these things could not be proved because it
was still just a faith.
Very, very few people got their Realisation
and when they talked, people did not believe
them and thought that they are just trying
to say something which they are using to propound
their own theories.
So the whole thing became a kind of dead science.
There was no science of religion. People started
thinking that: what’s the use of following
these ten commandments or these strict rules
of life, because by following that you gain
nothing. You lose all the fun of the life.
And why think of gaining some punyas also.
And that is how all the time there was a big
derailment of human value system.
Also these organised religions, this monolithic
organised religions started taking to [a]
course of gaining power, or gaining money,
because they thought that’s the only way
you can control people and can go on. They
were least bothered as to deliver the goods,
whatever have been described in the Bible.
Bible of course was tampered [with] very much
and has been lot of changes in that. And a
person like Paul, and Peter, who joined together,
tried to spoil most of the Truth. Though Koran
was not so much touched but still is dealt
with more the right side, with the reproductive
system and all those things. And so many things
are still ambiguous.
Now simultaneously two things have happened,
I don’t know if you are aware of it or not.
First thing that has happened is that now
we have a new science of microbiology in which
we have discovered that every cell has got
a DNA tape. Every cell has got a program in
it. As we have in a computer a chip, every
cell has got a tape in it, in a way, that
it is programmed. And according to that program
a development takes place. Now imagine the
intricacy of the whole thing!
So many computers are already programmed and
all these cells have these in them. So a very
mysterious sort of a thing has come up before
the scientists and they cannot explain it.
They cannot explain many things but one of
them is this.
Now what Sahaja Yoga has done is that it has
proved that it is the Will of God, it is the
desire of God, the Will of God, which is doing
all the work. And it has been proved.
All these Chaitanya, Adi Shakti, is nothing
but the Will of God. And Will of God is the
One is working out everything very harmoniously.
I don’t know if some of you must have read
my book, first book, where I have described
how this Earth was created. There was a bang,
but it was very harmonious, and how it developed
is through the Will of God. So everything
was done in a way that God’s will was working
it out.
Now the Will of God you are feeling it, on
your finger tips. After Realisation, now,
you have discovered the the absolute science,
which is the Will of God, which is an absolute
science. You people know that we have cured
people through Sahaja Yoga. You also know
giving bandhan, and all that, things work
out. So many things work out automatically
after Realisation that people don’t want
to believe.
In the beginning people would not believe
when the scientists told them something, but
now it is, you can see, the science is always
in the flux, all the time changing. One theory
is again challenged. Another theory’s again
challenged. But Sahaja Yoga has exposed you
to that Great Truth of science which cannot
be challenged, which is all there.
So anybody who comes out with any new proposal
about defaming God, or saying that there is
no God, we can prove, not [only] that there
is God, but that everything, the creation
of this Earth, the creation of human beings
and everything was done harmoniously by the
Will of God.
If Will of God has done everything, the human
beings should not take any credit for discovering
some things which were created by God. Supposing
this carpet is made by somebody and we start
discovering all the colours, what is so great?
It is all there. You cannot create.
So it is not the creation part of it [which
is] so much important but the fashioning of
this world, whole thing was done by the Will
of God. Now if the Will of God is so important,
it has to be proved. And now through Sahaja
Yoga, after the breaking of the Sahastrara,
you have now, for the first time, felt the
Will of God, which is such an important thing,
but for us it is come to us so Sahaj that
we don’t understand. We just give the bandhan
and the things work out and we feel that the
things have worked out, so it is bandhan which
has worked out, and we have managed everything.
It’s not so. It’s much more than that.
We have now become part and parcel of that
Big Computer of that Will of God. We have
become the medium, or we can say the channels,
of that Will of God. We are connected with
that Will of God which created all this Universe.
So everything we can manage because we have
got the Absolute Science in our hand. TheAbsolute
Science which will work out the betterment
of the whole world. We can prove it to the
scientist that there is a Will of God which
has done all this creation. Even evolutionary
process is the Will of God. Without His Will
nothing could have happened.
So many people used to say that – not even
a blade of grass moves without the Will of
God. Which is a very true thing. And you have
seen now that – the Will of God we have
got as our own power. We can use it. So how
important it is to be a sahaja yogi. Perhaps
we don’t realise how important it is to
be a sahaja yogi.
Sahaja Yoga is not only for saying “Mother,
I am full of joy, I am enjoying myself. I
got purified. Everything is fine“. But for
what? Why did you get all these blessings?
Why you have been cleansed? So that this knowledge
of the Will of God should be apparent in you.
Not only that – should be a part and parcel
of you.
So we have to raise our level, we have to
come up. For mediocre and ordinary people
it is really useless to give them Sahaja Yoga
because they are good for nothing. They are
not going to help us in any way because what
is needed is now, today that, we should have
people who can really manifest and reflect
the Will of God. And for that, you can understand,
we have to have very strong people because
this Will has created the whole Universe,
the Cosmos, this Mother Earth. Everything
is created by this Will of God.
So now we are exposed to a new dimension and
that dimension is that we are the ones who
are channels of that Will of God. So then
what is our duty and what should we do about
it?
As a result of Sahastrara being opened out,
one thing: the illusions have vanished. What
you call [in] Sanskrit is bhranti. Illusions
have vanished. You should have no illusion
as to the existence of God Almighty, the power
of his Will and the truth about Sahaja Yoga.
You should have no doubts at all, minimum
of minimum should be like that. But while
using this Power you should be aware that
this Power is given to you because you are
capable of handling it.
This is the Highest Power you could think
of. Take any governor, take any minister,
anyone, they can be removed tomorrow. They
can become corrupt. They can become absolutely
devoid of any knowledge of their own powers.
There are many people who just get elected
without knowing what they have to do.
So this is not just a conversion of people,
it’s not only even transformation, but it
is a new fashioning of a new human being which
has come forward and which is capable of carrying
the Will of God further.
So as a result of your Realisation, what you
have got? The first thing that has happened
is that your illusions have gone. You should
have no illusions about God Almighty, His
Will and that He is omnipotent, omnipresent
and omniscient. All His omnipotence has done
this work, and as a collective consciousness
you should also know that you are also omnipotent,
omnipresent and omniscient.
Omniscient is the thing, that He sees everything,
knows everything. Part of it, that Power,
is also within you. So to prove His omnipresence
you have to all the time be aware that you
are sahaja yogis. When I find, even now, sahaja
yogis struggling about their wives, their
children, their house, their jobs, I start
wondering what is their level now? Where are
they? When are they going to take up the role
of what they have got?
So the Omnipotent God who is everywhere, who
has done all this, the Will of God that has
worked it out, has to work through you people
and you have to be very strong, very sensible,
very wise, also very effective people.
The more effective you become the more energy
you will get. But still I feel that the sahaja
yogis are more, not taking the responsibility
of understanding that they have to represent
this God Almighty who is omnipresent, omniscient,
who knows everything, who sees everything
and who is potent, means Almighty.
If you understand that this is what has happened
after opening the Sahastrara, that you have
now got the power which has these three qualities
in it. Say now this big thing has to be supported
by a strong pillars, but supposing if they
are not strong, it will fall down. In the
same way such a Great Power which has come
to you. For that we don’t need very successful
people, we don’t need people who have a
big name or those who have lots of money,
what we need [is] people of character, people
of understanding, of wisdom and of strength,
that “Whatever may come I will stand by
it, I will take to it, I’ll cope with it,
I’ll change myself and improve myself“.
So now illusion has been dispelled. I hope
you all have got rid of your illusions. Also
you should have no illusions about yourself.
If you have any illusions you should leave
Sahaja Yoga. But know that you are chosen
for this purpose by God’s Will, that’s
why you are here and you have to take it up,
the responsibility of understanding of this
science which is absolute. And working it
out yourself, for yourself as well as for
others.
You have felt My love, but your love must
also be felt, because God is love. So your
love must be felt by others. Other must feel
that you are compassionate, loving, understanding.
That’s all the time this Will of God is
flowing through you. And you have to work
it out in such a manner that people should
know that you are a saint, that this power
is flowing through you.
Then the second thing that has happened to
you is that, not the illusion about God and
about yourself, second thing that has happened
– that you have understood the integration,
that in the world there is complete integration
which is existing.
Normally if you see the children, they have
their own natural, innate understanding. They
know. If you see, normally, a good child would
always like to share his things, would like
to love another child, if there’s another
little child is there, would like to protect
that child – naturally! It won’t think
whether it has black hair or red hair or blue
hair. Naturally, innately a child feels that
way.
Also if you take another child, supposing,
who is a little baby, they know that one should
be careful about the privacy of the body.
Children don’t want to be made nude before
others. No child likes it. Innately they know.
So all these innate qualities are within you.
Children don’t like to steal anything. They
don’t know what is stealing is. They have
no idea of stealing. I’ve also seen also
children that, if they go to a place which
is very beautiful, in somebody’s house,
they will always try to keep the beauty of
that place. But if it is already shabby they
don’t mind.
So innately all these qualities are there.
I think the countries which are supposed to
be underdeveloped have so many of these qualities
within them, which are innately built within
us. Innocence is innately built. So the Will
of God built up, first and foremost thing,
was innocence, the auspiciousness. The first
thing He did was to create Shri Ganesha, or
I would say, She, because the Will of God
is Adi Shakti. And all this was created first
of all to make the whole world very beautiful.
All these innate qualities were also placed
within you. All those Deities were placed
within you. [They] were specially made, human
beings, that they should become saintly people,
that they should have their saintly, innate
sense.
But it happened in the countries which developed,
that our brain was bombarded by all kinds
of television, all kind of things, and we
became very, we can say, we became very vulnerable.
We started getting into the ideas of others.
Anybody who is dominating could dominate us.
It’s not only Hitler who dominated people.
We also see today how much we are dominated,
if you really detach yourself from this world.
For example fashions. Certain things that
come up, people cannot give up at any cost.
They cannot take to something that is sensible
because it’s a fashion.
For example nowadays there’s a fashion,
say to have such a small skirt. You can’t
get a long skirt anywhere. Everybody has to
wear that kind of a skirt otherwise you are
not ‘in’, you are not in the madhouse!
Now this kind of thing is bombarded on us
morning till evening so, first of all, we
become slaves of these entrepreneurs. Whatever
they give us now, I was told that in Belgium
you cannot get anything fresh. You have to
take everything from the supermarket, which
is all tinned.
Gradually what is happening to us – we are
getting absolutely artificial. The food is
artificial, the dress is artificial, our whole
attitude becomes artificial because we are
so much bombarded by advertisement, by all
kinds of outside influences that we just get
lost and we forget what is our innate sense
which is being dominated by all these modern
things.
So adding up to the science also there is
a a big progress in another direction, that
we can call, the money became very important.
Once money becomes important, then all your
entrepreneurs become important, because they
know how to make money and befool you all
the time. Today you have this thing, tomorrow
you have that thing. Today you change this
and have this thing.
But those people who are innately built, they
do not change! They have their dresses of
the same type, they do not change. On the
contrary they find it very difficult to get
out of their traditional achievements and
they don’t want to change themselves. So
for sahaja yogis it is important to see and
watch if they are getting this slavery from
the entrepreneurs in modern times.
Then, the thoughts. So many books we read,
which gives you thoughts, which are some mad
rambling, I would say, of some madman, like
Freud. How could Freud influence the West?
Because you have lost your innate sense and
you accepted. You accepted that and that’s
how Freud became your, sort of a, Jesus Christ.
He became the most important thing. Sex became
the most important thing. I mean it’s so
simple. With little common sense you can understand
that, at every moment, we are put into this
kind of a domination by these few domineering
people who have certain ideas, and they put
[these ideas] forward.
Anybody puts any idea. For example, Sade (the
Marquis de Sade) or Sartre or anyone. That
idea starts becoming “Oh he said it“.
Who is he? What is his life? Just see for
yourself what sort of a man he is. With little
common sense. But with your will that you
have now, Will of God, which has fashioned
the whole world, which has fashioned you.
Every cell within you has been fashioned by
God Almighty and what you are doing is to
play into the hands of these entrepreneurs.
They have realised that these vulnerable people
are very good for having as their disciples,
I should say, to make money, to befool them.
Now on this side, you have such a Great Power,
you are chosen for a, such a great thing,
and on the other side you have this kind of
slavery.
So try to understand that your innate qualities
were lost. But luckily, by the Kundalini awakening
and by the breaking of the Sahastrara, all
these innate qualities which looked like lost:
like your innocence, like your creativity,
like your religion within, like your compassion
and love for the humanity, like your power
of judgment, wisdom. All these great qualities
which we thought were lost were nothing but
they were in a dormant state. They all got
awakened one by one.
I don’t have to tell you “Don’t drink
this! Don’t eat this! Don’t do that!”.
You yourself realise that this is wrong. You
yourself know what is good for you. And still
if you want to do wrong you can go ahead.
But already there is a light within you to
see for yourself what is good and what is
bad. It has come because of this Sahastrara
being opened out to this – a new dimension
of new knowledge. And this is not new, it
is all innately built within you. Now all
those innate qualities are manifesting and
you are enjoying them.
So now you have to get out of your petty ideas
and petty things. People are reporting to
Me something very funny – I can’t believe
sahaja yogis can do like that – that they
run away with the plates that I have bought,
or they run away with the cups, they throw
things here and there, all over the places
they are throwing things. How can you behave
like this? I mean this is so stupid and so
insipid. If you do not have a proper discipline
of life yourself, you cannot carry the Will
of God, you cannot. But I’m not going to
tell you “Do this or do that!” I respect
your freedom and I just want that your own
Kundalini should awaken that wisdom in you,
that greatness in you, that glory in you and
you start understanding what is our innate
quality.
So it will purify you. Once you are purified
completely, like you see, if you have some
gold which is not pure you put it in the fire,
the gold is separated. In the same way, the
fire of Kundalini cleanses you completely,
makes you absolutely clean, and you start
seeing your own glory, your own nature, your
own greatness. So the integration part comes
to you easily. You start integrating.
First of all, we used to have sahaja yogis,
say from, some from England, some from Spain,
some from here. They would always have different
groups, they would never sit together. You
could make out this is English sitting here,
they are sitting here, they are sitting here,
and they would form a group. But now it’s
not so. Now I find they all are becoming integrated.
The integration of human beings is the most
important thing for Sahaja Yoga. That comes
by understanding, not by your intelligence,
but by innate understanding that – all human
beings are made by God, by His will, and we
have no right to despise anyone.
The second integration that has come within
you is that all religions, all religions,
are born on the same tree of spiritual life.
That all religions are to be worshipped, all
incarnations, all prophets, all scriptures
are to be worshipped. There are defects, there
are problems with those scriptures which can
be corrected.
So gradually you start entering into the subtler
side of Divinity, to understand that all these
people have worked hard to create, today,
the atmosphere for Sahaja Yoga, and no religion
is to be despised, and no religion is to be
attacked, which is a very, very, absolutely
a unreal thing and you are working out a very
unreal theory which doesn’t exist in the
Divine plan.
So this is how we finish all fundamentalism.
Fundamentalists are the ones who believed
that this is written in this book, this is
written in this book, and that we, because
we read this book, we are something better.
Anybody can read any book, what is so great?
Same, I would say, in Sahaja Yoga people should
not become fundamentalist. Be very careful!
Because that’s what you are – born like
that, I mean, I don’t know, it’s not your
innate quality but the way you are made that
way, you have fashioned yourself that way,
that you start also making Sahaja Yoga sometimes
a fundamental. “Mother said so.”
Do not use Me anywhere! “Mother said so!”
Is a way you want to dominate others. You
yourself say because now you have a right,
you have an individuality in Sahaja Yoga.
You can say what you have to say yourself,
but don’t say that “Mother has said it!”
Because anybody can start it, like that: “Christ
said it!”. A clergyman or, a say, pope can
stand up on his own platform and say that
Christ has said it. They can just arbitrarily
use all these things.
So nobody has business to use Me arbitrarily.
Whatever you have to say you say yourself.
But don’t ever quote Me as that: “Mother
has said it,” or, “In this book such and
such is written, so this is the line, that
is important.” You are not bound by any
line, by whatever I say. It is you who has
to stand up and see for yourself what you
have to say, because you have to use now your
will and for that you have to develop yourself
to have Pure Will, the Pure Desire of God
Almighty.
The integration not only outward, but inward.
Like first of all, whatever we did, our mind
used to say one thing, our heart used to say
another thing, our brain used to say another
thing. Now what has happened that all these
3 things have become one. So, whatever your
brain says is absolutely acceptable to your
heart, absolutely acceptable to your attention.
So you yourself, you have become now integrated.
Many people write “Mother I want to do it,
but I can’t do it,” “Mother it was my
desire to do it, but I can’t do it.” Not
now. Now you are completely integrated and
you can easily do the whole thing very well.
If you want to examine yourself, you should
try to find out “Am I integrated or not?
Whatever I’m doing, am I doing with my full
heart or not, with my full attention or not?”
I’ve seen that you do with full heart and
full intelligence but full attention is not
there. Still the attention, which is the first
thing that was enlightened, is not fully used.
So the whole attention should be absolutely
there, that, “I have to do this thing with
full attention.” Otherwise, the integration
is not complete, integration is partial. So
these three things have to be completely integrated.
So the integration of all the chakras comes
in. Like whatever you do, has to be auspicious.
Whatever you do has to be with full attention.
Whatever you do has to be absolutely religious.
So like that, all these centres are being
absolutely, one integrated power that you
have. So the whole life should be integrated.
Now, say somebody’s husband is not that
level or somebody’s wife is not of that
level, you shouldn’t bother. You should
just bother about yourself. Don’t expect
anything from anybody else. It is your duty
which is important. You have to fulfill your
duty and you have to work it out yourself.
Unless and until you understand that it is
your individual being which has achieved it,
and it’s the individual being which has
to realise it, is the individual being that
has to become one, integrated with the rest
of them.
If you start putting things, like many a times
I’ve seen [that] if I say something people
start thinking that I am saying for somebody
else, they never take it for themselves. So,
not we have to see what is my gain: “I’ve
got financial gain,” say, “I’ve got
physical gains, I’ve got mental gains, I’ve
got joy, happiness,” that’s not the only
thing. That should not be the only criteria.
But what you should have is the understanding
of your own personality which is being specially
fashioned [through] many, many lives for you
to come in this life to get your Realisation,
to do the further work of Will of God.
Every moment when you see a miracle taking
place, you do realise that it’s all done
by Paramchaitanya. But what is Paramchaitanya
– is the will of Adi Shakti. And what is
Adi Shakti – is the Will of God. So, is
all, whatever is done, is all ‘fixed entities’,
we can call them, or these vibrations are
like, we can say, DNA tapes. They all know
how they have to fashion you.
See, today it’s very sunny. Everybody is
surprised how can they have. So many things
happen like this. The other day, we had havan,
it was absolutely sunny. So the whole Cosmos
is working for you. You are on the stage now
and you have to see to it, but if you don’t
have faith in yourself, if you are not confident
as to what you are, how can you help? How
can you work out yourself and work out all
the problems of the world, which are created
only by human beings?
So we have to absolutely overthrow all these
dominations on us. First from science. We
can prove everything that Sahaja Yoga, whatever
it has said about science, has been proved.
So, we can throw science which is just always,
all the time, in the flux, it’s changing
all the time.
Then the so-called religions that we have.
So-called religions because people who have
been Catholics, who have been Protestants,
who have been Hindus or Muslims, or this and
that, they all have got that thing on their
heads. And this has to be thrown away. We
have to become a new personality. After Realisation,
as I said, you become like a lotuses is from
the mud.
So now you have become lotuses and the lotuses
have to throw away all this dead mud, otherwise
fragrance won’t be there. That, one has
to achieve: is to throw away all these shackles
which are, which are killing you, which are
of no use, but a burden. And beautiful lotuses
as you are you have to understand that the
whole fashioning has been done so carefully,
with such sweetness, with such delicacy.
So first of all we must have respect for ourselves,
we must have affection and love for others
and we must have respect, means we must have
discipline. We have to have the discipline
because if you respect yourself you’ll definitely
discipline yourself and you’ll make it available.
Now as you can realise, that from My life
itself, that I work very hard, travel a lot,
much more than any one of you can do. Because
I have the will that – I have to bring this
world to that state of enjoyment, to that
state of happiness, to that state of Divinity,
where they realise what is their glory, what
is the glory of their Father.
So I work very hard and I never even think
that something will go wrong with Me, or “This
will happen”, “What will happen?” I
never have bothered you about My family life,
about My children, about anyone. Whatever
problems I had, I am dealing with them Myself.
But here I get such big, big letters from
sahaja yogis, writing about their daughter,
their son, this thing, that thing.
Another thing is attachment to family is the
biggest burden on your heads and all the time
you are worried about your children, you are
worried about this, you are worried about
that. That’s not your responsibility. Please
try to understand. That’s the responsibility
of God Almighty. You can’t do better than
Him can you? But when you try to take the
responsibility He says “All right, look
after!” and the problems start.
‘Detachment’ is the word one should understand
in a proper sense. When I ask people why do
you throw things here and there, say “We
are detached!”- wonderful way! And what
about your children? You cling on to them.
What about your own things? You cling on to
them. For a small little thing, they’ll
bother My head. And, when it belongs to Me
or to Sahaja Yoga, then they’ll have a very
nice time with it – and throw it away, wherever
they feel like. I mean this kind of irresponsibility!
How can you call them divine? How can they
be saintly people? Saintly people not only
are responsible for themselves, but for everyone.
Very slowly, smoothly, sweetly, with great
affection, I have brought you to this level.
I didn’t ask you to go to Himalayas or stand
on your heads or to donate all your properties
to Me. Nothing of the kind. We have managed
it in a very, very beautiful manner. Now further,
when you have to go further, then you have
to understand that your duties are to be fulfilled
by you and by nobody else. But these duties
are done by you, are towards your family,
towards your house, towards this, towards
that. No duties towards Sahaja Yoga.
So when you were, before Sahaja Yoga, you
were not attached to anyone, in the sense
– you were only attached to yourself, self-centered.
Now you have widened yourself a little more,
that now you are attached to your wife, to
your children. But that’s just the same.
That is also selfish, because they are your
children, you think. They are not your children,
they are the children of God.
I hope all of you are intelligent enough to
understand your responsibility and work it
out.
This is a very important thing that has happened
to you that Sahastrara has opened. Now you
can prove the existence of God, His Will,
everything, to the whole world. Nobody can
challenge Sahaja Yoga. Those scientist who
will challenge can be told. Anybody, whether
you’re a scientist, economist, politician,
anything, everything can be explained in the
light of Sahaja Yoga and can be proved that
there’s only one politics – that is of
God, one economics – that is of God, and
there is only one religion – that is of
God, is Vishwa Nirmala Dharma. It can be proved,
there’s nothing to be afraid of or to worry
about.
This all can be proved to the scientist and
to the other intellectuals and to some few
people if they want to listen to us. If they
don’t want to listen to us, forget it. Because
we are so powerful, why should you worry about
them? But, if they are willing to listen to
us, then is better that we tell them “Now
we have discovered this Great Power”, and
if it works out, if this Great Power works
out then only we can really fashion the whole
world in a new way.
I have great hopes from you people, but the
seriousness with which you should take Sahaja
Yoga, for example even meditation, people
don’t do. Simple thing like meditation,
you people don’t do, I can’t understand.
How will you grow without meditation?
Unless and until you become thoughtlessly
aware you cannot grow. So you have to, you
have to at least meditate morning, evening.
There are many people who are not even collective
by temperament. If they are staying in an
ashram they just think that ashram life is
no good. Such people should really get out
of Sahaja Yoga, because they have not yet
understood what this Sahaja Yoga is. Without
collectivity how will you grow? How will you
assemble your power? You see? You know very
well that in a sangha, in a group, in combining
together only, you can be strong. Is a fact
that if you have one stick you can break it,
but if you put many sticks together you cannot
break it.
But there are still people I know who are
still not so much in collectivity. Shows how
poor they are in their understanding of their
own Self, and they are telling Me that “Mother,
we don’t want to stay in the Ashram now
anywhere more.” So they should get out of
Sahaja Yoga.
Without the collectivity, you cannot grow.
Without the discipline of Sahaja Yoga, you
cannot grow. It’s better to have ten people
of good quality than to have thousand useless
people. That’s what is the Will of God.
So now, as you are today here, so many people,
I am really enamoured to see so many people
are there. And we have done so much of our
growth and grown out of all those nonsensical
things that we were following.
But today we have to take a vow that – “I’ll
now fashion my life according to the Will
of God. Absolutely. And dedicate myself to
that.” No family, no other considerations.
Just forget it! Nothing so important. Everything
can be looked after by Will of God. So if
you just try to follow the Will of God, your
children will be looked after, everything
will be looked after, you don’t have to
worry for anything. And that works. Just try
to understand that you have problems because
you don’t want to give those problems to
God, you want to keep it to themselves, that’s
why you have problems. If you decide that
“No, I just want to give these problems
to the God’s will,” Finished!
Also there are some who want to say that “We
are not so capable Mother, we can’t do it.”
Saying like this also is stupid. You test
yourself, you see for yourself. So first of
all, one has to understand why do we say such
a thing? Maybe that we are very money-oriented,
that we want to have money to ourselves, or
something like that. Or some people are there
who talk of business also in Sahaja Yoga.
There must be something like a money orientation,
or some sort of a material attachment that
they say that ‘We are not capable, we cannot
change.”
The second could be this mamatwa as they call
it. The attachment to your family, children,
this, that. Or, ‘This is mine, this is mine,
this is mine.” This could be the second
reason that you think that you are not bold
enough or you are not strong enough to do
Sahaja Yoga.
Thirdly could be that you are still playing
with your old habits and that you are enjoying
your life without virtues. There can be some
reason like that. So just try to locate, “Why
am I behaving like this? Why am I not getting
into the same beautiful path of my ascent
as everybody has got it.” If we introspect,
you’ll find out that “There’s something
wrong with me that I think I am not capable
of doing.” You are capable of doing everything!
You just try this and enjoy it.
So, most important thing now [that] remains
is that you should become a proper, strong,
compassionate vehicle of God’s Will. So.
Then, what is most important of course, I
agree, that you do My puja, because that helps
you a lot, no doubt. But other things are
not important. So many other things you people
tell Me is not of importance. Main thing is
that you should all ascend higher and higher
and compete with each other in getting into
higher situation.
As it is, I think in such a short time we
have achieved a lot, no doubt, but still we
have to speed up and work it out. I am sure
that this new science, or we can say, the,
which is the absolute science will one day
outshadow the other science, and tell people
that: this is what it is. It is in your hands,
you work it out.
So today is the day we are celebrate by which
we have opened absolutely a new dimension,
absolutely a venue of great Divinity, of the
proofs of Divine. And this is something so
great that we can really finish all the illusions
they have about themselves, about their ego.
We can manage them. That power you all have.
May God Bless You.