I am very happy to see so many people here
to know about Sahaja Yoga in all its details.
But in this short time, what can you be told?
That firstly you got your realization, you
felt the cool breeze all right, and that it
was an experience. But beyond this experience
you have to settle down. It is very, very
important that you must have desire to settle
down. You don’t know the importance of your
personality. You are the one who’ll save
this world. Because the salvation of the whole
world is not possible with Myself; and you
people who will be really developed, it will
be such a force. I told about England yesterday,
another thing is that England is the heart
of the universe, I think. Everything circulates
from here, whatever happens small or big,
it circulates. It is not that only England
has many newspapers or television centers
but somehow it circulates everywhere. I used
to think only in India, it’s not so. I’ve
seen everywhere, every country, there's news
about England. Even in America, even in South
America, I was surprised how people are worried
about England so much that they want to know
what’s happening in England. My own experience
is this, that they get so upset with the things
that upset your country, not only that but
anything that happens of a very small importance
is noted down and they always tell Me, “Mother,
we have seen in the newspaper, we have seen
in the television.”
America is such a vast country and also the
newspapers are vast, and their television
is impossible to gauge anything out of it.
Horrible. What they say also language wise,
we are not so good for American language.
So, they’re little exclusive people, I think
their idea is to be exclusive. For example,
if they produce anything electrical, it has
to have 110 watt, while normally people have
220, so nobody can buy their electrical productions.
Now they have started a small production of
that. They try to be exclusive, while I think
England is not like that, it’s not exclusive,
it’s not only keeping all its things to
itself. This is something, a very great quality
that England has. It has many other qualities,
as I told you yesterday, there has to be self-esteem.
One quality is that they never go to extremes.
I mean we had some hippies, we had little
bit of this and that, but they don’t go
to extremes. But in America or any other country,
if something starts it really blasts the whole
atmosphere. This balancing in England is something
really very surprising. Also they are disciplined
people, they have their own discipline, and
with their discipline, they… like people
who are disciplined, who are very much in
time, properly dressed for the occasion and
I’m not trying to just praise you, but this
is My observation. And in this observation
I find, once Sahaja Yoga settles down in England,
it will spread all over the world. Then I
don’t have to run about in every country.
That’s very important, that it should settle
down here, that is you should all understand
the importance of Sahaja Yoga.
When I first came to London, My husband had
a job and I started My work with seven people,
out of them I think five were hippies. But
immediately they got rid of their drugs, alcohols
and all that. Immediately. Next day they were
different people. But how to prove, how to
tell, was a problem. They improved so much,
unbelievable. And I felt very close to them
that they are the people who have achieved
it in such a short time. For which, I think
otherwise I have to work very hard for others.
They became hippies because of some sort of
a fashion maybe? But English don’t take
to fashions so much. I don’t know why. Why
they had become hippies, and they were very
well educated, all were professors, this,
that. And they said that we have taken to
this hippiedom because we wanted to experiment
as to what it is. I said “You can’t experiment
with a snake, that ‘let the snake bite us
and then we’ll experiment.’ Once it bites
you, you are finished.” All these things
have been always, kept Me attached to London
and I have been here for twenty years continuously.
But the work that we did, I don’t know why
it did not reach intellectuals, and newspaper
people, while all other stupid people who
came here were so much enamored, and were
given so much prominence, everybody was talking
about them. So that’s how the London is
based about Sahaja Yoga. It is a spontaneous
happening within, a spontaneous. Yesterday
you saw, I didn’t do anything, it just worked
spontaneously, because it is there and it
has to be awakened, that’s all. But I know
also people who have been cured, have been
completely cured of very difficult diseases
with Sahaja Yoga. It’s a fact, it’s not
just I’m boasting about it, but it’s a
fact. It’s a very powerful thing within
us. This power of Kundalini is extremely,
extremely kind, loving, affectionate and effective.
As I said it’s your Mother, and when it
acts, it works so well, it works so well.
It is impossible to avoid Kundalini awakening
once it has been awakened. But I know some
people who have been able to defy it, maybe
because of basically they were cheats or immoral
or some sort of people, but they were very,
very few. Mostly I have seen people have grown
to great heights with Sahaja Yoga.
Today I want to tell you a special thing about
Sahaja Yoga. That in Sahaja Yoga, slowly,
slowly you’ll find, most of your problems,
most of your, I should say enemies, as in
Sanskrit they are called shadripus, all these
will just disappear. You’ll be amazed, how
they are just disappearing. Jealousy, anger,
racism, all kinds of stupid things that are
lingering, of which you may not be even aware,
just drop out. And you feel such love and
such affection for everyone who comes across.
You try to give them Sahaja Yoga, you try
to tell them about Sahaja Yoga. They may like
it, they may not like it. English are little
conservative, so that conservatism has gone
a little bit sometimes, too much. There’s
no harm in talking about Sahaja Yoga. I have
seen people who have gurus, of the worst type,
worst type. One lady was sitting next to Me…
It’s quite warm today? They told Me it’s
very cold. That’s England [laughs]. It’s
cold or hot. The climate is whimsical, agreed.
Very whimsical, if you are going out, say,
we were living in Oxsted, 25 miles away, and
when I started from there it was, surprisingly,
it was absolutely clear sky. And by the time
I reached Victoria station, it was pouring
cats and dogs as you say. Horrible, I couldn’t
understand. Or vice versa. So the climate
is whimsical, but that makes you prepared
for every kind of climate, every kind of incident.
And you understand, that that is what is the
nature. We shouldn’t fight with the nature,
but we shouldn’t expect everything to be
absolutely first class when we are going out.
So this kind of taking risk has made you people
very courageous, I must say. Courageous. And
this courage is to be used now in Sahaja Yoga.
You have to use this for spreading Sahaja
Yoga. This is your mission. This is what you’ll
enjoy. You’ll be amazed, the more you spread,
the higher you’ll go. You’ll develop much
more, much more powers within you, and unlimited
powers.
As far as miracles are concerned, I’m just
- don’t know how to explain them. Such miracles
take place. We had a lady from America, she
was staying with us and she had some sort
of a funny disease, that all her intestines
and stomach were all entangled with some sort
of a growth. And she had it before also. So
she had an operation and they took out everything.
Again she came to Cabella, and she was staying
there. Again she developed the same problems,
the same symptoms. She was quite worried.
So they said, “All right, we’ll take you
to the hospital.” She said, “No, let me
first meditate,” and with meditation, you’ll
be amazed, when she went to the hospital,
the doctor said “There is nothing, you’re
absolutely clear. You are cleared out.”
This meditation can help you in so many ways.
It’s not a meditation of some sort of a
chanting, or some sort of a going into, as
they said you’ll fly in the air or all those
things, no. It just is meditation by which
you enter within yourself. Your Kundalini
works out with this meditation. She looks
after your illness, she looks after about
your curing. All kinds of things she looks
after. Even the traffic you know, you’ll
be surprised, it works in so many ways. It
is so miraculous, you will find all the time
as if you are helped by some people, some
angels are there who are helping you. You’ll
be amazed at yourself, when it starts working
out. So, instead of doubting, you keep watching
what’s happening, how it works out. So many
things work out in such a beautiful manner,
that you are amazed, as if you have entered
into the kingdom of God. Which you have. All
the possible help, all the possible solutions,
just come like that.
I’ve seen one fellow who had some case on
him, and he told Me, “Mother, I have this
case, and this and that.” I said, “All
right, you meditate,” and when he went to
the court, they said that you’re already
solved, that thing is solved already. He was
amazed, “How is it solved? I never even
went to the court.” Then he went to the
lawyer, and the lawyer said, “Yes, they
have solved, but I don’t know how, because
I didn’t go to the court. I was sitting
with Mataji, I didn’t go to the court. But
your problem is solved, because when I went
to the court next day, they said it’s all
done.”
“But who was arguing the case?”
“They said you.”
“I? I was not arguing, so who was arguing
the case?”
“There was, and even you see, the remark
of the magistrate is this, that you argued
very well.”
It’s a fact, I’m not telling you stories,
it’s a fact, it happened. He said, “Mother,
did you go to argue the case?” I said, “I
am very bad at that, I do not know how to
argue.” But such wonderful things have happened,
I mean, you won’t believe, unbelievable
things happen. And, it is just to be seen.
As I told you yesterday, you have to be in
the witness state.
Don’t you think that there’s anything
less or more with anybody. You are all there
and are looked after. But have faith in yourself
is the main point. If you don’t have faith
in yourself, it doesn’t work. Just have
faith in yourself. I’m not telling you just
tall stories, I tell you. It is the fact,
I Myself I’m amazed how things work out.
I’ll tell you about Dr Spiro, one day what
happened, interesting. You see, I had told
the boys not to go in the sun - in Indian
sun, you know?- after 10 o’clock. But they
wanted, I don’t know, to burn their skin
or whatever they wanted to do. Five, six boys
were there, and when they came away, they
had all blisters all over in their hands.
So he said, they have to be given tetanus,
that has to be done and all that. I said,
“Don’t worry, it can be solved.” I just
took some water and a little cotton wool and
put it on them. And I was, as I was taking
it down, it all disappeared, it was all disappearing.
But I told them, that in the evening, go and
sit in the sea so your heat is taken out.
I think they didn’t do it. I sent them My
saris to cover themselves. I said, “Take
these saris, cover yourselves, sleep with
them.”
After that, I went to My brother’s place
in Aurangabad. He was the judge of the high
court there. I went there and My brother came
and he said, “What has happened to Your
saris?” I said, “Why?” “See how many
big, big holes there are.” And I said “How
do you know?” He said, “These girls went
to take out Your sari for Your bath and there
are big, big holes all over.” All the saris
had those holes. So he said, “How will You
manage?” I said, “I’ll manage with one
sari, it doesn’t matter.” But, I just
remember these boys, the amount of heat they
had. They burnt the saris so badly. But they
were not aware of their heat, that was inside.
Though they were cured, the heat was inside.
Like this, there are many, many things that
have happened, and I don’t know how to explain
to you all these miracles.
Now, why do these miracles are there? Why
there is these miraculous photographs? You
must have seen them. To convince people. They
were never convinced you see. Christ came,
He crucified Himself. Nobody was convinced
that He was divine. The problem is, human
mind is so stuck up that they cannot accept
anybody as divine. And at this time, in modern
times, when there are so many false gurus,
all kinds of things going on, I think it was
necessary for them to produce these miraculous
photographs. Actually, I don’t do anything,
to be very frank, I don’t do. It’s all
done by this all-pervading Power.
I was once in Brisbane in Australia and I
was sleeping, daytime, so one girl saw a beautiful
rainbow and she wanted to take a picture.
She took a picture of the rainbow, but can
you imagine a painting I love very much of
Raphael, of the Mother and the Child, I like
it very much. And she sees that thing on the
photograph. And the circular light that Raphaello
has shown was on top of Her head. I thought
Raphaello himself has painted or what has
happened? I couldn’t believe Myself. Like
this, so many things, so many things, you
can see one by one, some are they have collected,
some are not. Recently we had a program in
Bombay where we get at least 2 lakhs of people,
that means 200 000 people and they were all
preparing, arranging the stage, and in the
photograph, I’m already there. And with
Me is Ganesha sitting. Even Shri Ganesha’s
actual body, actual face was there in one
of the other pictures. I myself start wondering
what is all going on. This is the work of
Paramachaitanya, which is trying to convince
people who cannot be easily convinced. It’s
trying to make people understand that this
is divine, this is Divinity.
They never believed in Christ, they never
believed in anyone. All kinds of things they
have said about Christ, all sorts of things
they have tried to talk about Krishna, Rama.
But, still there are very few people who really
believe in them. They think it’s a myth.
But all these myths become real. You’ll
be amazed how you will change. You’ll start
looking so much younger first of all. Myself,
you know, I’m very good at recognizing people,
but some people I could not recognize. I said
“Are you the same?” “Yes.” So transformed,
the whole face changes, looking so much different.
One fellow was bald, he’s got all the hair
on his head. And what did he do? He said,
“No, Mother, I just raised my Kundalini,
that’s all.” “You didn’t do anything?”
“No, no, I didn’t do anything.” And
he had become so bald, so much bald headed,
that in the passport, his photograph was there,
and when the passport fellow saw him he said,
“You?” Because he was bald-headed at that
time, but he had hair before, but now, his
hair has come back. Unbelievable things have
happened. Unbelievable. And all this is for
you. You’re in for it. You can have many,
many miracles.
My, another name is also Daisy, because My
mother was very fond of a teacher, her name
was Daisy, apart from this, she gave Me the
name of Daisy. Now, when I came to England,
I found daisies everywhere, but they had no
fragrance, no fragrance. We don’t get daisies
in India, you will be surprised. But then,
they got fragrance. All daisies got fragrance,
very surprising. They never had fragrance
and they started smelling very well, in a
very beautiful manner. So it works also in
the nature somehow. I mean, that nature should
know My name is Daisy, that this - it’s
remarkable. There’s no end to it.
So many angels and so many divine vibrations
are working it out. So I have to first tell
you that you must have faith in yourself,
very important, and you must meditate. Once
you start meditating, you’ll become masters
of Sahaja Yoga. For this, color is no bar,
religion no bar, race no bar, nothing. As
long as you are a human being and you have
got your realization, you can really go very
far. So many miracles have happened to Sahaja
Yogis, so many miracles. And I was surprised,
even when they write to Me, they say Mother,
nobody will believe, but this is what has
happened to us. So, I would request you to
have faith in yourself and do meditation.
Very important. Then the growth within, you’ll
be amazed. I have seen people who never wrote
any single line are great poets. Those who
could not stand on the dais to speak have
become great orators. So many people have
achieved so much. But I just told them, don’t
talk about it, if you talk about it they’ll
think we are telling some sort of a story.
It’s a fact. Now you also find out in your
own life, the experience of all these changes
that take place. How the relationships change.
There was one fellow in America, very rich
man, and he told Me, “I don’t know what
You did to me.” I said, “What happened?”
“See, I hated my cousin, I really hated
him, but the other day I saw him and I felt
like hugging him. And I kissed him so he started
looking at me, what’s gone wrong with me?”
You see, like, you change so enjoy now, you
enjoy the collectivity. Now in India we have
a seminar of Sahaja Yogis. You see we have
people from all over the world. We have from
Brazil, from Argentina, say from England,
also Spain, everywhere. Russia, such a lot
from Russia. And when they meet, I’ve never
heard anybody quarrelling or hitting or anything.
They are in thousands, last time we had ten
thousand, but I’ve never seen anybody - but
such understanding and love. Of course, they
pull each other’s legs, that’s true, as
friends, but on the whole there’s never
a fight, never a quarrel. Can you imagine
if this thing happened to the whole world?
All these wars that they have started, all
this kind of problems they have created in
the name of God, in the name of land, or whatever
it is, will be finished. This should happen,
this should happen to the whole world, and
I want this world to be a very happy and a
beautiful place. And I’m sure you all can
achieve it. Because of you, the vibrations
will spread. Vibrations of love, vibrations
of compassion.
We have also a great idea of having compassion
for the people who are suffering. So I’ve
started a hospital which is very successful,
and we don’t have to charge anything except
for what they have to pay for their food and
stay. And it’s working wonders. What has
happened? What has happened, how is it working
like that? It is nothing but sheer divine
power. We have another hospital now we are
starting in Delhi, and also destitute women,
and it’s surprising how things work out.
There was a lady who came and complained about
her husband. That he has been very unkind
to her and this and that. I said “All right,
once we have destitute women’s home you
come there.” Amazing, the husband came next
day and she tells Me, “Mother, he’s became
a very nice man now. He’s become very nice.”
“Really?” He didn’t come to meditation,
he didn’t get his realization, how has he
become so nice? How suddenly he has become
so nice to his wife? It’s really unbelievable
how it acts. I tell you, we don’t know,
this all-pervading power is the power of love.
God is Truth, but Truth is Love. Love not
biased, love not because there is some sort
of a gain or some relationship, but love which
is just love. The ocean of love, and you’ll
just start enjoying that ocean. I have seen
it Myself happening and you also should see.
Whenever is possible please come to Cabella
at least, is in Italy. There you can see.
And we have nothing but a hangar, and they
didn’t want Me to build anything for them.
I said in the hangar how do you live? “That’s
the best Mother, we want to live in the camp.
We don’t want to live in rooms. We have
had enough of it.” Imagine, Russians, Americans,
all of them in such beautiful enjoyment. I
tell you, we have to enjoy life. God has not
created us to weep and cry, but to enjoy.
It’s good for you, it’s good for your
children, good for your family, good for your
nation and for the whole world. As I told
you that you are important because from England
everything circulates, circulates, circulates.
So, how important you are in Sahaja Yoga I’m
just trying to tell you. Very important and
you can do a lot. One person went to Russia
and now we have thousands of Russian Sahaja
Yogis. Thousands of them, they are so dedicated,
so beautiful, you can’t imagine. Once I
was in Moscow when this coup took place and
big problem was there. So I asked the Sahaja
Yogis, “Aren’t you worried about this
coup that has taken place?” “Which coup,
Mother?” I said, “Which you had in Moscow.“
“Mother, we don’t live in Moscow, we live
in the Kingdom of God.”
Just imagine. So when you face reality you
are enamored, you are just filled with joy,
because reality is joy. Today’s function,
I have never attended before like this. But
they said “Mother, You should come” so
I’ve tried to make it, but I would like
you to ask Me questions now. It’s very important,
if you have any doubts, please ask, or if
you have anything to say, please ask. Thank
you.
No questions?
Q. Shri Mataji, what do you think of Buddhism?
A. Now see, Buddhism is very different from
Buddha. Absolutely. Buddha first got his realization.
First he became a Buddha and then he started
Buddha religion. But the way people are doing
Buddhism is the other way round. That you
give up your wife, you give up your children,
you give up even your dress, everything. To
whom? To these people. Buddha started after
his realization. After your realization only
you can become Buddha, means a realized soul.
And he said it the same way. He said Buddham
Sharanam Gachami, I surrender myself to other
realized souls, Buddham Sharanam Gachami.
Then he said Sangham Sharanam Gachami, Dharmam
Sharanam Gachami, I surrender myself to the
religion which is within me, innate religion.
And thirdly he says, Sangham Sharanam Gachami,
I surrender myself to the collective.
This nonsense of giving up this, giving up
that, I mean, it’s too much. If you are
holding onto something then you can give up.
If you are not holding onto anything then
what are you going to give up? Simple thing
like that, for example, in Canada, one fellow
came wearing that Buddhist’s dress. I don’t
like it. A Sahaja Yogi said “You’d better
go and change, Mother will not give you realization
if you are wearing this dress.”
So he came to Me and, “Mother, please forgive
me, I have no other dress left.”
I said, “Why?”
“I have lost everything.” He was a big
business man. “I’ve lost everything, I’ve
given away to the Buddhists and I’m left
with two pair of these clothes and if you
don’t give me realization, what will I do?”
“Really?”
“Yes.”
So, what is there to give up is the point,
what is there to give up? If you are not holding
onto anything what are you going to give up?
Simple thing like that. Buddha never gave
up his clothes, nothing of the kind. But he
wanted to find out, what is the truth. So
he went round, I mean he tried his level best
and everything, ultimately his Kundalini rose
and he got the realization. But what he was
doing there, he was just lying down under
a banyan tree. Now, whatever mistakes he has
committed, we need not do, that you give up
your wife, you give up your child, give up
this, give up that. Just the
contrast of what really Buddha achieved, is
the contrast of that. So Buddhism is not Buddha
by any chance.
Q. The gentleman wants to know what happens
after we die, Mother?
A. Now, that’s another point. Everybody
worried about what will happen if we die.
I would say that, as a Sahaja Yogi, you should
not worry about the future because it doesn’t
exist. You shouldn’t worry about your past
because it’s finished. You should be in
the presence which is the reality. Present
is the reality. What’s the use if I tell
you what will happen, you’ll become a bird
or anything, are you going to believe Me?
You shouldn’t.
Q. Could you tell us about angels Shri Mataji?
A. They are very beautiful, just like flowers,
very fragrant. And they will help you; you’ll
be amazed how they’ll help you. You won’t
see them, you don’t see them. But they are
there, in the form of some human being - in
so many ways. So you cannot describe them
because you can’t see them. But you’ll
see their help, and you’ll be amazed how
they guide you to the right path. Now, supposing
you lose your way somewhere, don’t get frustrated,
don’t get upset about it. If you have lost
your way it must be some purpose. On that
way when you go you’ll find somebody whom
you have been looking for ages, or maybe some
sort of a thing you’ll find, some treasure
you’ll find. So, if you have lost your way,
there’s nothing to worry. They work very
smoothly and sweetly.
Q. She’s asking how you begin to meditate,
Shri Mataji.
A. That of course they will tell you. There’s
a photograph of Mine, first you have to work
on that. Afterwards you will know that how
it works, but first you have to use My photograph,
I don’t know what to do because the photograph
has the vibrations. You can test it, you’ll
get tremendous vibrations from the photograph.
It’s a kind, as we can call, a figure, which
emits vibrations. I do not gain anything by
that, but you will gain. You will gain, so
you have to sit down and meditate before the
photograph. It’s full of vibrations. It’s
so effective I tell you, that when you put
these photographs of Mine all over London,
it works.
Q. Is prayer the same as meditation?
A. See, before you are connected to the Divine,
what is your prayer? It’s nothing. If you
telephone without the connection, what is
it? So after realization, the prayer very
much helps. But meditation is inner, prayer
is outside. For your inner growth, meditation
is necessary. You don’t have to spend too
much time, say about in the evening before
sleeping, if you can do it for about say ten
minutes, or maybe five minutes in the morning,
that’s very good.
Q. Sahaja Yoga is available to everybody,
is it even available to politicians, Mother?
A. I mean, you know, you’ll be surprised,
in India so many politicians have come to
Sahaja Yoga. In India. But I don’t know
about English politicians. I have met some,
but they are so much involved into their own
positions and things. So far none of them,
but if you can grab some people it’s a good
idea.
Q. The gentleman asks for your personal blessing
Shri Mataji, he wants your personal blessing.
A. May God bless you, may God bless you. It
is for everyone. It’s for everyone.
Q. What is the difference between the soul
and the spirit.
A. The soul and the spirit? It’s a subject
should be dealt later on but little in short
I’ll tell you. The soul is the essence,
essence of the five elements. Essence. For
example, for Mother Earth, the essence is
fragrance, so all these five elements have
essence, and this essence contains the soul
in the sense that the soul is the reflection
of God Almighty within us. So the body is
that of the five elements, the essence of
the five elements and the spirit is the one
which is reflected on it, that is the reflection
of God Almighty. But later on you’ll know
much more.
Q. Mother he wants to know if You still meditate
Yourself?
A. I am in meditation all the time.
(A gentleman starts to speak for a very long
time, Shri Mataji says “It’s a big lecture.”)
Q. He wants to know, there are different meditations
he says, and he’s confused, Mother.
A. Meditation cannot be different, it has
to be one, and the one that makes you deep
is the meditation. All kinds of meditation,
there was one meditation they had started
here by which you will start moving three
feet higher than normal. Now think of it,
already we have traffic jams. You can find
the stupidity in all of them. If you use your
intelligence, you’ll find out, because you
don’t grow. Meditation that is good is the
one by which you grow. Everything is not the
food. The food that you can eat is the food.
Q. What do you think about Islam Mother?
A. Islam is great, no doubt. But nobody follows
Islam. Nobody follows, nobody has read even
Koran. You’ll be amazed. They are fighting
without understanding what Islam has written.
Mohammed Sahib was one of the incarnations
of the real Gurus, but Muslims, stupid as
they are, they don’t follow. They don’t
follow the exact sayings of Koran. Now in
Koran is written, that at the time of resurrection
your hands will speak. See? And without that
you cannot be Muslim, I mean Muslim means
surrendered. Just imagine, it’s all Sahaja
Yoga, if you can read between the lines. We
have a book called as “Koran Enlightened,”
we have also “Bible Enlightened,” we have
“Gita Enlightened.” All right?
Q. He says he finds it difficult to meditate
because his mind is wandering. How to control
the mind Mother?
A. Never control. Don’t try to control it.
There’s no need to control. Your Kundalini
itself will give you thoughtless awareness,
She’ll work it out. Try on the photograph,
it will work out.
Q. It’s a request Mother, will you come
to Ireland one day?
A. Oh, of course! They are lost, fighting
among themselves. But I have a special feeling
for Ireland. Because of ignorance, complete
ignorance, now the Catholics were fighting
Protestants, now Protestants are fighting
each other, now Catholics will start fighting
each other. I don’t want to say anything,
but you must understand that all these religions
have created nothing but fighting mongerers.
Crucified Christ and how can you think of
fighting? All over the world there’s fight
in the name of God. Can you imagine the stupidity?
Irish are very nice people, very simple, but
they get lost into these different, different
ideas. Actually, religion should never make
you fight, but the religions have misled them,
the religions have misled them, all right?
We have to give them that real religion of
within. Innate religion. In Italy they started
an argument with Me and they said, “We don’t”
- ultimately, they said, “We don’t want
to have one religion for the whole world.”
I said, “Why? Because then you can’t fight,
isn’t it?” You want to have many religions
so you can nicely fight with each other. Like
Rwanda and all these people. Religion must
bring peace, joy, otherwise what’s the use
of having any religion?
Q. Will you one day come to Scotland, Mother?
A. Scotland I have been. I have been to Scotland,
but, the problem was, at about 12 o’clock
everybody was drunk.
Q. Can Sahaja Yoga change your fate, change
your karma, change your destiny? Can Sahaja
Yoga change it?
A. Your karmas are finished. After Sahaja
Yoga, your karmas are finished. And can change
your face also, but why do you want to change
your face? - Fate, fate!! I thought she wanted
to change…. Ah, of course, of course it
can. It can change your fate and all your
aspirations are changed. Then you just want
to spread Sahaja Yoga, and enjoy the company
of Sahaja Yogis.
Q. He is a student Mother, how can Sahaja
Yoga help with being a student, with education?
A. Very much. For student, it’s a blessing
I say. Do you know, Sahaja Yogis who have
been very bad students, have stood first,
have got first class, first all over the world
Sahaja Yogis are doing so well in their studies
because you get a clear cut vision. It’s
tremendous, for students it’s very good.
Q. Is it important to be a vegetarian Mother?
A. Not at all. You see, in Sahaja Yoga we
don’t eat animals which are bigger than
us and you need not eat animals in case you
are a person who requires more vegetables.
So it depends on your constitution. Now supposing
a person who is vegetarian and gets diarrhea,
he should stop. I’m not a vegetarian.
Q. He’s got a problem with his knees.
A. Can be cured. Knee problems can be cured.
And how and when, that’s what, you have
to see these people and they will tell you
how to cure it. It can be cured. It is related
to your chakras.
Q. She says You travel a lot, do You fall
sick? You travel all over the world, to different
climates, do You fall sick?
A. No, no. You see, people while they are
traveling, they think they are traveling,
that’s why they get sick. I never think.
I think I’m sitting nicely on a coach and
also they think that, when will they reach,
will there be people or not, worried about
that, or maybe their past things they are
worried. I am not. I don’t get sick.
Q. Another request, Shri Mataji, when will
you go to South Africa?
A. You know the problem was like this, that
on My passport it was written that Indians
cannot. Because I am a diplomat, diplomatic
thing, we cannot go to South Africa. Now they
have removed, so after that I will try to.
Q. He says, Shri Mataji, that he lives in
South Africa and You are very far away physically,
but he feels that You are there, helping him,
why is that?
A. That’s My attention. I really want to
go to South Africa. I’ve been trying, but
I haven’t got the permission. And now I’ve
got the permission, definitely I’ll go.
And when you don’t have permission you are
more concerned about that country, isn’t
it?
Q. What do you think about entities, bad spirits
Mother, earth-bound spirits?
A. They are, no doubt. They are there. But
you don’t worry, you don’t have them.
Q. Is there any similarity that we know of
between Sahaja Yoga and ancient Egyptian or
African religions?
A. In Africa, I was surprised that they have
talked about Kundalini. They have, and I have
seen some of the maps, old maps, of Africa,
they have made the picture of Kundalini also,
all over. Even in a place like Bolivia, which
is so far away, and somebody went to Bolivia
from Italy and he said, “Mother they know
everything about Kundalini.” I said, “Really?”
“Yes, they know, but they don’t know how
to awaken it.” And Sahaja Yoga has spread
so much in Bolivia, the Minister from there
came to see Me. And who told them? I said,
“Who told you?” They said, “There were
two saints who came from India.” Even in
Ukraine, I was surprised, they said, “There
were two saints who came here from India,
they told us about Kundalini.” Chinese people,
they believe that there is a treasure of spirituality
in India but they don’t know what it is,
you see. But these two I don’t know who
they were. Two saints known as Machindranath
and Goraknath who have been traveling all
over the world. I don’t know if they went
all the way over there.
Q. A question about Paramahansa Yogananda,
he’s quite famous here because of his book.
A. He’s famous? What has he done? What has
he done? Writing a funny book like that, that’s
all. I don’t want to discuss, but first
when you ask about somebody, you’ll have
to tell Me what he has done.
Q. The gentleman set up a “Self Realization
Fellowship” in America.
A. I know many in America who have done it,
and they are more difficult to get Self-realization.
There’s a big organization there, and they
all believe they are Self-realized, but they
don’t know any vibrations, they can’t
feel anything, and when they have been to
that organization, I find it difficult to
give them realization. In the name of God,
in the name of Self-realization if you spoil
the Kundalini of people, I don’t know what
to say about them.
Q. Is it possible to meditate for the benefit
of other people?
A. In meditation you don’t think of anything.
See, you have to become thoughtless, that
is meditation. And for other people, you can
always ask, you are yourself protected, and
there are ways they’ll tell you how to work
out for others. See, they’ll tell you later
on.
Q. Shri Mataji, will peace, complete peace,
ever exist on the planet?
A. I wish that, I very much wish that, but
it depends on you people. How much you work
it out.
Q. He wants to know if there is any connection
between the work that You do and the work
that Sai Baba does?
A. Which Sai Baba?
Q. This modern fellow, Mother.
A. Well. I mean, giving diamonds and this
and that. Shirdi Sai Nath is correct, Shirdi
Sai Nath of course, but not this one. People
who want diamonds can go to him, baba I can’t
give diamonds.
Q. Are there more people becoming Self-realized,
or less people?
A. Much more. It’s increasing, much more.
I told you I started with one lady and in
England with seven, now look at them.
Q. If someone develops astral projection,
by accident Mother, and they feel bad, what
can they do?
A. They will get rid of it if they become
realized people, because you’re protected.
It’s very dangerous to have that astral
nonsense.
Q. The gentleman is interested in Your experience
with Mahatma Gandhi?
A. Mahatma Gandhi was My disciple. You’ll
be amazed. And he told Me, let our country
become free, and in that freedom then you
can start your Sahaja Yoga. Then we had Lal
Bahadur Shastri, who understood Me and he
said, of course, let me come back from Pakistan,
he had gone to Russia for Pakistan problem.
He never came back.
Q. He said yesterday Shri Mataji, You said
you may feel cool under the hands, he wants
to know why, what it is?
A. It is, you should take it up you see, it
has some reasons, but I don’t want to tell
that. You just take it up there like that.
Q. What do You think about healing? There
are all different kinds of healing, what do
You think about the healing?
A. Healing should be done with full understanding
of Kundalini. Any other healing can result
into something else. So be careful.
Q. Is it true that with Sahaja Yoga your immune
system improves so that you protect yourself
against disease?
A. Of course. Immune system absolutely gets
cured, no doubt, and many problems of immune
system also get cured. But also, you are protected.
Q. Another request Shri Mataji, when will
You come to Malaysia?
A. I have been, I have been many a time. I
have been there, and the Chinese are coming
to Sahaja Yoga, but Indians, I don’t know
what to say about them.
Q. He’s asking Shri Mataji if you will guide
us into a meditation now? There are some people
here who were not at the Royal Albert Hall,
Mother.
A. I see. But are there any questions left?
Q. He said he has read in a book that it can
be dangerous to awaken to Kundalini, so do
you need a teacher, Mother?
A. That’s very true, there have been people
who wrote like this. But those who wrote,
just go and see their lives, what they have
been up to. You see, you have to be a master,
otherwise you can’t do it. Then it’s not
the Kundalini, but a Deity there, which gets
annoyed, and then it happens. It’s not Kundalini.
Q. What do you think of Ayurveda?
A. Quite good. Ayurveda is quite good, because
it deals with the three doshas and it’s
very near Sahaja Yoga. But with Sahaja Yoga
you get cured yourself, so you don’t need
anything much.
Q. He says he’s impressed by the fact that
Sahaja Yoga is free, but he thinks it sounds
too easy, he doesn’t feel that he’s completely
Self-realized, Mother? He says he feels the
cool breeze, but he thinks there must be more
work to do?
A. Yes, that’s true but I must say, but
are you an Italian? Are you an Italian?
Irish.
Because the way he was speaking I thought
he was Italian you see. I went to Italy and
I didn’t know, we were told not to use our
hands, and in Italy you see, they will go
on like this, like that. And they say something,
you don’t know what they are saying, but
their hands are moving in different, different
directions. So I thought he was Italian. All
right, what was his question?
He says it sounds too easy, he thinks there
must be more work to do.
It is very easy to get realization, but to
settle with it, you have to do meditation,
and you’ll find out what’s wrong with
you. You’ll find out what chakras are catching
on your fingertips, and then try to improve
that.
Q. Can Sahaja Yoga help with psychiatric problems,
with mental problems?
A. Of course, of course it can. Very much
it can help.
Q. Do you think that the world is a better
place? Are things improving?
A. They can. With Sahaja Yoga it will, definitely
improve. If human beings improve, world will
improve also.
Q. Shri Mataji, he is Italian and he is using
his hands!
A. Yes, they are very expressive you know
[laughs].
Q. Shri Mataji, his question is, is it possible
to raise your Kundalini when you are a child
by accident?
A. No. There are children who are born realized.
There are children. And you can raise their
Kundalini also, it’s very much easier to
raise the Kundalini of children, you can do
that. So, it’s not an accident, it is just,
it’s there, they are born like that. They
are special people, many people who are married
in Sahaja Yoga have got very great saints
born to them. I have a great grandson who
is another realized soul, you know. So when
nobody is there, he will sit before Me and
do like this. (Shri Mataji holds open Her
hands) He’s not even two, but he speaks
so much, he can count from one to twenty and
it’s tremendous.
Now, one thing I’ll say, if you ask one
question it should be sufficient, all right.
Q. Krishnamurti, Shri Mataji?
A. Loaded with thoughts. Another are Krishnamurtis,
they can’t get realization so fast I tell
you. So much have put in their brain. The
Kundalini has to cross the brain. But so much
in the limbic area, that’s My experience.
Q. He’s heard on a tape Shri Mataji that
you said that you are always in dreams, in
a dream state.
A. No, not at all. I actually don’t get
any dreams. I might have said it’s My dream
to see the world like this. It’s become
a fashion now to say that, isn’t it? “It’s
My dream.”
Q. How did you come to this Realization Shri
Mataji?
A. I was born like that. I was born.
Q. Why is there a difference, why are we all
not born Self-realized? Why is it so difficult
for people?
A. It depends on your past life. Your desires,
if they are unfulfilled, then you get a life
where you are fulfilled. Like, I know, I’ll
tell you one thing, I had a driver who was
very royal by temperament, and he was a royal
king you see. But he had to work very hard,
so he was desiring he should become like his
chariot driver so that he’ll have some rest.
So he became a driver. Also marriage, and
all these things are responsible, because
we should not have any earnest desire, then
it acts.
Q. In order to get Self-realization, do you
have to desire it Mother?
A. Of course. I cannot force. I cannot force.
Q. Another question Shri Mataji. What do you
think about Chinmoy?
A. Ah. You see, if you ask such questions
I don’t know how to answer because it’s
very embarrassing. What has he done? That’s
the only question you should ask. And moreover,
if you have been to all these it will be difficult
for you to get your Self-realization.
Q. Shri Mataji, is it possible that the Kundalini
can be damaged? And what happens if the Kundalini
is damaged already?
A. I don’t know. So far, I have seen that
so many of these false gurus and false people
have damaged the Kundalini of people. And
I have seen their Kundalini has been like
a snake, you would say, hurt. Difficult, but
you can mend it. If the desire is great, you
can mend it. But I’ve seen that, in some
people, the Kundalini is very much injured.
Q. Do you have to believe in God Mother?
A. Not necessarily. Whether you believe or
not, He is there.
Q. Mother, one of Your names is Moksha Pradayini,
what is Moksha, what does it mean?
A. All these names I’ll explain to you later
on, just now they’ll be all shocked with
this. It means the giver of Self-realization.
Q. She’s worried about the subconscious.
If we are trying to get into balance, how
can we ignore the subconscious?
A. It settles down by itself. You see, the
idea of subconscious is not like Jung. Subconscious
is on the left hand side. And supraconscious
right side. The Kundalini is in the center.
So you don’t have to worry about subconscious
part, it just disappears.
Q. Is it wrong to have desires for other things,
apart from self-realization?
A. No, there’s nothing wrong or right. You
don’t have, you don’t have any desire.
You just become so sweet. You don’t have
any desires as such. Wrong and right is not
there, it’s just you don’t have. I would
say, I have one desire, to now stop questioning.
It is now about 10 o’clock, and we should
have our, again, the experience of the Self.
So you sit comfortably with your hands towards
Me like that. And no more questioning, allow
your mind to rest, allow it. Now put your
hands towards Me please. Now, close your eyes,
please close your eyes. You can raise your
left hand on top of your fontanel bone area,
which was the soft bone in your childhood.
Just stop thinking, just stop thinking, by
saying “Not this, not this, not this.”
Now, please raise your right hand, and left
hand towards Me. Raise your right hand on
top of the fontanel bone area. Now, please
open your eyes and see for yourself if there’s
a cool or a hot breeze coming through your
fingertips, or on your palm, or out of your
fontanel bone area. Please, put your both
hands towards Me, like that. All those who
have felt, again cool breeze out of their
palm or out of their fingertips, or out of
the fontanel bone area. Or could be hot breeze
also, in some people who have not forgiven
themselves and others. Please raise your hands,
those who have.
Ah. That’s great. Everyone of you, may God
bless you. I bow to you. I bow to you. It’s
tremendous, with all these questions and all
that, still, you have achieved it. It’s
a great achievement. May God bless you for
the future.
Would you like to hear one song?
(musicians sing Powada)
Now, enjoy yourselves. Enjoy.