I welcome
all of you from abroad, and this Kolhapur
is regarded as one of the deities’ temple,
which have three-and-a-half deities, or you
can say three-and-a-half coils of the Kundalini,
so it is said that, in this triangular bone
of Maharashtra - because it is surrounded
by, on all three sides by mountains, and the
plateau is in the center so the all the three
sides make a nice triangle - is the
Kundalini of the whole universe, of the whole
world, is expressed by Mother Earth in Maharashtra.
These are three-and-a-half energies, which
are coiled together.
The first one is of Mahakali.
This Mahakali power is expressed in Tuljapur
as Bhavani, and Shivaji Maharaj used to come
on a horse all the way for miles together,
to get the darshan of this Bhavani at Tuljapur:
he knew this; and he had a sword which was
called as Bhavani talwar, and people said
that the Goddess Herself has given this sword
to him.
Now the second one is Mahasaraswati, is at
Mahurgadh.
We always sing Mahurgadawari song, that is
the one is Mahasaraswati, which is
also called as Renuka Devi, that’s the right-sided
Mahasaraswati.
Then the third one is Mahalakshmi, that is
at Kolhapur.
Here a very bad demon called Kolasur was killed
by the Mother, so this place is specially
very holy for all of us; because you got your
Realization as the Kundalini went through
your Sushumna nadi, which is being nourished
by Mahalakshmi principle.
So in the Temple they sit down - it’s a
Mahalakshmi’s Temple, but they sing that:
“Oh Ambe, please rise, please rise, please
rise.”
This comes with the full understanding of
the Sushumna nadi, but ninety-nine-point-nine
percent people don’t know, because all the
knowledge about Shakti is being lost due to
the different timings, and people never worried
about it.
So, one has to realize that in Indian shastras,
scriptures, Shakti is the most important thing.
It is to be understood why: because, say now,
if you have a light or if you have fire, what
is the power of fire?
The power of fire can be that it can give
you light, it can burn away things, but supposing
it does not have its power, then who’ll
care for fire?
Nothing.
So anybody who hasn’t got the power of being
the Spirit, it is useless.
So this power, this Shakti, has to be awakened
within us, because we do not have the power
of the Spirit.
We have to have the power of the Spirit.
That’s only possible if you get your Self
Realization.
That is the reason it is very important that
we should pay attention to our power.
Now this power is made as the power of a Mother.
Mother is the most loving relationship, and
through that relationship all the love is
expressed.
That is why the Shakti is that of a Mother,
and the affection, the love, the patience
that Mother has for Her children, the Shakti
too has the same powers, you see, and that
is how this Shakti never can harm you.
Out of all these Shaktis, all these powers,
highest of all is what we call as the Kundalini,
because without Her you cannot get Realization.
But also we can say, higher than that, or
complementary to that, is Mahalakshmi power.
Without the Mahalakshmi you cannot rise.
This is the ladder through which this power
of Kundalini can rise.
So both the powers are very important and
very much related to each other.
Mahalakshmi principle starts when we have
finished with Lakshmi principle.
Like in the West, people are fed up with affluence,
fed up with all the riches and all that, so
they are thinking: “What have we achieved?
We have gone into imbalances, so what should
we do?
We have to balance ourselves.”
So how do we balance ourselves?
We have to have the knowledge of the Spirit.
That is called as aadhyatma.
You have to know what is the knowledge of
the Spirit, and to know the knowledge of the
Spirit Kundalini has to be awakened, and that
you are to be connected to this all-pervading
Power.
Once that happens, you just become one with
that energy and you get transformation within
yourself, because there is light and in the
light you can see all your problems, all your
defects; and also if you know how to correct
it, is the easiest thing to do is to get transformation
in Sahaja Yoga.
All of you have been very much transformed,
and now I find it difficult even to recognize
you, because all your faces are changed, your
attitudes are changed, you look so different,
so beautiful.
Today it seems to be a special day for Me,
here in Mahalakshmi Temple, that Mahalakshmi
is being awakened, and I’m feeling really
in that state of thoughtless awareness.
I don’t know how I’m talking; and I am
merged just in the meditative mood, absolutely
into meditative mood.
Because when you are in the center you don’t
think, you are in meditation.
That is why Mahalakshmi is very important.
So when you are fed up, you can feel there’s
something missing, and then you take to Mahalakshmi
principle.
But in India because of so many saints, we
feel that we should short-circuit it.
First let us develop our own aadhyatma, let
us develop our knowledge of atma and then
take to science, so there is no more imbalance
within us; because without the foundation
of aadhyatma, knowledge of the Spirit, you
take to any kind of progress, you can topple
down.
That’s why all the Western entrepreneurs,
enterprises and also projections of religion
have gone to waste, because there has been
no balance.
It is important that we must have the balance
within ourselves.
Now in India we have people who have this
idea, at least that you have to rise higher
than materialism and that you have to become
one with the Virata, part and parcel of the
whole.
This they know, and that’s what, by knowing
that, once they get to Sahaja Yoga, they grow
very deeply; the depth, the depth they have
achieved with this faith, that we have to
be self-realized, and that we have to feel
the all-pervading Power.
This conviction itself gives them the depth
and so when they achieve Realization, they
just go down very deep.
But most surprising, people who have never
heard about Ganesha, who have never heard
about Kolhapur, have never heard about Mahalakshmi
are sometimes much, much better, much more
deeper than the people who know all these
things by heart.
So one can deduct that those who know outwardly,
those who know through their books, or through
some gurus who teach them something, are absolutely
outside.
They have nothing in them to tell us because
they have had no experience of the Self, no
experience of the Self.
That’s only possible when your Kundalini
rises and breaks your Brahmarandra.
That is the time the first experience comes
to you of this all-pervading Power.
So all those people who have been only just
praying to Mahalakshmi, have been going to
Her, doing a lot of penances, fasting, this,
that, have no idea as to what Mahalakshmi
wants, and they always complain to Me: “Mother,
we have done this, we have done that.”
People are very religious.
They are doing all kinds of ritualism, what
we call as karmakanda, but with that you do
not reach where you have to reach.
So one has to understand that whatever has
been written and told about all these great
things in India, people may know in words,
but in experience they do not know.
So Sahaja Yoga is very important to give them
this experience, so that they can really verify
whatever is said in the science of spirituality
about getting Realization, is absolutely true.
Not only that but it’s very practical, and
every person who gets Realization can understand
it very well.
So we are here in a very holy place, full
of unholy people.
But still there are some very, very good people
here also, and because of Mahalakshmi, they
make very good ornaments because these ornaments
are offered to the Goddess.
You can feel there a kind of a subdued feeling
for God, feeling for spirituality, but they
do not have the experience that you have got,
so you are much higher than all of them.
And those who have the experience can feel
more, once they go to the Temple, if you can
go to the Temple to see the place also; but
give yourself a big bandhan because I have
seen it, next to the deity there are very
funny people sitting.
They’re doing all kinds of commercial activities.
They are selling flowers, they are selling
this, selling everything.
So you have to be careful, with a bandhan
you can go and see for yourself.
Now they say that this Temple is made because
it’s a swayambhu – it’s the one that
has come out of Mother Earth – you can see
yourself if there are vibrations and moreover,
you must know that this puja of these deities
are done by people who are not at all in any
way religious, but are just commercial people.
Commercialism can never give you any satisfaction,
can never give you at all any satisfaction.
Apart from that it can take you to something
unknown, of dangerous shores.
But if your faith is pure, without any greed,
without any demands, then you develop your
depth within yourself; which is very helpful
after Sahaja Yoga.
It’s a remarkable thing how this Shri Chakra
is here and how they have made the complete
calculation of Shri Chakra.
I met a scientist in Russia, in Moscow, who
has done a research, very much big research
on this Shri Chakra.
Now, so we have Shri Chakra on the right side,
on the left-hand side we have Lalita Chakra,
so all the things that we do with hands after
Realization are worked through, on the right-hand
side Shri Chakra, on the left-hand side Lalita
Chakra.
Now how it works is a very complicated thing,
but we don’t have to worry about that.
As soon as you put your hand on somebody,
the chakra knows how to work it out.
It works by itself, as if it is a built-in
mechanism within us, which knows what sort
of vibrations to be given to a particular
person for a particular cause, or a particular
purpose.
If that person has certain defects also, these
chakras know what is to be emitted, how to
work it out.
So it is not that we have the Kundalini awakening
only, these chakras are awakened, we also
have these two chakras awakened within us
because of Kundalini.
But if you have Vishuddi problem, then you
can find that your hands are stiff and you
cannot feel guidance, or you can say, the
Divine intentions of Realization; because
when you start using your hands you don’t
feel any vibrations, so how will you know
what’s happening?
It’s a very complicated thing, and for that
complicated thing these instruments are made
already, are prepared already; they are quite
equipped with all the knowledge that is necessary,
like a feedback as you call it, or we can
call it a complete programming is there.
So as soon as you put your hand on a person,
the programming starts working it out.
Because it is programming is done by God Almighty,
it can never be wrong.
It cannot be two different things, as far
as Sahaja Yoga is concerned.
I have been thinking about writing about all
these big, big peethas that are in India,
so it will be helpful to you as well as to
others in India.
But here the atmosphere is so bad, as if to
think of God, to talk of God is absolutely
wrong, you cannot say.
The people are in illusion, and they think
that all these talks has brought us nothing.
To them it is the progress of the West is
more effective, more apparent, that they can
see how you have progressed in materialism,
and they can’t understand how we could progress
with aadhyatma very much in the area of physical
development or mental development.
So now we come to a point where we realize
that it is very important for all the Western
people to have the foundation of aadhyatma.
For that it is important to give up some of
your conditionings, because this knowledge
is coming definitely from India.
I mean the Indians had all the knowledge of
your medical science, this science, that science,
that science.
But God’s science is in India, and for that,
what are you going to do?
When the question of God’s science is concerned,
what are you going to do about it?
How are you going to work it out, that this
is the science of God, and the God’s science
has to be understood with full dedication
and devotion?
Because of the conditioning of the Western
influence, the Western progress, sometimes
we just do not know how to grasp this knowledge
within ourselves; very difficult.
But if you can understand that, as for science
we had to accept it fully from the West, you
have to accept the knowledge of your Spirit
from the East, East has the knowledge of the
Spirit: for that you have to be ready to receive
it.
But if you are still in your arrogance, if
you are still in your own conditionings, then
you cannot do it.
Like a boy who comes from a village, who has
never known about science, and you suddenly
put him in a science college, he’ll say:
“What is this nonsense, what’s all this
all?
I have never known these things.
Why should I use a test tube, why should I
go in the laboratory?”
All kinds of things he can start saying, and
this conditioning is there.
Then he’ll run away from school within one
year or two year, maybe earlier, and that
is what I find is their conditioning, which
turns away many people from Sahaja Yoga after
some time.
So we must watch our conditionings, what sort
of conditionings we have; while the Indians
have conditionings of so-called religious
beliefs and this ritualism, this, that, they
are very much conditioned also.
But is easy to overcome that when you realize
that whatever your worship: for example, in
India everybody has a kuladevata, means the
family’s goddess, everybody has; they must
worship that goddess, particular goddess,
everybody has.
So they have to, if they just ask: “Mother,
are You that Goddess?” the vibrations start
flowing.
So the conditioning gets very easily eradicated,
but the mental acceptance of something is
very difficult to go.
And I’ve seen also when they get married
or marriage is arranged, they go mental.
They go mental.
If you go mental, then you cannot understand
many things.
But if you are spiritual, then you can understand.
For example, we see Mother Earth giving us
these flowers and all that, how can we go
mental about it?
It’s a living process.
For any living process we cannot get mental.
So now you will say: “All right, this is
because of seed has got this, and the seed
is planted”; but how, why?
That you can’t answer, can never answer.
Then you’ll keep quiet.
But say if there’s a sage, he’ll say:
“All right, this is Mother Earth, She wants
to give to Her children, these flowers, fruits,
these trees, so She’s working it out.”
So one has to jump from one conditioning of
materialism.
Now you should see in matter, energy never
moves.
Energy is stationary, it never moves.
And also energies which are moving, so-called,
like electricity, this, that, are absolutely
blind.
Supposing there is electricity here flowing,
all right, well and good, but supposing somebody
stops it, it will stop.
It has no mind, it is a mindless thing.
So in materialism you become mindless.
You start seeing also that within yourself,
that you have become mindless; and becoming
absolutely, absolutely, I should say, like
robots sometimes, which is mindless, which
is fixed, fixed quantity.
And I see very much clearly, in the West I’ve
seen, that people have very fixed ideas.
It’s difficult for them to get out of it
because they don’t have that movement towards
the spiritual subtlety, where one can use
the mind to do something.
We would say that Mother Earth has got the
mind.
Now that nobody can believe in the West, except
for Sahaja Yogis.
That the Mother Earth produces these vigrahas,
She produces these deities, nobody will believe.
How can you believe such a thing, that this
Mother Earth thinks, that this Mother Earth
produces these things?
But logically you can see, logically.
Logically.
Say a tree has a certain height, the fruits
have a certain shape, certain colors, flowers
same: who changes all the seasons, specially
in India is very clear-cut six seasons?
It’s called as Ritambhara pragya in the
Hatha Yoga.
Now that is the One which is a Lady, which
thinks.
She has a mind of Her own, She decides and
She works out everything.
This concept was doubly denied in the West,
is first is that they cannot accept a Goddess.
Woman has no part.
Right from Socrates onward, nobody has talked
much about a Woman, except of course there
is Athena and all that, but it’s very minor
roles they have.
Greeks had goddesses who were just like human
beings, so that also gets ruled out, and very
little was accepted; and when Christianity
came, somehow or other Christians saw to it
that there should be no mention of the Mother
in any way.
But despite that, people worshipped the Mother.
They worshipped the Mother of Christ as, some
like a Goddess; though in the Bible She’s
talked as a “woman”, in a very derogatory
style She’s addressed.
So the conditioning of people is about the
power of God who hangs somewhere in the air,
that He’s there and that He gives us everything;
but what is the communication?
What is the justification or what is the logical
thing, how to explain?
So you have to say: “It is a mystery.
God is a mystery.
He hangs somewhere in the air.
He does everything.”
And how can people believe in it?
So the Christian conditioning has been even
worse than, I think, Jew conditioning because
they just took it out, Christ’s Mother,
away; though the painters, artists wouldn’t
do that, they wouldn’t accept: they had
the Mother there.
But despite all that, the Motherhood has not
been respected that should have been, in the
Bible, which is a very wrong thing, while
Mahalakshmi Herself incarnated as Mother Mary
Herself.
And to say about Mahalakshmi as “a woman”,
I think is a great insult.
And where women are insulted like this, where
the Goddesses are insulted, we cannot expect
any spiritual growth unless and until you
accept that it’s the Shakti, is the Motherhood,
who is the only thing that’s the communication
between us and the Divinity.
So this conditioning, Christian conditioning
has to go out, as far as the Motherhood is
concerned.
It’s very surprising sometimes when I see
how these people have tried to bring down
the level of a Goddess to just a woman.
So this is a very big blessing in India, that
they respect Mother as the Shakti, and that
the whole thing is done by the movement of
the Shakti, by the thinking of the Shakti,
by the coordination and the understanding
and the planning of the Shakti only.
It’s not done by God Almighty, He’s just
a spectator.
She does everything.
Once that concept can fit into your heads
properly, then you will see so many conditionings
will drop out; because religion was organized,
and in an organized religion you can put whatever
you like, the way you want to put it, and
it was such a big mistake.
By that people developed a lot of ego, lot
of things against women, and also the first
sin they call the “original sin” and all
that is because of a woman, they really ill-treated
women and they have no respect for them.
So the women have changed their role, and
instead of becoming mothers and goddesses,
they have tried to become something like actresses.
But you can understand that without the power
there is no sense in anything, and this is
the power of Love and this is the power of
Truth.
And once you get that power we should humble
down, and know that this power is within us,
which has given us all this knowledge, which
has given us all this ability to raise the
Kundalini.
All this is because of energy within us, the
Shakti within us.
Without that we are nothing.
And that too is the Mother who has done it.
I do not know how much to press this point,
but it’s important; because I find, specially
in England some newspaper people came: “How
do you feel as a guru, as a woman?”
I mean, it’s a kind of a thing, “a woman”,
as if I am sort of a, that movement where
women are starting a fight with the men, sort
of a thing, and now: “This is another guru
who is a woman, so She should be supported,”
or some sort of a nonsense like that.
It’s the only the Mother who does this job,
so there’s no question of asking such a
question.
But that’s what it is, that we should first
know that it’s the feminine quality of a
woman as a mother, is very powerful.
But we should encourage it and try to develop
it, so that spiritually you can communicate,
spiritually you can imbibe these qualities
for your own children.
The mothers who do not have aadhyatma can
never develop good children with proper emotions,
with proper value system of morality.
So it is very important for every mother to
be very proud that they are mothers, and for
girls who are going to be mothers to be very
proud that they are going to be mothers, and
that they represent the Shakti.
So now then, what is the part of the men is
to take full advantage of that power, by understanding
it, by complementing, by looking after that
power.
I’m not talking only about your wives.
I’m talking about your sisters, your daughters,
your mothers, and the whole society, where
women are to be respected, and they have to
be respectable.
And women should try to be respectable, to
try to know that they are the powers and they
are the ones who will be used by this Divine
power as channels, more than men.
But if they are useless, then of course they
wouldn’t bother about them, they would like
to bother then about men, much more than what
you are.
So it is important to understand what is your
role in Sahaja Yoga.
This is your role in Sahaja Yoga.
And I am sure you can work it out.
You can manage this part.
You can equip yourself for this role, which
is so beautiful and so good.
So much can be said about Mahalakshmi, and
there’s no end to it, but I think later
on we should keep this program on every year,
and you all should come to Mahalakshmi Temple
here, to the, I mean the Kolhapur, and then
I’ll again tell you all about the Mother’s
qualities, what She is as Mahalakshmi.
And today we’ll have the Shri Sukta.
Shri Sukta is about Mahalakshmi’s qualities.
I think we’ll have Ganesha Stuthi and then
we’ll have this.
So seriously you must understand what is it…
I’m just in meditative mood today, I don’t
know what I’m talking; because this Mahalakshmi
is a thing that goes, finishes everything
else.
Left, right is finished now, you are just
in Mahalakshmi state: what to do?
“Mahalakshmi state” means nirvichar, nirvikalp,
beyond that, I don’t know what stages it
is.
It comes down a little bit, then again it
goes back to
the same.
[End of English part of talk]