on the easter day we give people eggs to
remind them that you are egg now when
you have to become the bird but I don't
think people know that because
resurrection is the message of Christ
Lucy fiction is the compliment
accomplishment but resurrection is his
message and it is a very significant
thing and it is written in one of the
ancient scriptures in India why Easter
should be celebrated with an egg is most
surprising was clear it's very clear
that if one can see how Christ is
symbolized as an egg now what is an egg
in fact it's the language a branding is
called as three Jaya he Jaya theme means
the one who is born twice and a bird is
also called any bird is called as a
divita means twice for because first the
bird is born as an egg and then reborn
as a bird in the same way a human being
is born as an egg and then is born as a
realized
now see how significant it is that both
are called by the same name no other
animal is called as visa unless and
until it has an egg form first and then
it comes out as a another thing for
example no mammals
none of the mammals are called as DJ
except for human beings it is remarkable
in the zoology if you read that a
mammals do not lay their eggs they give
birth directly to their children and we
are also mammals but despite that human
beings are called as V jaha just like
birds
so that means human beings when they are
born are eggs or they become eggs how do
they become eggs is the way our ego and
superego develop within us now you all
being only sahaja Yogi's I think you
understand what I am saying when the ego
and super-ego when the ego and super-ego
there's no chart is it develop in a
human being to the full extent and the
fontanel bone area is completely
calcified then you become an egg you get
completely separated from your mother
from all pervading power of God and you
are left to yourself as an egg till you
make sure within yourself inside the
shell of the egg in your freedom to a
point where you are ready for hatching
the mother bird has to pierce in the
head of them egg and you come out as
first you are already there inside
developed and then you fly out into the
space of all-pervading power of divine
love
so how significant is Easter and why
Christ he came on this earth because he
had learnt the idea he had practiced the
idea or we can say that he was an expert
on this that he could himself surpassed
that hurdle by which he becomes worthy
job but he was that already but how are
you to believe that you can be Regis you
can be reborn it was said by every
religion by every prophet that you are
to be born again unless and until you
are reborn
that means baptism not this kind of
baptism but the real one unless and
until this shell is broken on your
fontanel area you cannot become the
region it is written in all the
scriptures said by all the prophets
somebody had to show you that this can
be done he he being the divine power
itself the Pranava she being the brahma
itself his rebirth was resurrection
bodily resurrection while yours is the
resurrection which is
in your consciousness and you see it
clearly this is what is Easter is I
wonder how many Christians know the
significance of an A
it signifies a stage where you are
before realization when you are in your
action that you are mr. a exactly this
is why all that but when you mature will
be inside the bird is ready and that is
the time you are hatched this is the
time you get twice born so actually the
resurrection of Christ signifies that
and that's why we give that it people
say you are anything reminder of that
and this egg can become respect and also
it is written that he was an egg when he
came first one taken as an egg half of
it remain as Ganesha and half of it
became harsh - then he came on this
earth I departed with all these elements
pure vibration found his body
he remained there using all of you to be
awakened and when the kundalini takes
your attention through that point there
you also become the spirit that's why I
said that I am the gate
I am the dope fiends I am the
destination he said I am the door
because you cannot become Christ that's
why he is saying I am the destination
that you have achieved but he has
created this space for you can become
spiritually awakened you can become
useful but Christ is an incarnation he
was the son of God and so he's an
incarnation and that incarnation came on
this earth just to pull you out of your
elements make you become