…and this is the place where My forefathers
reigned as kings and they had a dynasty also.
Now, the other place we went to, Musolwadi,
is the place where the Goddess first of all
hit him with a beam so it is called as Musolwadi.
It means a beam.
Musol means a beam.
So this is a place where Goddess has done
a lot of work.
There is another place called Aradgao where
he was running and he was screaming, so it’s
called as arad, ‘arad’ means ‘screaming’
(gao means village).
So the whole place is already very much vibrated
because also the Nathas, the nine Nathas,
we saw one Ganivnath there, but all of them
lived in this area, worked very hard.
The last of all, Sainath, was very near here,
as you know, in Shirdi.
So this is a very, very holy place and a place
of great worship where many a times the Goddess
was worshipped.
Rahuri itself, if you go round, you find there
are 9 deities sitting there.
These are also created by Mother Earth, they
are beautiful things.
No-one knows about them.
You can go and have a look.
There are 9 of them and these represent the
9 incarnations of the Goddess, or 9 styles
of the Goddess.
Now, in this beautiful place we are here,
though it is spoiled by many things, but,
as you can see, it’s very comfortable for
our Spirit to be here.
At this place I have seen a negativity kind
of thing was working out about [which] I want
to tell you today again.
That works out everywhere wherever there is
a leadership of a person.
Here Mr.
Dhumal came and he got his realisation, in
Bombay, at My residence.
When he came back, he started working it out
here.
His brother brought him, but his brother became
quite negative to begin with, and then the
negativity started working out and people
started opposing him and troubling him and
I had to go through [a] very difficult period
during that time.
So now, as you are travelling, I want to tell
you: don’t challenge your leaders.
Because not only that it disturbs the organisation,
but it gives Me a physical manifestation,
I suffer physically.
Specially if you come and say things against
the leader in My presence I feel even worse,
and once it happened that somebody was talking
about a leader and the whole of My back became
so red that lots of blisters came in and I
suffered a lot.
So I beg of you not to decide about the leaders
and don’t try to criticise them and take
up the ego position and try to see that “He’s
like this, he’s hot tempered” or “He
is this, that.
” They have to be hot tempered! Because
I’m not.
Because I cannot be very angry, they have
to protect Me.
As My protection, they have to be hot-tempered
and they have to tell you off.
And if they tell off then you should not feel
that they are bossy or they are doing these
things and all that.
Actually those people who are bossy only feel
it, because they can’t bear that others
can tell them anything.
So they think that others are bossy and they
are fine.
That’s not so.
So the trouble is that one should understand
that one has to work in this fashion.
I know what the leaders are.
When I find the leaders are going wrong, immediately
I try to correct them.
But you should not try to challenge the leaders.
But this is the greatest problem I had in
the West and later on I found here also, in
India, it used to brew up.
Whenever I went away, then it started off,
the leader was challenged.
As if I don’t know about the leaders, as
if I don’t know anything about them, as
if I am to be told, as if I am absolutely
ignorant.
So you don’t have to worry.
You shouldn’t worry about it.
I will tell you who is the leader and how
to work it out.
It sometimes of course happens, that the leaders
go off.
I know that they go off.
It happens that they fall a trap to a wrong
person.
It’s quite possible, after all they have
become leaders just like you, with My special
permission.
But could be such a situation can come up
and I want to then correct them and I always
tell them that “is a wrong thing you have
done.
This is to be corrected.
” But otherwise the whole administration
of Sahaja Yoga is impossible.
It has to work through the leaders.
You shouldn’t see how they talk, what they
say to you, what they work out, but do what
they tell you.
There is no freedom lost in that.
You will see that your freedom will be maintained,
respected and will be done.
On the contrary, I would say, when there is
a sloppy and a mild leadership it [is] just
impossible.
Everybody else becomes the leader.
Like England, we can say, that Gavin was very,
very mild and now there are so many leaders
who come up, talk big, “Do this! Do that!”
I’m having a big problem in England of so
many mushroom like egos coming up.
And they become so flippant and nonsensical,
and they talk all nonsense, they start giving
lectures, this, that.
It’s impossible then to control.
If Gavin was a strong fellow and he put them
right.
But he’s too good and too much of a gentleman,
I think.
That much of gentlemanliness is of no use
in Sahaja Yoga.
So if he had handled the whole situation,
with that thing is alright and would have
worked out very well.
But sometimes also the leader is told to shut
up, “You shut up!” And like that he goes
on shutting up everybody joins hands and shuts
up the leader and the leader becomes absolutely
a cabbage.
He doesn’t say anything.
So this is also a very bad habit is to say,
“Shut up, don’t say anything!” I don’t
like it.
If somebody is talking to Me, anybody who
is talking to Me, you shouldn’t just in
front of Me say “Shut up!” to that person
or pull his hand, or just punch him or…
I don’t like all that, at all.
That hurts Me.
So never do like that.
I’ve seen people have a this very bad habit,
“Don’t say!” “Don’t talk!” as
if they are the greatest, wisest people ever
born to say such a thing.
Is a very wrong idea and this should not be
done.
This should never be done in My presence,
I don’t like it, it hurts Me and physically
it manifests.
So don’t do like this, don’t say anything,
don’t do! I know how to handle it.
If somebody is very funny I can tell that
person, “Now stop it!” I can do it.
But you just don’t try to take over things
like that.
Of course the leaders can do it, leaders,
the ones who are grown up, matured people,
can just tell them to keep quiet.
But all the time some people have the habit
of saying “No!” and “No!” Is bhootish,
I would say.
Is really bhootish because they never allow
Me to see the reality.
We must know what’s happening, what people
have to say.
I should know about it.
There’s nothing wrong in it.
But on the contrary, they come and tell Me,
“Our leader is like that, our leader is
like that.
” That you don’t worry because My attention
is most on your leaders.
I do change leaders and I will change leaders
in case they are wrong.
But let Me decide.
That decision you leave it to Me.
So this is another point I wanted to say about
Rahuri, which I learnt a lesson here.
Then another thing I found out: The villagers
here are much more easily convincing, they
take to Sahaja Yoga very well and while the
educated take time to take to Sahaja Yoga.
Naturally because they think they are very
well educated and they find it difficult to
forget their education and become simpler
people.
So in the same way, you’ll find the simple
people will take to Sahaja Yoga much faster
than the people who are educated because their
mind works too fast, they cannot catch the
vibrations, mind is running fast, the vibrations
are running after them and it’s a big game
of hide and seek going on! But doesn’t matter.
Still once that intelligent get to Sahaja
Yoga, then it works even wonders.
Once they get to it, they take time, no doubt,
but they take time, but once they take get
to it then it works wonders.
So some people take it easily, but they don’t
work out that well; those who take with difficulty,
work out better, in the sense that they can
intelligently manifest it and talk to people
and tell them about it.
So this is another thing one has to remember
that – try to understand that through your
education you have not known anything because
you never felt vibrations, you did not even
know that there was something like that existing!
This is a new knowledge, absolutely a new
thing, absolutely it has nothing to do with
your degrees, M.
A.
D.
and Ph.
s and all those things.
It is something else that is existing, which
you have to feel.
So if you take that simple attitude it would
be a better idea.
Now the fourth thing which upsets Me is grouping,
to form a group.
That’s another very upsetting thing is to
form a group.
This is one group of this place, a group of
that place, we belong to this place.
And this grouping once takes place, you see,
there is a gap in the collective.
When there is a grouping, say, a nose, an
eyes they become a group, then there is a
gap between them and the hands.
So if there’s a problem in the nose, the
hands will not act.
So the whole activity becomes a disintegrated
activity.
So one should never form a group, you see,
those who have a habit of forming a group
must be completely discouraged.
They start saying against somebody, then against
that one, then this that, then they form a
group, the one group goes there, one group…
so grouping is not allowed in Sahaja Yoga,
it is malignancy.
It is malignancy.
If it starts working out, you become malignant,
the whole group becomes malignant and it’s
a very difficult problem then to put them
right.
And one should not accept any sort of a sloppy
or a very mild leadership also.
One should accept a strong, fierce I would
say, to some extent, leadership.
That will help.
Because our ideas are very different from
what you have had so far, that “The leader
should be pleasing to us, he should have a
personality that will be extremely lovey-dovey
type”.
That’s not so.
The leader has to be a strong fierce personality
that should make people respect him and have
awe for him.
Because we are so free we can pass remarks
about the leader, say, “This leader is bad,
that leader is bad.
” But it’s not a good thing, it doesn’t
help, it doesn’t help.
On the contrary, as I told you, the sloppy
people create horrible problems and then you
get so many egoistical people who come up.
I mean a sloppy person, if there’s one sloppy
person or who has accepted such a domination,
if he is there as a leader, all the rest of
the people, those who come in contact with
that person, also become ego-oriented.
They also start behaving in such a manner
that you can’t imagine.
Like Gavin’s is a very good example.
In his office he had arranged to work for
some people.
Everyone who worked in his office got into
this trouble, because he was so good that
they picked up their ego, you see, because
their superego was there, so they thought
better to use your ego and that’s how the
whole thing worked out.
Poor fellow had to ask all of them to get
out of the office.
So this is an example for us and there’s
nothing to feel that it is any criticism of
anything, but it doesn’t work out.
This system doesn’t work out.
So you should not try to make a effort that
you criticise them.
Now, another thing about leadership I have
to tell you that – supposing I’ve appointed
Christine as a leader, she is the leader of
North America, then she has to take the decisions
for North America.
But nobody else, not even her husband, should
not take any decisions.
He should not, he should have nothing to do,
he should be in the background.
Whosoever is the leader should deal with the
problem.
This is the trouble is, if the wife is there,
then the husband takes over, husband gets,
then the wife … Like I should say Poona,
Poona, I appointed somebody there, he was
shut down and his wife took over and the wife
is a horrid stuff, I mean, I don’t know
what to do with such things.
It is very difficult that, if it’s a husband,
it’s a husband, it’s a wife, it’s a
wife, then the wife becomes little dominating,
the husband comes back and then the husband
starts ruling.
Then My attention is on the wife, here the
husband becomes.
In leadership there is nothing like husband
and wife.
They have nothing to do.
Whosoever is the leader is to be accepted
as the leader, whether he is the husband or
the wife.
This is one thing, in Sahaja Yoga there is
no discrimination between women and men.
Not that the men should always rule nor the
women should rule.
It is whosoever is appointed as the leader
is the leader.
I must tell you these things because these
little, little things make such a difference
to the whole organisation that I don’t know
how to tell you.
Because husband has no right as a leader.
He’s not appointed as a leader, so he has
no right as a leader.
If you all understand this point that leadership
is very important for Me, it’s like the
main organ of the body.
And that leadership should not be challenged
at any cost, any time.
Like Dr.
Sangve is the leader of Nasik.
So he is the leader.
He has to do it.
It is he who decides, it is he who says.
Nobody should challenge.
So we have got leaders of different places,
if you have any problems about deciding who
is the leader, you come and ask Me.
I always appoint one person.
In Italy, Gregoire, I don’t know why, he
said there should be two persons.
I don’t know why he said two.
But I told him, “Gregoire, it’s not a
wrong thing”, but he just said, “No, must
have.
” And the second one was dropped out so
badly, I mean he really harmed us.
So just listen to Me! I know, I understand.
Guido can say that what has happened in Italy
is because they didn’t listen to Me.
Here we are not to please everyone.
No, you are not here to take any voting or
anything, we are here to do the job and for
doing the job you must take the right course,
right methods.
So those who think “O, have three of them”
then “have five of them.
” This is nonsense! For what? Just to pamper
ego?
Any leader is as good as you people are, the
only difference is My attention is on that
leader.
That’s why it works out better.
Don’t allow your ego to dominate you.
That’s nothing… What does he do? Poor
man, the leader now, for example, I would
say, Warren.
He worked so hard, he really laboured through,
he worked so hard he got so sick, I was wondering
it’s all right for Me.
I’m after all a, Adi Shakti, so it doesn’t
matter (laughter) I can be, I can be marathon.
But this fellow was working with Me.
I knew he’ll have to give way at a point.
It’s too much.
And then people start criticising Warren,
I can’t understand.
I mean, he is working day in and day out,
can’t they see this? Without him what would
have happened to us?
I mean those who are leaders work so hard,
they do so much and then you start criticising.
That’s not proper.
That’s being a bit ingratitude towards them
and towards Me.
On the contrary, I feel so much obliged to
them.
After all this is My job, this is I’m paid
for it, I can say.
So I’m doing this job, alright.
But what about them? They are human beings,
they have got their other things.
I don’t have to earn money, I don’t have
any problems, so why, why bother them? They
are the ones who have dedicated their lives
doing so much and then you start criticising
them.
It is impossible.
But if he says anything to you, “Don’t
do this and don’t do that”, sometimes
it is with My consultation he does it.
What things I cannot say directly he might
say indirectly to you, so you shouldn’t
challenge such things.
This is one of the things today I wanted to
talk, about leadership, because this is a
place where I have faced some problems of
leadership, and one should understand that
this is the only way Sahaja Yoga is going
to work out.
In the body also, as you know, it is not that
the heart, which is the heart is the complete
pumping source.
No! The heart’s work is to be accepted,
that it is this pumping source, and it gives
to all the other organs.
So liver is liver, brain is brain, brain doesn’t
want to become the heart, heart doesn’t
want to become the liver.
Now the liver cells, if they say that, “Now
we will work for the heart” or “We’ll
form a group”, then how can you do? So as
we have got very important organs, we have
got very important leaders and I know what
they are up to, I know what’s wrong with
them, so you leave it to Me to correct them.
Alright this is for the foreigners today because
now we’ll be moving further and further
into more difficult time, I think, because
there may be little spartan living for you
because you asked for it! You wanted to have
a camping ground, so I am having the camping
ground.
So then you should not say [about] the leader
“Where is he? Now Call him! What have you
done?” It’s all arranged by Me, so don’t
blame him and enjoy yourself.
And don’t try to say that he should have
looked after.
He is not paid for it.
I’m paid for it, they are not, in the sense
I’m paid because I am made for that, it’s
My job, I’m doing it because I have to do
it.
I cannot do anything else but to do this job,
otherwise I won’t exist, you see.
So Mine is a different point.
But if he’s doing it, then it is an obligation
on Me and in a way I feel, you also should
feel obliged.
May God bless you all.