I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset, I have to tell you that
truth is what it is. You cannot change it;
you cannot transform it; you cannot conceptualize
it. It is what it is; it was what it was and
it will be what it will be.
Whatever, I want to tell you today, I have
to request you, to keep your mind open, like
scientist. You need not believe into what
I say. We have had enough of problems with
blind faith. But keep your minds open in case
this proves; then you have to believe, believe
in it. If you are honest people, you have
to believe in it. Because it is for the benevolence
of your individual self, for the benevolence
of your city, your country and world at large.
Most of the problems of this world come from
human beings; humbly we must admit. There
something wrong somewhere that we create problems.
And these problems come to human beings when
there is a problem with these centres here
as explained to you.
Now these centres do exist. These are energy
centres within you. And when they are, (Mother
speaks aside, Thank you, (Lawrence?) thank
you, its cold, I don’t like, I like, just
ordinary (glass of water)) these centres,
when they go into jeopardy, we have this problem
of human beings behaving in funny manners.
When this power, which is within us, which
is in three and a half coils; that’s why
it is called as kundalini; “kundalini”
means a coil. It’s a mathematical thing.
It rises like a primule in a seed and rises
upward against the gravity, and pierces through
your fontanel bone area, which was the soft
bone in your childhood. (Mother speaks aside,
Thank you very much, (referring to glass of
water) thank you)
Now the truth is that you are not this body,
you are not this mind, you are not this ego,
you are not these conditionings. What we say,
“This is my house, this is my car, this
is my wife, this is my husband, my children”
but who is this ‘my’ which owns it? So
that ‘my’ which owns it is the ‘I’
the “self”; is the ‘pure spirit’ within
you.
The second truth is, that there is all-pervading
power of Divine Love, of love, which does
all the living work. Now you see beautiful
flowers all over since I’ve come to Australia.
I’ve been seeing all kinds of flowers, beautiful
flowers. Who does this miracle? They’re
different, of a different shape, different
colour. “Who” does that? Who runs our
heart, we never ask this question to ourselves.
We take all living work for granted. We never
bother to find out who does that.
The third question that should come to us
really, which cannot be answered by anyone:
“Why are we on this Earth? What is our purpose
of coming to this Earth, to be born as human
beings, to be evolved as human beings, what
is the purpose?”
Is it just to insure our self and die? Is
that? What is the purpose of life? What is
our identity? And when we start asking these
questions, we find that nobody has been able
to answer this question.
Science cannot answer this question. Science
has its own limitations. So this all-pervading
power, which does all the living work, we
have never felt it. We have read it in Scriptures
that there is all-pervading power of God’s
love, there’s the ‘Ruh’, is there. They
call it Paramchaitanya or also they say it
is the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost.
But where is that? Nobody has felt it, nobody
has known about it.
Another problem is this that our civilizations
grew too big in the West, even in Australia,
everywhere. Like a big tree but what about
the roots? If you do not find the roots, the
result is as you have now recession; this
problem, that problem. So where are the roots?
If the knowledge of Science comes from West,
this knowledge comes to you, say from India,
or from East, what’s the harm. Because it
is important that we should know our roots.
And these are the roots, this is the knowledge
of the roots that is within us.
When there is problem outwardly, we should
know there must be some problem inside us
and we don’t know anything about ourselves;
nothing. What we know; about outside. But
we don’t know what’s wrong with us; where
do we go wrong?
So it is very important to understand that
if there is a way of going through the last
breakthrough of our evolution, if there’s
a way that we can find out our identity, if
there’s a way we can know our inner self
fully, why not do it? For which you don’t
have to pay. You can’t pay; it’s an evolutionary
process. It’s a living process! For example,
how much do we pay for these flowers to Mother
Earth? Who’s done the job? It’s built-in
in a seed, to germinate and built-in in the
Mother Land that it will germinate. We don’t
pay for that. It’s already built-in there.
In the same way if it is built-in within you,
you can’t pay for it. One thing, if you
realize that you can’t pay for your evolutionary
process, for anything that is Divinity, for
anything that is pure; half of the problems
will be solved of this guru shopping that
you have been doing all these days. Because
if you are not going to pay for it, and these
people are asking for money, that means something
wrong with them! You cannot market it!
Thus, we reach a point where we realize that
something spontaneous living process has to
take place. And that has become very, very
easy in modern times.
Because it is described already, prophesized
in the Bible, it is the Last Judgment and
otherwise in the Koran it is “Qiyamah”,
means the Resurrection. Even in Indian scriptures
they have described about these special times
when people who will get so much disillusioned
in the illusion, they will be born and they
will be disillusioned that they take to reality,
and this thing will happen. It’s already
predicted and this is the time, such a fortunate
time when we are all born. And it has to work
out. It is your own power. It’s your own
Mother, it’s your individual Mother, and
She knows everything about you. It’s all
tape-recorded. And She is anxious to give
you this Second Birth. She is anxious. And
She does it very beautifully. I’ve read
some books which says that Kundalini Awakening
is very dangerous and all that. I can’t
understand! It has never happened before like
that. I’ve been working like this for the
last, I think, I don’t know how many years
now; at least twenty-five years and I’ve
never seen anybody being harmed. On the contrary,
everybody’s helped; physically, mentally,
emotionally.
Now there are three doctors who have got M.D.
in Delhi University for Sahaja Yoga, in various
subjects. Now there’s a fourth doctor who
is trying on blood cancer and all that.
For medical science, if you ask them who does
all these things they will say “autonomous
nervous system”. But who is this “auto”,
who is this “auto” that does this work?
They can’t answer; they’re honest; they
can’t answer.
So this autonomous nervous system, which is
parasympathetic and sympathetic, the parasympathetic
nervous system will take over and we can control
our parasympathetic through this.
Of course, I don’t know how far the doctors
here are sensitive to a subject like that
but in Russia I was surprised. There are two
hundred doctors who are practicing Sahaja
Yoga in Russia.
Russian people are not so materialistic because
they have never known materialism much. About
30% of them are funny type. They’ll ask
for Marlboro cigarettes but 70% are so sensitive
to Sahaja Yoga. I was amazed the way they
took to me and threw away all absurd gurus
from them. Not one person could prosper. And
no religion is allowed to be practiced there
where they have now started taking to Sahaja
Yoga.
It’s very amazing how these people who don’t
know even English, who don’t know about
God; they were not supposed to know about
any religion, they’re so clean, like a clean
slate and they have taken to Sahaja in such
a big manner; I’m surprised. In thousands
and thousands of people, so sensitive, so
open-minded and scientifically so equipped.
There were 300 scientists, I think maybe more,
who invited me. Started telling them about
I…I thought, better start from science.
So they said, “Mother, no, don’t tell
us science; we know everything about science.
No we don’t, You tell us the science of
God.”
Such eager, intelligent, educated people.
Now, this democracy of ours ‘so-called’,
today also in the newspaper. I read the same
thing: “so-called democracy”. Because
it looks sometimes like a demonocracy you
see, like you go to America; you can’t even
wear your wedding ring. They might take away
your wedding ring also and kill you for that.
That’s supposed to be democracy!
You have to be extremely careful. I was surprised
in Perth. We were going in the night for about
thirty-five kilometres. No gangsterism on
the way, I was surprised. How this country
is still saved.
But it happens that this kind of democracy
without being in connection with that all-pervading
power can take you to anything.
Same with religions. You take any religion,
whether you are Hindu, Christian, Muslim,
anything. One can commit any sin. What’s
the use of denouncing others; everybody does
the same I thing; no difference. All are only
convinced they are something excellent but
they are not, in no way!
And so many things like this, when we start
seeing, we get disillusioned and we start
thinking, “Where is the truth, where is
the reality, what are we doing?”
At this time, I see; I call them ‘the seekers
of truth’. These are special category of
people, as described by so many poets. And
when it works out, they are the ones who jump
into themselves. Jump into this beautiful
era, of what we call the New Age. It’s a
happening. It’s not just branding yourself
New Age; somebody calls themselves by some
other name, it’s not that. It’s another
Christian, Hindu, Muslim branding. But something
that has to happen and that happening is awakening
of the kundalini.
William Blake has said that men of God will
be born in those days, men of God. And they
will become divine and they will have powers
to make others divine, exactly that is Sahaja
Yoga.
Moreover it’s such an internal happening
that, all outside things are not needed. For
example, some people go to Himalayas, stand
on their heads. Or they starve themselves,
fast, do all kinds of things. And they find
nothing. They can’t understand how it happens.
They go on telling me; Mother we did this,
we did that and we never found anything within
ourselves.
So first you are to be connected to that all
pervading power, this is the power that’s
extremely dynamic no doubt, but it’s the
power of compassion. So you also become very
dynamic. I know poor people becoming very
rich suddenly.
I have seen people who are sick becoming all
right.
We have a very nice place in Perth, where
a boy who was already married, had children,
two children. He was in an accident and whole
his brain as if came out; a terrible condition.
And doctors gave it up that he will die. Not
that he was saved, but he is absolutely normal
now. I was in tears to see him so beautifully
cured.
So this all-pervading power, which is the
Ocean of Bliss, Ocean of Knowledge, Ocean
of Compassion, is the Ocean of Forgiveness.
This power starts flowing through you. You
become a vehicle of that power. And once you
learn how to make others the same way, how
to raise their kundalini, you can create thousands
of people who are self-realized.
Surprisingly, in Australia many children are
born who are realized souls, very surprising.
Maybe because in other European countries
children are killed by the parents. So maybe
they are taking to you people who are kind
to children and your government is also very
kind to them.
And these children are not understood by parents
sometimes because they’re very different.
And they are very moral. So all the problems
that we have created out of our ideas of sort
of modernism or any kind of thing. And that
we see that our children are going to dogs
is all stopped through this awakening.
It’s like this, that if I tell some children
don’t take to drugs, they’ll never listen
to me. If, supposing I’m carrying a snake
in my hand and there’s darkness all over,
I can’t see anything and somebody says,
“you have a snake in your hand”, I’ll
never give up if I’m very obstinate, I will
never give up. I’ll say, “No, it’s just
a rope.” But when there’s little light
I will myself give it up. In the same way
it happens; it works this way that you yourself
become powerful. Throw away all that is destructive,
all that is to be given up.
I don’t have to say “Don’t do this;
the Ten Commandments we don’t talk about
in Sahaja Yoga, but only in you, the religion
is born. The innate religion, which keeps
you religious, righteous, compassionate and
dynamic. You don’t have to change your dress,
you don’t have to change your lifestyle,
you don’t have to give up your wives and
children, but you get it just where you are.
It’s so simple, made so simple. I would
say, if you are hungry, you can have it. Like,
if I’ve done the cooking, and if you are
hungry and you will say otherwise “mother
just lets have the food.” But if you are
not, then you will go on discussing, arguing,
this, that. These are all mental feats. I
mean if you want to ask me a question, you
can ask me any number and I am quite an expert
now 25 years I have been facing all of you
and I can answer you, but its all a mental
feat. It doesn’t give you realization. You
are here for your realization, by which you
are helped so much that physically, mentally,
emotionally, and spiritually you become all
right.
Firstly, you become peaceful, absolutely peaceful.
The peace within you, you achieve. How? You
live with your thoughts. The thoughts rise,
fall, rise, fall and in between these thoughts,
there’s a little space. Mostly, you are
thinking about the future or the past. You
cannot be in the present. In the present,
there is no thought. You are with reality.
So when the kundalini rises, these thoughts
elongate and the space in between, of the
present is established. When that space is
established, you become peaceful, absolutely
peaceful within yourself.
I have met many people, elite people, I should
say, very elite, who have got Peace Prizes.
They’re so hot-tempered people, I tell you,
that you have to touch them with a barge pole.
I mean you cannot go near them. It is horribly
hot-tempered people, and they have got peace
awards I don’t know how. No peace within.
At the slightest thing, they just shoot off.
No patience, nothing. And then I realize that
it’s so outside; the whole thing is. They
don’t understand if you don’t have peace
within, how can have a Peace Award? Well you
can. That is our life.
Now this peace is established within you and
you become, it’s a new dimension of existence,
where you become “thoughtlessly aware”.
You are absolutely aware, but no thoughts.
Just in peace. But you are aware; you are
not fainted down or you are not in some sort
of a trance. You are absolutely aware and
very much more aware because, you are in Reality.
Then the second dimension you achieve is that
you start feeling on your fingertips this
cool breeze of the Holy Ghost. Sometimes you
feel it hot, also. On these fingertips are
your sympathetic centres. And these Sympathetic
Centres are from left and right. They join
together to make the Parasympathetic.
So we have the left side and the right side
within us, and these left and right side,
indicates on our right and left side.
On the left side we get our emotional and
the right side our mental. I mean English
Language, “mental” means something different,
but I mean whatever we do with our brain.
And also you receive your physical problems
on the right hand side.
These problems are indicative on your fingertips.
Said it by Hazrat Mohammed that at the time
of Qiyamah your hands will speak and will
give witness against you; means they will
tell you what’s wrong with you.
But not only that; they also tell you what’s
wrong with others. Now somehow if you know
how to correct these centres, you’re all
right, and correct the centres of others you
can also make them all right. It’s so simple,
it’s all within you, all the mechanism is
within you. It’s all there. Only thing you
have to understand the importance of it. Without
that you can never be happy.
This power, which is there, is the power of
pure desire. All other desires are not pure.
Today we want to have say; some flowers. Tomorrow
we want to have a house; the day after tomorrow
we want to have helicopter. I don’t know;
we go on and on. So every desire, which is
fulfilled, is never satisfied! Once we get
it, it’s finished. Then again of course,
it’s a law of economics also, that in general,
wants are not satiable. It’s a fact.
But this desire, whether you know it or not,
is within you. Whether you are aware of it
or not, is the desire to be one with this
all-pervading power. And all the powers that
you have within you start manifesting. You
have no idea at all what powers you have.
I always say about a television taken to a
very remote village in India where they have
never seen electricity. And if you tell them
that in this box you can see some films, they’ll
say, “What, this is just a box! What are
you telling us stories?”
We also feel we are just a box, nothing more
than a box. But do you know what powers you
have within yourself? What you can do for
this world? What can you do for yourself,
to your family, to your children? How you
can really be a great force of reforms and
transformation without troubling anybody?
Because, after this you know the absolute
truth. You know them on your fingertips. If
a man from India comes from the jail, he’ll
directly come either to Australia or he will
go to America, wear a dress of a what you
call this saddhu baba dress in saffron colour,
and go and sit in any place and become a big
guru. Earn a lot of money. How will you know
if this fellow has been to jail, or is he
a real person or not?
So on your fingertips you can find out the
absolute truth. A new dimension in you, that
on your fingertips you know not only your
centres, but the centres of others. Everybody
feels the same way, knows the same way. Then
where is the quarrel, where is the argument,
where is the war?
Now we have in India sometimes, people coming
from sixty nations because Sahaja Yoga is
now practised in sixty nations. I’ve never
seen them quarrelling, fighting, of course
they pull each other’s leg and have a little
humor about it, but never have I seen fighting,
never! No question, no question of argument.
Because, you do not know the absolute truth,
so somebody says that Christianity is good,
somebody says this Islam is good, somebody
says that is good or democracy is good, or
communism is good. How? How do you know that?
Because you have got yarn in your heads, and
that’s how you’re formed your own ideas
and you’re all fighting with each other.
It’s all mental, which is all limited.
But, with this, you know the Absolute and
is tangible. You can diagnose people. One
fellow went to Huston and he said “Mother,
I was half dead with diagnosis only. But I
said, “You don’t have to do anything in
Sahaja Yoga like that. You can diagnose about
yourself, you can diagnose about others. There’s
no need to go through all that.
This is what it is that you have to have your
own powers manifesting. And you must have
the full knowledge about it. It should not
be half way. Your attention becomes extremely
innocent and powerful. The attention, when
it is diverted everywhere; you see you get
confused and people get schizophrenia, this,
that; all that.
But here the attention is very innocent and
such a person, even if he radiates or even
if he looks at or glances at somebody; he
can give peace; he can give redemption; he
can do so many things, he can do, because
his attention has become enlightened.
Sitting down here you can know about anybody
you want to know. You can know about the people
who are dead, or the people who are very far
away. You can find out sitting down. This
is what we can call as “collective consciousness”.
A new dimension of consciousness comes to
you about which Jung has written, collective
consciousness. So you develop this collective
consciousness within yourself. For that you
don’t need any education, you don’t need
anything. Even villagers can do it. Even small
little children can do it, because they know
this power. As all of us have the power to
see something, as you all can see me sitting
down here, in the same way you can know about
others; know about yourself; without doing
any acrobats. So simple as that, all these
powers are your.
But above all, you jump in the Sea Of Joy.
The whole problem is taken over by this all-pervading
power of God. We say we leave it to God, all
right, leave it to God. But you are not connected.
When we pray also we are not connected. You
know a telephone, which is not connected,
you go on moving it, it will get spoiled but
you are not connected. After realization,
even to, just a problem comes to you and it
gets solved, because you get out of your problem
and you can see it clearly and the Divine
helps you.
There have been so many blissful miracles
of Sahaja Yogis that now we have given up.
We wanted to print them, but in one month
they became so much high and we didn’t know
what to do.
So, all over we have to not believe in God,
but you have to feel the bliss of God; how
He looks after you. It’s not just a talk
or a sermon, but it’s a happening and the
happening has to take place; otherwise our
attention, which is outside, will not be taken
inside.
It’s a question of understanding our own
value, respecting ourselves. And it works.
As you all are here I know you are all seekers.
Otherwise you would not be here. And it is
your right to get this realization. Sahaja
means “born”: ‘sah’ is with you; ‘jah’
is “born”. “With you” is “born”.
This right to get to this yoga, means the
union with the Divine. And is your right and
you should assert and all those who will ask
for it have to have it. It is their right.
The whole thing has built in our evolutionary
process. And now, the last bit has to happen
and it will work out.
I have to tell you one thing more; that it
is not an individual happening. It’s a collective
happening. It works better when there are
many people. Also when you have to know about
it, learn about it, take advantage of it,
you have to come to the collective.
It’s not like other organizations where
they have an introductory lecture and after
that they start marketing it. You cannot market
it. For definite, you cannot market it. It
is divine love. And love you can never market.
In the same way this is Divine Love; how can
you market it?
So, if you have respect for yourself, if you
really love yourself, and you care for yourself,
you are not self-centered because after all,
you are a human being; epitome of evolution.
So, only thing you have to give some time
and come to the collective and progress in
Sahaja Yoga. It’s not difficult at all.
Nothing is to be done as I told you; it’s
not to stand on your head or anything. Just
wherever you are, you’ll get it. It’s
so simple. Because the time has come. And
you are not obliged to me buying for anything.
It’s just happening, happening all over
and happens to everyone. So I would request
you to pay attention to it. And once you get
your realization, you should really come to
the collective because it would be like what
Christ has described as sprouted, seeds which
were thrown somewhere and were lost, so you
have to grow, and that growth is important.
Once it happens, if you have any concern for
your country, for yourself and for the world,
you should try to keep to it and understand.
It’s as simple as that.
So the last thing as I told you, jump in the
ocean of joy. That is, when your ego is pampered
you feel happy and when the ego is punctured,
you feel unhappy. It is joy, has no duality.
It’s just a witness state in which you witness
everything like a drama. And you lose your
age very much. You feel very dynamic; at the
same time very compassionate.
As you know I’m seventy-one years of age
and I’m traveling practically every third
day. And it’s all right. People said “Mother,
don’t you feel you are traveling too much?”
I said, “I’m not traveling, I’m just
sitting everywhere. Where am I traveling?”
In the same way, it happens to you. And the
ageing and all that never comes into your
mind. You just live; live in the present.
And you just enjoy life; enjoy the company
of all other realized souls. All over the
world you have relations. Wherever you go
they’ll be all there to help you, to look
after you. Something happens to one person,
all over the world they will try to help,
the doctors will run to that place, people
will pray, and I mean they will see to it
that the person is saved.
It’s such a big family, such a beautiful
family into which I would request you to join.
May God bless you!
Now, I cannot force self realization, cannot
be done, because I respect your freedom. You
are given freedom at a human level because
you have to ascent with your own, with your
own desire, I cannot force on you anything.
As you have to accept it that you want to
have it. I would request people who don’t
want to have it, they should leave the hall
and leave others, but those who want to have
it are very welcome, and they can have it.
Even the knowledge they can have it without
any difficulties.
So all those who want to go away should leave
the hall, please, I will be very thankful,
because it cannot work on people who do not
want it. On the contrary it doesn’t help
others also to have such people among you
who don’t want to have it. It will take
hardly ten minutes and I would request you
not to disturb others when we are in the process
of it. Actually it happens spontaneously without
anything but as there are little problems
on the centers, you have to nourish your centers
yourself as I’ll tell you, its very simple
and will show you how we
do it.
[Self Realization]