Because many people have written about it
(inaudible) and a lot of people have been thinking that
something should be done in this matter
of finding the truth. (Unclear)
Now when human (inaudible) his condition would be such
that he only believes this thing (inaudible)
and he has no other means.
Whatever have been the achievements of Science, we have
seen only through the medium of intellect.
But the intelligence that is, tells us only about what
is visible in the world. It tells us nothing about what
is invisible or can’t be seen.
And can’t even tell what is the difference
between the Truth and invisible.
Then it should be thought first that when a person
talks of the search for Truth then first of all
he has to consider
that whatever we have known through the intellect, have
known nothing, even then we remained in illusion.
What we have known through our intelligence,
whatever we have known till now, that much has happened,
we have known from what is visible (UNCLEAR) but
have not known what is in the invisible or hidden.
And could not even know that what we have to know from
what is visible whether it is the Absolute Truth or not.
Now when the achievement of Science is ours, then Science
is on our heads, we have known a lot through Science.
We have reached up to the atom and molecule.
The activities that we have understood are also
of all that is gross or non-living.
..... How it happens with everyone in the world,
no one has any attention towards it.
The first thing to be thought about in the search
for Truth, that whatever man can do,
is there any creation beyond that or not?
For example, as we watch any living thing - a human-being
walking, strolling, growing, becoming anxious, see everything,
but we don't look this way, we don’t visualize/pay
attention to the fact, why is this man made - first thing,
because we don't have an answer to it. The speciality
of man is that he turns his face away from the fact
to which he does not have an answer.
And says that, he would like to stay at the point
to which he has an answer. He thinks that it
would be wrong to go beyond that point.
But man came into the world, Science told us
that man has been created/made from an amoeba.
Then it should immediately come to our minds
that such special events that have happened,
and because of which they are all inferior to us,
these are inert/inanimate things, we can make them.
Man's vision reaches there, that okay
we're making it, so we made it and we
have become a very great person
or we have done a very great work. But even a stone
cannot be made by man, not even an atom or
molecule of it.
Only if man could think with a little humility that,
"Can I make this stone myself?
Of all the elements, can I make even a single element myself?
It’s valances etc. are made so beautifully
can I create something like this?"
It's okay, that you’ve assembled a dead thing.
But in it’s creation can you have any
intervention – you cannot have.
You can't change anything about/in it.
As it is, so shall it remain. You can make it’s
compounds, can make mixtures from it.
But if sulphur is burnt and if we make crystals from it,
they will be made in the same way as they are made of sulphur.
Now if you want to create your own style of
crystals, you cannot create even that.
You can not interfere in it’s properties.
Yes, you can use those properties
but you cannot change their basic fundamental properties.
So who has made this and in whose power is it that He
can change it? Here also one should have a point of view.
Living in the dark, if you say that there is
no light, then this would be wrong.
But if someone says that there is light, then,
be it any scientist, any intellectual man,
he should say that if there is light we should
see it. There must be curiosity or inquisitiveness.
There should be curiosity in the mind of man that, after all
if he is saying that there is some light beyond it,
so why not have a look?
But the way we are influenced by ourselves,
there's so much autohypnosis,
that we think that whatever we can work out
only that is true and what we cannot work out,
there’s no need to look there.
Thus you can understand how far away we are from Truth,
that we haven’t even touched it’s basic facts.
The first question is that the One who created the universe
that is created, and Who has made such a beautiful arrangement
in all the molecules, particles and atoms of this universe,
Who has made it so systematically,
Who is this administrator?
One thing can be said that people are honest,
that say, ‘We can't go any further than this,
so we’ll stay here.’
But if we say, you can grow,
you can go further than this,
and beyond this there is another area, another
dimension, so why not open your eyes to all this?
We have only an ego that, "We have done this,
we have found this out, we have this, that,
but whatever it is, it is inferior to you.
If you want to rise above, anywhere, you
have to hold on to something above.
Wherever one has to climb - you must have seen that when people
climb a big hill, then they hammer a nail up there first
and then hold it.
This is what you call hypothesis etc. in
Science where an assumption has to be made.
Nailed the nail of that concept, then holding
up that nail rose higher, and then went
forward to see what happens.
Whether the nail is actually nailed or not, whether
we have reached there or not, a person can only
see after reaching there in reality.
But by turning away completely, this work
is not going to happen.
Now if we say that those who great saints and sages that
have been, the great Incarnations who have incarnated here
In India, in this land of yoga,
who have done great deeds, whom till this day
the world is worshipping and believing in,
these people didn't lie, so you would say,
"Yes, they used to lie, what is the proof of this?"
If you say so, then we can’t stop you.
Whether there is God or not, this too if it is
now a matter of debate, we can't stop you.
But if we say that we prove it to you,
then why not move in that direction.
If you are a worshipper of Truth and you
want to know the Truth, if someone says
that you can progress in it,
not only this but you can know that Truth completely,
then why don't we most humbly accept that,
"Okay, let's go and see, which is the path Mother is telling?
Let's see whether it is correct or not.”
Accepted that this thing was not universal till now,
was not collective and very few people knew about it
That's why there were misunderstandings, but just
like there are things of Science electricity etc.,
as many as/whatever are discovered,
the way they are collective and global today
and are used for the common good,
when we want to get to something higher than this,
then the things we have used till date
to attain the things lower than us and
acquire them, not only this,
in order to have authority over them, we
have to give up the use of those things.
For example, if you want to move around in Delhi,
then car is fine but if you want to go/fly up,
you need an aeroplane.
It’s speed is also different, it’s modus operandi
or style is different, all it’s projects are different.
The motor-car is a different thing, it moves on the
ground and this is an air-plane flying in the sky.
Similarly, when I am saying to you,
that you have to know the Spirit,
the Spirit has to be used, with the help of the
Spirit only you can know the Divine,
so it means that with the help of intelligence only
you understand the whole world, you have come to know,
then you will have to find something
beyond that - that is the Spirit.
If there is no mention of the Spirit in Science,
then only this can be said that
yet Science has not been able to move in that
direction, it'll never even come to know
because the limited area from which you want to know
it, it is beyond that, you won't be able to see it.
It’s range is not such that that you get to know
it. Thus the range of this machinery, has to be increased.
And while increasing that range if I say that,
until the light of the Spirit comes into it
till then the work won’t be done, you must
accept it so that we attain it.
As we see a person has a very good microscope
that lets him see how each muscle is and how
is the flow of blood in it, we see all this
but when we see that another person has a
good machine, even better than this one,
so we want somehow to get it.
Similarly, if a person sees that
the other person has got something special,
so he should have a desire to achieve that
special thing, but it does not happen.
This is not the case with the Spirit because man
only wants to know that, "What I am today,
I should get everything in it only. If I want to
rise further, means it’s a disrespect to myself only.”
In the case of Science, he doesn’t think so.
In the matter of Science, if America did
some research, he will rush there.
Then does not think that, “We are Indians, why should we
run after them.” If Russia did something,
then he will run after them.
But if there’s some exploration in some other
area, then man is not interested in it.
Man knows all about the outside of the tree
but nothing is known about it’s roots.
And to know about it’s roots, you have to become subtle
and to achieve that subtlety, you need humility.
If you want that on the basis of your intellect
you achieve it, you can't.
One simple thing people don't understand
is whenever I give a speech etc., whatever/anything
then I see the first question is,
that it is written in such-and-such a book -
(It's) done, then what to talk about? Okay, whatever is written
(that) is not going to be judged by your intelligence.
You won't be able to understand it. I’m saying
that you will not be able to understand.
Please understand, if we can't see without glasses
then it’s important for us to wear glasses - this point
we understand.
And, if except the Spirit we can’t know/understand God,
then you should get to the Spirit – this simple
fact why shouldn't you understand!
Will you be able to find the Truth by doubting it?
If in reality you are a worshipper of Truth and
you really want to know the Truth,
so first of all there should be humility that
till now we haven't found the Truth.
This is a great virtue – humility.
Man learns anything but can't learn humility.
What do you do in humility? Some people
get the idea that being humble means
you have bowed down/succumbed before someone.
This is a big misconception. Humility means
that you have opened yourself up to accept -
accept a new ideology, to accept something new,
seeing, testing, understanding, getting deep into it.
Humility never means that you bow down before someone.
No matter how high the branches of the tree
may rise, till its roots
reach the source after digging the ground,
no power of any kind can enter that tree.
In the same way no matter how much your civilization/
decency/politeness increases and no matter how much
this mess of Science increases,
but until you have found your Spirit, the whole of it,
will be destroyed, will be finished, just like a bubble.
None of this is going to survive and that’s
what has been happening all over the world.
I just met a lady who said that they had gone
for the disarmament of the armament,
‘We worked so hard, told the people that there
must be disarmament and everything would be fine
with disarmament and there were many disputes
and there we worked hard for four months and
no one listened and we were great failures.’
Tell me. This means that human-beings are
not left with any intellect.
There should be disarmament – even a simple person
can understand that what is the need of one human
going around killing other humans.
Except man no animal kills other animals taking arms.
It doesn't have the power even to hold it.
God has given us hands, so now we kill others by
taking guns. Is this a matter of great wisdom?
Science cannot treat this, can it?
If scientists can fill wisdom in people,
then I will think them to be great.
Intelligence or wisdom cannot come inside anyone, through
Science. If he wants to, he can make an atom bomb.
And if he wants he can make one or the other
good hospital but it is at his will.
It is not a fixed thing, it is movable/transient. Today
he will build a big hospital, a huge one.
He will cure thousands of people there and later one day,
can all of a sudden destroy it by dropping a bomb on it.
You can't guarantee that.
Does Science guarantee it
that the man who is doing good work today because
of Science, will tomorrow not destroy it?
Can you give any guarantee of man
with Science?
When Science is so incomplete then we
should see why is it’s light so dim?
Why is it so, that in it’s light a person is
sometimes seen standing on the path and
sometimes falls into the ditch?
And as long as man is not capable or competent
enough, till the motivation or inspiration for Truth
is not strong enough in man,
till then, whether you do any social work of the world,
any political work or any work with your intellect,
there’s no stability for him.
Today you will be high up in the sky, tomorrow you
will drown in the river because Science doesn’t
make any human being capable enough and cannot make.
No man can ever be competent or capable
enough with ego. ‘sam’ ‘arth’
So must reach this result, what is called
the logical conclusion and think
that with the intellect alone we cannot find the Truth.
By intellect we can tell that a white sheet is spread
here, that it is a khadi sheet - just this,
what else? How far can we go?
But can you tell from this khadi sheet,
whether it was worn by a saint or a demon?
With Science you can't even tell whether
this person is a demon or he is a human being?
And can’t even say and don’t know whether the one
who looks like a human today, may tomorrow
become a ghost and sit on your head.
There is no surety of anything - everything
is mobile/unsustainable, unstable.
That's why nowadays in Kalyuga it is said that
man is completely in delusion, in confusion.
And in this tumult/uproar when man thinks that,
"Hey, now Kalyuga has come,
now what is Mataji talking about in this? Now
this is what happens in Kalyuga, this is Kalyuga."
It means that everything has become a guarantee. Now it
is Kalyuga, now in this, if you don’t do these things,
so how will it happen? This has to be done,
this Kali Yuga has come.
In this, if you do not move on this path, then no
work is going to be done. This is the way. It is Kaliyuga.
No matter how you keep turning your path in Kalyug,
whichever way you go, somehow you keep on moving
right-left, somehow you keep living.
Such a person lives on compromises because
the values which were stable, they finish off.
When man becomes delusional, his constant/stable
values definitely end.
When the war challenged and when the war broke out
in the European countries, when there was
great plight of the people,
so the values that were there, were greatly reduced,
were over, almost finished.
Because when everything started to waver/stagger,
then people could not understand that what
should they hold on to now.
If they hold on to this thing, it is wobbly
if they held on to that thing, it wobbled.
But then these thoughts should come to the mind of man,
that we may be we have not caught the thing
which is stable and immovable.
Such a thought must arise in the mind of every
intellectualist - this thought must arise in the mind.
Son, sit here, it is very cold there, come here.
There is a lot of space here. It's cold outside,
don't sit outside. Come sit here, don't sit outside.
Come ahead and sit here. You people come forward.
I can't talk comfortably if everyone will sit outside.
Sit here, what’s the problem? Spread something on it -
this is a good thing. Don't sit outside.
And seeing all this, the heart of man gets
filled with bitterness. His heart becomes very bitter
- he wonders where is the sweetness,
where is the love! If one has to live somehow
then what is home?
Some strangle themselves, some strangle others.
And in response thousands of people
will tell you thousands of things.
Some will say that the reason for this is social disorder,
some would say political disorder.
Some will say Communism is good, some will say
Capitalism is good, someone will say something good,
someone will say something else good.
And people will also stick to it. Some will become
a Communist, someone will become a Capitalist,
some will become Democratic, some Socialist,
then someone will become poor,
somebody will become rich - means by forming some or
the other group will think that they can live as a group.
and struggle, complete struggle and this struggle
also, they don't know what they want.
There is a Dalit party, someone is a terrorist party
a number of parties have been changed.
But among ourselves we are all human beings -
how did these parties come into being?
There is a huge mystery behind this.
And the secret is that we cannot see the
love of that Supreme Father.
We do not understand with how much love
He has created this Universe.
You people can't make a tree out of a seed,
cannot make a fruit from a flower.
There is nothing you can do. Just think,
how much beauty God has given us
and how much He has done for us.
This, man has forgotten, that the One who made us,
nurtured us - made a human-being from an amoeba,
there is no gratitude towards Him, there is no attention
there is no thought towards Him,
that's why incompleteness has come. And whatever was said
by those people, whatever was told to the other people, either
those who followed them, followed them wrongly.
They made groups out of them and some people said
that, “These are all useless things, there is no
meaning in them - everything is false.”
In such a situation when a person is completely disappointed
and desperate, and full of bitterness,
and in his sight there is no glimpse of the love of God.
Look in front of Me now, little-little leaves are visible
through the fog - how beautiful everything is made.
It’s joy is pouring within. And all this beauty
of creation has also disappeared from our eyes
and we are burdened with a heavy life,
then we do not understand, why is it so?
If God made us with His love, cherished us with
so much joy, He created this universe,
then after all, why did we get trapped
in such a big trouble?
The reason for this is that we ourselves
have got our necks cut/landed up in trouble.
Having necks cut - in Sahaja Yoga, what we call as
Vishuddhi Chakra, which is the place of Virata -
having neck cut means that we have broken off
our relationship with the Virata.
From that Primordial Being of which we are part and parcel,
which is known as God Almighty,
we have broken off our relationship with Him
and have gone astray in our own direction, and in our
own notions and ideas and in our own thoughts,
thinking that this is the only thing right, and
the rest everything that is there is wrong.
At this juncture only, today Sahaja Yoga
has come before you as a Maha Yoga.
You cannot know it by thinking about it, because
I already said that by thinking, you will find
only the thing that is lower than you.
What is higher than you, is the stuff of your imagination.
In your imagination you can think that we are roaming
in the sky, anything, but that is not the reality.
That’s not real, it is not reality, it is not real.
It should be accepted that whatever we think,
that we are such and such,
and this will happen, that will happen, is not real. Then this
must be understood that what we actually found,
found only that which is lower than ourselves, and if
we have to find something that is higher than
ourselves, something has to be there in reality.
And also what should there be in reality,
the Creator has thought about it.
Only He is the doer. He also has the idea/concept. The One
who gave you these eyes, nose, mouth, everything, this body,
mind, intellect, ego, etc all things are given in you,
He will also give you that peg, upon reaching which
you can come to a higher state than this.
With this thought only He has made you a human-being.
But first of all, the intellectual has to think
how far does this intellect reach?
What a limited thing it is, and when it comes to the
unlimited, it is not right to rub the intellect between.
After knowing this infinite, after recognizing it,
as Nanak Saheb has said 'after recognizing it'
then you can understand what are you,
why have you come into this world,
and what work does this living Power of the
All-pervading Lord do, and how does It do it?
Not only this, when the realization of the Spirit within you
happens, then this Power flows from within you
and is manifested.
You must pay attention to this word. This Power doesn’t
speak, doesn’t think, it acts, is manifested.
To speak and to think, is the work of the intellect -
useless – no work is done by it.
Just as you sit in the car and start thinking about it
- will your car move?
Something has to be done. But this Power is such that when
it starts flowing from within you, then it is manifested,
it works. As there is light, it is implemented.
When light is coming from it, then light is visible,
is working, is automatic. Despite doing nothing,
being light it is giving light.
Similarly, such a person, while doing nothing,
can give light and is implemented.
This thing, I think, is said in/for the university because
because the meaning of university is Universal.
But intelligence cannot be universal.
If it had been, it would have happened by now.
Everyone's intellect moves to the same place.
one does not match the other.
So in order to achieve this thing, first
of all, we must humbly admit
that whatever we have known so far is limited,
and in order to know the unlimited, some
happening must take place within us,
some sprouting must take place within us, because today
that we seem so limited, we may become vast like the sky
and cover everything.
In many ways have the elders tried to explain
that the drop should be the ocean.
Now all similies that are there, also the analogies, are
also with the lower things. It’s a very big question
from where to get that also because they can’t
even talk of higher things and those who give
analogies will do with lower things.
And whatever lower things they will give,
will pull you further down.
As soon as is said that, 'You become an ocean from a drop,’
they will say, 'Sir, how can we become an ocean from a drop?'
No matter in whatever roundabout way it is explained,
it cannot be understood, because the one who wants
to understand, is a type of the intellect itself.
When understanding is possible only through the Spirit, then
you tell Me, what can be explained through the intellect.
Like many foreign Sahaja Yogis have come here,
they don’t even know the basic notes of your music -
they know everything about their music. They don't know
anything about your musicology, don’t know
the names of your ragas
but if any pure Indian classical music is played,
no matter how difficult the melody, they get
engrossed in that.
They don't search it’s melody, they don't talk about
it’s aalaapa, but its effect, its work,
develops within them.
Otherwise, if our Indians sit to listen to it, then
first they will ask, "Who’s the one singing, sir?"
Then, 'Which melody is this,' thought comes in between.
To which family does it belong, what is it’s lineage,
(which theka is being used),
but the one who is not particular about this thing,
is just experiencing it with his Spirit,
enjoying it, and the reason for which that melody was created,
that joy, is being absorbed by that person.
The joy with which it was made, that entire bliss,
is being absorbed in him and is manifesting.
All this joy can be experienced by you all
- it's our own. If you say, I will also accept this fact.
If you say, “Why only I’m doing this work?” then I’ll say,
you do it, it’s very good, you must certainly do it.
Then I’m very happy that you people do it,
it’s very good - anyone may do it.
What can be better than this, that someone else should
do the work instead of Me, that's a very good thing.
But it is such, that perhaps I will have to do
this work, for a few days at least.
If you can do it, then you do.
The work is complicated, it is the work of love.
And love is Truth and Truth is love.
This is such a deep love, that in it man immediately
recognizes, what is the problem with others.
There is not the other, it is such an intense love
– everyone is part and parcel of our being.
When there is not the other, whom
are you going to oblige?
And when this love shines on anyone,
then the whole Truth of that person,
the complete is visible (in front).
The whole thing, the complete picture comes
to the fore. In that light you come to know,
what is the trouble in the one who is your
part and parcel – it manifests.(implemented)
You must see in the light of the Spirit, clearly
it should be visible, there should be no mistake in it.
Not just one, everyone who will see, will say the
same thing, that Mother is wearing a white saree.
There can’t be many thoughts in it, there can be no
question of any quarrel in it - there can only be one Truth.
And the only one Truth that is, in spite of
being many, looks the same though.
But no one has known this love till date.
Very few have known, and those who have known,
no one wanted to know.
They harassed them, tormented them and after
their death erected temples, churches,
and set up various gurudwaras, and all other things,
but did not know(feel) that love, which was the
basis of all these things.
In order to know that love, we will
have to depend on the Spirit.
Just as we rely on intelligence to know worldly things,
in the same way we have to rely on the Spirit
to know Supernatural(Divine) things.
Now someone will say whether there is the Spirit or not.
Why have you already started quarrelling?
Why is there such a fuss about it already?
At least see whether it is or not. Now I
have come to prove it.
You could say about the people of the past whether they were true,
or fake - you can say many things about them.
But now I have come to prove it to you,
that within you is the seat of the Spirit
and the Divine, omnipresent Lord
invites you to His kingdom.
This All-Pervading Power is the wave of
love of our Almighty Supreme Father.
Our Almighty Lord has created human-beings only to enjoy it.
Ego may delight a man but he can’t have joy, bliss.
Happiness can be followed by sadness, but in joy
both the feelings of happiness and sorrow are broken and
there is only joy,
which cannot be described in words,
can only be experienced.
But even it’s experience is not from this heart
which you call as heart.
It should not be called the heart because if this is
the heart, then it sometimes makes us cry, sometimes laugh.
‘Hrid’- The one who knows - it is the Spirit. From the word ‘Ri’,
the meaning of ‘Ri’ is energy. Ra, ra, ra, means energy,
power. The One which gives this power of love, is the heart.
Therefore the Spirit, which is giver of the power
of love, or is the knower, should be attained.
So far, if all of you intellectuals reach/come down,
then I can talk of something further.
First come down to this much - it is a very important thing -
because otherwise your intelligence will stand up in between
that, "But Mother, how is it like this." On the
level of the intellect whatever reply I give,
you will not be satisfied.
because it won’t be a complete answer. Although
logically I have brought you to that point
where you will say that,
"Well then, tell me Mother, how to get this Spirit?"
I hope that in all of you
there may have been such a feeling, that whatever
Mother says, there is some truth in it.
Now you’ve asked to speak in English, so if someone
asks questions, I’ll reply in English.
Ask questions, ask anything, you people
are very learned.
Sahaja Yogi: What is the Spirit? What is the Spirit?
Shri Mataji: What are you saying?
Sahaja Yogi: What is the Spirit?
Shri Mataji: Spirit is the shadow of that Supreme Lord.
The Spirit is the reflection of God Almighty,
which may be visible in this human being.
Is the reflection. It is a reflection of God Almighty
in our heart. If the heart is a good ...
[ASIDE - Yes this is better. If it’s a little
lukewarm, then will drink it. No tea.]
If the heart is clean, like a clean mirror,
the reflection is the best.
It's just simple thing, is the reflection of
God Almighty within ourselves.
Seeker: Mother, please tell me whether Kundalini
and the Spirit, are both different things?
Shri Mataji: Okay child, sit down.
Shri Mataji: She has asked Me a question -
Should I tell in English, child?
Seeker: Please tell in Hindi.
Shri Mataji: In Hindi, okay.
She has asked, what is the relationship between
Kundalini and the Spirit. Now I told you earlier,
that Spirit is the reflection of God.
This is one thing. And the power of God,
is known as Adishakti, is called Holy Ghost,
or if you like/want, you can call it ‘Ruh’.
The reflection of this power in a person
is the Kundalini.
As long as these two things do not meet, yoga
doesn’t take place. Yoga means union (unison).
And as soon as this thing happens,
then as if, you understand,
I’ll give an analogy again in a very gross way -
which is a very low/inferior thing -
that as soon as this is connected to the mains,
then just by plugging it into the plug,
it’s connection is established -
so in this we can say, that Kundalini is this,
and the plug is the Spirit.
Now it is a very gross thing, but what to do? Whatever
analogy is given, no matter how poetic it is made,
even then it will be inferior.
There is such a close relationship between
the two/with each other.
She asked me the question, what is the connection
between the Spirit and the Kundalini?
I said, I was telling them in Hindi language a point,
that whatever we have to achieve or we achieve,
or we describe, or talk about, is lower than us,
is not higher than us, because it is done through
our intelligence or through our emotions,
so it's not higher than us, the whole thing
is lower than us, which we can handle.
In imagination you may think of some greater things,
higher things, but this imagination that’s not reality.
So in reality when have to deal with something, in reality
then you deal with things that are lower than you.
That's why many people say that,
"Mother, you are not practical."
Many people say that, "Mother, you are
not practical," because to them it looks as if
I have a very impractical attitude towards things,
because I must deal with the lower things.
Like I said in Bombay that, "I will not pay any black money
or anything. If I don't get the land, doesn't matter."
So they thought I was not practical.
I must say that you should pay them.
By God’s grace, some man donated us one acre
of land, without even paying a single pie.
Sahaja Yogi: There’s another question Mother.
Why is man afraid of the dark?
Shri Mataji: Not all human beings feel.
There’s a question - ‘Why a man is afraid of darkness?’
Not all.... Darkness is sometimes afraid of some men.
This thing is not right. The question is incomplete son.
But one is afraid because - the same thing has come,
hasn't it? That a person is afraid of the invisible.
And in the darkness, the mess that humans have done
on each other, that's why they’re afraid of it.
There are many other things, but the main thing is this
that, when there is darkness inside a man, then
he’s very scared.
When he comes into the light, he’s never
afraid of the dark and darkness.
It's dark inside, dark outside, so there’s too much
darkness. Man gets nervous
that, 'Oh my God, as it is can’t find the way
and on top of it so much darkness.’
But when there is light inside, the outside
darkness is no longer visible.
You think it's dark now, and I'm seeing
very beautiful things in it also.
Seeker: There are such big-big universities
inside our country and even outside, and the
Government also spends so much money
and all the other people together and so many students
are engaged in it, day and night work laboriously
and achieve something. According to You it
is inferior, of a lower level?
Shri Mataji: Absolutely.
Seeker: So this system that You have made,
for it’s arrangement, if there’s any provision
or system, can it not be given?
Suppose someone is curious, has a desire to know,
and even if he’s not, then curiosity/inquisitiveness
could be created in him.
And to turn people that way too, some ashram system
or something of this type that was told before,
such arrangement is there.
Shri Mataji: I am telling about that condition only.
that they went to buy land for the ashram, then the
authorities started saying, "Give black money."
Then they started saying, ‘You give bribe,’ -
while doing all this, 12 years have passed.
Now a gentleman has given the land.
Your President gave us land because I cured him. Thus
they gave us land in the vegetable market where bulls sit.
That's correct. You go and ask. Very peculiar,
insane people roam around the world, tell me.
Now they’ve given in the vegetable market. To this also
four years have passed. From the vegetable market
they took us here and there - this is what is going on.
As long as man's intellect is not proper, till then
I don't think even an ashram will be built.
Ashrams can be built only when people think that they
are needed. Otherwise only deserted universities
will be made here and no one will come in it at all.
That's why, first it should strike a little in
man's brain - it should definitely ring in,
and that's why it will strike man in Kaliyuga only,
otherwise, this thing will not come to his mind.
By explaining like this, no one will understand. You tell Me,
today so many of you people are sitting here,
how many learned people of this university are sitting here,
I mean, not professors but college boys are sitting
Look, is there anyone - one, two, three, four, five, that's it.
Six - six children are sitting - you tell
what should I do now? This university, in this Delhi University
for how many years I have been coming here, let me
tell you - for about 11-12 years.
Got six children in twelve years, now tell?
What should I do, son - from My side I’m working very hard.
Working tirelessly day and night but nobody comes here.
Then if it’s Delhi University, the condition is even worse.
And that which is your Jawaharlal Nehru University,
in that only one person came to listen to my lecture.
I just spoke to the walls.
There is absolutely a great need.
Unless these people are going to get into a lot of
trouble, till then, wisdom will not come into them.
Like, we have a lot of work being done abroad. At Cambridge
University, New York University, in Canada
people are writing our thesis on Sahaja yoga, at three places.
Thesis is being written about Sahaja Yoga.
Would anyone in Delhi University do such a thing?
Would anyone here agree, that on Sahaja Yoga a
thesis should be written.
And even if they write, then such, so superficial,
that the work of Sahaja Yoga stops permanently.
They will say that Mother was sitting down wearing
a white saree, or her so-and-so is this or that,
anything, they will say things whatever superficially they
understand with their minds, as newspaper things go.
Thus there’s a little need that it should hit/strike the
minds of the people here.
Without that, they cannot become sane, I think so.
Son, I’ve been coming here since twelve years, then this
is the condition; From this you can understand.
Now from this you can understand that I have not
shirked from hard work.
And there are many such people here who are realized.
130 people from abroad are also sitting here.
The same number from here are also sitting.
If people from abroad didn’t come, then even
this space would not have been occupied/full.
It is true. What should I do? People are not interested,
there’s no thought in this direction. They think
that they have become great people. What to say!
Sahaja Yogi: There’s a gentleman who writes Mother,
"I failed to join your lectures on awakening of
Kundalini on Muladhara and Sahasrara Chakras.
Sahaja Yogi: My keen desire to learn the same by
tape recorder and I’m leaving to my native place
by 2nd or 3rd of this month.
Shri Mataji: Who’s it?
Sahaja Yogi: Some gentleman.
Shri Mataji: Who’s this gentleman? Alright. There is a
arrangement, that you can take my lectures, which is
taped and you can take from there. Alright?
But you see, My lectures are of no use, if you
do not get your realization.
It’s a good thing, you see, because Mother speaks
well, you see, She’s good at speaking,
so nice to listen to Her but you must
get your realization first, alright?
Seeker: (Unclear – I’ve taken?)
Shri Mataji: You got it? Then you take it
Then it’s alright, then you are my son.
Alright? You take whatever you like.
Sahaja Yogi: This same gentleman writes, " During my 30 years
of experience in religion and yoga, I have
not seen such a eminent person who, who’s got a
vast knowledge of Kundalini. Before I left Delhi
I wish to learn more about Sahaja Yoga and
treatment. I came to Delhi last December.
Shri Mataji: To whom did he go?
Sahaja Yogi: To whom did you go first?
Shri Mataji: Which eminent person did you visit?
Seeker: Mataji only
Shri Mataji: Yes?
Seeker: You only, Mother.
Shri Mataji: What? Which Mother?
Seeker: Went to You.
Seeker: I’m telling about You Mother, I have learned from You only.
Shri Mataji: You learnt it from Me?
Seeker: Yes.
Shri Mataji: Then it’s alright.
Sahaja Yogi: He’s talking 30 years of
experience in religion and yoga.
Shri Mataji: How did you get the experience of 30 years?
Hmm? I started my work only 12 years back.
Sahaja Yogi: He worked overtime.
Shri Mataji: It’s alright, doesn’t matter but you better
take the taperecorder
if you got your realization even today,
you can take it, alright? That's all.
You see, because without Self-realization
it's just a tool in your hands,
but once you get realized, it is a light in your
hands. Alright, that’s why. Give it to him.
You can take. We have got arrangements. Those who
want to take My tapes, can take it.
but you have to be a realized soul,
otherwise we don't give because what's the
use of this cheap popularity.
There's no need to have cheap popularity about
Sahaja Yoga - you have to become.
Here you cannot be just a member, we have no
membership, nothing – this is a living organism.
So, if you become, you have every right
but if you don't become, you have no right.
Just like, you have to be an Indian citizen to
have some rights in this country
– I wonder if we have any!
But here in God’s, in the realm of God, if you
just enter into it, you have all the rights
and He looks after you with every support, with
every help, so much so that you think you have
now lost the meaning of miracles
- every step you will be amazed.
Sahaja Yogi: The same person he has asked,
something about, how to cure insomnia?
Shri Mataji: Kill what?
Sahaja Yogi: Insomnia
Shri Mataji: Insomnia, alright.
Sahaja Yogi: and he says that, ‘I did not understand
last time because of 50% knowledge of Hindi.’
Shri Mataji: Insomnia is absolutely curable. If you
have attended My lectures before this,
I have told you how to give balance to yourself,
but in any case
you come to the centre and they will tell you
how to cure insomnia. It’s absolutely simple.
Sahaja Yogi: A boy has written that, ‘For the
realization of the Spirit whatever formula
or whatever we can do,
please tell, so that that energy can synchronize
or resonate with my body.
I am attending this discourse for the first time.
Shri Mataji: Huh?
Sahaja Yogi: For the first time I have attended this discourse.
Shri Mataji: Okay
Shri Mataji: Whose question is this?
Is it your son? It’s a matter of great happiness.
He asked the correct thing that, ‘I want to
have Self-realization.’ It will be done.
That's enough - it will happen. But when
this energy starts flowing through you
then you have to learn about it, you have to know,
because the yoga has taken place but another meaning
of ‘yog’ is deftness/trick/tactics – skill.
After knowing Yoga, you should understand,
it’s tactics, how is it to be worked out.