I thank you very much, all of you, for coming
over for a small meeting that we are going
to have and, it's very important for you people
who are responsible in life to understand
what is the work of Sahaja Yoga and how important
it is. I mean, now we have people all over
the world, it's working in 85 countries. In
a country like Benin we have twenty thousand
sahaja yogis.
All this is...why? Because people are trying
to find the truth, they are not satisfied
with whatever they know. They want to know
what is beyond and I started this work long
time back. I think I have worked in England
for at least 25 years. But, unfortunately,
England is nowhere compared to other countries.
Even Austria has ten times more people, Austria
and Germany. What's the reason? I think the
newspapers. Your newspapers are not responsible,
they are not at all responsible. Some may
be, I am not saying all of them.
But the newspapers that I have seen here,
they never come and ask me anything, they
never try to find out if there's anything
I'm doing that is good for people, which is
essential, which has to be worked out. But
somehow they take the very negative side.
This is the main reason why people are lagging
behind in knowing the truth. I'm sorry to
say that. I have written in my book also that
you have to be more responsible.
Actually newspapers are now even more important
than any political party or any, I should
say, kingdom or anything. They have achieved
that power by their sense, by their honesty,
by their steadfastness, their sense of honour.
I must say that we got our freedom in India
because the newspapers of England. They are
the ones who wrote the truth about us. They
are the ones who told how atrocities were
worked out on India. It's only they who have
really helped us.
I mean I cannot understand what has happened
to today's newspapers as they are. Specially
I am meaning the newspaper that I have seen,
which is absolutely nonsensical (reference
to 'The Independent' newspaper which had recently
published a negative and incorrect article).
It is talking about money. Doesn't talk about
what good it (Sahaja Yoga) has done. Now I
must tell you I have not taken a single pie
in England. Never! It is only when they came
to India they had to pay for their stay there.
They had to pay, also, in Italy for their
stay there. And whatever remains I used to
use. I have used my money for 20 years. Last
10 years since my husband is retired I'm using
this money. The houses that I have are all
of my money. Imagine these people, they should
have come and asked me before doing. It's
criminal to be like that. The problem now
in England is that they have developed a great
sense of criticism. Just criticise! Now we
have critics of the critics in this country.
But whom are you criticising?
Nobody is creating anything. Have you got
those old writers of England who were respected?
Have you got that level of novelist that existed?
Is there any, any person who can write like
those great writers? I have read them and
I know. I have great respect for them but
were they just the lotuses in a pond, who
were so great. They are the ones who established
democracy here. They are the ones who brought
such beautiful ideas to the whole world and
what are we doing now? What are we spreading?
All kind of malignant stuff.
I have never studied English in my school
because my father was a freedom fighter and
he said "No, you have to go into an Indian
school" Afterwards, also, I never studied
because I was a medical student. But only
reading these things we Indians still respect
you. Because of their intelligence, because
of their clear headedness and also the [sense
of] justice they had. That's all missing nowadays
in the intellectual people. I was surprised
to read in this newspaper all non-sensical
things, given by one boy who is just a teacher,
while Sahaja Yoga is working in 85 countries
and we have scholars and we have great writers,
all sorts of things we have here, and here
one boy, who is just a teacher somewhere...I
am sure he doesn't do it on his own. How can
he afford?
There are only six people who are working
against us. We could have really put them
into jail but we didn't want to. Because they
did something very wrong. Sahaja Yoga is a
very moral society and if they are immoral
we don't want them there. That's all! That's
the freedom we have. That's the independence
we have that we don't want to have immoral
people living in Sahaja Yoga. What's wrong
in that? We believe in morality and without
morality our countries cannot improve. It's
very surprising. They had some IQ. I used
to think they'll have some, also, some heart
but doesn't seem so. And after that now there
is also SQ, is the 'spiritual coefficience',
which you can achieve in Sahaja Yoga.
You don't know what heights you can go to.
But having such stupid things, by one man
coming and telling you something. And how
cunning it was that it was just done before
my program. Why? Why are they doing it? What
is the advantage? What are people going to
gain by that? First time I'm saying this.
I should have said this much earlier I think.
What is the achievement? Why do you write
all those things which are nonsensical? Which
are false. Absolutely false. Why? Is that
racialism? what is it? I can't find out. I
can't find out the reason why these people
are listening to one man who is just a teacher
somewhere and writing all falsehood.
We can pull them in the court no doubt, but
we don't want to, because it's an open thing.
If you want your Self-realisation we are here
to give you. There's no force on anybody,
there's no compulsion on anybody. On the contrary
we are anxious to throw away so many from
Sahaja Yoga! There's a code of conduct, no
doubt.
We have marriages which are very legal and
at the most 1% fail. We are very loving couples,
beautiful children and a very beautiful society.
One has to understand that you don't have
that. You have to get to it. What do you have
to sacrifice? Nothing. It's absolutely free.
My lectures are free. Self-realisation is
free. Now what else? We should offer them,
I think, some tea also free then it would
be better! That's, I mean, I don't know why
in England where we had such great people
right from Shakespeare. Think of them. I can't
understand.
Shakespeare I call him an avadhuta, means
a person who was beyond and was trying to
show all kinds of human enterprises as failures.
Just to show that to make them detached. Such
a great sage like him was born in this country
of yours. But if there are false gurus that's
the best! If somebody tells you lies is the
best!
What is the matter? Where are people going?
In a way it's good that I saw this article.
And all falsehood! About Hitler what I have
said I've brought the book. What I've said
was that...you can read it out. It's very
interesting to see what I have said it. Can
you?
Also today I saw very nice article in the
magazine they gave 'Culture' that what do
we owe to Germans and Beethoven, because of
him and all that. Such a beautiful article.
But who will read that? I think better read
it out so that it's cleared out! My memory's
very good, that's the trouble!
Derek Lee: "So there was a reference in the
recent article in 'The Independent' which
Shri Mataji is now talking about to Her supposed
attitude towards Hitler and towards the Jewish
people. So this is just a quotation from the
book
'Now to all the critics of Hitler he looks
like an idiotic foolish and maniacal type
of a person. Actually if you listen to any
ego-oriented person or see him, you'll definitely
witness the idiocy of his talk or his behaviour
very clearly. Of course, if you are not ego-oriented
yourself. If you are an ego-oriented person
then you will protest against him saying that
he's trying to assert his ego. An egoist can
always find the ego of another person very
easily but if you are a person who is afraid
and frightened of egoists you will either
accept his value system or accept the tyranny
and subjugation of such a tyrant. An evolved
soul would witness the babbling of an idiot
and may get into an enjoyment of humour at
this stupid drama. Hitler's ideas impressed
none of these two types, but he captured the
minds of a third kind, which was innocent,
simple, raw and absolutely immature. The young
teenagers whom he groomed for years. For these
people killing became a great natural enjoyment.
In the olden days people used to go to forests
to kill animals, especially tigers, and as
a result the tiger became a man-eater or attacked
human beings and this killing had to be accepted.
Even when eating the flesh of animals when
sufficient food was not available was quite
justified. Most of the people who went to
the forest for hunting did it just for the
pleasure of killing. This horrible desire
can lead to a very dangerous ending. The horrendous
war in Germany broke out against the Jews
who had to die in gas chambers because' they
were very greedy and cruel' and according
to Hitler they had killed Christ. There were
so many ways in which one could have controlled
these greedy people....
....And so it goes on. It's a criticism of
Hitler and of Nazism"
Shri Mataji: I mean how can I support Hitler?
It shows a complete ignorance of Truth. How
can you write such things in England which
is not a country where all the barbaric people
live? What has upset me is that I have worked
the most in England. Days together. Day in
and day out. Now I'm 76 years of age and I've
been working but really people give up. But
compared to these newspapers, in the smaller
places they're very honest, because they wrote
about me how I cured people, how I helped
boys and all that. (a reference to a miracle
in Northampton in 1982 in which a boy is saved
by Shri Mataji after a fall even though She
was actually in a Public meeting at the time.
That miracle was published in the Local Northampton
newspaper). But they (The Independent) have
nothing else to write but this, that I take
money! I do say that I don't take money for
Self-realisation. Because it doesn't understand
money. Your Kundalini is your Mother, She
doesn't understand money, how can you take
money for Her? Is a fact.
But if you come to Italy and live there five
days you want to do it freely everything to
give freely? Is it? Now we have made hospitals,
I mean, thousand and one things. List hai
na? (Do you have the list?) No? He's not brought
the list. But I mean so many things we have
made. Orphanage we have made for prostitute
women, for destitute women. So many things
we are making on the social level. At least
twenty things in India.
Then in America I bought a land. Hundred and
forty acres of land. Americans are much more
sensible I must tell you. They don't have
this kind of a mental attitude that whatever
is written (in a paper) is law, no. They will
judge it. Otherwise how will you take to Truth?
How will you know the Truth?
My worry is the country which I think is the
heart of the universe. I regard it as a great
country, while what's happening to the modern
people? Where are they going? You should have
been leaders actually, in Sahaja Yoga. I personally
think that way. You are all educated. You
are known for your education and you are known
for your understanding and here what do you
find? How are they lured by falsehood.
The problem now is another one, that, by doing
all this, they will reduce the number of people
who can get Realisation. They will reduce
the number of people who would know the Truth,
who will create a society of peace and joy
and love. This is what they are doing. They
don't understand their responsibility and
they'll drag the whole country into..I don't
know. It's a moral sense you should have to
understand that what have you been doing so
far and what are we to do? Where our children
will go? What will happen to them? They are
taking to drugs.In Sahaja Yoga you just give
up drugs. So many. In England itself there
were seven people who came for [Realisation],
all drug addicts, all first class [now]. Doing
very well. Doing very good jobs. Drug addiction
we can reduce in no time. In Italy I might
start a
hospital for drug addicts. Possible in Italy,
not in England. Not possible. The English
will come there and get there! Can you imagine?
Why this level has come down? If you have
read Pickwick Papers you know how he has described
in the democracy that time. Is that the same
democracy is coming now? For me England is
the same as India, because there are nice
human beings and good human beings, learned
ones. For me it makes no difference. And it's
important that you all should get your Self-realisation.
There are so many English here sitting. How
much money have they given me?
This is a very pivotal point that on such
a small thing like that the whole country
should be destroyed. Why didn't they come
and ask me? Every time there's one fellow
comes up. Maybe he's paid by someone. There's
hardly six people, I know all of them. And
I know why they are doing it because we have
thrown them out of Sahaja Yoga. In no other
organisation people are thrown out, no other.
Because they are wrong, they are doing wrong
things, immoral things.
And such people should form such a good group
for your newspapers here? The newspapers that
used to publish such things about Warren Hastings
(British Governor-General of Bengal, from
1772 to 1785) and all that, and gave us independence,
they are the ones. They are the ones who fought
for the right, fought for the truth, not afraid
of anything. I mean, I think the newspapers
are at such a pivotal position that they can
kill the nation or can save the nation. I
can't understand still. What is the purpose?
The purpose is to dissuade people.
Don't you all want to know the truth about
your Self? You don't want to know? Let it
be. You are free. If you want to know you
can know. I cannot force. It cannot be forced.
It has to be your will, free will. It has
to be your will otherwise it won't work out.
If you try to say that "Alright, raise my
Kundalini!!" I cannot, I cannot.
You must have that pure desire to become the
Spirit. If you don't have, I cannot, nobody
can raise, it's a fact. Because other desires
are never satiable as you know. That's the
principle of economics. There's only one desire
which is satiable is that you have to become
the Spirit, and that you have to become the
Spirit, is said by all the religions and all
the saints. I'm not the only one who has said.
Even if you say Tao, or any other such things,
they say the same thing, that, you have to
become your Self you have to know your Self.
'Know thyself'. Now how do you do it? Is it
not important to know your Self? If not, alright!
But if it is, then try to get it.
Now they told me your all very responsible
people have come here. And all of them have
read the newspaper and all. To me, I can't
believe it. Because you are all educated people.
You read every day the news and you know the
calamities what are following. What's going
to happen to this world? Think of it. With
hatred with killings. What is going to happen?
What is the destiny of human beings? Yesterday
I spoke about that. What is the destiny? Just
to make some money if you put some controversial
thing (in the paper) it's being very irresponsible.
This is what they told me that, they want
to know about the newspaper and this and that,
so I had to tell, but to be very frank, it's
nothing important. We are on the verge of
jumping over with the last breakthrough of
our evolution and there is this Kundalini.
No credit should be given to me. It's your
Kundalini, your pure desire and if it is awakened
and if you get your Realisation then first
you feel cool breeze in your hands. Mohammed
Sahib has said that, "At the time of resurrection
your hands will speak and they tell you what
centres you are catching".
All this knowledge was known to some people
but was never imparted to any, or to very
few. Only one Guru used to give Realisation
to one person. And whatever you read in Tao
seems to be something out of the blue, how
can that be? A saint described there is a
very different type of person. Now, how to
become a sage was not told. Though in the
Tao system they have said there is a mysterious
female energy within you. Respect the Mother.
But they didn't say who is this Mother, what
is this, what is her job.
That way I must say, despite all that, that
Indians are very much near it, because the
whole culture builds that up. We have also
very bad influences of very bad things, but
still, those Indians who have come to England
are not very near this, I must say. But those
who are in India, I don't know why, by changing
the land or whatever it is, very few Indians
in Sahaja Yoga in England. Why? What is the
reason? They'll go to some babaji who'll give
them a story, that's all, finished, in the
morning. Why are they not seeking their Self-realisation?
Only in England! Only in England! What's the
matter? It's difficult to understand. We have
tried. Sahaja Yogis have tried. They have
given up. Why? What's the matter with Indians
when they come here? I think they have become
very money-oriented. Whatever it is. I mean,
in India also there are money oriented people.
I don't know.
According to Indians, the thing that one has
to achieve is Self-realisation. In life that
is the most important thing. That's their
tradition that's their education. How they
are contaminated I don't know. It's surprising.
So what is it that works that way? This is
your country and you should be proud of this
country. You have given freedom to so many
countries. You have done so much of good work
and so many blessings are there upon you.
But be careful now. If you miss the point,
you will miss it.
Yesterday I told (at the Royal Albert Hall)
what is the destiny of humanity. You see every
day wars going, fighting going on, killing
going on. There's everywhere racialism or
anything else. Under the name of religion.
Anything! How human beings have become so
much perverted God alone knows. But now the
time has come to find your way and help the
whole world to come around. You can help the
whole world, you can be leaders of the whole
world, but what I find that nobody takes the
challenge.
Now the positive side of Sahaja Yoga I need
not tell you. You get cured, you also get
materially alright, I mean all kinds of things
there are. You become a nice person, sweet
balanced, happy and you give happiness to
others. We have marriages, we have children
who are beautiful. Our families are beautiful.
One in a million of course they divorce or
do anything, is allowed. Nobody is forced.
But we have legal marriages. First they are
married and then they are registered. Not
illegal, we will not have. As you have here
we don't have. We don't allow other nonsense
like homosexuality, marriage between men to
men and all that -- is absurd!!
They all give up, all give up all these habits
that's the best part of it. Once your Kundalini
rises they all give up all these bad habits.
All this perverted things which are very shocking
and surprising. And they get cured of many
diseases. Hospital they said "You have to
pay" I mean how can you have a hospital [free]?
The building I built but you can't live anywhere
free. And for one bed they charge £4. We
have five doctors working there now. And for
a room which is air-conditioned, where your
family can stay, which has an attached bath
and all that they charge only £12. Is it
too much? Even in India they charge much more.
I mean we can't go on giving free things from
where are we going to do that? But as they
say "cheap, cheap, cheap, cheap". Cheap it
is. It's written. Nobody sees the point. The
reason is you are lost in the whirlwind of
criticism. This is the curse, I don't know
why is this the curse in England. Italy, imagine,
where Pope lives we have at least ten times
more or twenty times more people there. They
are curing people, they are giving Realisation,
they are going in the villages, working it
out. But there must be some curse, I must
say, that you don't see the point. You have
to be satisfied about yourself. You should
know that you don't know the Truth. This is
a very subtle Pure Knowledge of a very correct,
to the point.
Now we have so many doctors, ask them. They
have cured people and they have seen how people
are cured and they all have this knowledge,
what is the problem is, what a person suffers
from. I don't know. It's very difficult, I
feel sorry. Every time they ask me Mother
please come, I come, alright. They are so
anxious I should come, alright, I come, but
every time? Last time also we had a meeting
like this. How many come out of it? Two or
three. It's just a function you know, go to
some party or something like that!! You have
to respect yourself. you have to honour yourself
that you are human beings, highest of evolution,
and that you have to have your Realisation,
you have to have. Why not? Africans are having,
why can't you have? It's your due, it's your
birthright I say. To take your Realisation
is your birthright, but you must respect yourself.
If there's no respect how can I do it?
I am sorry I had to say this because they
told me that they are all more anxious to
know about this newspaper. I said 'Alright'.
What good this newspaper has done so far?
Tell me what has it done? You want to do good
to yourself or no? If you want to do it, you
are welcome, I am here, if you don't want
to do it, you are free. We are independent
people and we understand the value of your
independence. Some things they screw up, tell
you. How can you believe these people? All
this comes because, maybe, they want to make
money. I can't see why. Now you are all intelligent,
educated people, you think it over, you think
it over, what wrong am I doing? Alright, you
can ask me questions.
Question: "Many of your followers meditate
in front of a photograph of you. Some possibly
regard you as a deity and seem to worship
you. Should they regard you as a deity and
do you so regard yourself? And I ask the question
as a Christian believer."
Shri Mataji: "I'm also born Protestant Christian,
and I know Christians where are they."
Derek Lee: "He's asking about the photograph
Shri Mataji, that, sahaja yogis meditate in
front of the photograph and asks whether we
consider you to be a divine personality and
whether you are a divine personality. He's
very direct person Shri Mataji."
Shri Mataji: "It's like confession (laughter).
It is very difficult to be born in those days
and talk about spirituality, very difficult,
but has to be done in these horrible days
only. And only I think I was capable, Christ
would have been crucified much earlier but
I have sustained myself. Photograph, who has
said you should not have, Christ never said
that. Did he? It helps, photograph does help,
what can I do? It helps a lot, it has helped
so many. All of them will tell you their experiences
about the photograph. I didn't allow them,
but they found it themselves and they told
me 'Mother, your photograph is very helpful'.
There are so many miracles that every time
I get so many letters. So I asked one gentleman,
he's a scientist, that you compile them. So
after a month he says 'Mother, now the letters
have come over my head and here also, this
side and I think you better see yourself and
tell me which one to write!' You see for yourself
how it works. It is, you see, it is something,
no doubt. There are prophecies about it, all
over. But to understand it first you get your
Realisation. Without that you cannot. What
is another objection? Have you shown them
miraculous photographs? "
Derek Lee: "We showed them in the Albert Hall
yesterday, not tonight."
Shri Mataji: "Now what are these miraculous
ones. We have not made them, nothing. How
do you see those lights, how do you explain,
all around me? I've told them now that Quanta
Theory is that. Let some physicist come round.
There are two physicists from Russia and one
from Brazil, they are writing about it. It's
the Quantum Theory, that will explain. When
I said something, anything about it, there
are doctors they can research it and find
out. Is the Quantum Theory. Unless and until
you have an open mind you cannot see things.
(Derek Lee talks about miracle photos on boat
in Italy in Sorrento.)
First of all one has to know that problems
are created by religion. Why? Why should any
religion create a problem? Because of our
reactions to the Truth! And Christianity,
because I was born as a Christian, I found
out the reason, what is the reason, why it
has happened. If you come to sahaja yoga you
will know.
Another thing, it's a myth that Christ made
alcohol in that wedding. It's a myth. The
myth is that He went there and He made water
into alcohol. No! It was grape juice. Now
think about it, can you make any wine spontaneously?
It has to rot and rot and rot and the more
it rots is better. Is a fact. I asked somebody
about English, why is it? They said "Mother,
they drink a lot". The best house in a village
is always a pub! You go to any place, [if]
you want to find out about somebody, ask in
the pub! Better than police station they will
tell you "This man lives there, this man lives
there" -- very politely!
Drinking is so much here, baapare baap, in
my book I've written down a little bit. Actually,
one of my husband's friends, very good man,
he died. So he said "You should come" [to
the funeral], I said "I would love to come".
But he said "Must have a full black dress".
"But I don't have full black dress". You have
to have a formal dress for the dead body,
can you imagine! I was so upset and I said
"I am not coming." Then he went there and
he described the whole thing. When he came
back he was so sick. He said "First they had
a lunch before going to the cemetery", can
you imagine? And then they said "Now to go
for dinner back". Everybody anxious to go
to the dinner. Nobody cried or wept or anything.
Only thing you had to wear a black dress!
It shows no emotional attachment! If somebody
dies, it's so heartfelt. Nobody! I
was so shocked and he was very upset because
a friend had died. They said, "What's the
matter are you not well?" They couldn't understand!
There's no relationship of love. As soon as
they die they will jump to find out who has
got what in the property.
Our neighbour was there, he died [and] for
one month, nobody knew he was dead there.
He was alone, poor thing. He was alone and
he was an old man and nobody knew. Then, I
don't know, something, but they said this
had smell or something like that, and the
man who was taking milk to him saw the milk
bottles one after another but he never enquired.
He said, "I thought he's gone on a holiday"
The house was open. This is our feelings are
not good.
This is a country which I call is the heart
of the universe. And also your newspapers
circulate all over. In one of my miraculous
photographs they were singing [the song] "Sitting
in the heart of the universe" and heart, heart
like that [appeared]. Just like the doctors
draw. Many hearts came in. Just imagine! The
proof. But they are heartless people. No feelings
for your own father, for your own mother,
for your own people. I can understand Americans
who are only 200 year old, this thing, but
you are one of the oldest people. Yes doctor?
Brian Wells: "Shri Mataji at the Albert Hall
last night many people experienced a powerful
experience they felt vibrations on their hand
they felt cool air coming from their heads.
Could you say something about why they seem
to ignore this, why do they not understand
that there is something very powerful going
on here"
Shri Mataji: "I can ask you the same question!
I don't know. They talk of baptism and for
that they'll spend so much money, everything,
but they don't realise their own baptism.
I don't know where are they lost. And every
one of them raised [their] hand (to say that
they had felt it), every one of them! You
are a different calibre doctor. I don't know
what to say. I don't know. What should we
do to awaken people to reality? What should
we do? Now as this gentleman says he's a Christian.
There are so many Christians, what do they
do? Go to church? The mayor in Cabella where
I live, he asked me 'Mother what do you do
to these people?' I said 'I do nothing.' He
said 'They are sitting with you for nine hours,
what are you telling them? What are you talking?
What's happening? While' he said 'I go to
church after 15 minutes I start seeing the
watch and after 30 minutes I run away'. You
must get your Self-realisation. Christ has
said 'Know thy Self'. That's the criteria.
Alright? Once you know your Self you'll know
everything. If you don't know your Self where
are you?
I am here to prove about Christ and about
all the great incarnations. How they were
one. And to give you that Spirit which enlightens
your mind. That's what you deserve. That's
what you should have. Not only reading Bible
but reading your Self."
(Somebody in the audience says he's coming
for the first time but his wife has done Sahaja
Yoga for 2 years and he sees that it has done
her nothing but good)
Shri Mataji: " That's the point. You have
to have transformation. There are many who
will say this. And you now come to Cabella
and see for yourself. " (applause)
Yogini's husband: "Is that a personal invitation?"
(laughing)
Shri Mataji: "Actually, you see, it's rather
spartan to be in Cabella because I bought
lots of lands there, but one thing bad about
this authority in Cabella there, they don't
give you a permission to build. So it's going
on and on and on still that permit for me
to build something for Sahaja Yogis. Though
I have bought one house, but this is little
spartan but people enjoy. In a camp they enjoy
very much. India is not that difficult. Italy
it is. And the government goes on changing
you see. So one government gives you permission
another says 'no'. But you will enjoy, come
along!"
Question: "I was reading somewhere that we
are not human beings having a spiritual experience
but we are spiritual beings having a human
experience have you any comments on that?"
Shri Mataji: "Of course. Of course you are.
You are not this body, you are not this mind,
you are the Spirit. That's what you have to
be! And once you become the Spirit you will
know your powers. You become just loving angels.
Very good idea!"
Question: "I follow the Christian faith and
I'd like to ask you what difference you see
if any difference at all between your experience
and the laying on of hands by the elders as
said in the gospel of St.James, chapter 5.
Perhaps you could give us your views on that
please."
Shri Mataji: "I haven't seen anything like
that happening. In Sahaja yoga so many things
happen I must say. I mean I am myself surprised
when they tell me how people are cured. The
other day only, in Italy, there was one fellow
who used to play ...what instrument is that?"
Sahaja Yogi: "Double bass"
Shri Mataji: "Ha! And he, when he came on
the stage, you see, they told me 'Mother you
have saved his life'. I said 'How?' So, his
heart was open for an operation and the doctors
gave up saying that his aortic vein is missing
and they closed the heart and they said he
will die. And he just saw my hand he says,
when he slept he saw my hand. When he was
in a slumber I think. And then he opened his
eyes, still he saw my hand. And he got cured,
completely cured. So many things have happened.
Actually I also don't know my own powers,
it has become like that. So many things like
that. This
is one I'm telling because it's recently.
It happens.
...Finished? Should we have Realisation now?
There's one fellow standing there he's writing
who is he?"
Journalist: "I spoke to your organiser, I'm
from the Daily Mirror"
Shri Mataji: "Ah, nice you have come, I'm
very happy. I hope you all understand your
responsibility as newspaper people. Very important.
They don't realise what powers they have.
They don't realise. Now they are better but,
first time in India, we had some people from
the newspaper and they openly told me, 'Do
you want one column? So you'll have to call
us to one restaurant there and give us a nice
treat. If you want two columns, then you have
to give a complete dinner.' (laughter) I was
looking at them, I said 'Sorry, I don't want
to have even a word from you but thank you'.
But now they have improved. They have improved
because some very important people in India
are supportive of Sahaja Yoga. Very important.
So it has improved. They don't do all this.
I think, now better have our Realisation,
is the best. That's your own. That you should
have. Just put your hands to me"