it is very difficult to describe this
inner joy you can only enjoy it you can
only feel it something so you need to
see that so many of you have learnt this
difficult music and all of you have been
enjoying it I went to various places in
the West and I felt that why even small
little children boys and girls take to
something which is self-destructive why
why do they take to drugs why do they
take to all these things which are
self-destructive I mean I could blame
the chip parents to some extent but on
the whole there was something within
them which was troubling them which was
trying to say that it's not true it's
not the thing it's not the thing that
you want and that's what made them go
into all kinds of various types of
rebellion I should say against all the
accepted truth or accepted goodness or
values and I just thought that of course
in India the parents are rather strict
ever say right but there's one more
thing in India there's a big outlet for
them and I found that outlet was the
talent that they had they had lots of
talents all of them I felt when I talked
to them and this and that I felt that
they have lots of talent but there is no
way to express it
people have been doing some sort of and
haphazard expression right and they
could not understand themselves why they
were doing and this was the main thing
that was lacking I think in the West
that the children had no way of
expressing themselves of expressing
their talent and this talent was making
them mad I think that was making them
absolutely rebellious it was not their
mistake by any chance it was an energy
within which was bubbling and had no
outlet and whatever outlet they had was
not recognised was not appreciated and
this made me feel that if these children
are given an outlet a means of
expressing themselves I am sure they'll
take to it they'll forget all these
things they'll never take to all
self-destructive ideas because they were
angry with them I think and it worked it
worked in the sense that first I wanted
you to start a school for small children
and I was surprised how this children
took to another kind of lifestyle very
discipline style and if they were very
different children like in the West I
found a child supposing you take him to
the shop he'll make you mad because it's
a find me this and buy me that not
understanding that one cannot afford it
and left to himself I would say that he
would go on dying with the whole of the
market so mad about it but I thought
that there was some sort of a thing
that's lacking in him in satisfied on
the contrary in India if you take one
boy or a girl to that market they'll say
Pass was only one one will do big very
big problem I add my own granddaughters
I took them once to Delhi because they
had broken their Chuck Paulson and they
had only one pair the parents have work
to do no problem but one cupful that
will get broken I said all right you
come along now in Delhi you can get good
ones we'll buy from so they came and I
bought for them they said nanny at any
cost will not take the second one we'll
just take one but I said supposing this
breaks and what we have then you will
come back again to Delhi to my chapel's
have one spare at least they won't
listen and they ran away into the car I
went there I said what are you doing why
don't you buy chapel's for yourself why
do you want to waste your money nanny
you can use it for something else now I
was surprised their way they were so
satisfied of course they are born
realized no doubt but also the whole
atmosphere I felt that this atmosphere
if the children from the West can get
they will definitely prosper they'll
definitely express themselves and
they'll become excellent people but I
know the energy was so much after
my brother your Baba mama I asked him
why not start an Academy of vision and
when they came to music I was surprised
I was really surprised when we had not
expected anything from them within three
months within four months they picked up
such a difficult music style it's
impossible it's impossible for Indians
to do that they can never do in four
four months
oh wow I've seen in my own family there
were musicians and my sisters my brother
for hours together every morning is to
get about five o'clock and start them
every day we asked for 3-4 hours every
day I used to think now when will this
end I mean after all if somebody has to
sleep after 5:00 you better stand still
but that's a custom in India to get up
very early in the morning but the way
these people are learning it so fast it
is because that urge to express
themselves was inside very very strong
much stronger than Indians just I can
tell you very clearly I have never heard
of anybody learning this difficult music
in three months and four months four
years together they would not show same
about two people how you have started
appreciating it I just don't know I mean
it's a different atmosphere that has
started so full of hope and joy you see
now there was one fellow who went to
Belgium
he was a Italian Italian sahaja yogi he
said mother I was surprised there was a
nice program with the Indians and the
Indian consulate had arranged so I went
to the program and they were talking to
each other and some of them went out
some of them came in these Indians they
never understood that it was Balloon
Rally when they do guten tag even an
ordinary pillow rock they cannot
recognize me I was surprised that this
Italian that he what he saying is really
I've seen the Indians when they go for
this kind of a very deep type of music
after 15 minutes they start slipping out
also they told me that in England they
went to a music centre or we can say for
the buying of the records or something
so all the boys who were there who were
Indians
we're buying pop music that music and
they looked at these sahaja Yogi's
decide you stupid fools why are you
buying this music this Indian music what
is there in this Indian music this said
is better not to talk to you because you
have gone now you see because some or
other this is a Sahaj trick I think that
your energies tuned up to a very circuit
and deep understanding of this otherwise
it would never have worked like I mean
it is the Kundalini of course no doubt
but their way she is nourished you to
absorb to understand to enjoy this is
very subtle music
and it has happened more with the
Western people than with the English I'm
sorry but Indians don't have that much
of understanding not that much of in
German
Westerners may not injure may not
understand but they enjoy Indians field
those who are a little bit educated in
music will start finding out faults
finding out ragas this was not good that
no but not Western Western people are so
humble about it isn't it remarkable how
is it they have picked up so quickly and
ever understood because they have become
subtler this is the only thing I can say
they have become subtler
and their energies are flowing through
the subtler level surprising from Imam
also for me for everyone that in 3-4
months
how can you play Malcolm's Rock first
time I heard I how can that be
and that gives such a hope to save this
music it may be that in India it may be
declining but in the West its rising is
the other way now the Sun rises from the
east and sets on the west here is the
other way round now for music and I
would request all the Indians to develop
that subtle understanding see say if you
are a honeybee only then you can suck in
Donnie
the Flies cannot so you have to develop
that sensitivity I would say to Indians
I'm sorry to say that you have to
develop that sensitivity with anything
which is possible through meditation and
through Kundalini awakening and
balancing and ultimately getting
connected with this all-pervading power
of Satan because sound is the second
state first was of course they said the
word but it was silent came into sound
and if you can understand the subtle of
the sound within you if you can get one
with it it gives you that joy you will
be surprised I have never studied music
never you see I don't know why but
somehow I never study because I could
not have a guru this is the problem I
couldn't have a guru
so some or other I never studied music
but what I have is the same as you have
now is that subtle enjoyment sense of
music and that's why I say this is
divine of course I also enjoy some pop
you'll recall so enjoy western music
very much and the Western great composer
side no doubt but this music has one
speciality that nothing is written down
there is no composure the musician is
the composer he is the player and he is
the book it's so individualistic if you
see that but today I was happy to see
all of them see this is the western side
of it that so many of them put together
we're singing see like a choir but not
so bad as that in the quiet you see
because I have attended many choirs also
it was too systematic to discipline this
is not here it is complete freedom
within themselves and the whole thing
worked out so well I mean it's such a
good combination of both the thing one
side is the music another side is the
collectivity so I have not said a word
about Baba's University or Academy but I
told him that I'm very proud of
he's very lovingly brought up this
Academy and has that character of our
old guru system which is very important
that keeps the whole place very holy as
you called power and that is working out
is working very hard I know Baba is
working very hard and all of you are
working very hard to help him but this
Academy will definitely I'm sure one day
we'll give that universal knowledge of
that subtle thing I am telling you about
I know it is late today
and tonight I should say but I'm used to
this more because you see in our when we
were young my father was so fond of
music and with position that so many
times we have slept at about five
o'clock in the morning so makes no
difference to me
same I find me new people that you are
the way you are enjoying so we have
great hope of saving our young people
who are going astray people who are
frustrated people who are unhappy
because they have no satisfaction people
who are committing suicide in the
affluent countries also in our country
people who are becoming politicians I
think that's the worst thing that can
happen to it also we have people who are
doing all kinds of criminal things
bring all kinds of violence and
everything all that can be completely
covered with the ocean of music and if
it is done by sahaja Yogi's it would be
such a great emancipation for the whole
world which is absolutely do it is going
to work out so I am thankful to Bob mama
and to all others who are supporting him
in this and I hope you all will enjoy
this music on a very subtle level
because immediately with a mind which
reacts one start discussing arguing
condemning all that's not the way to
understand this music but just to enjoy
enjoyment he hasn't got two sides only
enjoyment signal and that should happen
to you all of you I am so much so much
overwhelmed really by this beautiful
renderings we have had for example now
we had from Oregon I mean I can't
believe that you know Rhonda Barr you
could have such beautiful dancing this
mr. Oren's a doctor who this name is
giving or Indaba
I don't know why it's called on the but
whatever it is it's such a horribly
phonetic man every day he used to kill
so many Hindus and thank God he was a
thin man he was wait in there thread
Jenna you thread how many were healed
you know imagine what a great man he was
and under his name is this or Inaba if
you have to change any name in this
country it should be or ins a man around
about Annie he had no sense of music he
never used to listen to music you know
but he was extremely honest that's
another point about honesty and he would
not take any money for his survival from
the state is to stitch toe piece and
sell them then imagine if you had not
done that and had been a little bit
loving person would have been much
better but from that around abbath comes
this music and gamble I was amazed I
thought how can it be how did they call
it or Anka bod I don't know but he's the
one who hated music how these people be
born there and what dancing they show
also you have seen the Kuchipudi from
Baba's Institute was another one of us
just I hope right these are girls from
absolutely from countries where they
have never known always and in such a
short time to learn such a dance like
Kuchipudi is the most difficult done
very fast my goodness I thought that
what has happened to them
oh you may say mother this is due to
surge whatever it is but sahaja also is
to be borne by you people
now if you have a very small little
candle how much it can burn but these
are
like the ocean of energies and the way
they are expressing themselves is
remarkable of course I love you very
much and it is not out of that love and
admiration I am saying this but it's a
fact
is a reality I I had no idea that one
day a will go that and this global
movement is going to work out wonders
you must spread also the music along
with the vibrations I am sure it would
be really or definite I can't believe I
asked Baha is how how is it is there
only four months time everybody four
months very remarkable then we have one
from Spain I saw him playing Spanish but
Spanish rhythm I don't understand much
because it goes hectic you know it is
very fast sometimes very slow but it's
very rhythmic but is hectic ours is very
much I should say discipline whatever it
is he also is played so well so there
are so many examples to show that you
may be from the western country it's
better to be from the western country
now for music and from this I can't
understand why they say it's a miracle
but why should this miracle work in the
West and not in India I don't understand
though I am sure the Indians are
enjoying this music no doubt because
they are all sahaja Yogi's but you go to
any program
any other program where there are very
few sahaja Yogi's you see that the way
they behave without any discipline the
respect that is paid in India to the
musicians has to be of a very high level
or any talent say even art see also
people who make beautiful things from
their hands all these people who are so
talented are to be respected very much
because it's a special gift God has
given now in India we have got a very
big problem also all great artists but
in - there should say into the influence
of the West and so many of them take
scotch whisky or dizzy - that so many
and their music is finished you can't
even play cricket with Scotch whisky
live alone music and this Western
influence of taking drinks and things
like that has rained our musicians I
don't know what's going to happen I was
quite worried that how is it going to be
retained in this country but now I have
great hopes because if they see the
Western people doing so well see four
against this goes into their heads that
how can they do it oh that was very much
where you can see Western people doing
such good music it's very influential so
instead of having any Indian artist on
the stage we should really bring foreign
it will have a great effect I tell you
on English now it was very shameful the
way sometimes Indians behave in a
classical music programs very simple for
anybody they have no sense nothing and
they go on misbehaving they come there
for social social affair I think that's
all on this point the Indians as sahaja
Yogi's are to be responsible and to see
for yourself how much they have achieved
how much they have understood somebody
who saw them said mother now even in
Indian music if they go ahead of us what
will happen to us but still we have very
great musicians as you have our own apt
a before you I must tell you we had a
program in Pune
that's called a shearing and I was very
tired and so I told yogi what's the
program next one he said some musician
has come he wanted to sing so he has
come I said which musician I don't know
his name but you see yogi I think was
that time not so much music landed
typical Indians time so what are you go
and sleep so I'd lay down and I heard
his voice and I'm hurting I said who's
just seeking I came back I to change my
sari I asked you who is he they told me
the name I said she's a great seeker
what do you understand
how much are you going to pay he told me
such a meager thing I said are you mad
you'll be then I went out and I heard
this great music I heard his guru also
before who was also very great that time
and also got it characterized a guru
bandhu both of them but I was surprised
that none of the Indians could
understand him what he was saying this
Maharashtra is known for music for
classical music but surprisingly it's
not that level now that we had seen I am
happy to see this resurrection of Indian
music through you people that was one of
my greatest desire to get the art
handicrafts and music all kinds of
things which are created through this
talent should prosper and I am very
happy to see that despite so late you
all are still alert and enjoying I can't
say about other artists who have very
much impressed you and impressed me so
this is a very good chance than
particular where we can have very nice
music beautiful views so enjoyable thank
you very much
you
[Applause]