Today I was thinking of telling you about
the ego problem, because I think everybody
feels that that’s the biggest problem they
all have; and there’s a big ego trip one
gets into, and they don’t know what to do
with it.
So first part I will tell you how the ego
rises and how, what it does to us; the second
how to understand it, how to tackle the position
of ego and put it in its own aspect.
As you see in the map here, the yellow stuff
that you see on top is the ego.
The balloon that is yellow is the ego.
You see down below it starts from the Swadhishthana.
This is the colour of the bile within us,
and this Swadhishthana Chakra which is for
our creativity is directly connected to that
ego there.
And when it starts rotating round the Void
and going to the various parts of the Void,
it collects all the problems of the Void.
Void is that green circle within us where
physically we have in the Void, we have uterus,
we have kidney – it’s a complete viscera:
all the intestines, ascending, transverse,
descending colon, liver, is the upper part
of liver more, then also pancreas and the spleen.
So all the problems of these organs are collected
by this chakra which moves.
It comes out of the Nabhi Chakra and moves
round and round and round, and collects all the problems.
It nourishes, gives power, the vital power
to these organs, and also it generates necessary
power for our creative action.
It also collects the fat cells of the Void,
convert it into the proper cells for the brain,
for its use, for the grey matter.
All this work it has to do, one chakra.
It manifests aortic plexus outside.
On the physical level we call it as aortic
plexus, and it has got six sub-plexuses which
look after all these organs.
This is meant for our action.
When we go into action, this chakra starts
working.
By the first power, which is on the left-hand
side, we desire.
But by the second one we go into action, and
it’s called as kriya shakti.
Now when this action starts within us, it
produces the by-products or we can say all
the problems of these organs, which are to
be deposited somewhere, and they are all deposited in the brain as ego.
All the problems that we have out of these,
this creativity and the action of all these
organs are to be counterbalanced, and as a
counterbalance the ego develops.
For example, now I have to come and meet you
all here.
I had to get out of the house, I had to change,
I had to drive, whatever it is, then I came,
I had to put in effort.
I had to plan out how I’m going to talk
to you – that I don’t do normally, but
I’m saying in generally people do it.
And I put in the effort to come in.
Now how am I to justify this, all this effort?
What is the satisfaction that one gets out
of doing this effort, this kriya, this action?
We go on doing some action, and why should
we do it?
After all, action means, any activity means
exertion, botheration, problems, so best is
to sit at home and do nothing of the kind!
But we do not do that, we take up challenges,
we rush up to it.
All this we do with our kriya shakti, with
our right action.
Because we do action, we have to have a satisfaction
about it.
As a reaction to that, ego develops.
If we do not have the ego we would not do
anything – is a fact.
But ego is the one that rationalises all our
madness, the rat race we are running into.
If we did not have the ego we would not go
into this nonsense.
The more we try to rationalise our activities,
the more ego develops to satisfy.
“All right, very good, very good.
Now you are a successful man, see?
You’re a very successful man, you have got
this, you have got that."
Lots of misunderstandings creep in when we
pamper our ego like this – or I should say
that when we are satisfied with our ego – that
we really get lost.
We get identified with our ego and not with
ourselves.
So if you do some work very well: supposing
you have, say, made a beautiful poetry or,
say, not piece of poetry but say you have
made a very good painting, then you would
like people to appreciate.
If they do not appreciate you, you think you
have done nothing, though you have done a
beautiful poem – of a canvas.
But still you will be so dissatisfied with
yourself unless and until people appreciate you.
They must garland you, they must say, “Oh,
you are great, you are really unique, you are a genius."
You know many artist who created great art,
got trapped into this kind of misidentification.
When they created some great art, the art
could not give them satisfaction.
They had to go to ego, and Mr.
Ego would not be satisfied unless and until
everybody says, “Yes, yes, you are very good.
You have done this, you are a genius, you
are this, you are that."
That’s how the ego develops then within
us.
But a situation can arise where even when
we have done nothing, we want to take the credit.
Then we call such a person egoistical who
says, “I will do this, I have done this,
I, I, I, I” – then we call him an egoistical
person.
Because he gives words to his ego, that’s
why we call him egoistical.
But all of us have got this Mr.
Ego there, sitting on our heads.
When it starts bloating, the more successful
you are, the worse it is.
The more you indulge into planning and thinking,
the worse it is.
The balloon goes on, you see, pumped as if
you are pumping a balloon, you see.
The more you pump, the more it becomes.
And you can never realise that you are not
that ego.
Then you start feeling very nice about it,
because everybody says, “Oh, what a great man he is."
The whole society develops on those lines.
Today only I was discussing about the way
people give you “C.O.B." , I don’t know, “V.I.P." and “M.A.D."
like that, and we carry those banners with
us.
And we expect everybody should respect those
banners which have been given to us, you see,
because we’ve done some work, somebody has
recognised us, branded it, stamped it, so
we believe really this must be something great.
So we accept that brand and we want to keep
it up.
So there’s a doubly fixed thing that you
are really rewarded for what work you are doing.
That’s why people start become nuisance
also.
Supposing in a society some people do not
find any significance to their lives.
Then they will go to Oxford Street, stand
there, wear funny dresses, start jumping and
singing something nonsensical, and people
make a nuisance out of themselves.We have
seen people who paint their hair in different
colours, put pencils in the noses, I think,
and do all kinds of mad things just to attract
the attention of others; because we want to
attract the attention of others, because our
ego is not yet satisfied.
But this ego is never satisfied.
It goes on asking for more food, more food,
and you enjoy it too.
When such a ego is bloated within us, we cannot
understand what we are doing.
People can befool you like that.
It’s very easy to befool a person who is
ego-oriented, than to befool a simple person.
A simple-hearted man not, cannot be easily
befooled, because he’s not on a trip, you see.
But those who are on a ego trip, you tell
them that this is the best way to go to hell
– they will be the first booking their seats.
There will be a queue for it, and people would
be asking for it, “All right, if it is so, it’s good."
That is how many gurus in this world have
come forward, have befooled you by telling
you that you will get these powers, those
powers, that will happen, this will happen.
And they know how to pamper your ego.
For example, they might say this is a world
organisation of spirituality, and you are
the head of the world organisation; and you
believe it.
Ego means misappropriation.
You believe in it because you think that “after
all I must be something, and I have done this, I have done that."
But actually what happens physically is then
when this balloon spreads on your head all
over – the aura of the brain surrounds the
heart normally, normally; but when there is
ego problem, then ego surrounds the heart.
And when ego surrounds the heart, the brain
is cut off from the heart.
So you are a non-integrated person, or we
can say disintegrated.
Your heart runs one side, your brain runs
another side, your body runs third side, your emotions run fourth side.
So four people running four horses, and that’s
how you are completely torn.
I mean, it’s impossible to stand on two
stools, but if there are four with two legs, it’s a big feat to exist.
So this kind of ego trip comes in, by which
you start behaving and living in this world
in a very unnatural way.
And if somebody says that “No, not your
ego, not that.
That’s not you.
You have to be yourself.
Ego is not yourself.
Do not be satisfied with this ego,” then
you don’t like it.
Because you are much higher than ego, much
greater than ego, much more than what you
think your ego can do.
With ego what, at the most what can you do,
say?
At the most what can you do with your ego?
What people have achieved through ego?
Nothing.
Whatever they have discovered even in the
sciences has come from the unknown, from God’s
own treasures.
If God has given you some knowledge of the
unknown, you should not feel pampered about
it and think that “Oh, this is what we have
found."
No, He graciously gave you this knowledge
which has come to you, so just take it with humility.
And this ego is very, very dangerous for Kundalini
awakening.
Now you look at the diagram, imagine the whole
of your head is covered with that yellow stuff,
and this blue thing becomes a very small one.
So first of all the desire to seek, itself,
is diminished.
You see, you go for seeking as if you are
going to a cinema hall.
There is no combination of what you are thinking
and your heart.
You are not seeking from your heart, you are
seeking just with your brains.
Because you have read three, four books, there’s
a fashion, everybody is seeking, everybody
is looking as if they are seeking something,
so let us also seek.
It is not coming from your heart, because
you can see that the activity of heart has become practically zero.
You do not desire anything, it is what your
ego desires you run after.
Anything that doesn’t satisfy your ego,
you get upset about it.
One must go on all the time saying that you
are the fastest horse, you are the greatest
person, you are the most unique personality,
then only you are satisfied.
It cuts you out so much from your heart.
That’s why we cannot find joy, because joy
you can only get through your heart. But this Mr.
Ego gives you some sort of a satisfaction
which is very superficial, temporary, leads you nowhere.
With this ego-orientation only you get so
many diseases, as I have told you before,
like diabetes, heart attack, we can say also
cancer could be one of them, arthritis you might get.
You also get with this too much thinking,
paralysis, paralysis is because of that, and kidney failures.
The worst is liver.
Because of over activity, liver is neglected.
We are least bothered about the liver.
If you tell a child “don’t eat chocolates”
in childhood – I mean, it’s an impossibility,
you cannot talk like that.
I mean, I just once said that why not stop
giving chocolates to children, who cannot
digest it because their liver is not that;
or make something that is digestible to their
liver from childhood, till they grow up.
And why not dilute the chocolates also a little
bit more?
So the question comes in then, that “How
can you do it, Mother?
It would be chucking out everything, and children
would protest without chocolates."
Gradually they’ll forget.
The liver problem starts within you.
You become thin, lean, pale, aggressive, all
the time grumbling, grudging, sulking; never
in joy, never in happiness.
You call it tension, stress, all these things
– it’s nothing but over activity of this chakra.
Tension is because the whole of it is covered
with this balloon, and the balloon is still
going on and on and on.
That has to reduce.
Sahaja Yoga is the only way really we can
face our ego, because through Sahaja Yoga only we can see ourselves.
But it is an impossibility with human beings
to face themselves, even after realisation they find it difficult.
For example, all our misidentifications are
there.
Say I’m dealing, say, with English disciples
here.
Before I start saying about the misidentification
of the English, I must condemn all the Indians
of the world, and all the Japanese, Chinese,
Greeks, everybody else, and then I should
say, “There’s also something wrong with
English."
Otherwise I had it!
Unless and until at every stage I condemn
all the rest of the world, I cannot talk of
saying that we also have certain misidentifications
which are sitting on our heads, by which we
are oppressed; we think that this is the correct
way of life; by which we have oppressed others.
And this ego business is so much prevalent
in our society.
Now, with all due apologies, I am talking
about the Western society.
When it comes to India I talk to them, but
now I’m talking to you and think that I am also a Western person.
So I can see certain things as a Western personality.
I don’t feel bad about it.
For in the so-called certain traditions that
we have – today only I was discussing, you
see – like on the table we have to sit for
dinner.
All right, simple thing it is to sit on the
table for dinner.
Now dinner is there because God has been gracious
to us; for our well-being, for our friendship
we are all going to sit down.
But go to any formal dinner or you arrange
a formal dinner, people would sit down, ten
times discussing where is the seat of X and
the seat of Y and the seat of Z.
But if there is a slightest mistake in placing
the people according to their date of birth,
their face colour, their head colour, their
height, their noses, their length, their upper
lips; any difference is there found in the
“Who’s Who” book, you see, that somebody
was placed little higher in M.A.D.
degree – then you had it!
All the good wishes of entertaining people,
of doing some good friendship, of having,
creating something very, very great is all
lost.
All the effort is lost, and you are left wondering,
“Now what have I done?
I did consult all the dictionaries and the
‘Who’s Who.'”
I mean, this “Who’s Who” is another
ego-pampering, you know.
But despite that there was a mistake somehow,
and the person has taken a very big objection that Mr.
X, who is one day junior to him, has been
made to sit ahead of him.
It’s the greatest calamity to his ego.
The poor chairs do not know what happens for
their different shapes, you see!
How much we fight over all such things, pampering
our ego.
So on and so forth, we have so many things.
But if I say “Scrap all this nonsense,”
why don’t you scrap it?
Why to have all this, protocols, this, that?
What is the need to have this seat for this
gentleman, that seat?
After all, if there are ten people for dinner
they can find their seats, there won’t be
a chaos for ten people.
Even for twenty people, even for three hundred.
Why should there be seat allotted?
If you have invited three hundred people,
all right, they’ll all sit down.
If they are remaining they’ll sit down for
the second one or for the third one.
What is the, such a hurry of having that program
altogether, or in such a systematic way that
everybody feels unsystematic after that, everybody
feels disturbed and upset after the program is over?
With all the system, with all the corrections
and with all the great planning we do, ultimately
we find all have become nitwits.
There must be something wrong about it.
And it becomes a frenzy, with mob-like behaviour
people have, you see.
Everybody will come out with very big faces,
“Oh, what a mismanagement, you know, they did this."
What is it?
One can’t even understand what is the value
of these things.
That’s why we have to be like small children.
To them it does not matter where they sit.
And so we are grown-up and matured, supposed
to be mature people also; while children are
still innocent and still ignorant, and still
they have to grow up.
We are supposed to be up-grown: what has grown
within us is nothing but this Mr.
Ego, not you.
When this happens, when this happens in the
worst possible way – you know, today’s
paper I was reading about this Ripper.
Now the conclusion is reached that he’s
not a psychopath, but he is on an ego trip.
He’s doing all this for his ego satisfaction,
because he telephones to the police, he sends
a, what you call a tape to the police that
he should be caught.
He tells them “You’ll meet me here,”
and still they cannot catch him.
So he thinks, oh, he’s such a great person
that nobody can catch him, the greatest thief
ever born who could not be caught.
So that is what you call – he’s not a
psychopath, but I don’t know what name will
you give to such a man.
I mean to a egoist like this, the one who
lives by ego, tries to satisfy his ego, and
if his ego is not satisfied by something,
he doesn’t feel satisfied.
I don’t know what should you call him.
Now, how to overcome this ego?
Because people start seeing gradually this:
it happens.
They start seeing Mr.
Ego, “Oh, very great, you see it’s coming
up, giving me ideas, all right."
You feel sometimes very depressed with the
idea that this is Mr.
Ego I was identified with.
All right?
You see your ego.
Then when you see your ego, then what do you
do with it?
Or if somebody says “Better watch your ego,”
then what happens?
You start fighting it.
You say, “No, I will not say anything, I’ll
just keep quiet.
Let them say anything, whatever they like."
Then you’ll become another type.
You become a person who is suffering from
superego.
So you are left with desires, but do not act,
and you’d say that “Let others aggress
me, I’m not going to aggress anyone.
I’ll be very careful about non-aggression."
But by this kind of a thing, what happens
that when you raise the left side – I mean,
left side which goes up on the right-hand
side, superego, it presses the ego down but
again is bounced back, and there’s a kind
of a bouncing going on.
By this behaviour when you fight your ego,
the ego sits on your head much more.
The more you try to fight ego, it sits on
your head.
You are not to fight it.
Supposing you take a balloon and start hitting
it, it will hit you back further.
Go on hitting it, it will go on hitting.
Now, which is the way to deflate this ego?
How do we deflate a balloon?
In the same manner, take a pin and give it
a prick.
You just look at yourself, say, “All right,
Mr.
So-and-so, now how do you do?” and you laugh
at yourself.
You said, “Oh, you were very unhappy, you
see, when you saw that you were not placed very much.
All right, now have a pin from me!”
And that’s how you deflate it, by seeing
it, by all the time making fun of it yourself,
and piercing a pin into it.
Not by deflating, in the way people say that
you deflate the whole thing by pushing it
down or by killing it, but actually just making
a hole in it.
In the same way, if you start looking at yourself,
and make fun.
Human beings only know very well how to make
fun of themselves.
No animals know that.
If you learn how to make fun of yourself,
your ego will go down.
Otherwise this ego will suggest whatever you
are doing is the best, “This has to be done,
that has to be done.
I am the best, I am doing everything good."
And you might be torturing someone, aggressing
someone, you might be just playing into the
hands of ego like a madcap.
And you might be a real madcap, but you don’t
know that you are.
Because with ego a person becomes successful,
so-called, he becomes very brilliant, shines
out, in competition he comes up; and nobody
dare say a word to him, otherwise he’ll
have punch on the nose, you see.
So also he becomes very mighty and powerful,
and everybody hankers after such a behaviour and such a thing.
But a time comes when he realises that “I
was hanging in the air.
I forgot my basis, and now I have to come
down,” like Humpty Dumpty sat on a wall,
and they had a great fall.
Such a beautiful … this thing is, written
long time back.
And all the men … all the king’s horses
and all the men could not put Humpty Dumpty
back again into its own shape, you see?
So don’t be Humpty Dumpty, and don’t live
with that idea of being a Humpty Dumpty.
Is a simple thing to fight your ego.
And that happens very often in Sahaja Yoga,
is a very common happening in Sahaja Yoga
where your Kundalini itself, you see, creates
such situations that you are flabbergasted at your ego.
You don’t have to judge others, just see
yourself, because it is for your own good.
If somebody is egoistical it makes no difference
to you.
Or non-egoistical, makes no difference.
Only thing is, you should really see for yourself
what is good and what is bad.
That’s how it works out.
Otherwise, as I always say that when I give
a lecture immediately we start thinking of
somebody whom we think to be egoistical.
Actually I’m saying to each one of you to
see it, would be a better idea.
Now this ego when it covers your entire head,
the complete Sahastrara which is shown there,
the white area gets covered.
Your brahmarandhra, the portion from where
the Kundalini has to pierce also gets covered.
It’s very difficult, the whole thing is
covered and this is small here, the gap is here.
Now you cannot open the gap here.
You have to open the gap here.
So this has to go back like that, and this
has to come up in the centre like that.
Then only Kundalini can come up.
So what happens at such stage, you will find
such people have a left hand very weak, and right hand throbbing.
So you raise their left, put to the right
side.
Again raise their left put to the right, again
raise their left put to the right, so you
bring down the ego like this.
And once the ego comes down, then this comes
up and the gap comes in between, and then
you raise the Kundalini in the centre.
Kundalini will come out, and then you tie
it up.
This is Shri Vidya.
This is the knowledge of Shri, of the Holy
Spirit.
All other knowledge of where you have to sit
in protocol, what you are, is all avidya and nonsense.
Reading “Who’s Who” I don’t know what
you will become, monsters or maybe some sort
of a Frankenstein-style personality.
This is the vidya, Shri Vidya is the secret
vidya of the Holy Ghost, by which you balance
your ego with superego, your desire and action
should be equal; and then raise the Kundalini, put it up and tie it up.
All these days people who been realised souls,
great people, have tried to point out the
problems of ego, have talked to you.
They said, you shouldn’t have ego; ego is
the worst thing, one should not be identified with ego, and all that.
And as soon as they have said it people have
started just finding out how to do it, and
in doing so they have become great “gurus”
– themselves egoistical.
The fact is, you do not do anything.
This is not ego, but is a mirage of ego that
you have got.
You really do not do anything – everything
is done by God.
He is the Doer, He has the great Ego.
Your ego is just a copy, made artificially.
Like He creates the flowers, and you make
plastic flowers and say, “Oh, we have created flowers."
He does everything.
It is He who expresses His ego, while you
feel you have done something.
It happens to you when you get realisation,
when your Kundalini pierces the brahmarandhra,
then you find the power flowing through you.
And when you put your hands at somebody you
find the Kundalini rising there, and then
you find that you can feel the centres of
that person and catching of his centres, and you’re amazed.
You said, “Mother, how is it?
Just now was nothing, suddenly what has happened
to me?”
Because your ego has subsided and has become
one with that of God, and you are giving vent to that power of God.
You are playing the role of an instrument,
of a hollow personality, and through you is
passing the power of God which is doing the
real work, while you are thinking “I’m
doing it,” without getting realisation.
But after realisation you just feel, “Oh,
it’s flowing through me.
I can see it flowing, I can see it working,
it is …” You’d start talking in third person, you don’t say “I."
You just say, “It’s going, it’s coming,
it’s not there.
This is catching, that is catching."
It is in the third person you talk.
You do not say “I am catching."
You do not say also that “I have risen the
Kundalini,” you say “The Kundalini has risen."
Who has risen it?
You never say that you have raised the Kundalini.
You just say, “The Kundalini has risen.
It is not coming up.
It’s just going there,” as if you have
become an instrument of some power which is flowing through you.
And this is how we become one with that, and
all our karmas dissolve into akarma.
Karmas are only the effect of our false idea
of our ego.
When there is no ego, where are the karmas
going to be?
If there is no one who is doing and the doer
is lost, then who’s going to do the karmas,
and who’s going to take the load of the
karmas upon themselves?
Like when there is an organisation, then it
says, “I have got assets and I have got
these debts, and these are the things,”
you see.
But the association or that organisation disappears,
then who has the debt?
In the same way, you as ego disappear, and
there is no effect of your karmas – all finished.
All that was when one Mr.
Ego was there.
When Mr.
Ego has gone, all liabilities have gone with
him.
We are something different now.
Now we have become the Self, the Atma.
And when we have become the Atma, then we
are one with that Universal Being, and He
is making us do everything.
Like My fingers don’t have ego that I’m
doing something and I’m touching the thumb,
because it is a part of this body.
Our nose does not have an ego that it is something
special which is breathing.
We say “I breathe,” we don’t say “this
nose breathes."
Neither the nose would say this mouth with
which we eat food, it never says that this,
“I eat because of my mouth."
When you become one with that whole, then
you just feel that the whole is working and
we as part are working with it; and all the
responsibilities are finished.
This is a little talk about ego today, because
I felt I should tell you that in Kundalini
awakening so far in the West, we have always
faced this problem of ego.
Also of superego; those who have been to the
gurus have been possessed by their gurus.
And these come as a relief to ego-oriented
society, because you have been, a horse has
been running, all right, and you have been
running on the horse.
So somebody comes and says, “All right,
now, I’ll tie you up to the stomach of the
horse and I’ll be sitting on the horse myself."
This is the possession part of it.
So you feel relieved, you know, quite relieved:
after all, you don’t have to ride the horse, you don’t have to jump.
And the rider becomes somebody else, you see,
you feel also that there’s no responsibility, the rider is doing it.
But after some time under the belly of the
horse, you start having all kinds of physical problems.
With superego you have physical problems.
That’s why is better to have superego than
to have ego, because you know you don’t
want to have any more of physical problems.
But if you have ego you never get physical
problems, or physically you may improve; you
know, you feel very fine, on top of the world,
you see.
That is the biggest problem.
But you get mental problems: you can’t sleep,
you go on thinking, thinking like mad, you cannot stop thinking.
You go on arguing that it should be done.
You think that everybody should do your work,
while you are the most important person ever born.
So we have only one choice left, is to be
in the centre, to watch your ego and superego.
For all the Sahaja yogis who are realised
have to watch themselves, not others.
You should not expect anything of others,
just expect something of yourself for a change.
With ego you do that and expect something
of the others, in superego you do for others.
But in Self-realisation you emit your Self
as joy, love and beauty.
May God bless you all.
Now, should we go in for vibrations and realisation?
Now for the new people I would request if
they can take out their socks it would be
even better, they’ll be freer.
Put both the feet on the ground, and sit in
a most relaxed manner.
Now as you must have understood, it is a happening.
You cannot force it down, you cannot work
it out, it has to happen to you.
So no effort is to be put in, nothing.
You just leave it, it works.
Put your hands just like this, in a very relaxed
manner.
Even for Sahaja yogis it is very important
that they should go on exposing themselves
more and more to divine Power.
And then when the Kundalini pierces the fontanel,
you’ll immediately start feeling the cool
vibrations in your hand.
But it happens in many various stages in many
people.
For example, some people may not even get
the rising of the Kundalini at all – some people, very few.
With some people it rises halfway, again falls
down.
With some people it gets caught up in different
chakras, centres which are not all right.
With some people there may be physical problem,
so you might feel some heat coming out.
Specially with liver you get the heat coming
out, lot of heat is there with the liver.
And with some people it could be very cold.
Both things are not all right: you have to
be in the centre.
If you start feeling any cool in the hand,
then it’s perfectly all right.
But if there is, say, a hot coming in the
hand, doesn’t matter, you can just throw
it away and it will work out, in case it is
hot.
But if there is trembling in your eyelids
when you close your eyes, then please open your eyes.
Kundalini moves up in everybody, it works
in everyone; only thing, it has reactions
according to the person who is facing it.
So if there is any reaction, or if the Kundalini
doesn’t rise, there’s nothing to feel bad or argue about it.
By argument if I could do, I would take you
to courts and argue there things.
But by argument I cannot do it, you see, it
has to happen in you.
I’m anxious that it should happen, in the
same way you should be also anxious that it should happen to you.
There cannot be argument about it, you see
– it’s a happening.
How can you argue about the sprouting of a
seed?
If it does not, you cannot argue with it,
you see?
It has to sprout.
It’s as simple as that.
If it is not sprouting there’s something
wrong, all right?
Then those people who are realised who know
this, those who know Shri Vidya know how to
raise it, and raise your Kundalini, tie it
up and all that.
But even that, people have objection.
They don’t mind becoming naked and dancing
and doing all sorts of nonsense, but if somebody
raises the Kundalini and ties it up, they
don’t like it.
There is nothing to be afraid of Kundalini.
Somebody told Me the other day that English
people are very afraid of “Kundalini” word.
Now some English people who went to India
came by the back door, I believe, met all
kinds of horrid people who had no right to
talk of Kundalini, who were unholy people,
unrighteous people: naturally they had very
bad experiences about Kundalini.
As I say that some villager comes and puts
his fingers into the, into the holes of two
plugs and says that electricity is a horrible
experience.
In the same way it might have happened to
many, but there’s nothing to be frightened of.
It works out very well, and it gives you what
you are asking for.
She is your Mother, eternally your Mother.
She loves you the most than anybody can love.
She’s not going to give you any trouble.
She’s just waiting for you to have your
second birth.
So there’s nothing to be frightened of anyone.
And also about gurus, you shouldn’t quarrel
with Me.
If your guru is all right, I will Myself write
a nice letter to him.
But if he is not all right, he has ruined
your Kundalini, he’s ruined your Agya, he’s
ruined your chakras, then I have to tell you
that something wrong with the fellow, because you do not know.
Supposing there’s a policeman, he comes
to your house and he says there has been a thief in your house.
Do you get angry with the policeman?
In the same way you should not be angry with
Me, because if your guru is a real guru, satguru,
then I would really worship that man, I’ll
be really happy; but I have yet to come across
– they are very few, very, very few.
So what’s the use of being identified with
your guru?
He never gave you your powers, he was just
showing off his own powers, and was promising
you that today you’ll become a frog, tomorrow
you’ll become a bird and third day you’ll
become a fish, and then amoeba, I think.
You’ll end up as amoeba, I believe!
[Comment from a yogini]
Otherwise they – she’s saying, another
thing they can tell you: if they don’t give
you anything, they’ve taken away all your
money and everything, that you must, you see,
you must detach yourself from your money,
your family, “Send your wife over to me,
I’ll look after your wife, you be detached,
you see.
Give me all your money, everything very nicely”
– still she’s saying that.
Then also you say that “Still, sir, I have
given you everything, still I haven’t got it."
So they’ll say, “Now you go to Himalayas.
Otherwise that’s the reason, you’d better
go to Himalayas.
Give me your palatial building, I’ll live
here very nicely.
Give all the money that you have, and you
go to the Himalayas.
And you’ll be an unmarried man, that’s
a better, you’d better divorce your wife.
You see, she’s the one who is standing in
your way."
And he sends you to Himalayas to freeze there
and to die.
[Yogini comments further]
She says, “Where is the pure person?” ….
She says, “Among ten thousand, You are the
only one."
No – even if they are not pure, they should
not be sinister.
You are much greater people than they are,
because you are not realised, you do not propagate
anything, you do not preach anything.
These are not realised, nothing, they have
no authority.
They have nicely have their flags on and they
are collecting money.
Fundraisers!
All right, put your hands towards Me again.
Take out your sock, socks.
Now, it’s all right.
Put both the feet like this, put your hands
like that.
(You want some water?)
Close your eyes, please close your eyes.
Now, the first thing that happens is if you
watch your thoughts, there is no thought in your mind.
That means it has crossed the Agya.
Sahaja yogis must go in a chain.
All of you hold each other’s hands, all
of you each other’s hands you hold.
Not you, not – the people who are realised
already, who are.
You just hold each other’s hands, that’s
all.
Put your hands like that, yes.
Close your eyes please, all of you.
Please close your eyes.
Are you getting cool breeze in the hand?
No.
Yes, close your eyes, it will work out.
It has to work out, is the point.
It will work out, you just don’t worry.
Some of the Sahaja yogis are getting more
on the right, I think, less on the left hand.
Should put their left hand towards Me, right
hand up, in case such a situation is there.
Feeling something?
Hot.
It’s all right.
(…) make straight, straight neck.
Make it straight.
Not it will, backwards, just make it straightforward
(…) Those who have come for the first time,
those who are getting cool breeze raise your
hands.
In the hand.
If you are getting cool breeze in the hand.
Good.
Both the hands?
Very good.
Please put down your hands.
Left, left, not right so much.
Right hand is the problem, what’s the problem?
Right hand is it?
Alright, where is your father?
Do you write to him quote often?
No?
Now you promise Me that you’ll go and write
to him a letter.
Alright?
Just promise.
Put your left hand on here, yes, and now you
promise, put your right hand towards Me.
What are these rings you are wearing?
Better take them out, is better thing.
Is to take them out for the time being.
And also your kala take it out for a while.
Just for five minutes.
You are getting something cool in the hand?
Nothing so far?
This gentleman here, are you getting any cool?
There only, not in the fingers.
It will work out, it will work out.
What is he catching?
Just see.
Tell Me.
Vishuddhi.
You are smoking something?
Vishuddhi is very catching.
Now can you take out?
No, it’s alright, forget it.
Forget it now, let’s see.
Alright, it’s alright (hindi).
That also.
Accha.
Better cut it out.
Alright, put your hands towards Me.
Put your hand, left hand, here.
Since when are you getting this spasm?
Since you have come to this country?
Alright, just push it like that.
Still Vishuddhi’s there, is it?
Just come here Marcus, come.
Just work out his Vishuddhi.
(Sighs) This is his Agya and this and that.
Now, have you been to any guru or someone?
(Just Vishuddhi’s here… Vishuddhi..)
No?
For this, but not to any guru as such.
She’s great, I tell you, she was teaching
Me, She was telling Me that Nabhis are catching
on both the sides.
And what about (…) what are the chakras
catching?
You’ve been to some guru?
No one.
Have you been smoking?
You too smoking.
Are you alright?
Are you getting cool breeze in the hand?
Are you relaxed?
Keep your eyes shut, it’s the greatest thing
that can happen to anyone, just keep your
eyes shut.
What about you?
In both the hands you are now getting?
Both the hands?
Nicely.
Good.
What’s your name?
What’s your name please?
Nick.
What country you belong to?
Cyprus.
Cyprus obviously (says something inaudible).
And this lady comes from what country?
England.
Great.
From which part?
(Essex)
Very good.
You have not gone to any guru or anyone I
believe.
That’s good.
So what do you do?
You are a housewife?
(Lady: Psychology)
Still I must say you have maintained yourself
very well.
Otherwise when the psychologists come here
I have such a problem with them.
They are themselves suffering from psychology.
(To a child) Yes, come here, come, come, come
to Me.
Let him feel the chakras which is catching.
Are you better now?
Not yet.
Vishuddhi…
Are you alright?
Freddy?
Getting it?
Good.
What’s it?
Left.
Did you go to any guru?
No one.
Smoking you also?
Not much.
Put your hands there and one hand outside,
just see.
One hand outside like this.
Good.
(Hindi)
Better.
Vishuddhi is terrible.
Good.
Are you better now?
Starting.
Got it.
Better now?
It’s improving.
Yes.
It will work out, it will work out.
What have you been smoking?
Something wrong?
Hashish.
(…)
He feels the vibrations (…) Heart.
Now, Nabhi.
Left.
Now how is it?
How is your brother now Mark?
He is out of intensive now?
Then it’s alright.
Better.
How do you find the gentleman sitting before
you, just see, here.
And the lady there.
They’re alright.
Do you live in London?
Essex.
You have come all the way from Essex today?
Oh, I see.
In this London university?
Oh I see, I see.
Now, is better now?
This gentleman, are you better?
Anything whatsoever, nothing.
Warm still.
Alright, let it pass out.
What about him?
Much better now.
Alright, good.
Just see him, let’s try.
Still left, left Vishuddhi.
Left, here is left.
You are the one who has really helped Me the
most of all, I tell you.
So bring your friends also with you.
What about her?
He feels right heart, let’s help him.
[Yogi: Left Swadhishthan]
Go and ask him to ask the question about Shri
Rama.
Are there new people?
Have they got realisation?
Warm.
Put the left to the right, you’ll be all
right.
Who’ll come, who..
These two are realised souls, aren’t they?
So they must, they must come and see here,
you see, come and see things there, come along,
one or two, come along.
Come along, come along.
Put yourself into bandhan.
(Shri Mataji laughs) Now come along, make
effort, yesterday you asked Me that – come
along, make some efforts now.
With this gentleman first of all.
Alright, try on her.
She too had hashish so better try on somebody
else.
Now you don’t do on that.
What about you?
Come along.
What’s … Don, allow these people to work
on you.
Come along, you, come along there.
Be careful Don.
Work on her, those people who have not had
hashish.
Marcus had hashish (laughter, She laughs).
Oh I see, so did you smoke cigarettes?
Ah, you too.
Cigarettes and hashish.
What else?
That’s all?
No, you have been smoking cigarettes and hashish.
Both you have smoked.
Both have today also, before just coming before
here.
Constantly.
Alright, you put him left to the right, all
of you, come along.
You’ll be alright.
Once you’ll find your Self you won’t smoke,
at all.
You’ll enjoy your Self (…) You all go
up to the, you see, this place.
(Yogi says that a female seeker’s father
died)
Tell her to tell her father… she has to
tell the father that he shouldn’t worry
about her.
Did you ask the question?
Now are you better?
Not feeling much in the hands.
Alright.
Still.
Alright, just come, alright?
(Hindi. Then probably to a child) Sit down, sit down,
sit down, sit down.
Yes?
Good.
Better now?
Now rub My foot.
Now let’s see.
Yes, rub it.
Rub it hard.
Really hard.
Hard.
With your fingers.
You too.
Press with both the hands, press with both
the hands.
Void is caught, catching, Void, Void catches
with this one, the left Void.
Ah!
Are you relaxing now?
(Seeker says yes)
Very well.
(Seeker says he is feeling suspicious)
You are suspicious of?
(Seeker: And frightened)
Suspicious and?
Shri Mataji: Frightened of whom?
(Seeker: You)
Me?
Why?
I am not as bad as hashish is!
Why are you frightened of Me?
(Seeker: I had another guru)
Who is he?
(Maharaji)
Who’s Maharaji this… you were not suspicious
of him?
(I’m suspicious and over it)
That’s correct, that’s good, that’s
very good.
(It’s good to be suspicious of everybody)
No, no.
You must know who is the right and who is
the wrong type.
If you are sensitive you will know yourself.
What do you expect is to get your own powers,
isn’t it?
To become your Self, that’s what should
help you – not all other tricks of giving experiences and this and that.
You have to become your Self.
Isn’t it?
Like all others said.
Now, there’s nothing to be suspicious about.
I have not taken any money from you, nothing.
Nothing selling here.
See?
Alright?
Now, you are asking for something great, something
Self-realisation I am talking about, no experiences,
it’s self-realisation.
Yes?
Now rub it on the Void, here.
(…)
Better now she?
Agya?
She’s never been to a guru she said.
You did some pranayama also?
Pranayama?
Breathing?
(Breathing, yes)
(To a child) Just see, just see!
Is he alright?
Really?
Where is the problem?
Come, come, tell Me.
(Sahaja Yogi: Sahastrara catching)
He said I’m doubting.
Suspicious.
(Yogi: Sahastrara, heart)
Heart also.
Hold your breath.
Good.
Again hold your breath, hold your breath.
(Yogi: The Sushumna has a hole…doesn’t
flow)
Hole?
How long were you his disciple?
(Seeker: Four, five years)
And what did you get out of him?
What did you get?
Nothing.
(I never mistrusted him. I still don’t completely mistrust him.)
You do not mistrust him.
(No, because I don’t know if he has done
any harm and I don’t know if he does any harm)
He hasn’t said anything about hashish and
cigarettes and why you…
(Yes, he said I shouldn’t, it’s since
when I was first his devotee I didn’t smoke).
Now you started smoking after becoming his
devotee.
So this is the achievement.
See, if you have found your Self you enjoy
your Self so much, alright?
That you just don’t run away from your Self,
minimum of minimum, that should happen to you.
(Yogi: Mooladhara.. And His Kundalini doesn’t move)
Doesn’t move?
(No, I can’t feel any movement, sorry)
See.
This Raktabija’s…