[Music]
[Applause]
the Purandar Felicita Adela giusti
Humana Casa Grande equally Kevin Owens
Valley so not evil
wrong effective no popularity
proprietary a Kahlua committing just
easier not a super cute assistance of
taco Peralta he recorded El Malecon Mesa
love arrived at zero level to ado
Pellicano sensible proper been lock on
oceans
Ella practical
[Music]
[Applause]
under despair
he'll record the clinically to tell a
story la Via del Tamura Delta P Rita are
Sempra mean to
[Music]
[Applause]
la sol La Joya Peru Omo Ellery cerca de
la varita sensitivity ooh la vita Valley
espera de tomar un giorno la varita
[Music]
man doesn't stand before ever
his nullification once there will be a
reaction and I see I see it setting in
you know when I think of my patients
they all seek their own existence and to
assure their existence against that
complete atomization into nothingness Oh
into meaninglessness man cannot stand a
meaningless life to achieve in our
evolution this is what we have to jump
into to become the spirit is told by all
the Scriptures not only India everywhere
if you take Tao if you take Zen if you
go to the Jewish or to the Christian
philosophies or to the Islamic
everywhere it is said that you have to
be drunk yourself you have
self-knowledge for many thousands of
years the secret was known only by a few
there is a force within and you were
born with it
they call it Kundalini it lies down in
the sacrum bone at the base of your
spine then the Kundalini is awakened it
rises through your spinal cord
how can you know the meaning of your
life if you're not connected to the
power of the creator
you feel as a cool breeze
[Music]
you