So we have decided, we have decided to have
the puja after our dinner because Shri Krishna
was born in the night, about twelve o’clock
while I was born twelve o’clock in the daytime,
same with Shri Rama.
And also Christ was born twelve o’clock
in the night.
I’ve told you that today I’m going to
tell you about Gita.
That is the second part of Krishna’s life.
So different and varied that some people,
intellectuals as usual, say that the Krishna
who played as a child in Gokul was different
from the Krishna who was the king of Dwarika.
So when He became the king of Dwarika there
was a war between Pandavas and Kauravas, one
representing the good people, another representing
the bad people.
So they came to ask Him if He would join on
their side.
So He said, “I’ve got My army and I Myself,
so whichever you choose you can have.”
So Kauravas said, “We’ll have your army,”
but Pandavas said, “We’ll have you.”
And that is how the war started and in the
war His greatest disciple was one of
the Pandavas called Arjuna.
And Arjuna asked Him to fight for him.
He said, “I will not take any weapon in
my hand but I will be your charioteer and
drive your chariot.”
And when He was driving the chariot it so
happened that
Krishna saw Arjuna’s depression.
And Arjuna said, “What is this war?
Why should I fight?
I’m fighting my own gurus, those who have
taught me all the vidyas of the battleship,
battle, and also the vidya of archery and
I’m fighting my own cousins.”
So Shri Krishna said that, “They’re already
killed, they don’t exist, they’re already
dead people, because they’re not realized
souls, I’ve already killed them.
So you have to just play this drama of killing
them.”
So the foremost contradiction that people
present about Gita is that those who read
Gita should be vegetarian.
Krishna told, Shri Krishna told Arjuna that,
“You kill them.”
Human beings, his own relations, his own cousins
who were bad people.
What about chickens and goats?
But all those who start reading Gita in India
give up all meat eating and take to vegetarianism,
or they fast.
So how contradictory these things are.
So He never preached vegetarianism, at least
in Gita.
And He asked Arjuna to kill.
In the modern times there is a war going on
between the evil force and the good.
You don’t have to kill them; even if you
give them bandhan they’re already dead,
they’re not realized souls, they’ll be
all neutralized.
But you have to kill them in the sense you’ve
to kill your connections with them.
Like I see many people who come to Sahaja
Yoga, “But my mother is not yet a Sahaja
Yogini, so she troubles me, how can I do Sahaja
Yoga?”
For anything else they’ll fight the mother
but not for this.
“Kill your attachments and your relations.”
That’s what He said, if in case they are
troubling you in your ascent.
This is the message of Gita to begin with.
But on the contrary I’ve seen there are
people in Sahaja Yoga who once they get married
want to get out of Sahaja Yoga, take out their
husbands or take out their wives or want to
live away and want to be non-collective.
So you have to kill.
There are , there are six enemies
human beings have but in the modern times
they have multiplied, I think.
The first one is the lust.
Kill your lust.
The lust that is today finishing the West
more than the greed.
So first is to kill your lust.
Then kill your anger.
There are certain people who have a built-in
response that as soon as they see somebody
they get into anger.
If a white man sees a black man he gets into
an anger, a black man sees a white man he
gets into anger, surprising.
I mean, God has made all kinds of things;
the life would be boring if you all have the
same parched skins, all of you looking the
same.
So he has made different types of beautiful
people.
But this anger can come from any source.
This is what it is when you kill anger, actually
you kill all your connections with the past,
the responses, the conditionings you have
had.
Then the vanity that people have; I find it
much more when I go to places where people
call themselves bureaucrats or they’re “in
charge,” like matrons telling people what
to do, “Do this, do that, do that.”
This is the Krishna’s finger, using Krishna’s
finger on others.
The vanity, the vanity that you are perfect,
you are perfect, “Nothing wrong with me.”
You are the best people, English think they’re
the best, Germans think they’re the best,
Italians think they’re the best, or, say,
the best of all are the Switzerland, Swiss
people.
This vanity, this forge, has to be cut up.
What have you achieved by being a certain
nation, let us see.
What have you contributed, belonging to a
certain country.
Those who only belong to the Kingdom of God
have achieved something.
The rest of them are useless people, just
finding some way to fight each other, to denounce
others and vanity is just like a balloon.
If somebody just puts a pin into it the whole
balloon will collapse.
Now the worst of all is jealousy, and that
is among Indians, Indians are very big jealous
pots.
Specially the Indians who are again in the
government and the politics but otherwise
also there are jealousies.
They’ll always complain about the other
people and will be jealous.
And also in the West people are quite jealous,
I must say.
They’re jealous of things which is most
surprising.
One day I was going in the car and one gentleman
was very furious for nothing.
So the another one tells Me, “They’re
jealous because you’re sitting in a Mercedes
car.”
I said, “But it’s not Mine, that’s My
husband’s, you see.”
What is there to be jealous because I’m
sitting in a Mercedes car.
I mean, this is being a very stupid, nonsensical
thing but still I can’t believe you can
be jealous of somebody because he has a Mercedes
car, what does it matter?
To Me, it’s a foreign idea absolutely, I
can’t understand.
But there are stupid and stupid things like
that.
I can only understand one jealousy, that is
between husband and wife, little bit.
Then the fifth thing that He asked us to kill
is the attachment, very important, “This
is my child, this is my…”
This is Indian also, more Indian, “This
is my cousin, this is my brother, this is
my fiancé, this is my wife.”
Also in the West, the other way round is that
they do not care for their children.
They do not care for their mothers, they do
not care for their fathers.
They do not care for anyone whatsoever, but
for themselves.
That comes from the last one, is called as
the greed.
Now when you have greed, you don’t care
for anybody, you just want to have everything,
from another person.
You want to grab another person of everything.
Whatever another person has, you want to have
it.
But when you don’t want to have it everybody
wants to give you it, that’s My case.
I’m very afraid to say even that, “This
is nice,” because immediately tomorrow I’ll
find it in My house.
So this greed is the one which has done such
a harm to the whole world.
People have gone into great dominations on
other countries, for what?
For these diamonds and nonsensical things
like that?
They have ruined their own lives, the progenies
of the progenies they’ve ruined.
All their cunning they have used to ruin so
many nations just to put them one against
another, creating problems, doing all kinds
of intrique.
Just for what?
For greed which is absolutely like cancer,
doesn’t allow anybody else to exist.
And then you start eating yourself out.
It’s a disease, I think, greed.
And with that goes the miserliness; people
become miserly.
Then where does this greed end up.
After all the money that accumulates or things
that accumulate in your house, what happens
to them?
You want to use them.
What’s the matter with this one?
Try to be, not to be, I’ve told, otherwise
I’ll ask you to go out, all right?
Concentrate.
So what happens to the people who are greedy?
They become miserly, they can’t enjoy life,
they cannot spend money because the greatest
joy is in giving things to others, no doubt
about it.
And they cannot give any joy to anyone, they
cannot create anything for the future progeny
to see.
So what happens to them?
Their children when they come in they become
wastrel, waste.
They waste all of them, they lead a wasteful
life, they get into wrong things, and ruin
themselves.
So their children who are born become miserly.
So the vicious circle starts moving.
He has said, “Kill all of them, these are
your six enemies.”
Now the contradiction, again people use, about
Shri Krishna, in so many other ways that it
is surprising that not only Christ, not only
Mohamad Sahib, not only Lao Tze, not only
Shri Rama but even Krishna was misused by
His followers.
He’s the one who is datast, the one…,
datast means who stands on the banks of the
attention and sees everything, who watches
everything, he’s the one who is the witness.
He described, “Sakshi rupena samsthita,”
he becomes a sakshi, a witness.
That’s what He has said, it’s a play,
it’s a play.
But in the name of Krishna you find all kinds
of absurd things people do.
They make dramas, they become Krishnas, they
become , they make people…,
befool them, make money out of it or they
sell books on the street.
Like if you go to Southall you’ll find so
many Westerners wearing funny dresses going
round asking for alms from Indians and Indians
say, “Oh look at that, these beggars, see
they have come to get some, let us give them
some money.”
So the contradiction of Krishna’s life is
such a miserable thing, is such a absurd thing
that it hurts Me to see how such a great incarnation
who was misused in this world by human beings.
If there was anything lacking in that incarnation,
was this, that He did not give realization
to people but He did talk about it.
He said about it, talked of meditation; He
did all that was needed at this stage.
But what is the result?
All His incarnation was misused.
Throughout Gita if you read, you’d be amazed
how people have changed Gita and its writings
also.
Same in the Bible and same in the Koran.
Things that they could never have said it,
how could they have said it, you’d be surprised,
impossible, because they cannot contradict
themselves.
For example, Gita is written by Vyasa who
was an illegitimate child of a fisherwoman.
But in the Gita it is written that your caste
is determined by your birth; how can it be?
The one who is the son of…, an illegitimate
son of a fisherwoman, how can he tell like
that?
See the contradiction.
Same in the Bible, same in the Koran, same
in the Koran, in all these books, all these
people have tried to play a very nasty role
by changing it.
But you can find it out.
Luckily, whatever they may try, the truth
comes out in this manner and you can prove
it that whatever you’re saying is wrong,
cannot be.
The one Vyasa who wrote was the son of a fisherwoman
and how can he say that Brahmins are the highest,
when he’s not born as a Brahmin.
And to say that your caste Brahminism comes
from your birth…
From your rebirth!
Only they removed little bit – rebirth.
This is how they interpreted Gita in various
ways in such contradictory manners.
His whole writings or sayings could not be
changed, of course, they could not change
it but wherever they wanted to put their own
style, they did it.
Because ultimately, it went into the hands
of the Brahmins who were not really Brahmins,
they were the people who were sudras because
they were not even realized souls and behaving
in such a dirty manner; they should not be
called as Brahmins.
But it went into the hands of so-called Brahmins
and they misinterpreted it.
Same thing with Bible.
It went into the hands of horrid people.
Mr. John said something which was sensible,
all right, but what about the other fellow,
Paul?
He comes in and spoils everything.
Then comes Augustine, he spoils everything,
why?
Because they’re devils.
There is a evil force; this theory that there
is no evil force is a wrong theory, doesn’t
exist.
There is a evil force and don’t play into
the hands of evil force even this much.
And that was clearly taught by Shri Krishna.
But even then the contradictions can come
in.
Like if you are a Krishna bhakta then if you
just start running on the street, “Krishna!
Krishna!
Krishna!” like that, then you are celebrated,
or like a madcap go on, “Krishna!
Krishna!
Krishna!” like that.
Or else being worse than that is some people
said we’re Krishnas.
Like this horrible Rajneesh did.
He said He used to make the women naked, so,
“I’m making the women naked.”
I started wondering, “When did Krishna make
women naked?”
When He was a little boy less than five years
of age, He used to climb up on the trees and
the ladies used to take their bath in the
river Yamuna.
So He used to hide their clothes just to raise
their Kundalini and see how it works.
At the age of five years what does a child
understand?
This horrible fellow, was he five years of
age when he was doing this nonsense?
Using Shri Krishna’s name like this?
And when he used to break the pitchers of
these gopis, what was He doing?
He was doing Kundalini awakening, because
the gopis were taking out the water from the
river Yamuna which was vibrated by Radha and
He used to break them on the back so that
the water would fall on their Kundalini and
they would get their realization, in this
lifetime.
That’s what’s His purification.
But first thing they will do is to separate
Shri Krishna as a child and Shri Krishna as
the one who talks to Arjuna, very nice.
So there is no relevance and use Him the way
you want.
It’s a very common thing that people start
talking about Shri Krishna as if He’s in
their pocket, or they are the writers of Gita.
Like we have in the churches those bishops
and things who drink a lot and then they take
out their Bible and start reading upside down.
All these  class whether this
belongs to this or to that, all of them are
hypocrites of the worst type, just money spinning
people.
Even Indian temples which are not far-fetched
are ruined.
All the ganja and all that are sold in Indian
temples.
All these popes and all these people are doing
something that is never expected.
Imagine they make a kind of a wine called
Benedictine in your Vatican.
Can you imagine a nonsensical thing like that?
Tomorrow they’ll open a beer bar, I won’t
be surprised.
So we come to a position to understand that
all those people who talk of these great incarnations
and profess a religion are all hypocrites.
There’s no religion.
Simple people who believe these hypocrites
because they’re so simple, so innocent.
These cunning, greedy devils who started these
religions, exploited these simple people,
used them for making temples, churches, mosques,
they have no religion within them, how can
they talk of God?
Their life is so impure.
So we have to start our own innate religion,
our own spontaneous, natural religion which
is the human religion, which is the Vishwa
Nirmala Dharma.
The one that will give you the inner ascent,
not just talk, no hypocrisy; and all that
which goes with religion to malign the names
of these great incarnations has to be brought
to the light for the people to see this nonsense
that has been eating into our societies, eating
into our families, eating into our children,
has to go away.
, whenever the religion
– normally doesn’t mean this nonsensical
religion – falls down, that time, <Sanskrit
expression>, to save the sadhus, the seekers.
, and to destroy all
these devils, “I take My birth again and
again.”
, “Every yuga I take
My birth.”
And this is what is an incarnation.
You must be very fortunate people that now
you can see the cunning of all these devils
and can exist into that purity, into that
benevolence, the hita, which was promised
by Shri Krishna.
He never told lies, what He told was the truth.
He was truth.
But those who tried to use Him had to take
course to something which was falsehood, hypocrisy
and cunning but that in no way could stop
the truthful people from getting to reality.
May God bless you all.