in this totality a world has to be
created of people by the people who have
no fear
this fear has to do behind all this
nonsensical nervousness is fear so for
that what she does is to give a Vida
under her protection you are beyond fear
you are protected but if you don't want
to believe in yourself and you don't
believe into her protection then nobody
can help because everything is mythical
for you in every venture that we take up
we should not have any fear because God
is with you is a fact - the truth
you just try but when you try through
your ego you fall into the trap of fear
I have seen egoistical people are the
most frightened people and panicked
because they panic others and so they
think they can be panicked one day when
the English were here first of all in in
India we are all frightened of them now
I see that in England every English
family is threatened of others
they only open a [ __ ] of the door to
see who is there and shut it the so
frightened I'm surprised that they say
English we're over us here and we were
soapy which before them and now they are
the ones who are frightened of us
because when a person who is egoistical
tries to dominate others he sees himself
in the mirror and thinks that the other
person will dominate that's how this
fear crêpes creeps in inter minds and we
start getting all kinds of these stupid
Tantrums out of this mythical fear the
fear is created by our ego
a person who is no ego he'll have no
fear because you are not harmed anyone
why should you have any fear and such a
man are such a woman will be looked
after by God because God takes over when
you surrender your ego to God he takes
over but those who have ego he says all
right go ahead use your ego try to
protect yourself cut your throat
that's what it so when I talk of total
benevolence I am talking about your own
total benevolence so first is the fear
we should go out of your mind completely
if you believe in the Almighty God will
say you are Almighty God is Almighty
this thing is all lip-service if you
believe that god is almighty and you are
connected with god then why should you
have any fear of anything but when we
say don't have here another extreme
comes up we don't have fear we can do
what we like we can perform everything
ourselves we need not tell anyone you
have to tell God whatever you are doing
you have to take permission you have to
inform in his garb are in his coat that
sir you have son they are thinking of
doing such a system but you think you
are God
we are not and that's why the another
part of lawn fear is this kind of an
arbitrary behavior which is very
dangerous for sahaja yoga for yourself
or for everybody else the second fear I
mean I have is that if I tell you
anything
99% of you understand is for your
benevolence is for your good but there
is one percent of people who can just
react because they have too much ego and
they won't take it because they don't
think of their own benevolence they
don't understand that if I am telling
them anything it is just to give them
completeness totality but on the
contrary they take a very wrong attitude
this is another non sensitive so now one
has to develop a kind of a indifference
to this kind of people who unnecessarily
go to the other limit of their own
destruction I don't want to see what is
the point in everything that I am
Telling only I can tell you who else I
have to tell you what's wrong with you
what you have done wrong and then you
must change