clean our ganache torte them
and it is recited for the love of Shri
Jagadamba a mother of the universe as
part of the door gossip tusheti our main
salutations to fetch and iike free
Markandeya spoke to us o goddess
Jayanthi who wins everyone Mangala who
gives salvation Kali Bhadrakali who is
benevolent devotees Tapani
Durga Shama who tolerates everyone shiva
rathri swaha and swaha salutations to
you
victory BTU Oh Davy Chamunda victory BTU
or a mover of miseries of all living
beings
victory be to you Oh Davy was present
everywhere
salutations to you Oh cholera three the
last night salutations to you Oh Davy
the killer of the demon madhu and kotoba
and the restorer of boons on sri
brahmadeva
please give us the spiritual personality
the victory for glory and destroy our
enemies salutations to you Oh Davy the
killer of Mahishasura and giver of
happiness to your devotees please give
us the spiritual personality the victory
the glory and destroy our enemies
Oh Davey but killers raktha beeja and
destroyer of demons Chanda and Wanda
please give us the spiritual personality
the victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy the killer of demon
shimla new shaumbra and Doomer aksha
please give us the spiritual personality
the victory but glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy was lotus feet are
worshiped by gods and gives good fortune
please give us the spiritual personality
the victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy was form and character
are beyond the mind will destroys all
the enemies please give us the spiritual
personality the victory the glory and
destroy our enemies
Oh Davy chandâga the destroyer of
sufferings
please give those who always humble
before you in devotion the spiritual
personality the victory the glory and
destroy our enemies
Oh Davy Chand iike the destroyer of all
diseases please give to the devotees who
praise you with devotion the spiritual
personality the victory the glory and
destroy their enemies
Oh David Chandrika please give those who
always worship you with devotion in this
world the spiritual personality the
victory or glory and destroy their
enemies Oh Davy please give us good
fortune health complete happiness
spiritual personality the victory our
glory and destroy our enemies
Oh Davey please destroy those who hate
your devotees give us strength a
spiritual personality the victory the
glory and destroy our enemies Oh Davey
please confer upon us the benevolence
great wealth the spiritual personality
the victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davey Ambika your lotus feet
are robbed by the gems of the crowns
worn by gods and demons please bestow
upon us
the spiritual personality the victory
the glory and destroy our enemies Oh
Davey please make your devotees
knowledgeable glorified and wealthy and
give us the spiritual personality the
victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davey the destroyer of the
ego ferocious demons Oh Jun Ditka please
give us the spiritual personality the
victory the glory destroy our enemies oh
but initially the supreme goddess having
four arms and it was praised by the four
faced one true Brahma Deva please give
us the spiritual personality the victory
the glory and destroy our enemies o Devi
Ambika who was ever praised with all
devotion by shri krishna please give us
the spiritual personality the victory
the glory and destroy our enemies or
Parameshwara the supreme goddess was
praised by the husband of the daughter
of the Himalayas Shri Shiva please give
us the spiritual personality the victory
the glory and destroy our enemies o
paramesha
was worshipped with true feelings by the
husband of Indrani Hinderer please give
us the spiritual personality the victory
the glory and destroy our enemies
Oh Davey the destroyer of pride of
Beeman's by your strong arms please give
us the spiritual personality a victory
for glory and destroy our enemies or
Davey Ambika you enlighten the supreme
joy moksha of your devotees please give
us the spiritual personality the victory
for glory and destroy our enemies
Sasha Shri Adi Shakti my body
Sriman my love
namaha
you