This Spirit when it manifests, it also gives you a state
which we call as collective consciousness.
Is the state by which you become you, again I say become
- it's actualization, it is not just talking -
you become conscious collective,
means you become
conscious of another person's centers on your fingertips.
You also become Self aware,
you know about yourself,
what centers are catching, where are we going.
Like a person who becomes mentally upset, he doesn’t know,
really becomes mad,
goes to lunatic asylum and dies, he does not know.
But in Sahaja Yoga immediately you can find out
that there’s something going wrong with your mental side.
If a person gets into cancer,
he might get, gets into the state of galloping cancer, about to die,
then he may discover that he has got cancer.
But in Sahaja Yoga if there’s a little imbalance,
immediately it shows on your fingertips, and if you know
how to do it, how to correct it, then every problem is solved.
So as I told you yesterday, yoga has double meaning.
Yoga means union with the Divine, that’s one.
and the second one is the expertise, the depthness,
what we call in Sanskrit kaushalam.
You must have a depthness,
how to handle this all-pervading Power that is flowing through us,
how to understand ourselves, how to understand others,
that’s an important part of Sahaja Yoga.
First of al a little light is enlightened.
You get the experience of the Spirit to begin with.
It's an actualization.
But then you must make it grow.
Christ has given beautiful parables
explaining this, the sprouting of the seeds,
which were thrown on the rocks,
some were thrown in the good soil and somewhere neglected.
And we find that everyday happening.
Thousands come to My program and then I find
some of them are lost in the rocks,
some of them are wasted,
but some of them become huge big trees
to give shade, joy and support to others.
We have to change this world.
How are we going to change this world, this horrible world
which is just under precipices of destruction?
The only way is that we have to change ourselves.
That’s the transformation just waiting to happen.
It's nothing that I am doing about you,
I really tell you, I don’t do anything.
I don’t do anything, I’m just waiting to get it.
You just catch upon it and you get it.
I’m maybe just triggering it, but you can trigger it also.
So one has to understand that you have to be honest to yourself,
you have to be fair to yourself.
You have to understand your value, you must know your worth,
that you are a human being created
out of small things like amoeba, from carbon,
and today you are sitting here as human beings,
you must be something very special.
And this special thing has to become that thing
which will make you understand what you are.
Only thing you are not yet connected.
Only thing is that you have not yet felt that divinity within you.
We are all potentially divine.
We have to just feel that divinity within us.
But as a result of that, you are such a powerful personality,
power of love.
We have never used the power of love,
We have only used the power of hatred so far.
Power of love is much above power of hatred.
It can angle all hatred, can just
suck in everything that is hatred.
It’s very simple. Very simple methods are to be put,
only you must have desire to get transformed.
Now the third thing that happens with Self Realization
is that you get a state of peace, of bliss and of joy.
When the Kundalini rises above this Agnya chakra
you become thoughtlessly aware.
It's called as Nirvichara Samadhi. Thoughtlessly aware,
when there is no thought in your mind.
If you want, you can think.
If you want you can think, but if you don’t want,
you can be in that state when you don’t think.
Actually it’s maddening sometimes
the way man is thinking morning till evening,
yarns after yarns, useless things, a joyless pursuit.
But when this thinking stops, you are above the thoughts.
I would say to give it a similitude,
that the waves of thought come and go away.
Another thought comes and goes away.
We are jumping on the cusp of the thought all the time
Supposing we can just get
in the center of the thought,
that is the present.
If we can, could stop at the present moment,
then we are not worried about the thoughts.
Like the waves of water, if you are in the waves,
you are frightened of that.
But supposing you are in a boat
then you can see the waves and enjoy them.
In the same way what happens to you
that you jump up to a higher state of existence
through which you see the thoughts
if you want, you don’t want to see you can, you need not see.
Now the thoughts that you see also, are very wide and deeper
where you get inspirations.
That’s why, as Dr. Warren has told you,
that your creativity improves.
You can become tremendously dynamic.
Because your time is not wasted in wasteful things.
You just know this is it.
This is the exact, this is what we have to do.
And that’s how people get rid of
many of their problems of mental tensions.
There’s no tension at all. You don’t have any worries.
You just see the thing like the witness.
You become the witness of the whole drama.
When you are in the drama,
you think you are a part and parcel of the drama
sometimes you weep with it and cry with it.
But when the drama is over, you realize it was just a drama.
“I was not there”.
In the same way it happens to you,
that you achieve a witness state.
It happens to you. Even if you want to get involved, you cannot.
You just cannot get it.
That’s how you can solve the problems better
because you are away from the problems.
You can see what the problem is, but when you are in it,
you are upset, full of tension, worries,
and sometimes people get so upset with it
that they commit suicides, when they find no solution.
But if you are away from it,
then you can definitely solve the problem.
Now this witness state has to grow within you
gradually, with little understanding and with little meditation,
which is very simple, which you can do very easily.
Nothing has to be done about.
But first thing you must know, it is actualization,
it is not your mental projection that is going to do anything.
Like we may say, "we are all brothers and sisters". We say so.
But when it comes to wars, we become enemies.
Even in a family there are brothers and sisters,
when it comes to property, they fight.
Not in Sahaja Yoga. You really become part and parcel of each other.