It is good that all Sahaja Yogis have come together.
When we meet like this, we can discuss many things of mutual interest
and tell even small details about them to each other
how to clean yourself as your Mother’s name itself is Nirmala
and it contains many powers.
The first word is NIH which means not.
Something that actually does not exist but appears to exist,
is called Mahamaya (illusion).
In fact it is not there but we feel it exists
and this is called Mahamaya and the whole world is like that.
It is seen but it is not true:
if we are trapped into it we feel that it is the only thing we have to live for.
Then we feel that economic conditions are unsatisfactory,
social and domestic (family) conditions are bad,
everything around us is bad and we cannot see anything good.
Water on the sea surface is very dirty and turbid.
Many objects are seen floating on it.
But if we go deep into the sea there is so much beauty, wealth and power
that we forget that on the surface the water is so bad.
The point is that everything that you see around is illusion.
You must remember first of all it is all nothing.
If you have to establish ‘NIH’ you have to tell yourself,
whenever a thought comes, say “not this
(ya neti neti vachane nigamor avochus)
another thought comes, say it is not there.
You have to say this again and again.
Then you will understand the meaning of word ‘NIH’.
The illusion that you see is not just the illusion,
but there is something beyond that.
However, we have wasted so many years of lives in these illusions
that we give importance to all that actually does not exist
and in doing that we have made heaps of sins.
We have tried to derive the pleasure from many things.
We have received nothing from whatever we have tried to enjoy.
Essentially, it is all nothing – tasteless.
So, the outlook should be, it is all that nothing, it is all false.
Only Brahma is real the rest all is false.
You have to adopt this view point everywhere in life.
Then you will understand the true meaning of Sahaja Yoga.
What happens with most of the Sahaja Yogis after realisation, is that they think,
“now that we are realised we have Mataji’s blessings.
Then why are we not prosperous?”.
That means they think God is in the prosperity.
Inspite of having our realization why our family conditions do not improve?
Instead, you should think that, inspite of the realization
why my temperament (swabhav) has not changed.
Then you’ll realise that my swabhav has not changed.
See, how beautiful is this word ‘Swabhav’
– ‘Swa’ is Atman i.e. the spirit and bhav is the nature.
Have you become the nature of your Self ?
If you become your self there is so much beauty within,
that all that goes on outside would appear like drama.
So long as this witness state is not fully awakened within you,
you have not followed the word ‘NIH’ and also you have not practised it.
Suppose you are aware that you have not established ‘NIH’ within you
and even now you become s emotional or egoistical,
coercive or submissive and feel sad about it,
then the state of being on ‘NIH’ is at the centre of these extremes.
You are neither in this state nor in that.
This state has to be established and it can be best achieved in meditation.
Just by following the idea of ‘NIH’ in your life you will become (Nirvichar) thoughtless.
First of all, you should become thoughtless.
Once you start jumping on a thought however good or bad it may be,
you go into some sort of inertia
and in that state you jump from one thought to another.
So some people have said that a bad thought should be opposed by a good thought.
In other words if a vehicle or train coming from one direction,
is pushed back by another one, both will stop somewhere at the centre.
It is good but occasionally it can become harmful.
A bad thought when put down by a good thought remains suppressed
but it can suddenly come up and it happens with many people.
They press down their normal thoughts and always tell themselves
that they must be good to others and must be well behaved etc.
These people can sometimes be in trouble.
Suddenly they get exasperated and others cannot understand,
why these well behaved people are annoyed.
Also they lose their inner peace.
All the beauty within them is destroyed. So we should be always thoughtless.
Ban all thoughts from your mind
and then you would automatically remain at the centre in the Vilamba.
You must make all efforts. Now you would ask
“Mother how can we do anything without thinking?”
But what are thoughts? They are hollow.
In thoughtless state you are one with the God’s power
that is, the drop, which is you, comes in the ocean which is God.
Hence His power also comes to you.
Does this finger think? Is it not still moving?
Give your thoughts to God and ask Him to think about you.
But it is rather difficult, because you are not thoughtless.
Many people say “we have surrendered everything”,
but it does not happen because they do it only in talking.
Surrendering is not just talking.
When you attain thoughtlessness then surrendering is automatic .
That is you have stopped thinking.
When you stop thinking you come to the centre.
When at the centre, immediately you go into thoughtless awareness, i.e. become one with God’s power
and when you are one with the God’s power, He looks after you.
He takes care of your small things also. You will be amazed.
Sometimes try doing things on your own.
Then you’ll experience “Sankalpa vikalpa karoti” (Man proposes and God disposes).
If you want to go through a particular way, try doing it.
All the countries have tried it and failed.
It is worth trying and after that you will realise
that what you were doing earlier was wrong.
So once you are in thoughtlessness you will get all inspirations,
all powers and everything.
The idea that you get in thoughtlessness is an inspiration.
You will be surprised.
Everything will come to you as if on a plate.
You are standing to give a speech.
Just be thoughtless and start.
Although you have never given a speech earlier or do not even know how to do it
or have no special knowledge of any subject, you will speak so well
that others will be astonished how you know so much.
But once you are deep in the thoughtless state,
all comes from there and not from your brain.
I tell you about Me. You pray:
‘Mother kindly see that such and such happens to me’
and I do not think about that.
It is amazing. I put all that in the thoughtlessness.
All machinery is working there. J
ust put it to that machinery and it is all ready.
Allow that machinery, you can call it silent machinery, to work.
You should put all your problems to it.
But it is very difficult for intellectuals
because their habit is to go on thinking about everything.
You should be able to go into thoughtlessness
while trying to understand a subject.
All becomes clear automatically.
Research that you are doing should also be in thoughtless state.
Let your hands work while you are thoughtless.
You can do your research extremely well in this way. I tell you many things.
I have never read science in my life and know nothing about it.
Still I tell you all that. Where does all the knowledge come from?
From the thoughtlessness; I only speak and see all that is going on.
It was all kept ready in that computer which is speaking.
If you are not in the thoughtless state
you do not use your computer and put your brain on top of it.
It is such on old computer and lot of accurate work has been done on it.
You are bound to make mistakes if you use your own brain
and do not consult the computer. It has no meaning.
Thus the solution for all this is the prefix “PRA”.
We say PRASHIKSHAN (Enlightened Education) in which we use the suffix PRA.
[Ndlr – Whenever prefix “PRA” is used (in Sanskrit, Hindi or Marathi) it means enlightened].
All that happens in the thoughtless state is enlightened and thus is PRA.
It is so PRACHANDA (Enormous) – here again it is PRA.
Some other words are PRAKASHIT (brought to light),
PRADNYA (wise), where we use the prefix PRA meaning enlightened.
Light never talks. If you switch on the light in the room,
the light won’t speak or give you any ideas.
It would just make everything visible.
Same is about the light of thoughtlessness.
That ‘NIH’ is common in all such words like ‘Nirvichar’ (thoughtless),
Nirvajya (Selfless), Nirahankar (egoless), Nirakar (formless).
Thus lots of words come from the prefix NIH.
You establish it and then you come into Nirvikalpa (doubtless state).
First become thoughtless and then doubtless (Nirvikalpa).
Then all your doubts go and you know that there is some power that works.
It works very fast and is all subtle. You will be amazed how it happens.
This is also about time. I never see watch.
Sometimes it stops and shows, when the time is 3.00 o’clock.
Just to show others I wind my watch.
But my real watch is in the thoughtlessness. It is permanently stopped.
If anything is to be done, it takes place at the right time.
Then there are no regrets whether it is late or not.
Whatever it may be I am where I am.
Yesterday, my car failed but I was relaxing because I wanted to see the stars.
That beauty is not visible in London and I wanted to see it.
Thus I was enjoying the starlit night.
Others were worried and they started giving vibrations (bandhans).
I told them, why are you wasting your vibrations?
See the stars which you do not watch often. I had to see the beauty in the sky.
Its splendour was spread all over the sky.
The sky thought Mataji should see it also
because (it thinks) She always Her attention only on Sahaja yogis.
I wanted to get down and watch it but I was worried
that the Sahaja yogis might think that I am in trouble.
So I was just watching the sky from where I was and enjoying it.
In short, you should not be a slave of anything.
If you are thoughtless God takes you everywhere as if on his hands.
He makes all arrangements.
He knows everything and there is no need to tell him about anything.
But you must see whether you are in the PRAVAHA (main stream) or not.
You should see if you are in God’s Pravaha.
If you are not in it then you are stuck up somewhere on the bank;
then current comes and takes you in, twice or thrice
but again you are on the bank.
Then you say ‘Mataji, nothing goes smoothly for me’. It won’t.
Because you are entangled.
Shri Ganesha’s praise that you sing is excellent. It says,
PADTA PRAVAHI “flowing in the main stream (Pravaha)”
which means enlightened main stream.
We should swim in the pravaha.
You should not bring your own separate, current in it.
Pravaha also means enlightened vehicle.
The Arti of Shri Ganesha also says ‘Nirvani Rakshave’, i.e. protect me when I am dying. Y
ou also pray ‘Raksha Raksha Parameshwara’
O God protect me, but you want to protect yourself.
Why should, then, God protect you? He says, “let him protect himself.”
Then you have all the sufferings of the world upon you like big mountains.
I feel like laughing. These are all like balloons. They have no meaning.
What I want to emphasise is that you must learn to go deep within yourself
and realise all this in the thoughtlessness then you can become Nirvikalpa (doubtless).
You should attain Nirasaktata – Asaktata means attachments.
You must have no attachment (Nirasakta).
We have here, (India) ‘my son, my daughter’.
In England, it is just the opposite.
There, they are not attached to son or daughter.
They are worried only about themselves.
Son is left to the dogs. They even kill their children.
Some might not believe it but they kill.
Each week a mother kills two children. They are so cruel.
Here you have this attachment; my son, my daughter, my husband, my house etc.,
everything is mine and at the end your “self” is left out!
You should say “Nothing is mine and everything is yours.”
Kabir says “so long as a goat is alive it is bleating ‘main, main’ (I, I)
but when it is slaughtered there is no life left,
she realizes that I spent my whole life in saying “main, main”.
Those whom I called mine have turned out to be useless
– everybody in the family, in the house –
all those whom I considered to be mine have turned out to be useless.
They themselves killed me and ate. Then it realizes it’s mistake.
Then someone creates taut strings of its guts
and fixes them on an musical instrument.
When these strings are pulled they make a sound “Toohie, Toohie”
(you alone are.) You must become like that.
Once you are established in the idea I am nought, I have no existence,
then only you will understand the word ‘NIH’.