Today, we are celebrating the birth of Jesus
Christ.
The birth of Jesus Christ is very symbolic,
because
he was born
in such a manner that even the poorest of
poor won’t be born in the stable.
And he was put in the
bed which was made of dried grass.
He came on this earth to show people that
for a person who is an incarnation or who
is a highly evolved soul, is not bothered
about the comfort of the body.
His message was so great and so deep, but
he had disciples who were not prepared for
the battle they had to fight.
Is the same thing that sometimes happens with
Sahaja Yoga.
He had only 12 disciples, we too have 12 types
of Sahaja Yogis, and all of them, though [they]
try to dedicate themselves to Christ, fell
a trap, some of them, to the worldly aspirations
or to their own hankerings.
His message of love and forgiveness is the
same even today.
Preached by all, all the saints, all the incarnations,
all the prophets.
They all have said about love and forgiveness.
If it was challenged or people felt that this
won’t work out, they were asked to have
faith in what he said.
But they were simple people in those days
so they obeyed him.
Some of them definitely were very good, some
of them half-baked and few of them were people
who were doubting.
He came on this earth to prepare for us our
Agya chakra and despite all his efforts one
finds very difficult and the people who follow
Christianity have the worst type of Agya.
Worst type!
Extremely aggressive, extremely planning type,
futuristic.
I mean all the troubles of the right side
are found in those countries who claim to
be Christians.
Even the early Christians who were Gnostics,
‘gne’, ‘gne’ in Sanskrit means ‘know’,
though [they] had the knowledge, the beginners
were also suppressed and tortured by the people
who were supposed to be in charge of Christian
religion.
And so many Christians were massacred by the
so-called Christian priests and Christian
churches, and still it is going on.
What you find in the west is a great influence
of these churches on the minds of the people.
Otherwise they are supposed to be intellectuals,
otherwise they are supposed to be analytical,
otherwise they are supposed to be something
very brainy.
But when it comes to temples and churches,
when it come to religion, when it comes to
Christianity, I think their brains are blocked,
completely blocked, by some sort of a mesmerism.
They just can’t think that there could be
something very wrong with these people.
When living in Italy, I found or I was shocked
how this catholic church was working out and
what the priests were doing and all kinds
of scandals much more than we have in our
country!
Money bungling and molesting women and having
children – I mean every sort of dirty habit
they had.
Supposed to be priests.
They were called ‘fathers’, they were
called ‘mothers’, they were called ‘sisters’,
they were called ‘brothers’.
And to me it was really a shock – I didn’t
know that such things are happening in the
name of Christ.
What Christ tried to show through his birth:
there is no need to have very comfortable,
great birth in a big hospital in London, no!
The simplicity of his birth should have made
all the Christians extremely simple and not
at all money oriented.
For money they went all round, crushed so
many people all over the world, when you go
to Brazil or to Chile or to Argentina, you
do not find a single man belonging to the
aboriginal people and they’re so unkind
to them.
Unbelievable how aggressive these people are.
Even in England, where theres protestants
I find the same thing among them.
You must go on saying “thank you, thank
you” morning till evening, otherwise you
are finished.
Racialism.
What was the race of Christ?
Was he a fair man?
No!
Was he a white person?
Not at all!
What was His colour?
He was brown like Indians.
From where does this racialism come to these
Westerners?
I just don’t understand.
It has nothing to do with Christ or if it
is real Christianity.
You go anywhere, you’ll be surprised, how
the faithful, simple-hearted people are misused
by these churches.
They’re used for voting, they’re used
for money, for everything – to such an extent
that money was made, artificially counterfeited
in billions, by the church itself.
Such autocracy, such control, such authority
they had that whatever they did was, the pope
is infallible, whatever he does is alright.
No idea of sinning, no idea of hell, no idea
of Christ – which was nothing but purity
and innocence.
Christ had taken a hunter and hit all the
people who were selling in front of the temple,
because God cannot be sold.
They were not selling God, they were selling
only goods, but he said the respect of the
temple, talked about the respect of the temple.
Another great thing Christians have done,
is to blame Jews for killing Christ.
Wonderful!
Put all the blame on others, this is the speciality
of Christians even today, is to put the blame
of what wrong you are doing on others, very
common.
And this is what you see very clearly in those
countries, who call themselves Christians.
They blamed Jews.
First of all, those who were Jews at that
time might have been Indians later on.
Alright, so they don’t believe in reincarnation.
I mean to say the same Jews who were there
are born again.
Thirdly that the Jews never killed Christ,
never, because in the multitude how can you
decide?
Is the judge who decided and ordered, he was
a Roman.
So the Roman empire didn’t want to take
the responsibility of His death so they said
Jews have killed Him.
So Mr Hitler got after them and he really
tortured them, really it’s too much, one
can’t even understand how can – he believed
in catholic religion, how could he kill small
little children, in the gas chamber?
But now the same people who were tortured
are also becoming very aggressive and now
they are against the Palestinians and the
Palestinians on their own are Muslims and
the Muslims are playing a havoc all over.
So when you go through the history, and see
the life of Christ, what do you find is aggressiveness
from one to another, from that to another,
passing from one to another.
If somebody slaps somebody, the another person
will try to kill that person.
So this religion has created this divisiveness;
people are just killing each other in the
name of God, in the name of religion.
Even in Sahaja Yoga, you’ll be surprised,
I have seen people taking advantage of my
name, and trying to get into some mesmeric
groups.
I can’t understand.
Using my name, using my photograph!
So beware this should not happen to you people.
Using the name of Christ, the Incarnation
of Divine Love, they are doing all these works
of violence, hatred, of cheating, I mean very
debased people.
And from one to another it passes, to the
another it passes.
Same thing happens in Sahaja Yoga.
If I told somebody that you are no more a
leader, somebody else is the leader, immediately
that person gets angry, he forgets what good
sahaj has done to him, he just forgets.
If I tell him the leadership should pass to
somebody else, finished!
Then he forgets that whatever good was done
to him, whatever Sahaja Yoga has done for
him, he’s living only because Sahaj has
helped him.
So this leadership goes into the heads of
people.
Sahaja Yoga is not here to make leaders out
of you, no never.
It is just for convenience we have leaders
and if they become inconvenient we have to
change it, that’s all, as simple as that.
But still I find this idea of authority is
something very great and they start using
it left and right, everywhere it is happening
practically in every country, has happened
and still happening
which is a very sad thing.
This will never bring forth my efforts.
My effort is to synthesise the whole, not
to divide, by no chance to divide.
Only thing, whatever is wrong, whatever is
unholy has to be brought to your notice.
See as a housewife, when we clean the rice,
there are some white stones in it, we take
them out.
We don’t cook rice with that stone, do we?
And such stones have to go out.
So some of them are just like stones.
You cannot change them.
Namadeva has said that they are like a fly,
who when lives gives us trouble by coming
on our food and by making us feel nauseated
and if by mistake we take her inside in our
stomach, she is dead but still she troubles
us.
These are all rakshasas, I should say.
They can never understand Sahaja Yoga and
they will always try to trouble us.
But what must the people who have achieved
Sahaja Yoga should do.
Should they also take to such methods?
I have never blamed anyone for anything.
Like, people say, “Mother he didn’t give
any money to Sahaja Yoga so he has lost all
his money.”
I never say like that “He should have donated
some money!”
I never ask for donations, I never ask for
money.
Every time I say it’s all sufficient.
Don’t need.
I have never asked for a single pie from anyone
to be given to me even when I needed
because I know I don’t have that problem.
From the life of Christ one has to understand.
He had no problems.
He was fearless.
He knew he was the son of God.
He had no problems at all.
He faced everything, even his crucifixion.
And people, I think, liked his crucifixion
or what?
They carry the cross.
Of course is the transformed symbol of Swastika
no doubt but still.
He had to sacrifice his life.
He sacrificed his life for all the human being
not for only white or black, brown or blue
but he sacrificed his life for all of us so
that we could cross over our agnya.
The condemnation we should do is not of others
but of ourselves.
We can call that as a crucifixion of ours
by which we see as Sahaja Yogis where are
we going.
I’m told there are some 80-90 Sahaja Yogis
who have come, who were mesmerised by some
people.
How could Sahaja Yogis be mesmerised?
Is it possible?
They never must be praying, they may not be
doing meditation.
How can they get into it?
And now they are asking for forgiveness.
I forgive but that doesn’t mean they will
be alright.
We cannot fix them anymore.
We do not put spoiled apples with the good
ones, do we?
This [is] no wisdom.
They are already spoiled, and they should
keep out till I say.
They should not attend any centre, they should
not come to any puja.
They should let them cleanse themselves.
Though a rotten apple cannot get well they
can.
They should try to understand that they were
not Sahaja Yogis.
If a Sahaja Yogi can get mesmerised, then
what’s the use of doing Sahaja Yoga.
What’s the use of getting your Kundalini
raised?
That means that they are very poor Sahaja
Yogis.
Surprisingly I have not seen this kind of
a phenomena in the west, very surprising!
Western Sahaja Yogis, whatever they were,
they are great Sahaja Yogis, I must say if
you consider the number of good people there.
They have given up so-called Christianity,
they have given up all this nonsense, drinking,
drugs, womanising, everything they have given
up.
And I haven’t met one person who has taken
to drinking again or who has taken even to
smoking.
This Yoga bhoomi of yours, which is India.
How could it happen here?
Specially in Maharashtra.
I think some devilish people are born in this
Maharashtra all the time because how is it
they tortured each and every saint?
How?
How is it, they have been so much enticed
by somebody who is saying something which
I have never said?
Shows a very low type of people, very low.
And they must have been always being born
in this Maharashtra, I am sure and again they
are born today.
I never wanted to talk about this at the jubilant
time like this when Christ was born.
Yes, it’s a thing of jubilation because
He came as a Saviour.
He did everything that is possible under the
sun.
For us it’s alright but what about Him,
what did we give Him?
In the same way many Sahaja Yogis go on demanding,
Mother we can’t even meet you, we can’t
even shake hands with you, we can’t even
fall at your feet.
We can’t do this, we can’t do that.
It surprises me.
“You must do this, You must do that.”
All the time lecturing to me.
What you must do?
You must do, is to meditate and to believe
that this Paramchaitanya is My power and that
you have felt My power within you.
The more you are away from you the better
you will be.
Absolutely, I can’t understand the demanding
nature of some Sahaja Yogis.
They have got their Jagruti (awakening of
Kundalini) which would never have happened.
If Christ wanted, He would have killed all
of them and lived very well, but I think He
must have been fed up with the stupidity all
around.
So at this time, we have to understand that
such a great Incarnation came on this earth.
Of course he couldn’t give Realisation.
Imagine the people who were about to crucify
Him, how could he give realisation?
Supposing somebody comes with the dagger at
Me, can I give them realisation?
It’s all right.
Nobody listened to Them, nobody thought anything
of them but not you!
You people have got your realisation.
You are born again people.
You are great people.
Your potential is there.
Instead of utilising that now, what are you
doing?
How many people are really involved in Sahaja
Yoga?
Introspect.
They have their own business, they have their
own this thing, they have – How many are
really involved in Sahaja Yoga?
He had only twelve disciples, except for one
or two, all of them dedicated without realisation,
dedicated fully to the work of Christianity
and which spread because they had not much
idea about the whole thing.
The Christians that they had were just converts,
useless people
and I would say that if they did not do any
justice to the birth of Christ, one can understand.
But what about you people?
Who are born twice, who have got their self
Knowledge, who are so equipped with all the
powers, who are connected with this all power,
what you can call the power of Divine Love?
All your powers can be utilised, can be known.
It’s like some dynamic machine which has
started.
Few wheels are moving but there are so many
wheels after wheels and so much you can do.
I cannot blame the Christians who are so stupid
because after all they never got their awakening.
Only some priest would bring some water, put
it on their head and baptised them, finished.
But what about you people?
I have lived because of you, because I wanted
to see that you people mature.
That’s the idea of the Mother is.
There are many who are matured, I would not
say, but still many have to be matured.
Doesn’t mean that you should be able to
give big lectures, or write books or anything.
But within yourself you should mature.
Your own personality should flower into the
fragrance of love of divinity.
This is what I would say is the difference
between Me and Christ.
He said “Baba I had enough, No, No, No more!
With these stupid people.”
Not Me, I knew what was the world like.
I knew what had happened to this world.
Today the world is much worse, because all
the religions are fighting among themselves,
firstly.
All the politicians are trying to be very
badly corrupt, competing in that corruption.
Nobody has sense of truth and honesty.
Everybody is involved in the advertisement,
newspapers, media, this, that, which is the
most corrupting influence today.
With all this background, I know by the year
2000, Sahaja Yoga will come out in the whole
world as something very great…(applause)
– You did not allow me to complete the sentence
– if you people become real Sahaja Yogis.
All of you.
All of you who are attending to Me here.
Even this much group if it becomes real Sahaja
Yogis.
It doesn’t matter if I cannot meet you personally.
It doesn’t matter if I cannot go to your
places.
It doesn’t matter, nothing matters.
Christ’s disciples worked when he never
existed.
So it’s not important, what is important
is that you are the people who are responsible
for the emancipation of this world, for the
synthesis of this world, to bring peace and
joy and happiness to people.
Just now when I was coming, people spread
the shawls.
It reminded Me of Christ when he came, they
brought palms leaves to wish him and spread
their shawls on the ground for him to go,
and where does he go?
To Gallows.
He goes to cross, he goes for his death.
When you show your love for Me, you have to
know that you have to love the whole work
of Sahaja Yoga.
It’s not some personal relationship with
Me that is going to work out.
All these western countries in the influence
of Christianity will go down, you will see.
They are going down already because there’s
is no morality.
There’s recession, all kinds of problems,
their children are wavered, they are drinking,
smoking, doing all kinds of things.
Even their influence on us is corrupting us.
Antichrist activity, throughout if you find.
It’s nothing but antichrist activity.
Who is the Antichrist?
They are describing he is the antichrist,
that fellow is the Antichrist.
That’s not the thing.
There is an antichrist within us, who accepts
all these things which are against the purity
and love of Christ.
So first of all among yourselves.
What is he going?
Sit down!
You must teach your children some manners.
This girl who was drowned is because you neglected
the child.
The father, where was he?
I don’t know.
I can’t understand how can a child be left
like that.
It’s important to discipline your children.
…if you have a neighbour, you’ve had it.
He will try to find out where you go, what
you do.
He will have a binocular to see and you make
any noise, you are finished but even if you
sing, you are finished.
In that way, Indians are better.
They don’t have that noise difficulty.
We don’t have.
Indians can live in the noise.
I wanted to find out why Indians are so adjustable
to noise.
They don’t mind noise.
I found out the reason is that in the west
people are under stress and strain and that’s
why they can’t bear.
But in India, people don’t know what is
stress and strain is.
Still that has not developed, I don’t know
how to that extent.
That disease has not come.
That might be the reason that they are so
much frightened of noises.
People will come from villages here.
They’ll sleep on the station, nothing happens.
The trains are coming and going, nicely sleeping.
Imagine in the west, thank God, in Italy we
have neighbours little far away, we had a
little trouble.
But in England, we had to go on changing our
ashram from one place to another, run away
from here to there, because of great neighbours,
we had one of them had the name Mr Peace.
I don’t know who gave him that name.
Such contradictions in life.
Such horrible contradictions.
I don’t know how will they learn how to
love their neighbour.
But Indians do.
Somehow they don’t have this problem, not
much.
Sometimes they have but not so much.
But if there is a music supposing, all the
neighbours will join, bring tea, bring this,
they’ll be enjoying the music.
But there the collectivity is so little I
think, I can’t understand how can they call
themselves Christians.
Only they go to church, well dressed and our
Mayor told Me that for fifteen minutes hardly
we can sit.
We start looking at the watches.
Fifteen minutes.
And after half an hour, we all run out of
the jail and how is it these people are sitting
with you for hours together.
I said, I must be mesmerising them.
I mean they are not so collective, unless
and until they drink, they cannot be collective.
Unless and until they get intoxicated, they
cannot talk to each other.
They are all the time tired.
They are supposed to be Christians.
They are so tired, you see them in the films
or anywhere, they come and sit down “hah!”.
What has happened?
Young people.
All the time thinking, thinking, thinking,
which comes from Agya.
Which comes from anti-Christ activity!
Anti-Christ activity, thinking, thinking,
thinking.
What should we do tomorrow?
What is to be done and all that.
Still we have to hope that this kind of religion
will finish.
All such religions must finish.
They have to go now, it’s too much.
you cannot support them.
They are so much full of anti-religious temperament
that you just can’t bear them.
Better to finish Islam, Hinduism, Christianity,
Sikhism, Buddhism, Jainism, all isms one after
another.
To what religion did Christ belong?
I don’t know.
You belong to one religion which is Sahaj.
Which is the universal religion, which is
the pure religion, which is born within you.
You don’t belong to any other religion because
there is no religion in that.
So by the time 2000 years, I hope all these
religions will run away from this earth.
(applause).
All of them fighting for nothing at all, killing
each other for nothing at all.
They want, they want to fight, they like to
fight.
Why blame Koran, why blame Bible, why blame
Christ, why blame anyone.
They want to fight.
They are of divisive nature.
They want to have separate nations, separate
communities, separate this.
Once you start separating you are antichrist.
Absolutely.
In Sahaja Yoga also I say that you are one
identity, you are not separate country, separate
organisation, separate this, doesn’t exist
in my own idea.
Doesn’t exist.
I never thought of it.
We are all children of one Father and of one
Mother.
We have no business to think we are separate.
Even now, I have seen groups are made very
easily.
How?
The groups are made.
Like I find Maharashtrians
are sitting together (Mother talks briefly
in Marathi.)
Then we have group of the North Indians.
Indians are quite separatist I tell you, somehow,
by temperament.
North Indians also have separate separate
ideas.
“You must come to Indore.”
Why?
Is it not a part of India?
They can’t come to Delhi?
“You must come to Kanpur, You must come
to Allahabad, you must come to Indore.”
You must go to every village, every place.
Why?
You are born today in Delhi, tomorrow you
will be born in some horrid place, then, “This
place is mine.
This is my house..must come to my house.”
That’s another headache.
“You must come to my house.”
Mine, mine, mine, mine.
Once you start that, you are finished, you
are no more belonging to Christ, no more.
This is a very, very common programme – even
today that, if you see around yourself, must
be people from your own country.
Just see around yourself, are you sitting
with another people?
Who is the other?
In Sahaja Yoga, who is the other?
We are all one and this unity we have to learn,
if you really love Me and Christ.
All this groupism and all this has to end
now among Sahaja Yogis, must end.
We are all one identity, we are all one living
body.
We are all one living organism.
We cannot say we are separate.
Can this hand separate from the body, can
it exist?
Once you start giving it up, you will be surprised,
you will have real enjoyment.
But once you have all these ideas about my,
my, you can’t even enjoy Sahaja Yoga.
Cannot enjoy anybody else – “my wife,
my children, my house”, my this, my that.
That awakening has to come within.
“I don’t belong to this country.”
Many girls you see and boys have written,
“We’ll have Indian marriage.”
Only the age of the woman is 35 years.
Only!
Now where will I find a husband for her in
India, must be some widower or somebody.
Must have an Indian marriage!
Can you beat that?
Such people, is impossible to marry them.
I give you choice, all right have a choice.
I also have a choice – I can’t marry you!
That is My choice!
You have the freedom to say where you want
to marry – alright marry.
But as far as I am concerned, I can’t marry
you like that.
You have to marry wherever there is a good
match for you.
Many Indian girls have married with Indians
boys, and have suffered a lot, such a lot,
you won’t believe! (talks in Hindi briefly).
Not in Sahaja Yoga any more!
We have not been able to organise even one
marriage of a Hindustani with an Hindustani
– not possible.
That’s not the desire of the Divine.
Why don’t you find in your own community
somewhere [the] same thing.
As in India, is very particular.
Very very particular.
Like when my daughter was to be married, they
said “No!
He his not a Shrivastava.
If he is a Shrivastava also, he is not the
same Shrivastava.
Even if he is the same Shrivastava, his this
thing is different!”
I mean.
I said, “Now this is going to finish”.
Because I had all my elders living and they
were after me.
I said “Whether he is a Shrivastava or not
Shrivastava I am going to marry them, finished!”
My husband agreed.
Same with my grandchildren.
If you get Shrivastava, well and good, otherwise
forget it.
Maharashtrians also same.
Maharashtrians who have become Christians
[are] also the same, you be amazed, Christians!
Now they are saying we are Dalit Christians,
means who were converted from the lower caste
into Christianity.
Now there is a new caste that’s come.
Once you have become Christian, what is your
caste?
You are Christian, not that.
They are Dalits and they are higher Christians.
They will not marry in the Dalit and Dalit
won’t marry in the higher.
Supposed to be Christians, following Christ,
going to church regularly, well dressed.
Even if they do not have a proper suit.
They must wear like English some suit, borrow
it, and go to church because according to
Indian Christians, Christ was born in England.
(laughter) Really, you won’t believe.
Unless and until you wear a suit and a tie,
you can’t go to the Church.
Can you imagine, anybody, going with a dhoti
to church? (more laughter) Impossible situation.
Even in my time, thank God I didn’t marry
a Christian, but my own sisters and all were
forced to wear veils and not the saris, wear
the frocks and the veils.
Can you imagine the wedding dress.
We, Indian women, can’t do without the saris.
But they were forced.
So many women married the way English marry.
And I was amazed even the Japanese who are
Christians come to Australia and dress up
like these English brides and get married
– because they are Christians.
That shows that they believe that Christ was
born in England or what?
Actually, for Christians it’s not necessary
to worry about any dress.
All this nonsense comes from the West that
you must dress up like this, you must have
your spoon here, fork here.
Did Christ eat with fork and spoon?
He was born in the manger.
It’s impossible to understand these people
are Christians.
So much worried about the spoons and forks
and they came to your house for dinner, they
lift the plate to see from what company you
have bought it.
[That’s] very important!
Such silly people!
I tell you they call themselves Christians.
Christ was born in the manger and [they are]
so particular about nonsensical things.
You see one must understand the greatness
of His birth, in which he has shown that he
was born with the cows tied there and the
calves were there.
He was born in the manger.
Not only the Christians abroad but they are
also in India the same – you can make out
a Christian in no time.
See them on a Sunday morning.
That way my father opposed it – he used
to wear kurta, because Christ wore kurta.
He didn’t wear suit, did he?
And so superficial they are.
Nothing to learn from them.
They will put here on top [a label written]
“Saville Row”, On top of the suit!!
Such stupid people, I tell you, and the Indians
are following them left and right, I can’t
understand.
They are anti-Christ.
Don’t follow them on these points.
Indians have at least certain sense of dignity.
If you have any, why should you wear a suit
on a May day here?
In this heat?
We are Sahaja Yogis.
We have to wear a common dress of a common
man.
Whom are we going to impress except for this
Paramchaitanya?
They are extremely superficial extremely meticulously
particular about their dress, how they live
and it’s really horrible.
I have seen this and that is the reason I
think I should warn you.
Don’t take to that culture, that is anti-Christ
culture.
Absolutely anti-Christ in every way.
In every way they have insulted Christ out
and out.
You people should not anymore insult Christ.
In a simple way you live.
I mean now this sari, they forced me to wear
is like a big bag for Me but what to do.
Yesterday also they forced Me, today also
they forced me.
I am supposed to wear all this because I am
Adi Shakti, supposed to be.
If I was Christ, I would have been better
off.
He was much more free than Me!
Now, with all this what we have to know, what
is the message?
What is the message of Christ?
That you develop your spirituality, your divinity
by which you know what is the dignity of a
Sahaja Yogi is.
He was your eldest brother I should say.
His lifestyle you should follow.
Absolutely not afraid of anything, not worried
about any job, nothing, not worried about
any business anything, absolutely free from
all worries.
So many examples we have, beautiful examples
of his life, but when we see Christians, we
try to reflect it as an expression of the
life of Christ and that is where we make mistake.
They are, by no means they are for Christ,
they are, by no means, following Christ.
So as Sahaja Yogis, we have a different culture.
We have a culture where we respect morality.
We have dignity, we have our own personality.
We are fearless, we don’t tell lies, we
don’t cheat and we can never get mesmerised.
So we have to have, now we can call it “the
Mother’s culture”, and which is not in
any way showing off, or in any way taking
to artificial things.
The whole thing will change, the whole concept
will change, whole idea will change, once
you understand that you are now in “the
Mother’s culture”.
Now they have forced me, so I am wearing all
right.
You want me to wear, alright I’ll wear.
But normally if you leave it to Me what do
I wear, you know that.
Secret is out already!
If you want to give me presents, give me,
I never asked you for presents, nothing!
Forcing the presents on my head!
Alright, for your joy’s sake you have it.
What to do?
But one thing I must request these Maharashtrians.
They are not going to give me anymore, anymore,
again anymore what they call is the oti part.
My oti is overfull.
Absolutely, nobody has to give me oti.
If somebody gets married, if somebody has
a child, somebody has anything, they’ll
bring the oti.
There is no need to give me any oti, you can
go to the temple, you give your oti there
it is resold and resold and resold in between
the sellers who are Gujaratis, the brahmins
who are the pujaris make money.
So no more oti, nobody is going to give Me
any oti whatsoever.
On a Christmas day I have to say one thing
– what did we give to Christ.
And the second question what are we going
to give to Mother.
This is very important.
I don’t want anything from you, nothing.
I am fully content with Myself.
What I want is that you must dedicate yourself
to Sahaja Yoga, to truth and to love.
I will be very happy and also not to talk
like, what you call, Christ has called them,
“murmuring souls” – talking here there,
one saying there.
All this.I don’t like at all.
I don’t like it and it should not be done.
If you do like this, you will fall, fall very
badly.
This is the last judgement.
Either you‘ll go to heaven or you‘ll go
to hell.
It’s already working out like that.
So let’s see.
Where are you?
So I have to again and again tell you as your
mother, I have to correct you and tell you
that remember this is the last judgement and
please, do not take anymore to the activities
which are anti-Christ.
You can judge within yourself – [whether]
whatever you are doing is not good, and for
that, best thing is to dedicate yourself to
Sahaja Yoga.
But not to make money out of Sahaja Yoga.
Not to make politics out of Sahaja Yoga.
But make Sahaja Yoga like a big, huge, big
tree and it will work out.
I know it will work out.
You have the potential.
That’s why you are here.
May God bless you all