We talk to you directly about things and though
you know I’ve been looking after
you very well…
[Marathi ?]
And I didn’t have so much time but you know
I have to work very hard and when you have
only one program, I have three or four programs
and I’m working very hard for them. And
you see, I’ve told you that Maharashtra
is going to be very fast movement and we have
to move very fast. Now what you have to understand
is that you have come for this program of
Maharashtra for what? Why have you come here?
That people must understand. What I find that
there is no understanding of this simple fact…with
some people…Some people are murmuring souls
among you and they don’t understand why
are they here. They are here to learn certain
things for Sahaja Yoga.
Now, especially if you do not have an ashram
also there’s always a problem to learn how
to live with others and in a way that we should
move
in a Spartan way, in a Spartan way, how to
live in a Spartan way and how to be smart.
Now see these people here, Maharashtrians
are. Just look at them, you have to learn
from them. How quick - I don’t have to tell
them anything. See they are so self disciplined
within themselves… I don’t have to tell
them anything. You see, they organize, they’re
working so hard, you can’t imagine. You
are doing no work, if you look at it, what
work are you doing? Just taking your luggage,
putting on the busses, getting down, sleeping
again. What work are you doing compared to
them? But there is no smartness about it.
What I find, they themselves are seeing you,
they think you are all lethargic people and
some of you are druggist or what is it? And
the complaints are so funny, that as if you
think there’s a package deal of a touring
thing, bus going and the organization is not
good and some are dominating, and this and
this. It’s absolutely absurd, I think. Some
people are taking Sahaja Yoga as a lethargic
stuff, you see, like a drug business, that
you get into lethargy, nobody has to tell
you: “Get into the bus.” But why don’t
you get yourself? Everybody must organize,
must learn something, otherwise it’s a waste.
I think it’s a waste coming down. You have
not come here for a tourism. One thing. Must
understand, this point must be understood
by all of you: it’s not tourism department
working this for you! Little comfort you get
immediately you get into that nonsense and
you must know that too much of materialism
has brought you to this stage that you have
too much of Ego. It’s a big headache - for
Sahaja Yoga and for you also. You know that!
Too much of materialism. And this matter always
tries to overpower the Spirit and your Spirit
is always overpowered by the Spirit. And you
get into a lethargic mood and then anybody
tries to tell you: “Get fast or get do”,
you think, “You are dominating!” and “This
is a - This is a nonsense”, I can’t understand
this!
Now why aren’t they seeing they want to
do any more organizing? Who wants to do it?
Now, those who were complaining raise your
hands. Take it over. Good idea! He says: “I
don’t want to do any organizing”. All
right! Who wants to do it? Let’s see who
were complaining that he was crossing the
maryadas. Now let them take over! It’s not
the way to behave. You see, you must have
your own disciplining, you must learn disciplining.
People have taken many things for granted.
You see and that’s what happened with Nick
when he tried to do. They are very comfortably
settled down in Linda’s house. And there
also I’ve seen people do the same thing.
Because when you – they live there, there’s
no need to have any disciplining, there is
nobody to tell. That’s not lethargy! Sahaja
Yoga is a Spartan thing, a smart stuff.
See, look at these people, how smart they
are. Early in the morning, 5.30 they’re
up and they are doing the jobs. You see the
way they are organizing, you can’t imagine
how much they are organizing. In far fetched
places, here also to organize everything is
an impossible situation. Now what are we doing?
Just trying to think that, you see, “We
are in a very package deal, we are here and
that everything should come to us in a way
that is a tourist, this thing.” Now Warren
has retired, now, who wants to do the job,
let me see? Those who have complained should
I put?
What’s this going on, I just don’t understand.
One person starts a joke and everybody starts
with it - it’s absolutely wrong, there’s
no tourism going on. You better go back, I’ll
return all your money that you paid Me and
you go back. Here you have come to learn about
Sahaja Yoga, how to become smart, how to be
Spartan, how to be light.
How much your Mother is working at this age?
I’m sixty years of age. How much I’m working
- just look at that. You have to be - I’m
your ideal or queen Elizabeth? Who is your
ideal? I mean I just don’t understand. Why
are you here? And one person starts a joke,
another takes it over and they all start talking
like this. This it’s absolutely an impossible
situation. I don’t have to tell them, even
once. Can’t imagine? In the night they cook
the food for you, you know? In the night - After
the program, they came down, made all that
food for you here and we took it. Those who
were with Me know that. They cooked the food,
all of them, these young boys and again up
they are in the morning 5.30 organizing everything.
Look at that! Learn from them! You see, you
people, in quality are no good, must understand.
You have nothing but Ego and a self-consciousness
that you are very great. No, you are not!
I’ve to tell you very frankly. You have
to come down with that Ego, completely. Material
development has ruined you completely there.
You see thousands of people raising here their
hands. See the people here! Are we going to
forget all the civilization that’s doomed
one in the West? You are the people, who are
the foundation. What are you, you are not
saints, are you not?
How does a saint live? You have seen Ramdasa
Swami, I went to see. Now do you realize that
you went to Mahalakshmi, that’s one of the
- one of the pithas of, one of the Kundalini’s
pitha, you see, of the whole Universe. Did
you follow that? Looking after your comfort
state or looking after your Spirit, what are
you doing here? Did you go - did you understand
that the temple was for that? Did you follow
that point? And now I want you to see another
temple and then another temple I’m going
to have. It’s not so easy, no tourist has
gone to these temples. Actually no Indians
are - no foreigners are allowed in these temples.
Because you are saints they have allowed you,
but behave like saints. What’s this nonsense
going on? Talking about comfort, this nonsense.
What comfort do you have there? I feel most
uncomfortably in the Western countries. There’s
no comfort of the Spirit. Most uncomfortable
I feel. Everybody drinking, everybody nonsensically
- so materialistic, so materialistic. Horrible!
Now don’t think too much of yourself for
Heaven’s sake. I don’t want you to talk
that somebody’s dominating you, crossing
your maryadas, Sahaj means lethargy. Why don’t
you have your own Spirits and your own arrangements?
Everything you have misleft, 2 rooms, 4 rooms
there unlocked this thing. There’s one girl
looking after Me, how smart she is, just see
how smart she is. Even ten English girls can’t
look after Me the way she looks after Me.
Every little bit of that she knows. I’m
not saying only English but all of you have
this problem. Please get rid of it! Otherwise
forget the West!
You have to do tremendous jobs. I’m trying
to look after you the way I can. You have
to look after yourself. The way you are moving
I just don’t understand. Is it a package
deal you have come? Those who have come for
the first time are more troublesome also.
Because they have never seen this before.
I mean those who want to go back, can go back
tomorrow. I’ll give you money, you go back.
Rahuri is going to be much worse than this.
This is the first time you got a hotel - Aaaaa!
I mean, I don’t understand the way you have
to be feeling comfortable. You want a bathroom?
All right, get attached to a bathroom and
move about with the bathroom all the tour.
I mean you know how I live in England, what
sort of a house I have and what sort of bathrooms
I have. I’ve have never complained, I’ve
never thought of it even. Never! For Me it’s
the Spirit. And don’t think too much of
yourself. Please! Everything they are running,
Puja they are running, things they are running.
Look at them! Never a problem for Me.
Now you have to go tomorrow to Tuljapur place.
This Vitthala is a very big place here of
Vishuddhi that you have to see and you have
to go to Tuljapur. They are not comfortable
that’s why they never appear in the West.
They are not comfortable there. Who would
have built temples on these stones? They would
have? Do you think they would have understood
Hanumana? See the standards! Look at him how
he lived. Even a person like Shivaji, he lived
here. He was a king! I mean I have never put
you to any test or anything, but the amount
of, you see, not that I want you to sleep
in the cold or anything, I didn’t want you
to sleep in the cold, that you misunderstood.
But what’s this going on? Why don’t you
get up 5 o’clock everyday? I sleep - I work
much more than you too! Today you know what
programs you have? Puja here. You don’t
have to run the - anybody’s chakras, do
you? You don’t have to raise mountains of
Kundalinis, do you? Stones and stones after
thousands of - do you have to do that? I need
not talk about Myself. Then after that this
program I have to deal with intellectuals,
then there’s a press conference, then after
the press conference there’s a huge meeting
at 6 o’clock.
The so-called comforts are nothing but enslavement
of your Spirit. It has enslaved your Spirit,
the Spirit is enslaved, believe Me. Get out
of it! It’s a nonsense! Your are saints,
you are seekers of ages, now get out of it,
absolutely get out of it!
They are so Spartan, so smart. Mooladhara
is first class, just see….Early in the morning,
5 o’clock bath and finished, they are ready!
What are you thinking all the time, that you
are lazy, every time people see - they told
me some are taking perhaps drugs. That’s
what they felt the way some of you are lethargic.
What is there to tell you, you can’t get
into the bus and they can’t understand.
In 5 minutes they’ll arrange things, 5 minutes.
Can you imagine, after the program they came
here, cooked food and I was there.
Now don’t think too much, thinking too much
makes you just lazy lumps….that’s all….it’s
not good. Thinking is another style of materialism,
is a subtler materialism. What is there to
think? [Get into bhoots ] Get rid of it! And
there is one bhoot who is of fussy one here,
I know all of them, very well, they have been
always a headache and I don’t know why they
have come and they introduce to another person
and that bhoot goes on, on, on, on, on.
But all such misfits will get out of Sahaja
Yoga, take it from Me! They’ll get out!
You want Sahaja Yoga or not, that’s the
point. Then, why worry about comfort? It’s
most surprising! Some of you who have come
for the first time from such a long distances,
like Frankfurt people are perfectly all right,
Toronto are all right. From New York they
are all right, these are all right, Steven
and his wife they are all right. I mean they
all have the same profile. Why other people?
Now, please, try to give Me some joy. I don’t
want to hear, “Now he wants to resign.”
You see, everybody starts talking, “He’s
very dominating.” But why? What are you?
You don’t deserve any bad thing better,
do you? You have to be smart. Are you smart?
Your Mooladharas’ like stones hanging round,
all the time thinking, thinking - what? Clear
your Mooladharas!
You must have Me as your ideal in Sahaja Yoga.
Look at Me! I mean, can you imagine? I have
so much [slunk ?]! I’m working very hard,
you know that! I’m not - I’m marathon,
you’ll go away. You’ll go to England,
you’ll go away to Europe, you’ll go away!
What about Me? I’m still working, working,
working, working…Only reason is that I have
a very good Mooladhara and a very good Agnya
and an excellent Sahasrara! I don’t think!
Talk too much, better not talk! I think you
better stop talking to each other! That’s
the best way it will work out. All this nonsensical
things you talk, you have nothing great to
talk, sublime things, about God, about the
Spirit. You must have peace in yourself! If
you have peace, you’ll enjoy it! The whole
place is so peaceful! Why don’t you see
the peace of this place which is lacking in
that horrible comfortable place? All of them!
There’s no peace. Feel the peace, you are
saints! Feel the peace of this place; in their
hearts see - feel their peace. The riches
have ruined you. That’s the curse! That’s
the curse! So feel the peace of the place!
There’s no peace within. Feel the peace
within. What side of all these sides you see,
anywhere you go? ”Oh very nice, this is
very nice” What is nice about it? The peace
of it, the subtler side, you have to be subtler
persons to feel the subtle side. Feel the
subtle side, the music behind, the fragrance
behind.
If I’m your ideal, I feel very comfortably,
to be very frank. I don’t know when will
I be out of that, I call it vanwas, is that
staying in a forest, a jungle. I feel it’s
a jungle of people who are anarchist, arbitrary,
such Ego oriented, horrible people those who
don’t know how to talk to each other. Horrible!
I’m for vanwas, I hope it finishes after
12 years. It’s real vanwas for me!
But now, you people give me some hope! Now,
no more talking like this! Shut up yourself
for this point! Absolutely! Nobody’s going
to talk like this, it’s anti-God. See, why
are we here? Get individualistic in the sense
you sit down for meditation, don’t talk.
Sit down for meditation!
You see you are trying to find organization
mistakes. I just can’t understand, what
is the matter? Pull your ears for this, please
pull all of you. No more of this nonsense.
And next time such people should not come,
I request such people who have been complaining
please don’t come. Look at Genuine, she’s
so old, she never says anything. Whenever
I ask her she says: “Mother, I’m happy.”
You are not going to enjoy anything, you see,
because you are not subtle. Even coming to
the subtlest places you don’t enjoy anything.
Where is your attention going? Inward? Believe
Me, they’re the most peaceful places where
you have been. But your brain will never allow,
this brain, this horrid Ego will never allow
you to enjoy. So get rid of it! All right?
Please, I want you to enjoy. I brought you
here to enjoy. Don’t criticize! And any
side of comfort, you just get rid of it. You’ve
got a cot? Sleep on the ground. Best is. Tell
your body: “I’m here! I’m a seeker!”
You must know your true nature that you are
seekers, you are not like other people but
that is still sticking on into your heads,
you still think on those lines.
You must know that you should never challenge
anybody who’s organizing. That hurts Me!
Never! He’s doing some job, you’re doing
no job. Must do that! What job are you doing?
Very nice to criticize another person! What
job are you doing? Are you responsible for
anything? Even for your clothes? He’s the
one who is working hard, it’s very nice
to criticize such a person! It’s like any
Dick, Tom and Harry comes and criticizes Me
that: “Why don’t You do this and why don’t
You do that?” Is exactly the same situation.
You are doing no job, very nicely criticizing
others. Why, for what?
You think you’ve paid for yourself, you’ve
paid very little, not much, I know that. How
much I had to take for your traveling and
the amount of luggage you have brought. It’s
a big problem in these places. Even if you
pay you can’t get it. But I’ve not brought
you here to give you comfort at all. You must
know I told you it’s a very Spartan one.
I’ve told you some that don’t get more
than 80 people. It’s an impossible situation.
You can’t get busses, these are from the
state trading busses, we got with great difficulty.
They gave us 2 busses, you see. They have
their own passengers, they have to sacrifice
a lot. These are not the places we - I didn’t
want to travel this time, you remember. I
was telling I don’t want to travel this
time with all of you. I want to go alone.
I’ve told you that we have to spend some
money, more sometimes, sometimes less, sometimes
we have to spend quite a lot, much more than
we expect, sometimes it’s lucky that we
have less money. Whatever money remains it
will go for Sahaja Yoga. I don’t want your
money, you know I’ve already overspent My
money. My bank is exhausted! You know that
all! So, why you talk like this? You don’t
think how much Mother spends. You never think
on that. You know Portugal - what happened.
You know how much money I spent in England.
Then you don’t think on these lines, do
you, ever? Are you going to return that money
to Me, anyone of you? But why stupidly talk
like this, as if there’s some tourism department
going on, you paid for the money, you paid
for it, so you find faults with the organizers.
Give up all these bad habits, absolutely.
Even if somebody beats you, you are not to
complain now, keep it on that point. Ego needs
beating, nice beating, I tell you. Sometimes
good beating will sort out all the problems.
Otherwise, if nobody beats you, beat yourself.
That’s the best way.
Now not that everyone is like that; most of
you are very good, I know you are enjoying,
but these are few people who are bhootish
and they are creating this problem and these
bhootish people will give others bhootish
nature, so be careful. Those who have got
the bhoots better turn them out. Just don’t
do anymore of this, just stop it. All right?
We have to have self discipline. These people,
look at these people, no problem, no problem,
such love, such organizing capacity. How much
- from 3 o’clock they’re waiting here
for Me, 3 o’clock. Every ended up, you see,
they came back by 3 o’clock. Twelve hours.
Again today they are back for Puja. And they
are engineers, they are doctors, they are
everything. At least everybody’s a graduate,
at least, minimum.
It’s true that in England even a garbage
cleaner gets more money than these people
can get. But what, so what? Are they going
to carry their money with them or their bathrooms
and their comforts? All these mythical ideas
you must give up. This is another world, that’s
another world. You have to adjust yourself
to this world. It’s very sickening to Me,
I tell you. Even if there are one person like
that, will be so sickening. Now don’t pay
any attention to anybody who talks like that.
Just shut him down! You are so many who are
good, only there are few who are funny. You
just shut them down: “ Now you will shut
up, this is a bhoot!” on this point. You
must get up early in the morning, do your
meditation, get into busses. You are here
for a package deal for one month to spartan
yourself.
All right? So, it’s a promise. It’s a
promise [since forward ?].
Now with Rahuri it’s even much more, you
see. The villagers, they are going to get
a shock that I brought some drunkards with
Me and those who cannot get into the bus,
can’t get out, everything and, “I can’t
do this and I can’t do…”. Everything
you have to do! Just it’s a promise, it’s
a promise. We are going to do it. All of us!
All right? Even I! (Shri Mataji laughing)
All right!
May God bless you!
So not to feel bad, most of you are all right,
most of you are enjoying, I’m not saying,
but there are few who are stupid and you don’t
listen to them! Just don’t listen! If somebody
says that you shut that out, you’ll be amazed
if you shut that person out, you’ll be amazed
that person will improve, you’ll help that
person! Nobody should talk like this! Noone
should talk like this! It’s nonsensical!
All right! May God bless you all!
Let’s sit down with the Puja - with that
smartness! We have to be smart not lethargic
in Sahaja Yoga! Sahaja means what? Like lazy
lumps? How are we going to do the work of
the whole world if we are lazy lumps? Imagine
the amount of mountains we have to lift in
the West, to think of them. And here we are
already exhausted… Haaa - like that! What
are we going to do that? Ha! It’s a tremendous
task! See, it’s like, I don’t know what
to say, it’s like taming a hippopotamus
or I don’t know what to say! Horrible! And
you better smarten up yourself, maybe next
year I may never bring anyone of you, I tell
you, I’m so fed up. But this is the style,
is the last chance perhaps, now I was saying
it’s just last time but everybody said:
“No, no Mother!” Is it, remember Gregoire…
I was not wanting, really, anybody to come!
It’s a headache you know! You still carry
the ideas. Now, so that’s Paul! And look
at down there! Look at him! He’s any [UNCLEAR],
he has a house of his own, he has a wife,
he has children, all that he’s given up,
he’s coming. Look at him! He’s a big engineer
with the Municipality, he’s so doing so
much of big, big bridges and all that – he
is here? Do you see in it any Ego? Do you
find any Ego in him? Learn, learn from them.
If not from Me, from them.
The one who arranged our program is a multimillionaire,
do you know that? He’s a multimillionaire.
The one who took us to his to his farm house,
he’s a multimillionaire. But do you find
anything, any …While my grandchildren themselves
have just come from a multimillionaire family.
Do you find that in them? Why? Not that they
don’t have money, they don’t have comforts.
But he told Me that “I haven’t got a car”
- he’s a multimillionaire, “because I
don’t need it, I need a jeep so I bought
five jeeps”. Finished!
But if somebody gets some money there, he’ll
have a swanky car to show off. They can’t
understand, “why to buy when I don’t need
it, I’m working on the farm”. Finished!
And you’re telling Me he‘ll go by ordinary
bus, he’ll do everything. He’s a multimillionaire,
can you believe? Have you seen his business?
How many [looms ?] he has got, which is working
out? Not that he’s miserly, how generous
he was! How his wife lives, how everything,
just see! They might be having hundreds of
diamonds in the house but they don’t show
off. I mean we must learn from them, you see,
also there are poor people, all of them are
smart, very smart. They may live in a small,
little tent but you see, early in the morning
they go to the river, have their bath, they’re
ready for the job! Smartness is one of the
things you have to get in Sahaja Yoga. Spartan!
Living should be Spartan and smartness. Those
two things you must keep in you.
All right! Otherwise they think half of you
are sick. All right! So no thinking, just
now. Put yourself into Nirvichara. Watch Me,
all of you, watch Me. Raise your heads again.
All right! You’ve got rid of your vices
and things, but now get rid of this nonsense,
of a Ego. This is the biggest problem you
have. The Ego is the biggest problem. And
when you think you are dominated better accept
it - hundred times. Don’t tell others!
Who’s right sided, left sided, right sided,
left sided - everybody’s branding everyone!
In Sahaja Yoga nobody remains left, right
sided.
Better? Much better. Whatever is good for
the Spirit, the enjoyment for the Spirit,
then you will be in
the other world, you see. Forget this nonsensical
world that you have been. You
are all seekers, you are great people, God
gave you birth in that country, just to see
what materialism is, not to get involved into
it. Get out! But evolve! Get out! We
have all this poverty, we
have all this discomfort. See the peace. Feel
the peace of the landscape, of human beings,
everybody has peace. Look the smart little
children this age, so happy here. All right?
May God bless you!
And don’t look miserable, anyone of you.
They can’t understand why are you looking
miserable. They are -
they think that they are
not doing their work properly or you don’t
like the food. They just don’t understand
because you look so miserable, anxiety and
tired for nothing at all. All right, may God
bless you!
Let’s have it now! Get up fast and go down!
Let’s see
how fast you can get up. All right! Let’s
see how you
get down.