In life. In the same way, vibrations, vibrations are coming,
they are radiated.
What you have to do is to expose yourself to it.
The best way is not to put in any effort.
Don't worry at what point you have a problem.
Say, many people during meditation, I have seen,
if they catch somewhere they go on looking after it.
You just don't have to worry.
You just let it go
and it will work by itself.
It's very easy.
OK. So you don't have to put in any effort.
This is what meditation is.
Meditation means exposing yourself to God's grace.
Now the grace itself knows how to cure you.
It knows how to mend you,
how to settle down itself
to your own being, how to keep your Spirit kindled.
It knows everything.
So you don't have to worry as to
what you have to do
or what name you have to take
what mantras you have to do.
In meditation you have to do absolutely effortless,
expose yourself fully
and you have to be absolutely thoughtless at that time.
Supposing, possibly, you might not be thoughtless.
At that time you have to just watch your thoughts, but
don't get involved into them.
You will find gradually as the sun rises,
darkness goes away
and the sun's rays go into every [?] and every part
and makes the whole place enlightened.
In the same way your being/kundalini will be completely enlightened
but if you put in an effort at that time
or try to stop something within you
or try to give it a bandhan it will not.
Effortlessness is the only way into meditation,
but you should not be lethargic about it -
should be alert and watch it.
The other side could be that people just dose off. No,
you have to be alert.
If you dose off, nothing will work out.
That's another side of it is.
If you are lazy about it, nothing will work out.
You have to be alert and open,
absolutely aware,
completely effortless,
absolutely effortless.
If you are absolutely effortless,
meditation will work the best.
Don't think of your problems at all,
whatever charkas you have,
anything,
just expose yourself
See when the sun shines
all the nature exposes itself to the sun
and this is the blessings of the sun, effortlessly,
you doesn't put any effort,
it just receives itself -
when it receives the sun's rays and the sun's rays start
acting an activity.
In the same way the all-pervading power
starts working.
You are not to maneuver it,
you are not to do anything about it. Just be effortless,
absolutely effortless.
Don't take any names.
Do not bother if your Agnya is catching,
this is catching, that is catching.
It is working out.
It will go on working
as long as it can
and it will do the miracle that it has to do.
You don't have to worry about it. It knows its job.
But when you put in an effort actually
you create a barrier for it.
So no effort is needed,
be absolutely effortless and say 'let it go, let it go' - that's all.
No mantras been chanted,
in case you find it's impossible, then you can take my name,
but there is no need even.
When you put your hand toward me that is the mantra, it is sufficient,
this gesture itself is mantra.
You see there is no need to say it more,
but the thought, I think, in the mind,
the emotion should be
that we have to spread our hands to that
and it should work.
When this emotion is absolutely complete,
there is no need to say any, and you go beyond.
So one has to be absolutely effortless, absolutely effortless.
That is what it is.
Meditation is for your own ascent,
is for your own capital gains that you have to have.
But once you get into it,
you also achieve your powers.
Like if you become the governor, you get the powers of the governor.
At this time you don't have to think about anybody else.
You are not put your attention to anybody else
but just receive it, just receive it.
Do not think of any other problems,
but that you have to be effortless, absolutely effortless.
It would work best on the people who are just receiving it.
You have problems, that's why you are here,
but you cannot solve them,
they are to be solved by divine power.
[?]
This must be understood fully,
that we cannot solve our problems.
It is beyond us
to solve our problems.
So leave it in the hands of the  divine power
and expose yourself effortlessly, absolutely effortlessly.
Sit in comfort, and properly with both the feet on the ground,
with both the hands relaxed like this.
Be comfortable, you should not be uncomfortable at all.
Be very comfortable because you will sit for quite some time.
And try to put your attention to me, within yourself,
if you can, to my Kundalini if you can.
You can come into my Kundalini and it will be done in no time.
Just like this, the hands should be like this [?]
So effortlessness is the key word,
absolutely effortlessly,
whether you are meditating before me, or before my photograph.