but first and foremost thing is to
meditate and to raise your meditation is
the only way you can grow there's no
other way out because when you meditate
you are in silence you are in
thoughtless awareness then the growth of
awareness takes place then it opens on
but if you are thinking supposing
there's a lake and the lake is
completely in a turmoil nothing can grow
but supposing it is silent then lotuses
can grow and if you can grow in it in
the same way if your mind is agitated
and your growth is not yet fully
expressing itself then it's such a
vicious circle that you are agitated and
your growth is hindered again you are
agitated your growth is inter so the
best way is to take to meditation when
you take to meditation this turmoil will
settle down and ready to settle down
your growth will take place after
meditation will feel definitely that you
have come out very well
you have grown wherever but for that
what has to be very honest you cannot
force people to be honest that's one
thing you can't do you have to be honest
yourself you are not to be hypocrite you
have to see for yourself that whatever
you are doing is for your benevolence
it's for your good and that you have to
do it because it is good for you to
begin and then for the good of the
humanity we are doing for the good of
the humanity now some people who come
for the first time will have lots of
doubts because of ego they have lots of
doubts because of ego how can that be
how can this be how I mean all kinds of
things they ask now you have to say that
first of all you develop your inside you
develop your enlightenment your light is
not sufficient in the light only there
are no doubts supposing in darkness you
think that
this table has no cover it's alright you
can think whatever you like but when
there's like to see for yourself there
is a beautiful cover on top of this
table in the same way it happens to us
that we have to achieve a state and as
we achieve that state then there's no
question there's no doubt there's
nothing and you become so empowered it
is such a simultaneous thing it works as
soon as you achieve something it works
when it works then you are convinced
it's so I'd say it was a very beautiful
new chain starts within yourself and
then you really starts enjoying your joy
of yourself in the most chaotic
conditions this world is today so at
that time a kind of a silence will come
within you when there will be any such
crisis immediately become extremely
silent but this is again estate
attempted so now if there is something
that makes you upset or makes you
unhappy try to reach that point that
axis which is just silence and this
silence will make you really powerful
because this silence is not only yours
when you are in that silence you are in
the silence of the cosmos silence of the
cosmos and the silence of the cosmos
works for you you are in connection with
that cosmic power we can call it it's
more than that is divine power I should
say divine power which is working all
the cosmos also so if you just become
silent within yourself know that you are
sitting in the kingdom of God is like
this
when say you get the great honor of
becoming a king then you walk up to your
throne and you sit down and look around
and you feel the silence of the state
that now you are the king this silence
is the sign that you are definitely
definitely you are now in contact with
the divine you're silent because the
divine is going to look after everything
you don't have to do anything just keep
silent but not forcibly it's again a
state see if any turmoil takes place any
problem takes place suddenly your
attention will jump on to that silence
and once you jump on to that silence you
being in contact with this whole
all-pervading power and when I talk
about all-pervading power we still don't
understand what it is what it means this
all-pervading power of love is it some
sort of an energy floating around or is
it some sort of a river or some sort of
a ether
it is the complete the totality of
reality
you