It’s nice to come back to America....now
there are lots of seekers in this country;
lost.
They are frantically seeking, no doubt.
The are genuine seekers,...ave no doubt about
it....ame back after...ears; it was unfortunate
because...as busy with other parts of the
world and...new I’d find them again when...ame
back.
It is for us to know first of all that if
you are seeking reality, if you are seeking
the truth, we have to be very honest about
it; extremely honest.
You have to know that unless and until you
find it, you should not believe anyone., You
should nbot accept any surface anything.
People may say anything....ay tell you that
you have to have your realization.
That doesn’t mean that you have to believe
me...t doesn’t mean that at all.
But you should not also deny me.
Now, first of all we should know what we are
seeking.
There has been never on this earth such an
urge to seek.
So many seekers!...on’t know if you understand
that...eally different type of category of
people...
call them men of God...re born who are seekers.
And they will go on seeking until they find
the truth.
But one has to know what we are seeking.
What are we to seek?
It is said you have to become.
You have to be.
What do we have to be?
We have to be our Spirit.
Now we do not know what our Spirit is.
The Spirit exists, no doubt.
It watches us.
We know there is...pirit.
But how to bring that Spirit into our conscious
mind...nto our central nervous system...s
the point.
And when people know that there are such demands,
the market also gets filled with enterprise...s
very common.
Americans have the worst hit because you have
worse...ou have money.
That is the worst part of it.
And that’s how all of them are different
down here and they have exploited you.
I’m sorry for all that.
But...ust tell you that you cannot pay for
your realization.
It’s an insult of God.
How can you pay?
How can you p[ay for His love?
Do you pay to...ree when it gives you fruit?
You do not.
Maybe...erchant might take...ruit and settle.
It’s much more than that.
“How can we pay for it?”
Is...imple question we should ask ourselves;
honestly.
Then second point is, you cannot have courses
in God realization.
What university did Christ go?
He was...imple man.
Did he go to any university?
There is no understanding for us.
That God is for everyone, whether you are
rich people or not.
Whether you understand this language or that
language, God’s language is of love and
it’s for everyone…
every person….for every case.
It cannot be for one person or one type of
people or of one category.
But one category is there and they are the
seekers.
Seekers is...pecial category; but only trouble
is they do not know what they are seeking.
For this we have to divert to some authentic
people.
For example, we should see now Christ.
Christ said that you are to be born again.
Last time, when...ame to America, they were
taping my speeches and all that in Los Angeles.
And...as amazed, you see, that poeple objected
to it; felt they should not tape....aid, “Let
them tape.
What does it matter?”
They said, “No Mother, they will publish
it."
...aid, “Let them publish it.
It’s...act.
They should get it.
They should get their relization.
They are to be born again."
But...as amazed!
Then, they write books as if that was their
knowledge....on’t mind that either.
But saying that you are to be born again and
they got...ertificate...
sales certificate...hat we are born again.
How can you certify yourslf you are born again?
You have to be honest about it.
If you are born again something special has
to happen to us.
Like Jung has said that you have to become...ecome
collectively conscious.
Not that...ay we are all brothers and sisters
and we are all one.
No, you have to become that part and parcel
of the whole...s you say the microcosm.
You have to become this microcosm...as to
become that.
That means in evolution, your awareness has
to become something more.
As an animal you see, for example, for an
animal.
He doesn’t see any colors.
He doesn’t see whether is filthy or good.
But you do.
I’m the same way, if you have to rise higher,
the change has to come in your awareness.
That is one thing one should know...hat the
transformation has to take place in your awareness.
And that is what one should see.
Is there any transformation in awareness?
For example, there is some lady who starts
jumping on the seat.
I’ve seen some poeple who come to me.
They just start jumping and they think they
have got realization.
How can that be?
You are not in possession of yourself.
You have to be your own master.
Here somebody is making you jump.
Maybe you are possessed.You have not have
authority over yourself.
You do not know how to control yourself.
And how do you say that you have got realization?
If you become self realized, you are not going
to be enslaved.
You are going to get over all
kinds of slavery.
You have to be...aster.
This should be the test of anything that you
are seeking.
What have you got, you say?
Are you emitting your own powers?...ay say
(as he has said it,...ean,...on’t know why
Warren said this because...eldom start with
this kind of...hing); but if you wanted to
see who said it.
Now to say that...m such and such and such
and such is nonsense....ay be anything.
So what?
What did you get is the point!
Did you feel yourself any more than before?
Did you get anthing more than you have had
before?
Not that you become crazy people or recluses.
That’s not the way.
You are going to become most normal person...as
to be extremely normal.
And above all, you have to have complete control
of yourself.
That is the minimum of minimums one should
know.
But our idea about self realization is so
much spoiled and so many psuedo people have
written., even about Kundalini....as amazed
when...ound out that such big, big books are
written about Kundalini....
saying it is in the stomache, some say it
is in the nose....
it is here and there.
It is not there!
It is in the sacrum bone.
You can see it yourself with your own eyes.
When the Kundalini rises you can see the pulsation
just like...eart....
not in everyone, of course.
But in some poeple who have had an obstruction,
you can see with your naked eyes.
You should be able to see it...appily...nd
you can also feel the pulsation coming to
the head....ean so many pleople have said
it.
There are people now,...m told, who are converting
people into Shikhism and this and that.
And what is Shikhism?
If you need...ead Kabir (sp ?) who is the
basis of Shikhism.
He has said that you have to feel the cool
breeze coming out of your head.
He says...
(Mother quotes in another language).
This means, on the head first of all, there
is the sound of Anahada, is this thub-dub
of the heart and then you feel the cool breeze
coming out.
Is so clearly said, but who reads those people?
Those people who talk even of Hinduism and
all that, do they read Adi Shankaracharia?
What Adi Shankaracharin has said?
He has written books after books on Kundalini;
and not only, but on this Chaintanyita (sp?)
he has written...omplete book.
But people don’t read that.
You get these...
don’t know...xtracts and some sort of...on’t
know how they are not afraid of God?
They are not afraid...ust to make some money...
don’t know.
Are they going to carry this money with them?
It’s very, very wrong!
It’s very sinful....on’t mind what ever
they do.
It’s alright if they want to be smugglers
and all.
There are many like that.
But they spoil your Kundalini.
You are damaged.
And this is the thing which...m concernd about.
It’s...ery sad thing.
Coming to America is...eal _____?
for me because...id send some of the people
who were really realized sould and they came
here.
They ran away within...ays.
They said they will never recognize us...here
is...arrier...here is...arrier.
They will never recognize Mother.
They rushed back.
They stayed in New York, one of them stayed.
He ran away.
He couldn’t stand it.
He said, “They just want something else.
They don’t want Ìod.
They don’t want their spirit."
Of course,...on’t believe that.
These barriers are created to us because we
read about it.
We try to understand through reading.
It’s good, but you must come to...ight conclusion
through logical, logical understanding; not
rationality.
Rationality is something which can take you
anywhere.
Rationality can give you...you can) rationalize
even...urder...nything!
But, logically, you must understnd.
Where should we reach?
What should happen to us?
As seekers, what are we expecting?
This is...ery, very precarious and important
time...s more to say.
The Last Judgement has started.
That has started.
That’s how you are all here and you are
seeking.
The way it will judge, is the Kundalini has
to rise.
Your have to become self realized.
Then you start feeling your centers on your
fingers.
Tomorrow...ill give you all the information
about the centers and all that and...ill tell
you how He will judge you.
What are your centers that are catching?
And then you will judge that and you will
know what is the problem....
how to get it done...ow to get it alright.
There is no technique for _____?...ike if
you sow...eed it becomes...ree.
There is no technique.
If you have flowers, they become...ruit.
It’s...iving thing.
And living things don’t have any technique.
But once you get connected, then you must
know the Divine laws and you must know the
Divine technique.
But first you must be realized.
Unless and until you are put to the Mains,
how can you use this machine¿ You are not
yet put to the Mains.
How can you do anything?
It’s like telephoning somewhere without
having connection.
You must be connected., first of all to the
Divine.( but this is not...ifficult thing.).
In modern times is very easy.
Formerly, it was, like you can say,...ree.
In the beginning you get only one or two flowers.
But the time has come.
The blossom time has come.
Already today,...ent to see William Blake’s
drawing exhibition.
And he said, “All your sins and blasphemy
and everything will be forgiven.
All your sins will be forgiven."
He has said about these days.
He said that the God of _____?
will become prophets and they will have power
to convert and transform others into prophets.
He has clearly prophesized about Sahaja Yoga.
Every word he has said about it.
But people don’t read Blake.
If you go
and see his exhibition, you’ll be surprised
how in the “Pilgrim’s Progress” only
he has given clearly how you face life.
And there are some Sahjaja Yogis here sitting
down at your back here.
And they have come from London and some of
them from Australia.
And they could see.
This is how you face it.
But to get realization is the easiest thing;
to maintain it...ather difficult.
But also that is possible.
Now we have in London (you will be surprised)...all
at least one and one-half times bigger than
this.
And the hall was completely filled.
And they rose up to sing...ong of Jeruseleum
which was...reat experience for me to see
that.
But( you won’t believe)...tarted the work
in England because my husband got elected
to...ost there.
That’s how we were there.
And in the beginning,...as working with seven
people...even hippies,...hould say...even
people for four years.
And now of course, in the whole of England
we have many centers and lots of people have
got realization and they are working it out.
It’s working out very well.
We have some people here from there who have
come.
Dr.
David is here and Hesta is...arrister.
Then we have these two from Australia...r.
Warren, who was...iplomat.
And these two are American girls...oth of
them...h Christine...as been with me since
long and Marcia who got her realization only
two months back, but she was so upright and
so straight forward.
And you should know that it is you who should
decide.
If you say...m your Guru, alright...ccept
it for the time being.
But...other is always...uru.
If you say that your mother had to teach you
so many things...lso...ave to teach you some
things.
But actually, it is you who is your own guru.
You have to become it.
Unless and until you are connected, how will
you judge?
Once you get connected, you will be able to
check.
But you don’t think it is...ental activity
that is going to bring you your realization.
No, God has placed everything beautifully
within us...verything.
You have got your Kundalini very nicely placed
in the sacrum bone.
Now, see this bone.
Sacrum is...riangular bone called “sacrum”
so that Greeks know about this bone.
They knew it was...acred bone.
Sacrum means sacred in Greek.
When...ent to Greece,...as surprised.
They have the complete idea of kundalini;
complete idea.
And they have this Athena also...eans the
Primordial Mother.
In Sanskrit language, Athena...thens comes
from that and the way She was holding...erpent
in her hand and everything...bsolutely She
is the Primordial Kundalini.
And the whole concept was there and when...ent
into the study of that...ried to find out
what it was....
how did they know?
They said we had some Indo-Aryian groups coming
down here and they told us these things and
that’s how they know about it.
But, that was all lost
because they brought all the Gods to the level
of human beings and made alot of mess out
of it.
Now we have to know that how Christ was such
an important incarnation on this earth.
We have really made...ess of the whole thing.
He said that you are to be born again.
Actually, he came on this center where you
see this red mark.
You see...t is placed in the optic chiasma.
In the center is...ubtle center called as
Agnya chakra.
In the Hindu scriptures, He is called as Mahavishnu.
But...ill tell about His advent when He came
on this earth.
We say, He is the gate; he is the door.
He is the door below the limbic area.
And the limbic area is the Kingdom of God.
Where one has to center, the attention has
to enter.
How you enter into it...ot bodily, but your
attention has to enter it.
Your attention is apread out in this area.
But not there...t has to enter through that
area into the limbic area and ultimately,
is the fontanel area.
It becomes soft and the kundalini has to come
out and with the cool breeze, this is your
actual baptism.
Is not the baptism you go to some theological
college to learn and say alright...
baptize...t’s all artifical.
It’s absolutely artificial.
That’s not the way you can baptize.
You have to be...ealized soul to do that.
John the Baptist was...ealized soul.
He was the one who knew how to do it.
And he did it for all of them.
And that’s how it should happen to you.
The kundalini has to rise and give you realization.
Now the Christ advent came at this point.
It’s...ery important one because today we
have brought the charts and all that but tomorrow
we’ll be giving you, in...ull way, how the
ego and super-ego are sucked.
They create...arrier here.
Our ego and super-ego gives us our I-ness.
We get seperated.
When He’s awakened, this portion gets opened
out and then the kundalini can rise.
That’s why it is said, Christ is to be awakened
within you.
But it can be only done by...erson with Divine
authority.
And such...erson cannot live on your money.
He cannot be...arasite.
Such...erson has nothing to do wioth money.
How can you purchase such...erson.?
Such...erson is beyond....
beyond your purchase...eyond your money.
You cannot do anything for such...erson.
Such...erson just gives.
He just gives.
He emits.
It cannot take anything.
It cannot receive.
It cannot!
You may try, but doesn’t.
One day...as walking...ittle bit, my foot
was...ittle twisted and one of the doctors
she said, “Alright Mother, I’ll try to
massage it."
Yet she was relaxing that side and...as saying,
“What’s happening to you?”
She said, “Mother, what is this?
Lots of vibrations are coming and...m just
massaging yourself and...m massaging myself....
the way it is cooling down and soothing."
So, such...erson cannot take anythging from
you.
Now, the most important point which...ould
like to reach you is this: that we don’t
realize hos precariously we are placed otherwise,
also.
There are equal and opposite forces working
on us.
For example,...isease like cancer....as surprised
to hear at this country, theere are patients...ne
among four...f cancer disease....ave told
this ten years back, that cancer can only
be cured through Sahaja Yoga.
There’s no other way out....ave cured many
cancer patients and you can also cure once
you get realized.
How it happens...ow you cure cancer...ll this
knowledte you can have...ree of charge.
Free of this thing.
Actually, first you must get your realization.
Without that, there is no use telling you
because you come into this room; it is all
dark; you are blind; you cannot see anything.
What’s the use telling you the size of the
room, and color of the chairs, and color of
all this?
No use telling you.
Best thing is to open the lights and open
your eyes so that you can see for yourself.
And the complete knowledge becomes your own.
Then is better to talk.
Otherwise supposing even though when you can’t
see,...o on giving you the complete history
about electricity and about everything.
You’ll be bored and stiff.
And its of no use.
First thing is you must get your realization.
That is the first thing.
Cancer can easily be cured by Sahaja Yoga.
Absolustely there is no doubt.
And there cannot be another doubt that it
cannot be cured by anything else.
In our body, we have...articular system called
as...ympathetic nervous system.
How this sympathetic nervous system goes into...errible
tension when we go to extremes of any kind.
Say smoking, for example.
Now smoking is...ery interesting thing.
According to me, this America is the Visshuddi
chakra....
is the center of this çenter.
This center gets spoiked when we smoke and
the smoking is the maximum here.
Like the Europe is the liver and there people
drink.
And they are so much in it and their lives
are the worst of all in Europe.
England is the heart.
It (England) is lethargic....ean the whole
thing is in such...ess that...on’t know
what...ave to face.
But...as happy to know that now the smoking
is going down.
But with realization, smoking just disappears.
You don’t have to work at it.
Marsha herself used to smoke alot.
She told me....as amazed.
But she has biven up completely.
Drugs and all those things drop out just like
something unnecessary because...ransformation
takes place.
And the transmutation starts...hen the transmutation
starts, all these things drop out.
You enjoy the best of health...est of your
heart...est of your miond....
and your emotions come out.
The best part of it is that this is what one
has to achieve....
the whole humanity has to achieve.
But the few who are the seekers have to do
it first.
They have to do it first; they are the foundation.
Like in every evolution, only...ew fishes
had to come out; then many came
out.
In the same way, few people have to do it.
I’m happy there are...ew today.
Though others are disappointed,...m not....m
happy because I’ll have to work harder.
If there are too many, maybe difficult.
As he said, it’s true that...ave realization
to six thousand people in...illage in India.
But they are not complicated.
See, they aren’t so complicated.
They don’t live with the sorrows (word?)
you have here or the tensions you have....
or the litigations you have....
the problems you have....ave seen Indians
who have come here to earn money.
They have all gone off their heads....ean
really, they have become half crazy.
The gentleman with whom...m now putting up,
he told me already so many Indians have been
under litigation.
This happened, that happened and all kinds
of tensions are building up.
Here, despite all our modern vest(word?) we
also have landed ourselves into terrible tensions
of this machinery; this machinate and all
that.
The villagers in India are extremely simple
people.
They lead an extremely simple life.
They have no complications....on’t say that
it would be so easy here as the way they have
got realization.
Of course, one has to work hard.
Like we had about seven people....ad all of
them...t took about three hours to get realization.
So, it could be that way also.
It cannot be guaranteed; it cannot be promised.
It cannot be certified.
It has to happen...s the main point...s the
happening...s the happening.
You have to become.
It has to be actualized.
It is not to be believed.
That’s what you should know.
If you are honest, you are to prove.
And, you want to have it, you’ll get it.
I’ll work very hard.
It’s you who has to have patience with yourself....ave
all the patience and love.
No doubt about it.
But you all have to have patience....old you
seven people...as working for four years.
Suppose its not going to be that bad, because
with them...orked out many permutations and
combinations.
Now,...now all the permutations and combinations
that are really harmful to people and how
they are eradicated.
But still...ould say...ould still have to
study some American complications which...o
not know.
Nine years back, people were simpler people
here and they are all mostly have gone away
or also at that time the same thing is that...ould
not contact and everything works on money.
You see you have to give them money so they
publisize you.
Then they publisize you...hen you get more
money.
Here there is no question of money, you see.
You see my whole basic thing is you have to
get real people so the real thing, without
money.
And then, you cannot have...ig circus; you
cannot have...ig thing and it has to be started
in...enuine way...n...eal way.
They asked me that there is, there are agencies
who work out all these tings....aid to begin
with...on’t think that
this is important.
We should work it out.
Let’s see.
There will be some people who feel attracted
and come.
And let’s work it out this way.
Still,...ould like your advice as to where
we can go, when, and in...ecent manner whenever
we can advertise.
Just now...ady told us that if you go to these
shops it will be good idea.
We would like to invite people for this experience.
This is your right.
You are seekers and just like...ank, you have
got your bank accounts and you just cash it.
And these are lots of places also.
And whatever mistakes are done, don’t worry
about it.
One of the big problems...aced in Englad is
that they all suffer from...enter or left
visshuddi which comes out of guilt.
You see, they are guilty all the time.
Maybe Catholicism that makes them feel guilty,
but it’s...ery, very common trouble with
them.
They all the time feel guilty.
Now, what are you feeling guilty for?
We must suffer.
Why?
Why should you suffer?
Christ has suffered for you.
Did he leave anything for you to suffer?
We whould be guilty about what?
Why are you guilty?
I’m talking of ocean of compassion...cean
of love.
Now what guilt can you have?
And is...ery big mistake to think that we
have done little mistake here and little mistake
there.
God has to save this creation.
It is He who has to come in compassion and
has to do something about it.
If He doesn’t save you, his creation is
lost.
You shouldn’t feel like that inb...mall
way.
It’s all very childish,...ould say, like...hild
to feel “Oow” after this mistake.
But no...our Father is so great, is so full
of love you have to just look at Him and He’ll
work it out.
You should forgive yourself; that is one of
the things...ould request of you.
First of all, before forgiving anybody else,
you must forgive yourself.
That is the first thing you have to do before
realization.
Of course, in one lecture,...annot tell you
much about it.
This is just an introductory lecture.
And we haven’t got our charts and all that
because first day, if you start seeing the
charts, you (word?) mechanical and you think
it’s some sort of...omputer.
You work it out.
Actually, you are...omputer, you become...ivine
computer.
But that’s...ifferent system and so it’s
better that we talk about it just now.
And you get your realization; work it out.
We are going to be here for some time and...ope
you’ll be able to follow my lectures and
follow the whole thing.
It’s such...remendous thing....ust tell
you about this in five hundred...00...ectures
in London...t least...inimum....ay that every
time...peak.
They say, “Mother, you are speaking something
now."
So, you can imagine how much knowledge there
is there.
But you are knowledge; you become knowledge
yourself.
In Australia, the newspaper people were very
good to me because there was some happening....ady
was very seriously ill
and she had some sort of...ery serious stroke
and...riend of hers was...ig man at the newspapers
and one of the Sahaja Yoginis there gave my
photograph to her.
And she did get well from that...rom the photograph
only.
So, this man started thinking about it and
then they did...ig publicity for me.
So, it was lucky ,I should say, for Australians
and...as there for about one month or so...hree
weeks.
And we got thousands there now...housands.
There are seven cities where we have seven
centers.
It has worked....ust say, Australians are
very good for realization.
It was surprising because certain people got
realization and settled down and they knew
it was the trugh.
That was the thing.
YTou have to be intelligent enough to see
what i8s the truth.
Don’t allow your intelligence to cheat you.
Be careful about your intelligence...lso,
it can cheat you.
But you should be really sharp about it to
see what is the truth.
And wise.
And that is what you are going to have.
Now,...ould request you to ask me questions
because you see you all must be having lots
of questions.
You have your mind and you should better ask
because...on’t want whild we are giving
you realization that you should feel that,
“Oh,...idn’t ask this question to Mother,”...though
this makes no difference whether you ask me
questions or not.
It is...ery different thing.
It is beyond your mind.
You go beyond your mind.
You go beyond your mind; beyond your ego;
beyond your super-ego.
You become something else.
So if you have any questions, you can ask.
Question: There are many people who come offering
realization.
You come offering realization....ould like
to know something about this.
In other words, you have something unique
to offer, is that right?
Yes, of course...ould say...on’t know how
many have come here and how many have been
thugs and how many have been real.
But, actually most of them have been thugs
only because what they offer you...
don’t know...
have had people from other gurus...ll kinds
of gurus you see.
And there are one or two sitting here.
All of them have been to someone or something
like that.
Now as...old you, the uniqueness of Sahaja
Yoga is this: Sahaja means...Saha” is with;
“ja” is born...s born with you....
is your own....
within you.
Now the uniqueness about it is this: that
it is what you are seeking.
That’s what you are going to get....
is your spirit....
is that you become that...s the uniqueness.
It’s not that...an say there is...ourse
of
ten days...ou go through the course or you
pay for say...umping course or...o-called
flying course or something like that.
It is what you are.
You become that.
The uniqueness of it is that it’s...appening
which is...iving happening.
You see, we don’t do anything that is...iving
work.
What we do is...ead work.
Like...ree died; we make chairs; we think
we have achieved alot.
You see this wall is all made of dead things,
isn’t it?
We have just changed the form.
And these forms actually try to dominate us.
This chair becomes...ort of an obsession for
us because we can’t sit on the ground....
this...e have to use...hair like that.
Now, anything that we do is all dead.
Supposing somebody has to jump.
Anybody can jump., What is there to be jumping?
People pay money to jump.
Can you imagine?...o take off clothes?...eople
pay money.
How can that be?
What is so great about it?
We must understand: what do we become?
What powers do we become?
You see, there’s...uru.
He says, “Alright,...ive you some knowledge."
Now, what knowledge has he got?
One gentleman came.
He said, “I’ve already got knowledge."
...aid, “What knowledge do you have?”
For example, Warren can tell you where is
your chakra catching.
Where is your kundalini; where it is obstructed;
how to raise it; how to bring it us; how to
take it down.
The he can cure patients.
He must have cured...
don’t know how many.
You all can cure patientes and knowingly...hat
it is.
What chakra is catching...hat is happening...hat
is the mental process.
Everything, you know in your awareness.
You become...ifferent person...s...ransformation
that takes place.
You become master of yourself.
To explain,...ill tell you...ery simple anology.
Say we are traveling by....
we are trying to learn how to drive.
Now you have got an accelerator and you have
got...rake.
You’re working it out.
You see one, then another....e have two centers...wo
channels within us which...how tomorrow...ne
for our actions.)
So we start working both of these and start
managing.
We go to extremes....
this way...hat way...nd make all kinds of
mistakes...hatever it is...ut we try to balance
ourselves.
When do we learn the car driving?
When we learn it.
Once you have done that there the Master is...itting
at the back.
And once He sees you have balanced it, He
gives you your place.
You become the master of your being.
This is what has to happen....
the breakthrough!
The breakthrough has to take place.
Is not just...ake believe that, “Oh, we
have become like this."
...ean there are people who believe they are
self realized.
There are many like that, you see, that believe
that they are that.
They are not.
Because they should be able to tell.
They should become collectively conscious.
They should be able to tell where is the kundalini;
where is the problem.
Now, for
example, you are sitting....
alright, now you do not know about the gentleman
next to you...here is the problem?
Where is his kundalini?
You cannot give him realization.
But the people who are realized souls...ven
the small children...an do it...ery small
children.
They will immediately say, “This is the
center catching.
Here...he finger...ittle children will show
the same finger.
For example, if you have...roblem, say on
this center.
Alright.
All the children you put some sort of...hing
to close their eyes.
And ask them, “Which center is catching?”
They’ll all say this.
All will say the same thing.
And they also know how to correct this.
Little, little children know how to correct
this.
They are born realized and born realized children
are dynamic.
And they know...o many born-realized children
are born these days.
How will you know whether they are born realized
children?
You do not know who is...alse guru and who
is...eal guru.
You don’t know anything!
There’s no discrimination power.
But, if you want to know also about that,
you can just put the hands towards them and
they can find out.
Your vibrations will vanish completely.
You’ll have heat coming from horrible gurus.
If you see any horrible guru, you’ll find
very bad vibrations coming in that...ll burning
and some of them just stop the vibrations.
You just don’t get any vibrations from them.
You can make it out from everyone what sort
of...erson he is.
For example, there are athiests who don’t
believe in God.
Alright.
Now when they get realization they can ask
the question, “Is there God?”
Tremendous vibrations.
To find out relatively, we can say, take three
people...ne from...uru who’s horrid, one
from...unatic asylum, and one who’s...ealized
soul, according to us.
Alright?
Now you put themn together.
You’ll find the one who’s from the guru,
maybe feeling hot...ery hot...r may not get
realization at all...aybe frozen...nything.
The one from lunatic asylum may feel hot...orrible...ut
he may get well...e may get realization.
And the third person, who is the one who is...ealized
soul will get only...ool breeze.
We have cured many people who are meantally
like that...any have been cured...ou can cure
also.
It is you who become that...s the point.
You become that...t’s your right.
You have been seeking all your lives.
Actually, it is impossible to believe that
there could be someone who does it just for
loves sake.
You can’t believe itr because it’s so
money oriented...he whole thing is so money
oriented....
that we can’t believe it.
Even our parents; we think they love us for
money....ean, it has gone to that limit of
absurdity.
But God is l,ove and love is there.
Ånd in his love everyone should do it.
It has to happen.
Any other questions?
Question: (A woman asks where the other public
meeting will be).
(Warren says he’ll make an announcement
later)
Mother: You see, all of us have got it and
we’ll give all that to you and you’ll
come along to those lectures and you will
help us to bring...
(you see actually we do not know how to meet
the seekers.
That’s the main point with us.
And we don’t need anything else.
Like the lady offered...lso.
We don’t need it.
We don’t need any money.
We have everything.
We have no problem.
And no money...othing.
We have got places to live in and we have
no problem of any kind.
What we want...e have also got halls and everything
and we don’t need anything.
But what we want...hat we want...eekers to
come down and you have to suggest how to get
them; that’s all.
(Announcements of meetings)
Question:...
lady asks for Mother’s comment on somebody
but asks Her not to judge.)
Mother: No,...ave to.
I’m sorry,...ave to.
You see, it’s very good of you to say that...hould
not make comment(word?).
But...ave to.
I’m sorry.
Because you see,...an’t bear to see the
way their kundalini’s have gone down.
The connection has to be.
You see, when Christ was criticizing them,
they said the same thing to him.
“Why should you criticize them?
They don’t critisize you?”
So He said, “The Satanic are not going to
speak against the Satanic."
That’s what it is.
You do not know how serious it is.
When you will know, you will be amazed.
You do not know how serious it is and that’s
shy you are saying that.
Once you find out shy...m saying this.
You see, it is not easy to say anything against
these people.
It’s not easy.
Bust none of them...
have said about them...ach one of them about
l0 years back...penly...bout each one of them...ho
they are.
Nobody has even tried to even bring any suit
or any law suit against me.
And whatever is wrong,...ave to say that.
I’m sorry, my child.
You see, this is not...hing where you can
allow Satanic things to happen.
We have to discriminate.
You will know yourself.
You cannot love...nake like that.
You must know...nake is...nake and...uman
being is...uman being.
Everybody has his own values.
You see,...m not here going to be angry with
you for that.
But...m angry with them!...ith all of them...efinitely.
You do not...ou just wait and see.
You yourself will be so angry.
I’ll show you.
Say,...irl who came from one of them...hugs.
She was epileptic.
Her daughter was epileptic.
Her husband was epileptic.
She was...randdaughter of...uke.
She had lost all her money.
They had sold their house.
They were on the streets.
Absolutely.
And she is...eeker!
If you are...ohter, what would you say to
that?
You will say they are very nice people?
You will go and garland them?
Not one, but I’ll show you thousands of
them.
Here we have cases who have come.
She is Hesta...itting here.
You just ask her.
How much she was harmed!
How she was harmed.
She would have been dead!
Do you think...hould say they are nice people?
Apart from anything else, they spoil your
chances of realization.
I am not here for votes or anything.
Why should...ry to please them?...ave to tell
the truth, if you don’t mind....ave to tell.
Question: Oh, then...ould just like to ask,
what about people that are doing chakra therapy
and they charge very high prices?
Maybe they are not high prices and they help
people and yet people don’t have that kind
of money....ould like to ask you, what do
you think about people who do chakra therapy
and charge fees?
Mother:...on’t know what sort of...
(word?)
make believes.
How can you have any kind of chakra thearpy
without realization?
It’s all make believe.
You blieve all this nonsensical people.
What am...o do now?
Why do you believe them?
You see chakra therapy,...ean...on’t know...n
ordinary Indian can understand.
Only...aint can do it.
He has to be...aint.
How can he charge money?...aint will not take...ie
from you.
It is...imple thing, try to understand that.
Question: Well,...lways thought that, but
this is America.
Chakra therapy is...ew thing, I’ve heard...laugh)
(woman keeps telling her story)
Mother:...ell you that.
What is it.
You might get...emporary help.
No doubt about it.
You can get...emporary help.
You see, now you are bringing into controversies
so...ave to tell you about it.
But you don’t mind it.
What heppens within us, we have some stored
energies in the chakras, alright?
And, like acupuncture, is also...s not to
be done by someone who is not...ealized soul.
Is to be done only by realized souls.
If acupuncture is done by someone who is not...ealized
soul...
mean it’s against Zen (?).
It’s against.
You have to be...word ?),...ean people don’t
read about it....usha (word ?) means...ealized
soul.
If you are not...ealized soul, you are not
supposed to do it.
Now, this one also...hakra therapy...hat you
can do is to work on the sympathetic nervous
system.
Now the sympathetic nervous system, you can
pull out the little energy that you have,
but you develop other problems with it.
Sahaja Yoga is...hing by which you get open
to the all pervading power....ll the time
flowing within us.
You have to open yourslf to that universal
being within your heart...hich is the spirit.
You don’t have to sort of lessen energy
here and energy there and energy there.
You don’t have to take that energy out.
But the energy from the above comes in.
Like grace, it flows.
And that’s how always such things can lead
into terrible problems...ental problems....
all kinds of things.
Supposing you try to treat somebody mentally....
then you extract the physical energy.
Then the person will suffer physically.
You see, this
stored energy for...articular chakra, which...ill
explain to you...verything...ll right?
And you cannot charge for raising your kundalini
because you have your kundalini intact there.
You are just there.
You have everything.
Only thing, by my being here, your kundalini
rises by itself.
So you cannot pay.
Do you pay the Mother Earth for sprouting...eed?
They do help temporarily.
They do.
For example, somebody gives you...antra.
Alright, take...antra...’ll tell you...ay
they say Rama Sita.
Now, there cannot be only one mantra belonging
to any one in any science of mantras.
Because you people are so naive...ou see...hey
say “all right, you take the name of Rama."
This cannot be done.
Rama mantra is only on the right heart chakra.
If you have...roblem, has to be given by...ealized
soul because it has to be...onnected one.
It is...cience, you know.
All of them know what mantra is to be said
at what point because they know how to raise
the kundalini....
they know where it is obstructed and what
mantra is to be said and which Deity is to
be awakened.
Notice the mantra for which particular mantra
(word?)...hey know all that and they know
all the methods.
But why they may give you...antra?
Now, you may feel better...eally, sometimes
you may feel dynamic.
You feel, “Oh,...m very activated; maybe...m
over active."
And...pirit (if that name may be allowed)
may come around...nd you may become possessed...nd
you might become extremely active.
But, then you’ll go down.
Within five years, there will be...omplete
decline.
You’ll be...ecluse.
You’ll be...rightened person.
You’ll be...oward.
You won’t be able to even...here are people
I’ve known who can not even face (what do
you call that...arlic.
Can you imagine...fraid of...egetable?
It’s really...here are people, if you snow
then garlic, they are frightened....ean, are
you going to become like that?
Is that freedom?
Question: (A man had treid raising his kundalini
and was asking about seeing something (?) in
his head and other places).
Mother: You see, if you try your own self,
you see trying with the kundalini...ctually
the sympathetic goes into activity.
You have no right on the parasympathetic.
Parasympathetic is the one which balances
and that is the central path of Sushumna through
which the kundalini has to rise.
But if you try anything, what you do is...lways
you can use sympathetic.
I’ll give you an example.
Supposing you are running fast.
Alright, then you can raise the rate of your
heart.
But you cannot slow it down.
It slows down
by itself.
That is parasympathetic activity.
So you just get into sympathetic activity
and sympathetic activity, if you overdo it,
then all these symptoms happen and it’s
not healthful.
On the contrary, chakras go into...
.(quite like this is the left and the right
sympathetic and these are the centers).
They get pulled down like that and if they
are pulled like this, then you are harmed.
So is not an experience of kundalini; is of
the sympathetic.
Question: “....his wasn’t anything...as
looking for or asking for, (etc.)but how come
it went down, instead of coming up?”
Mother: No, it doesn’t go down.
Kundalini never goes down.
It goes upward...lways.
The thing that comes down is the grace, you
see.
The grace comes down, not the Kundalini.
Kundalini always goes upwards.
And the grace comes on your sympathetic which
cools you down completely.
You become absolutely relaxed with the grace.
But the kundalini itself always goes up.
It never comes down.
But, in people, it so happens that kundalini
goes through this central path.
Now, if it is...ort of...ery much rugged or
if it is extremely smooth due to the mistakes
of the seekers, then it falls down.
It falls down...t falls down is...ifferent
point then going like that.
It falls down.
Then you have to raise it again and tie it
up.
Again, raise it and tie it up.
In many people, it has to be done but it can
work out.
You will get the complete knowledge, don’t
you worry.
Now, he has been in eighteen months, but he
is...aster of kundalini.
He can raise your kundalini and you are just
like him.
You would become the same.
There’s no problem at all.
It will work out.
Question:...ow did you get your realization?”
Mother:...as born like that.
I’m like this for ages....
ancient....m...ystery...
should say at the beginning.
We should keep it as...ystery.
Then you’ll discover me, all right?
Let’s have it that way.
First you discover yourself and then discover
me.
Will be better idea, isn’t it?
Because...on’t want to say something which
will unnecessarily make some people upset.
Best is...ou become something.
Question:...s it true...ealized guru has cool
air; not hot?”
Mother: No, hot is very dangerous.
Interuption: “....ut...ool one, is also
dangerous?”
Mother:...ut you don’t get air.
You might feel extremely cool if you are...ow
blood pressure patient.
If you are...eft sided persons...f you are
possessed, you feel absolutely cool, very
cool.
That’s not good.
Feeling cool is different from...ool breeze;
like you feel...reeze coming.
But should not be hot in any case.
Hot is...ery dangerous thing.
If it is too hot, that heat...t’s not good.
Question: “Why do you get...low of hot air?”
Mother: It’s...riction.
It’s...riction of the Divine.
You see, when the Kundalini’s rising, She
should normally give you cool breeze....
cool breeze in the hands...hen She does.
But if there’s...riction...lways friction
makes it hot.
But it cools down.
There’s no problem.
In the beginning, most of you will get hot,
little bit.
Because, after all, you see you know...ou
are all very complicated people.
Our brains especially are modern brains, you
see.
So we have been thinking, thinking, thinking.
Just, we cannot stop our thinking for...inute
even.
But the first thing that will happen is that
you enter into thoughtless awareness.
That’s called as Nirvachara Samahdi, in
Sanskrit.
Means you become....
you are aware, absolutely aware.
There are no thoughts.
The thoughts(word?)...hat the awakening of
Christ...hat’s the thing that should happen
to you.
Once that happens, then it passes through
here and you can feel the cool breeze.
Many people who smoke cannot feel breeze in
the hand at the beginning because of this
chakra being...ittle bit in trouble.
But, then you start feeling...arsha (??), you
feel quite all right in the hands?
She used to smoke.
She is...reat seeker,...ust say.
All right, should we have it now?
Question: “If we’re going to receive the
Kundalini awakening, is it...rocess over several
days?”
Mother: No, it is...plit of...econd actually;
it is...plit of...econd.
But it takes time in some people, as...aid,
because if there are obstructions...ou see.
Now if you have...eautiful runway and...eautiful
aircraft, then the landing and take off are
very smooth.
But sometimes it is...econd-hand stop.
Interruption:...hen, you mean it may come
tomorrow?”
Warren: No, it’s highly likely you’ll
get it tonight.
Mother: Yes, of course, just now.
Just now.
But you have to learn how to maintain it,
is the point.
Just now, you are going to have it.
It’s spontaneous.
It is just now.
But only one thing is that you should know
how to maintain it.
Now supposing you get it and then outside
you start thinking about it.
Then it goes down.
The vibrations will be lost.
You have to be careful.
It’s like...eed sprouting, you know....eed
sprouting.
It’s...eedling in the beginning.
So you have to be careful for about seven
days.
If you are careful, it is settled down in
about seven days.
You have to be careful.
We will tell you about it.
Interruption: “The reason I’m asking is
because we’ll become messengers...
”
Mother: Yes, of course, of course.
Next time I’m not going to import people
from Australia and from England.
You have got to have the Americans here to
do this job.
We are not going to import them from all over
the place.
Two are coming from Switzerland.
So that’s not...ery good sign....hink, actually,
Americans should go abroad and do it.
They’ll go to India and to Indian villages....
and they’ll do it in the Indian villages.
Very simple, alright?
Question: (Unintelligible....
something about...eadache).
Mother:...ell you what’s the problem with
you.
You have...iver problem.
You have...iver problem and that is showing.
You see this is the beauty of Sahaja Yoga.
Once you get realization, you start seeing
your body; feeling it.
Whatever your problem, you know.
You have You have...iver problem and it has
to be corrected.
Now,...now you have...iver problem sitting
down here.
And it’s very simple.
Now in Sahaja Yoga, you can correct your liver
in no time.
Once you correct your liver, you’ll have
never...eadache.
But, it suggests that you have that and you’d
better get rid of it.
You see it’s good you have...eadache, now
you’ll get after your liver.
Otherwise, it becomes horribly bad, if you
continue....ean,...erson becomes mad and still
he doesn’t know that he’s gone mad.
It’s like that.
The disease crawls into you.
But in Sahaja Yoga, immediately you know.
And you are...iver patient, you know that.
It has to be corrected and it’s not difficult.
Most of the diseases can be cured, except
for...ew like...hould say, cataracts or something
like that where something is dead or maybe
where they put an artificial limb and all
that.
We can’t work out all of these things.
But most of the things get cured, automatically....ean,
here they say if you cure someone, you’ll
get put in the prison....ean,...on’t cure.
You just get cured, you see.
So...ope legally I’m all right.
Christ would have been in jail here....on’t
know about the laws.
But this time, I’m sure they cannot crucify
me.
It’s alright.
Let’s work it out.