Today is the happiest day for all of you,
for the whole universe, because Shri Ganesha
was created.
He was created to emit auspiciousness through
His Chaitanya [- Divine Vibrations –ed.].
First, the whole cosmos was filled with this
Chaitanyasrishti [- creation of Divine Vibrations
–ed.].
Then Brahmadeva came into play, and He created
all the matter.
But
the greatest blessings of the Divine Power
was to symbolize Chaitanya, and this Chaitanya
has many aspects, but specially in Shri Ganesha,
it is auspiciousness.
In these modern times people have lost the
sense of auspiciousness.
Everything that emits vibrations, Chaitanya,
is auspicious, is shubh, and whatever does
not is not by any chance auspicious.
So first of all, whatever you worship, whatever
you accept, all of them have to be auspicious
things.
Every shape has a coefficience and all these
shapes which you see, not necessarily give
vibrations.
But in the human beings also, we find there
are many people, like you, who have Chaitanya
flowing in them.
But this Chaitanya when it flows, we just
take Shri Ganesha for granted.
We do not understand that we have to awaken
Shri Ganesha within us.
Means what?
What we have to do?
There is Shri Ganesha already existing in
you and as I said that innocence cannot be
lost, so Shri Ganesha is eternal being, eternal
child – He cannot be lost and He cannot
be destroyed.
So He’s all the time there.
Maybe some clouds of your ill doings are covering
the great personality of innocence.
But it is always there present.
So now, what should we do to keep this Ganesha
all the time shining within us?
Is to first remember that you were made in
the same pattern as Shri Ganesh.
But His Kundalini is on His stomach; His pure
desire is on His stomach.
It’s very significant to understand why
it is there that His Kundalini is on His stomach.
That means He does not have to conquer the
temptations of Mooladhara at all.
But He has His Kundalini on His stomach, that
means He is also beyond the temptations of
food, of power or anything because His stomach
represents absolute abandonment, absolute
freedom.
He’s not bothered as to how He looks that…
these days there is a big fashion that you
cannot have a big belly.
I mean this is becoming a big… not only
fashion but a big business.
But as age grows, you have to have it.
Even small children have that and they look
so sweet.
Those people who are very thin must understand
that they might be getting some prizes in
the… maybe beauty contest or something,
but they do not have that majesty, that royalty,
that dignity in them as they should have.
So Shri Ganesha accepts everything.
He has a head with a trunk.
He accepts it.
Of course, is important, He should have that.
Because head of the elephant suggests that
He is not like a human being who develops
ego, superego, conditionings, but He is just
all the time one with the Divine.
He accepts His body, He accepts His head,
He accepts His ears, He accepts everything
that He is made of.
He doesn’t aspire to something – some
entrepreneurs put some ideas and He wouldn’t
go run after them.
He won’t try to change Himself; He won’t
try to create that fashion and all that.
He is what He is… because He is a satisfied
soul.
The Kundalini on the stomach shows a complete,
self-contented, satisfied personality of Shri
Ganesha.
When you have all the powers within you, you
know you are powerful, then you don’t hanker
after all these things and you don’t try
to make a position or an impression of others.
For example, He would never go and read books
like how to impress people.
Very common.
So now, as you are created in the same image
of Shri Ganesh, you have to understand that
you have to accept whatever God has given
you, whatever position He has given you.
Same with Christ.
Christ accepted His father who was just a
carpenter.
He didn’t aspire for something higher or
some sort of a special position or a power
because He was so powerful – what more power
can He have?
Though people mocked at Him and laughed at
Him and could not accept what He was saying,
but still He was self-contented, self-satisfied.
He knew what it was.
So, for a Sahaja Yogi first thing is to be
self-contented.
As I told you, the fundamentals of the western
life is to see and to be seen.
Both things were missing completely in the
incarnation of Shri Ganesh.
So when I say these things, suddenly people
start thinking, “Let us become hippies,
or let them become punks, or let us become
this, let us become that.”
You don’t have to become anything.
Whatever you have – your body, your face,
your hair – everything is there, just meant
for you.
You don’t have to change anything outwardly
because inside is complete Chaitanya.
Shri Ganesha never tried to change Himself.
Though there were so many clouds on His being,
though many people insulted Him, tortured
Him, hanged Him, crucified Him, still the
Eternal Being didn’t bother.
So the first and foremost thing for a Sahaja
Yogi is to accept, go on accepting things.
But when I say accept, I must say the other
side also: that doesn’t mean you start accepting
bhoots, all the bad qualities of others.
“Mother, You said you must accept”, so
they’ll start accepting all these bad qualities.
“What’s wrong?
You have said it already.”
Whatever I say has another side, always.
Like I said, “Now you have become your own
Guru.”
So, “Why should we listen to anybody else?”
Like this, you see, we go on diverting ourselves,
deviating ourselves from reality just to cheat
ourselves.
And this comes because we have no wisdom.
We have no wisdom because we do not know what
is for our benevolence, what is for our good,
what we should do for our good.
I mean even if we know, we don’t want to
do it.
So, what we lack is wisdom.
That’s a vicious circle, I must say, that
Ganesha is to be awakened to give you wisdom
– He is the giver of wisdom, He is the giver
of wisdom – and He has to give you the wisdom,
He is to be awakened; but you are not wise
because He is not awakened.
It’s a very vicious circle.
How to make this vicious circle break?
That “Let my wisdom shine in my attention.
Let Shri Ganesha throw His light in my attention.”
Mentally you people are very alert, no doubt.
And you can always cheat yourself nicely.
That’s the point where you could see yourself
– introspection, which I have seen among
Russians.
Just introspect: “Why do I do like that?
Why cannot I meditate?
Am I going to miss out?
Why can I not do something that is good for
me?”
Introspection is the only way you can see
yourself how far you are from Shri Ganesh.
Even, I have seen, when I say something in
general, people always – the mind is very
clever – thinks that I am talking about
somebody else, not about them.
It’s a convex mind, convex, which never
receives anything inside itself because there
is no wisdom.
If you are wise, then not only that you’ll
accept but you’ll understand and it will
penetrate into your attention through your
central nervous system.
You just know that this is it.
Now you know that this… you put your hand
towards this candle, it… you’ll… your
fingers might burn.
You know it definitely, with experience, and
you won’t do that.
With experience you have learnt not to put
your hand on to the candle.
And this wisdom is there, I don’t have to
tell you that.
But this is a new life you have started – a
spiritual life.
When you are going into the spiritual life,
try to remember your experiences, one after
another: how you got transformed, how you
changed, how many the bad things that you
had disappeared gradually and how you have
become so nice.
This will take away your depression – to
begin with.
Then you should think that, “What do I have
to do further?
Am I really wise, or I’m stupid?”
There are lots of stages between absolute
stupidity and absolute wisdom, and you see
all those shades all over, and combinations
and permutations of these I see every day.
And I am surprised that after getting your
Self Realization, when Shri Ganesha is shining
in your attention, you should see your reflection
clearly and try to correct it.
Only this much wisdom if you have that, “I
have to work out my benevolence”, you’ll
do it.
I know of somebody who would never get up
in the mornings, say for example.
But one day I saw him ready at about six o’clock
in the morning – I was surprised.
How this gentleman who has no self-discipline
has suddenly got up at six o’clock and ready
to go somewhere.
I said, “Where are you going?”
“You don’t know?”
I said, “What?”
“I have got a job now and I have to be present
at 8 o’clock and it will take two hours
to reach that place.
Also, I am keeping some margin.
So I have to leave now.
I can’t talk to You even.”
Quite alert, awake.
Now, what is the thing is as far as money
is concerned, lot of wisdom is there.
Don’t have to tell them, that is automatically.
Money wisdom is quite a lot, job wisdom is
quite a lot.
Because these things means prestige in the
society, this means security in the society.
So this kind of business you find in many
people and in some even that is missing.
They don’t even understand that they have
to earn their living.
But that’s the minimum, you cannot be parasite.
Then the second stage, as I said by many stages,
is this: that we are not for money, money
is for us.
The attention if it is on your Spirit, on
the Ganesha Principle, then whole situation
will change.
Your priorities will change.
And suddenly people will say, “Mother, what
has happened to this gentleman?
He was a stupid fool, now he has become such
a wise person.”
So to awaken Shri Ganesha you should have
minimum wisdom already there.
I mean, even if that is not there, how can
you work it out?
Is not meant for stupid people, Moodhas, not
meant for Moodh.
So now what is our benevolence is?
Let us see.
Is it money?
No.
Those who have money don’t seem to be very
happy people always.
Then what is the next, is jobs?
Those who have jobs – all right, should
have jobs, I am not saying you should be jobless.
I mean immediately the another side they will
take, I mean so quick you know, that, “Mother
is saying we can be jobless you see, nice.”
Immediate, escapes.
Now, then the power: you want to have political
power, this social power, this power, that
power – is absolutely a joyless pursuit.
You go and see those people who are supposed
to be powerful, so called, half way they are
towards hell, one foot there and one foot
here and about to be gulped down by the crocodiles.
You can see it clearly.
Specially in this Kali Yuga it’s so obvious,
so clear-cut.
We don’t want to be like them, we want to
be like Shri Ganesh.
So once you start accepting your circumstances,
accepting your body, your… accepting your
face, everything, you will see that lot of
time will be saved.
Another problem that faces us is planning.
And that is missing in Shri Ganesha completely.
He did not do any planning whatsoever.
I wish He had done some planning, things would
have been much better.
He doesn’t believe in planning because He
is so powerful.
Whatever He wants, He can get it done.
You want the sun?
All right the sun is there.
You want the moon?
Moon is there.
You want the stars?
Stars is there.
The
dust of His feet can create the whole universe
– universes after universes.
For such a person, there is no need to be
planning everything because whatever He wants
happens.
But why, why it happens?
Why He has this power?
Because He is in that state.
Are you in that state?
You have not achieved that state.
You talk somebody… tell somebody that, “Oh
my, I have to go and catch the plane.”
There are ten people standing next to you,
they’ll all get panicky.
I have to go, and they are bothered; something
sort of goes off their heads.
I don’t know what goes, they go amuck.
I never tell them like that.
I say, “There’s still time for the plane
to go, and don’t worry.
When I reach there then the plane will leave
so you don’t worry.”
But because of this kind of a… presumptions,
and the planning system of the mind, you just
think that, “Now I have a plan to go today,
I must go.”
Why?
I won’t go.
I may decide at the last minute I don’t
want to go.
I’ll make the plane go away.
We did that many a times, you know very well.
I wanted to buy the Rome Ashram, so I saw
to it that the plane never arrived.
But you have to be in that state.
Specially buying this Cabella, you know what
happened.
There were five great intellectuals on My
head sitting.
I didn’t know how I will manage these five
intellectuals with all their planning, this,
that; they made Me run up and down, do this
and that, Ultimately they all had to come
here.
But I was telling them, “Go and have a look.”
Nobody would look at it, nobody would listen
to Me, nobody wanted to know about it.
How things work out – is your pure desire
that can work out anything that you want.
But you won’t want funny things also.
Like Shri Ganesha would not like to follow
some entrepreneur who is saying, “Have a
punk on your head”, or something.
Is stupidity, all kinds of stupidities.
Because you are stupid, these entrepreneurs
are having a good time; they can befool us
all the time.
At His state, He is Himself, on top of the
pure desire.
The pure desire is on His stomach, tied up
nicely.
It is to be seen in Sahaja Yoga how things
work out, how miraculously they work out,
and these can happen to you also.
All these Powers can come to you also.
You know about some people who came to us
who didn’t know even how to sing.
I mean, they had no voices; something very
funny they had – I mean I didn’t know
from where they learnt to even talk.
When they opened their mouths, if you were
at one note, they were on another note and
they went on and on and on without even listening
to what they were singing.
After some time, I find they are singing beautifully.
So the Kundalini itself is working it out,
the pure desire is working it out, but what
about you?
What are you doing about it is to be seen.
There are so many things that could be understood
very easily through the lifestyle of Shri
Ganesha.
The first and foremost thing for Him is to
obey His Mother – never to say no, no question,
and also not to ask why.
He will go and fight with all the Gods and
Goddesses and every one.
And that’s what Christ has said, “Anything
against Me I’ve tolerated but nothing against
the Holy Ghost.”
There should be no question, there should
be no explanation.
Sometimes even My patience goes out, the way
they do not want to accept what I am telling
them.
At the end of course they all come around,
no doubt – at the end.
But you waste so much time convincing them.
What is the reason?
They have no wisdom to know what their Mother
is.
Like, you know the story of Shri Ganesha that
His Mother said, “The one who goes round
the Mother Earth, I will give you a present.”
So, Ganesha again accepts a little mouse as
a transport – imagine.
Nowadays people can’t believe it that Shri
Ganesha, so powerful, should accept just a
mouse for His transport.
Because He’s so humble; he doesn’t have
to show off His Lincoln or Mercedes to anyone;
He is very comfortable with His mouse.
Now what does He do?
He thinks that…
He understands, in no time, that His Mother
is much greater than the Mother Earth.
“So why should I go round the Mother Earth?”
His brother is going round on a peacock.
He just goes round His Mother – He gets
the present.
It’s such a simple thing to understand because
He is the wisest person.
The wisest person knows what is what, he knows
who is who, he knows what are the qualities
of these persons.
He is not impressed by superficial things,
no.
If somebody is well dressed, then people get
very much impressed by them, and they turn
out to be bank robbers – walking with umbrellas
and with lined suits, as if some big executives
are coming, and they decamp with all the loot.
So for a wise person, the superficial behavior
doesn’t appeal, not bothered.
It is a kind of a very penetrating intelligence;
just like a computer you know.
In a second you know that what is this gentleman.
Oh, he may come with a great, you see, ado
and he might come and praise you and do this
and do that and you know the person very well.
If some body is unduly very friendly, very
kind, very nice, not necessarily that he is
really appreciating you but he is looking
at your purse, maybe, maybe something else.
But not only on this level, it is even on
a spiritual level we have to understand how
people try to put you down spiritually; what
they try, what tricks they try on you.
It could be your husband, your wife, your
children, your relations, your friends, anybody,
any Sahaja Yogi.
But in the case of Shri Ganesha, it’s the
other way round.
They say that if you put one apple, bad apple,
all the apples get spoilt.
But if you put Shri Ganesha among all the
bad apples, they’ll get all right.
Because He’s the life-giving force.
This is one of the greatest qualities, that
He knows that He is the source of life and
He gives life, He gives Chaitanya.
He doesn’t say… think that, “Now supposing
I give Chaitanya, give life to this person,
my ego will come up,” – very common problem.
“Mother I don’t want to do it because
my ego will come up.”
Everybody is psychoanalyzing themselves ‘because
this will happen’ – Baba!
[- Hindi expression of a general exclamatory
nature –ed.]
You are all realized souls now, you are all
saints.
The false people are talking so big, and you
the people who have got something are still
thinking, “My ego will come up, this will
happen.”
No, no, you have the powers.
But as you keep it under a manger, as Christ
has said, the light will go out.
You have to give it to others, you have to
open it out.
And that is how you will judge your state.
“What is my state?
Let’s see.
Where am I?”
That confidence, take it from Me, should be
with you.
All of you have to work out this way.
Very many…
“Mother, my Mooladhara is caught up.”
How dare anybody catch Mooladhar?
That’s the anger of Shri Ganesha.
How dare?
How can anybody?
What’s missing is complete faith in yourself
and faith in your Mother.
In Russia recently… in Prague, there was
a lady who was brought on the stage, very
old lady, couldn’t walk.
I mean they just carried her and she came
and sat before Me on a chair.
She said, “I know You…
I’ll be cured.
I am in Your presence; I know I will be cured.”
I said, “Then get up.”
She got up.
Those who were with Me in Prague, you can
ask them.
She came down and she started running, and
everybody laughed.
But her faith – she was not a Sahaja Yogini
as such – but she was sure; she knew Me.
And she just started running like that and
everybody started looking at her.
Same thing happened in Russia for many people
– very serious diseases.
So that, one thing is for sure, either you
don’t know that you are realized souls or
else you don’t know Me, one of the two things.
Why was He so obedient to His Mother?
Why was He?
Because that was the wisest thing to do.
The one who knows everything, it’s better
to be guided by that person.
And many a times I have seen, people try to
do things without telling Me, important things
– they fall into traps.
Then they come back to Me and I tell them
the solution, it works.
It’s not necessary that you should tell
Me everything.
But when you are in a fix, you can always
just go into yourself and ask yourself, “What
would Mother do?”
You’ll get the answer.
You are at a… quite a higher state.
But still, even if you are on a tree and you
are still thinking you are falling down, you
are nowhere.
Steady yourself.
That’s what is, we say, the Adhishthan of
Shri Ganesha.
Is the steadiness, steadiness in your achievements
of Sahaj Yog.
Believing in yourself that you have entered
into the new world, into the new atmosphere
It is for you now, to work it out.
Shri Ganesha is just waiting.
But He is not meant for people who have no
courage.
Such a courageous man who could go and fight
with all the Devas, because He knew the Shakti
was with Him.
Today is such a joyous day for Me because
we have children, and we are dealing with
children.
Most of them are born realized.
They are of a very special category, I have
told you many a times, but we spoil them;
because we were not born realized, so we don’t
know how to handle these children, we spoil
them.
Not only we spoil them, but we interfere with
the school, we interfere with this as if we
are the wisest parents ever living.
Because we are Sahaja Yogis, we have to be
much more sensible than other parents.
How can you interfere with any school anywhere?
But in Sahaja Yoga you will.
It is because there is no wisdom and no understanding
what is good and benevolent for your child.
If you love your child, then you must think
of its benevolent.
You must learn from the experience what happens
to children if they are left like that.
You cannot spoil your child, you cannot because
it’s a special category of children they
are.
They are not children who can become vagabonds;
they cannot become thieves.
So you will make them something funny – they
are neither here nor there.
They are born realized and they have to be
channelized properly, to achieve their complete
manifestation of their Spirit.
So the possessiveness and the stupid attachments
to children must be given up.
There is no force on you – if you want to
destroy a child, you can destroy.
But in an advice – if you were Ganeshas,
you would have understood it, I don’t have
to explain so much.
What is good for your child, because we have
to have beautiful children.
They are born beautiful children, I tell you.
If they are spoilt, it is because of you,
you have spoilt them.
You have ruined them.
You are responsible.
I know of so many children – they’re very,
very sweet.
I have conference with them also and I find
them much more congenial; I have much better
rapport with them than I can have with you.
They never argue, never.
They never says no, and they have very good
information about all of you.
So it is such a nice thing that today you
should desire that our children should very
soon become the images of Shri Ganesha, His
Ganas, who have to work out so much.
It’s a tremendous task.
Sahaja Yoga is the greatest achievement of
Spiritual evolution.
We all have to dedicate ourselves.
We don’t have to sacrifice anything as the
Saints have sacrificed – nothing, don’t
have to suffer anything.
Only thing you have to have – wisdom.
For that, I am very happy that today we are
worshipping Shri Ganesha.
So the pure desire should be that, “Shri
Ganesha please give us Divine Wisdom.”
That’s all.
It contains everything in it.
May God bless you.