Shri Ganesha Puja. Nasik (India), 18 January 1983.
Please be seated.
[Hindi/Marathi]
It's all right.
It is such a fortunate day today,
that we should come on the birth of Shri Ganesha
– today is Vinayak Chaturthi, today -
that we should celebrate this Puja.
Also, it is so fortunate to have people like
Dr Sanghvi, his wife and his son, his daughter-in-law,
who are so much dedicated to Sahaja Yoga.
In 1972 I had visited Pune, Nasik,
and we had a big session here.
People from all over came; we got a lot of Sahaja yogis here.
Raulbai is one of them.
But the people of Nasik did not come forward much to do Sahaja Yoga,
and sort of, we didn’t find any
footing place here, so we gave up coming to Nasik.
And today after so many days, now I’m back here.
And it’s so surprising how we have been able to manage.
So many people yesterday, about,
they are saying about ten thousand people were present.
And at least, I would say that ninety percent people
got Realization, at least.
Now, I have to say that the quality of people is very important,
and in Maharashtra you must understand that there’s a quality.
These people have a special quality of purity, I think,
that invariably
I’ve seen the amount of working it takes place in Maharashtra,
doesn’t take place in other place.
Perhaps the people are very much aware
of the three and a half peethas they have here.
Now for, they are Jains and have been following Jainism but
still they always worshipped the Goddess, the Devi.
So, we can understand that what is an impact
of those three and a half peethas is.
And you have visited
the great shrine of Chaturshringi.
Saptashringi.
I’m sorry, Saptashringi. [Hindi/Marathi]
Today being Ganesha’s day,
only it is going to come "chatura" in My mouth.
So this Saptashringi is the one
who has got seven chakras, means the limbic area,
and She is the Sahasrara, representing the Sahasrara.
That’s why she’s the Ardha-Matra.
And Her face and body and all that you can see,
is so beautifully made,
that it emits vibrations for miles together.
Those who are sensitive can feel it.
And you have been so lucky to go there and see that
miraculous place, that this have come out of Mother Earth.
And since ancient times it has been there.
Nobody knows when it appeared.
So we are in a very holy place,
because as you know Sita lived here for so many years
and Shri Rama was also with Her, and also Shri Lakshmana.
So it is obvious that this is a big kind of,
we can say a,
quite a big meeting place of various holy things,
that happened during the different periods of Maharashtra.
And the River Godavari also flows and the, also the
[Hindi/Marathi] source, source of this river is also very near.
Actually they wanted to take you down there,
but it’s another high climb and I thought you will be all exhausted
so I told her better not take that way.
But normally those people who come to Nasik always go there.
And there is one sad incident was that
there’s a Trimbakeshwar where is there is one of the Jyotirlingas.
There are twelve Jyotirlingas.
Actually we should say they are fourteen because
two of them are half, so .…
There are twelve Jyotirlingas,
and the complete are ten.
Out of them, one of them is here.
But the gentleman was quite funny and he said that
"Those who are not Hindus, we cannot admit there".
So it’s again
all nonsense going on which will all stop one day, I’m sure,
because they have no sense how to recognize the saints, you see.
And once they start recognizing the saints, they will know that
they are the first who should go inside,
than those who are not realized.
Moreover, for Shiva doesn’t matter whether they are even bhoots,
doesn’t matter to Him. His temple need not be so guarded.
Any other temple I can understand, but Shiva’s I can’t understand
why there is so much guarding is needed.
But I think it’s a money-making proposition.
Whatever it is, it brings to My notice
all these nonsensical things that are going on in this country.
And then one starts realizing
that how much people have to open out themselves and give up fear
from people who are coming from other countries.
They suffer all of them, not only,
not only the people
who are religious but also people who are political, social.
They are all frightened of foreigners coming in now,
in the country, and they always start doubting.
And you can understand that’s why they doubt, but still
they should also understand that in these advanced stages
if there are saints, they should be able to recognize,
and this is what’s lacking in them.
And I was sad on that point, but doesn’t matter.
I think next time I’ll put him right, this gentleman.
So, on the whole, our whole stay was,
I think was very interesting and nice, and this evening
we are going to have a very beautiful musical program,
variety entertainment and classical music by children,
which you, I’m sure you’ll all enjoy very much.
That we’ll have here.
So on the whole we should be thankful to Mr. Sanghvi
and to Mr. Mehtani for organizing
this stay in Nasik so well
and with such comfort to all of us,
and such elevating experiences which has brought you
to something higher, and the experience of your own depth.
So may God bless you all.
[Hindi/Marathi]
They have to first ask for forgiveness of all of you,
and they are asking My forgiveness also.
[Hindi/Marathi]
They say, "If we have done any mistakes,
please forgive us,our whole family.”
[Hindi/Marathi]
First you have to worship yourself. Otherwise …
that’s why she has to worship herself,
that she should make herself, cleanse herself,
and she should worship herself, she should have respect for herself,
and she is worshipping Me.
If you are not a respectable person
you are not supposed to worship Me.
[Hindi/Marathi]
He has to, now they'll be saying mantras. [Hindi/Marathi]
Here it is. [Hindi/Marathi]
[Hindi/Marathi]
There are ten, ten guards
of the ten directions, digpal.
[Hindi/Marathi]
They have invited
all the ten devas of the,
who are the guards of the ten directions,
to come and settle down and guard this great occasion,
when she’s worshipping the God.
[Hindi/Marathi]
This is known as sugar-cane juice. Abhishek of sugar-cane juice.
SM: This is, you put the ghee.
Y: Ghee.
This is abhishek of milk.
[Hindi/Marathi]
There should be peace, and for the peace there’s a shanti mantra.
Is important. Shanti, the peace has to be within and without.
First it has to be established within.
You must feel your peace within yourself.
For that, this is a special mantra.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Saraswati, Saraswati Mahalakshmi. [Hindi/Marathi]
Now the Puja of Saraswati and Mahalakshmi.
This is our offer to the Devi
so that the disease of hunger should be eradicated.
This is the worship of the deepa
suggesting that “Oh Mother, we need not,
we should not forget the Spirit, the light of Spirit within us,
and we worship You with this light, so that our attention
should be on that light which is the Spirit within us.
And then they are praying, saying that
“Remove the great darkness of moha.”
“Moha” is attachment.
Attachment.Ahamkar.
And remove the, and “moha” means the attachment.
- SY: Attachments.
- SM: Ahamkar. Aham attachments.
Ahamkar, [Hindi/Marathi].
Attachment, attachment.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Now by doing karmas, our brains have muddled up.
So Goddess, we offer You this dhupa
so that You remove the enemy of karma in our head,
remove all of the karmas from our head
so that we are clarified, we give dhupa.
Now, see, it’s so interesting that
what they are suggesting is dhupam,
is the, dhupam is given to Shri Krishna,
who is the one who gives us the witness state.
So how it is connected. Deepam is the Spirit,
so you see how it is connected. The whole thing is so connected.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Now, it is so significant that a coconut is offered for moksha.
Now, you know, coconut has a limbic area inside it.
It has the three shells,
just like your brain has, and inside is the limbic area.
It represents the limbic area, and that’s why
for moksha you have to go into the limbic area and that’s why
a, is called as “shripala”, Holy Ghost, you see,
the pala of the Holy Ghost, you see,
the fruit that is liked, or representing Her.
This is your limbic area, and that’s why it is given to the Mother.
How significant, and how absolutely appropriate it is.
God has also created this, just to suggest that thing.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Now, this is a [Hindi/Marathi]
This is, she has to offer Me a supari,
which is the Ganesha Tattwa, and that is Agama Shastras,
means the shastras which have come out of that.
So “make me a virtuous personality”.
All has come from Shri Ganesha,
and Shri Ganesha makes you auspicious and also virtuous.
"So the one from where all the shastras have come out,
so this is the Shri Ganesha Tattwa which we offer You,
so that You also make us virtuous
and auspicious, by Your powers".
[Hindi/Marathi]
Apple is for you, the Ganesha.
See, it has an effect on the Mooladhara.
If you are suffering from diarrhea this helps you.
SY: [Hindi/Marathi]
SM: So this is for you people, the Ganesha,
and for these country people this is the Ganesha.
So God has given everything according to the need.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati, Mahakali.
Seven times.
You have to say seven times the first mantra of
Mahakali, Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati, seven times with her.
Gavin, why have you dropped “Shri Mataji”?
You should put “Shri Mataji” essentially
because that’s the first name of the Sahasranama, all right?
Should be there, “Shri Mataji”.
When you are standardizing the thing - who has done this?
– you must ask Me;
Because that’s the biggest part, is that I am the Mother, isn’t it?
[Hindi/Marathi]
And that is actually the name given by the modern people,
so it must be accepted. Is an additional thing.
When you are standardizing the things, you must ask Me, all of you.
I don’t know who has done it, but whosoever it is.
Realized soul [Hindi/Marathi].
[Hindi/Marathi]
[Hindi/Marathi] Collective.
Collectivity. [Hindi/Marathi]
Collectivity. Sangha bhi means collectivity. Sa means collectivity.
[Hindi/Marathi]
And we can do hundred and eight names of Devi.
This one is all written in Marathi but so well done.
I wish you could all remember by heart,
so that it’s a very nice way of getting rid
of our six types of enemies.
You also don’t know what to ask God.
You are always asking for something which is not important.
Our priorities are all wrong.
So this is a very good way of knowing exactly
what a Sahaja yogi should ask.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Mr. Sanghvi said that he would not accept any money
from the people for Puja. I said, “But they must all join in”.
So with great difficulty they agreed that we should collect
eleven rupees from all of you for the Puja,
and somebody should do it.
Twenty one.
You have done? You have done twenty-one? All right. Whatever it is.
[Hindi/Marathi]
[Hindi/Marathi] Remove that, a little bit.
Now all the people from Nasik are going to do this,
so little bit you have to move out.
Those who are from Nasik.
[Hindi/Marathi]
And Nala if you can move out, these people will sit that side.
[Hindi/Marathi] You must spread something for them.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Gavin, get up for one minute, all right?
Alexander, you also move out a little,
because others have to sit there. All right?
Would be a good idea. Take your [Hindi/Marathi]
Give [Hindi/Marathi]
[Hindi/Marathi]
SY: And water?
SM: Water bhi. [Hindi/Marathi]
[Hindi/Marathi]
It’s so auspicious, they have got all the auspicious trees here.
You know how much we did last time, how many names?
Two thousand and …  two thousand one hundred and eight
Thousand of Saraswati and thousand of Renuka Devi,
and hundred and eight of the Mahakali.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Those who want to take photograph of My feet.
SM: Are, be careful, be careful.
SY: Please don't touch your feet to the Puja material.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Done?
Gavin, [Hindi/Marathi]
[Hindi/Marathi]
This is the first time you will have a photograph without My mudras.
Did you follow Me?
“Without mudras” means I have not put up My hands.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Just make little loop.
Rustam, you come near.
[Hindi/Marathi]
[Hindi/Marathi] one thousand names of Devi?
You haven’t got? How many? Hundred and eight. All right.
[Hindi/Marathi]
Lalita Sahasranama ….
This is a very nice one about ….
[Hindi/Marathi]
Rustam will you be able to read it?
See, thaey didn’t have Devi’s, Devi's thousand names today.
Ganesha’s we have.
Today is tuesday, Mother.
They are saying, “You are doing everything.” I said ”I am just
siting here, I am doing nothing.”
[Hindi/Marathi]