yes
What did he say mother could you please
say something about the collective and
the need for real-life selves to be
together but alright that's a very nice
addition I would like to say something
about connecting so far as you know in
the history of spirituality people have
gotten realization many people one after
another many people got it but I will
say one in a million one in a ten
million like because we have to have
some of the food to talk about beginning
we are missing what was written in the
past but they those people who got
realization single-handed suffered a lot
and they could not transmit what it was
needed to be given to others in a way
that would be accepted now as you see
any discovery is made like that people
can benefit individually every person
can say oh I have parted so I can have
it
ha but it is of a movin it is of Norman
I can take it I will say a personality
like Christ we once we had Christianity
what have they done about it I mean it's
a Saturday I mean to think such a
personality too common what a great job
he has done to establish himself for our
detriment
what people have done the reason was he
wasn't he was alone it was not a mass
thing that was not the time because he
had to establish this Center without
that it could not be mass all right
it could not be a Hamas realization but
he talked about you have to be born
again and all that but the whole thing
fizzled out because they could not get
to the essence of it one person of that
value coming on this earth found it
impossible to convince people in fact so
one has to understand that any anything
that is if evolutionary first-first
happens to one or two persons only but
then it happens to many me now in sahaja
yoga this another problem apart from
that that it is happening to many people
is them no doubt thousands are getting
realization is no doubt is working out
that you know that now the evolution has
come to the stage as I say it's the
Blossom time many flowers are there and
they have to become fruits but now why
necessary to have connectivity when
people are between or as a shield
that is a very important point one has
to understand the thing is that now when
you are getting realized what is
happening to you you are getting related
to the whole a my proposal is getting
related to the mattress say your body is
there and you are sleeping first you get
a little a vaguely you open your fingers
alright then you open your another thing
now there is a little trouble on your
finger and you can't see anything so you
open your eyes and you pay your
attention to your hands so that trouble
may be all right but you need another
hand to help so you want the another
hand also to be awakened to that point
like that so when the search opens are
getting awakened more and more see the
problems that are facing us we can sort
them better because so many people are
working out the problem you understand
my point now together when we are
together we understand now this problem
I moved to America I had one in 1970
1973 for starting yes 1973 Allegra's I
was alone I mean I gave very good
lectures we had very big halls filled up
and everything is enough the reason is
the people who got realization didn't
have anybody to look after them there
was nobody to support them give them
assistance so they got lost I mean they
are there some of them are here and
there now now what has happened now
today when I am going to America
everybody is playing in Australia
they're playing in India they're playing
like the tension and we surprised some
people are coming from India to go down
Dominika some are coming from Australia
to go down to America some are coming
from France some from Switzerland they
are all rushing to America now the job
is in America all right so like the
attention see as soon as somebody pricks
me of my hand goes there my articles
that everything works so the collective
working out effort is going to solve the
problem but supposing if this finger is
fighting with this finger can I write
anything or if they are secluded and
alone then I can I use them all this
body has to become absolutely in Concord
with each other but so many are still
sleeping those who are awakened at least
must stick to it otherwise sahaja yoga
cannot go today I find it much easier to
give realization much as I was
struggling with six people for four
years in your London four years
seek speed but once they got realization
it started working fast and the more
people we get because the channel that
is to be used
it's like nerves in the body you become
a nerve of that body which is awakened
and once the nerves start working out
together realizing that there's one
force that is flowing through them all
of you have to work it out together with
understanding of the divine it works
first any person who's all nerves are at
work will be much more dynamic than a
person who is half dead or is full
length so you can understand how
collectivities important then another
thing is that going to a very enjoyable
part that when the colour sahaja Yogi's
are collectively there they really know
because for the first time I'm starting
first before this you never enjoyed you
enjoy flowers enjoyed everything else
but not you wanted pure enjoyment of
human being starts coming when you
become truly realized I'll give you an
example we went to Calcutta one day and
I was in a room in a in one hotel and
there were three for sahaja Yogi's in
another hotel another one and one
gentleman came to me for his daily
language and whenever I raised him
Kundalini you see they've all got
vibrated and they all rushed to my to
know what has happened suddenly how is
it we got some joy within ourselves they
came to see and this man was there it
was a great room but they felt the
vibration is tremendous so it is not the
happening of an individual which is the
happening of the world and the
individual effort is going to be
absolutely useless it will be all
neutralized if you sit at home do your
meditation it won't work you won't have
any fun because the whole has to come I
give an example that when you churn the
butter in India I don't know you don't
do that way we do it very naturally you
put a little butter inside that and then
again you structure so the butter starts
gathering around that butter all of it
comes together but some particles have
left they stick to the sides stick to
that there are no more as butter they
are thrown away as but it is as simple
as that you see the more you gather
together really enjoy the spirit of
friendship
spirit of mirth spirit of love and pure
form so far the loves buyers they say
it's last there's money there space
that's the relationship this is you a
British so I must love you I'm Indian so
I must love you all these nonsensical
barriers are there you love a human
being because he's a human being and
he's a yogi speaks the same now today I
have attended a wedding party and the
bride and the bridegroom said we are
coming to Paris with you mother there
are hundred people coming to Madison
because I haven't changed pets but I
said you are asymptomatic I better enjoy
your money who said what are we going to
enjoy a line just to get our humans even
if I tell you don't come they won't
listen
they will enjoy their honeymoon there I
never said you come on the contrary I've
seen you go where you might be to enjoy
your honeymoon where every left they
won't know because they know we're in
German hands with their brothers is
famous ancestors it's absolutely so I
think that the enjoyment of human beings
has not been there now there are people
who live in India who live in Australia
who live here all over the places but
when the sahaja Yogi's go to you I
should see them in the way they are
sahaja Yogi's in the villages way to
impress them way to feel the oneness
never there felt like this for a white
scheming they saw might scream they
would just run away and hide themselves
under this thing I see and even now
people are sometimes writing to see a
white skin in a village they say Oh God
they have come just to destroy something
but now that's all one now it's a human
a human being is coming that all of this
for there is nothing like a black or a
white or anything left now it's such an
such a love that promise and understand
that's only possible if you learn how to
live collectively and collectivities
also teaches you where you are very
important a person was not live collect
cannot understand and seen people for
their own families even their families
their surgeries but once they come to
the ashram they know what yet because of
their chests you have to learn to adjust
you can't have private bathroom to
yourself and private room to yourself
alright you can have if you want to have
but you should also know how to exist as
you know I live very comfortably myself
but if it comes to live anywhere I have
no problem of comfort already in the
same way we are not barred from a job
because of all these things away we can
your bathrooms with us we do not enjoy
life so you want to have everything
absolutely first class that has lead
said that even when we go to the picnic
we take on the Metropolitan with us in
the same way we cannot enjoy life you
cannot enjoy nature we can enjoy
anything as long as we become a just an
individual oh I am the one who is well
to it the last of all we must know by
individualism will become malignant I
don't say become communist because
that's another monuments but by becoming
individuals will be combining them what
is malignancy that an individual self
takes up upon itself
I will grow I will put it doesn't know
how to grow with the whole it has no
coordination with the whole that's why
you say it is a cancer cancer is nothing
but is a malignant cell which is alone
and he's saying that I have to achieve I
can unit I can manage it and once it
starts going like that whosoever touches
that person becomes all these ideas we
are higher race or we have greater
people we are moneyed people we are
something
special we are of this club all these
disappears it's all nonsensical they are
identified with nonsensical things I am
making ourselves miserable another salsa
mr. eyed well you give up on that
suddenly you find Oh what did you you
don't want in it we just want to be in
the company of sahaja Yogi's I have seen
people ambassadors very highly placed
people just getting me lost when they
search the other day I had a businessman
from Bombay I took him down with me to a
place called hooray and it was all in a
message that says there were no proper
bathrooms aware it was just like he got
for second act expected and there
weren't even places to sit down properly
only the beach and the palm trees and
all sorts of thing was there and the man
but mustard absolutely lost and he said
I never wanted this day to finish still
only they are really enjoyed myself
though because there was such content
such spontaneous love such attention and
such purity in that to enjoy that purity
you have to be in collective sitting
down in the room you can't understand
there is no reflection of you can't
understand where are you how far your
collectivity is the most important thing
and those who try to break the
collectivity arguing anti sahaja we call
it a sahaja movement
sahaja activity you have to be one with
the hope those who have tried to
separate themselves all of them go down
in sahaja yoga try to be one with
everyone to share and enjoy everybody
speak because God has created you so you
are salute and the enjoyment should not
be lost because you have certain
barriers like some people can't take out
their shoes I mean just imagine how will
they are identified with issues they can
take out their shoes to that extent
they're stupid
see all this kind of stupidity drops out
once you meet really wise people around
to get rid of all these nonsensical
ideas which are really haunted your head
all these days get rid of them and you
really enjoy everyone
whether he is a doorman or he is the
chairman all of them are mental it's
nothing more than all that drops up and
you start enjoying yourself
that's why collectivity is the only way
I can work out
I can't think I can work out through the
people who are separated divided it is
said Christ has said also that they said
what you know what having to do he said
if when you love each other you have
done that it is just students true and
when I hear the loving conversation of
the sahaja Yogi's I feel the happiness
that's the greatest happiness for me
that all of you should love each other
in spirit without any return only for
love's sake you're or should love each
other and that is what it is and also
Krishna has said wherever people are
there together together in the name of
God I decided so in the knee joint so
called because you are all one moving
with one rhythm with one understanding
with one language so you all should
always meet all each other and have
record with each other it's so beautiful
it's music it's political we understand
that may God bless
I'd see for yourself when you got out to
a collectivity just abusing yourself at
that point that this is one thing we are
trying to teach me now I'm not going to
listen to this nonsense we are going to
be in otherwise also I mean we cannot
people cannot take even drinks without
somebody in there you can't take your
food alone there's so many things I mean
if you are not absolutely recluse you
can't live alone then in religion in in
the city especially in the realm of all
how can I be you all have to be there
I think it was a very good question
right chaos this individualism must be
given that doesn't mean you dress up
like a military people
that's not fascism or you should all
behave in the same manner that's not
necessary what I feel it's all the
beauty but does that mean that if I say
it is it is East you should say it is
West that's the main number case is it
that you can't dive into each other
what's the problem in connectivity
I can ask
must get out of individual limitations I
think everybody for some time more and
given a national survival but Ashna must
be such when there is collective dues
now I show me there fighting and
following this reversal yourself being
in the National ones but I leave it to
you it's all freedom you just decide
yourself I have not any rules and
regulations on how much because I've got
you to use your wisdom and put
everything right or self you are all
very wise people but first have them God
listen to others talk to them find out
what's the problem is on small small
things people find it's a very long
moreover you have to have one person as
a leader to whom you should listen to if
I find that fellow is useless I'll throw
him on it you know that throw him away
not in the way people throw me but he
just get out of sahaja line you know not
so there should be no problem but
everybody should not try to dominate
each other that's a valid try to change
your head as I would say how far can you
just how far can you accommodate
let's see that we have to learn that for
me isn't it
you must find out ways and methods of
accommodating yourself and others just
try to learn it's not difficult that's
the whole attitude of life is of
competition
this another should be changed you must
compete in level conflict in doing good
things confident working for others like
I won the know now I love take the fall
is very comfortable and watch the TV
this morning and I will not wash you
[Music]
then people start taking advantage
essence let them take advantage
disadvantage wonder actually if you see
the other side competent service
competing love confident good things of
saying good words of communicating in a
sweet away that others feel happy making
others happy try to change your attitude
towards others and you really enjoy I
tell you you'll enjoy that's the way you
know if you say something to hurt
someone and upset someone it must be
upsetting you definitely you may not
sure but it must be because whatever you
do to others comes back to you straight
forward march
I take it doesn't stay there altogether
it comes back so just try to be kind you
may say that the other may try to con
doesn't matter nobody can harm you
because you are the spirit you cannot
you are the spirit so just try to
understand the person I tell you after
some time and find that person will
become very some so many sahaja Yogi's
have become like that automatically we
are here for seeking God isn't it so to
help them you have a patient give up
your old methods and ways I must
to be good to disturb to be angry
there's no need at all I'm telling you
from my experience I've tried my wisdom
it works is it does work and you're
probably and failed in your ascent in
their quality I like you to move brings
others to you I don't like people to
criticize others try to support any
children I never talk about their past
or anything like that it's very sad
sometimes I've seen people are very hard
and in anger they say things which one
should never see it's not gracious it's
not in the mannerism of sahaja Yogi's
you should never say these things do I
ever say anything like that about your
past when you write to me I know
everything about you did I ever mention
those things to you at all then why
should you say things of the past I have
heard these things people just rake it
up and flung it back
I've heard this kind of thing that you
bring it on other people is on
one should be very gracious many time
and understand that everybody has
tremendous potential respect yourself
and respect others I hope now you won't
have problem of collectivity after this
lecture and if you are you can listen to
this lecture again and again and my
special humble request there try to come
down your angles automatically other
angles will come down but if it is a non
surgery then you all should fight it
together won't you join together if it's
a nine century nobody dare touch you or
trouble you
those days are corner none of you will
be drawn these are all satanic forces
and they can work through yours we must
know when they give you such ideas to
fight and to quarrel understand that
this is anti God you are doing horrible
you have to move towards more
understanding more coordination because
this is such a tremendous book and of
such a sublime nature and we have to be
supplying ourselves
all right now is there any other
question with a very nice suggestion but
don't give me such big suggestions that
I have to speak for half an hour
I'll say I just want to get even
you come here and tell people no no she
said that when collectively sahaja
Yogi's become one that those who are not
so lonely and isolated he stops you see
sahaja Yogi's have to be strong enough
not to eat like that there are people
say who are in the water and some people
are at the board
all right now the people who are in the
boat are in the boat so they are in a
way different from the people who are in
the water that's the situation
all right now the people in the boat
have to save the people who are in the
hope in the in the water right so what I
am saying that those who are on the boat
must first of all be united and then
with full strength will them on why this
collectivity is just to pull out the
rest of them this collectivity is just
to achieve their emancipation their
realization all right it doesn't mean
that is they should exclude that to be
the whole collectivity is to bring those
people are but you see there are what so
anti-god activities going on as well you
know that for example there's a guru who
makes lots of fun right and he has
destroyed many people now they
to me and they're saying so he may send
somebody here paid for a job just to
disturb us then the duty of all the
sahaja Yogi's to get together and see
that you tell him that you see now you
are doing wrong guru has done wrong to
us and he's going to do wrong to others
why do join me that on that point
everybody should be one but if they are
not strong and if they are not one they
cannot pull out of us you see my point
is like not to exclude ease all
collectivity is to include everybody all
right I mean to say there is no
specialization in sahaja yoga in simple
words everybody is a doctor of em
I mean to say that all the sahaja Yogi's
must form a strong by which they achieve
enlargement of sahaja yoga getting more
people into such more people benefited
by sahaja yoga all right well anyway
have seen wherever there is connectivity
like I would say Australia has the
maximum collected or India positive but
Australia in all the European countries
on to the western-style communities
Australia has the maximum connectivity
and there achieve the maximum results
only in Sydney today only one had told
me that the halls like this get packed
for programs very well there is no hope
for new people who are coming and it's
such a big company I am amazed I mean
how many must be going there and it is
because of collectivity and as soon as I
went there it started gathering enough
but before that the people were fighting
among themselves and many people ran
away from sahaja yoga because they
thought these people are fighting what
are going to give us maximum using
Australia IT and is Austria is having
some problem then I as soon as the
problem came in the whole thing became a
very small group again that problem is
over now positivity has come the people
have joined together again it has been
nice it happens here was a TLC why
Labour Party lost if they had not
followed they would not have been so bad
he's acted simple a simple equation
united we stand