My dear seekers,
I’m thankful to Gavin Brown
that he has been able to sum up some of the things I’ve said before
and I don’t have to go into all the details of
what I told you last time.
Some of you have come for the first time here. (Tape interrupted).
As he said Tantra is the technique.
It’s a technique and Yantra
in Sanskrit language means the mechanism.
So the technique of the mechanism.
Now what is this mechanism we are talking about?
Is there any mechanism outside or inside us?
Or is it worked through some subtle method?
All these questions should come to our mind
if you are thinking and if you are true.
But I see that in the West
people though are very much developed materially,
they have sorted out very material questions and problems,
they are very well equipped,
but as far as spiritual life is concerned,
they – they are very naive.
Though they have such a great personality
like Christ to follow about a model form
but maybe because of an organized religion
perhaps it was not possible
for people who were seeking truly
to penetrate into it through meditative methods.
So this Tantra or the technique
which works out our Self Realization
is to be known, to be understood fully
and the Yantra that works out
you have already got and thanks go to
Patrick who has made a beautiful sketch of that
Yantra which is within you, is the instrument which is within you.
But when we think of an instrument
with our human mind we cannot think of
an instrument which is a living instrument.
It is beyond our conception to understand a living machine.
This one is a living instrument within you.
When you see a tree sprouting out of a small little seed,
working out its blossoming one has to know
that there must be some technique of some mechanism
that works out this beautiful tree to grow.
And when we evolved from amoeba to this stage
we have to think there must be some mechanism
which thinks, understands, organizes, loves,
which has brought about this human stage from that amoeba stage.
In the ancient India – long time – people had lots of time
they went into themselves, into their
being through meditative understanding.
‘They’ had a glimpse of this mechanism
and they talked about it and wrote about it
and that’s how this Yantra
– the mechanism – and the Tantra – the maneuvering of it,
the technique of it – came into being.
But it was a secret science.
It was a very secret science and
it was kept hidden from general public.
It was used by very few great masters
who lived in the jungle, had one or two disciples,
worked on them for years together
and taught them about the technique of Divine.
They had to leave everything, their family, everyone,
live with the Guru, lead a complete separate life
and go into a complete transformation
under the guidance of their loving Gurus.
This was in ancient times.
And what did they achieve, and what did they have,
is all written in our scriptures.
What do you expect out of Self Realization
is written in the Bible, in the Koran, in the Torah
and also in all the Indian philosophy.
Only people say it that in some of these scriptures
it is written in a very secretive manner,
under some words that,
“I will appear before you as tongues of flames.”
Now nobody knows what’s ‘tongues of flames’ is.
There are so many sentences which
you can find out now that you go and read
which nobody can explain unless and until
they have had an experience of Kundalini.
This is the Yantra – the mechanism, is the Kundalini,
is a living force within you, It exists,
it is there, is placed for your Realization,
for your jumping into another awareness
which is promised to you through various scriptures,
through various incarnations.
It is within you. Nobody told you lies.
There is nothing but truth written in these books
but it was to be guarded. It was to be made into secret
because people would have used it for their purposes.
And they have despite all that.
First, I would like to speak about Self Realization
because that is blissful and then
answer you about the so-called tantrikas.
I have to talk about it though I have told about these things
in the previous lecture because
there are many here that were not here.
I have now shown here all the centers
and all the mechanism that is within us.
We have also given you a picture of that, I have told you
which are the deities sitting on all these different
Chakras as we call the centers which have incarnated on this earth,
have built up our being one by one gradually
in different evolutionary processes
and how we have become human beings,
this I have told you last time.
This is the Yantra and the mechanism
that is this Yantra – Kundalini –
is a holy mechanism. And this mechanism is specially created
within the being of the One Main , of the One means the Macrocosm
and we are the cells – all of us – in that.
We were made aware as fishes of the soil, we became reptiles.
We were made aware of the food available at the heights,
we raised our head. Gradually we became human beings.
After this state we started thinking of God.
We started thinking on something beyond.
Man is the only animal who thinks of God and of searching.
Is the man aware that he has to become something?
Why is he so confused? Why is he under so tension?
What is he searching?
He is searching something of which he has a glimpse
– a glimpse of that Joy he kept with him
and that Joy comes from his Self – Atma – in his heart –
he has not felt.
He has not been able to manifest the power of his Self
but there is a mechanism placed within him,
properly built up inside,
all the time present in all the human beings
just like this as it is placed in the One Being.
In His image it is also placed within you.
As I said last time that you are
all built to be just like computers.
Now the job is to put you to the Main’s.
That’s why you are seeking. That’s the only urge you have in life.
All other urges are actually the side issues.
You think you are searching in money, in position is a myth.
Those who have money are dissatisfied, those
who have positions are dissatisfied, everybody is dissatisfied.
The satisfaction time only comes to you
when you will reach the real thing which you are searching
and the real thing is your Self and nothing else.
All other things are useless because
you are not searching anything else,
you are only searching your Self
and that Self is the reflection of God almighty,
that is within your heart.
Now the mechanism that is placed
within you is this beautiful thing inside
which is placed inside your spinal chord and not outside
except for the last Chakra which is in the red color
that is outside in the prostate [the pelvic plexus].
And this is a very, very important Chakra
which controls the survival within us
– I’m sorry the Pelvic plexus within us.
It is very important because it is very sensitive
and also it is very delicate because
it is placed outside the spinal chord.
This mechanism that is placed outside the spinal chord,
down below there, is the most important Chakra
and was created first. When the creation
started this was the first thing that was created
and what does it emit holiness, innocence.
It emits innocence. And the deity sitting on this,
is the embodiment of innocence.
This deity was created in another dimension
and He is – you have seen there – is Shri Ganesha.
This is the image of Shri Ganesha that was created
at that stage and what does it represent is
the stage between the animal and the man
and the head is that of the animal showing
that an animal does not have any Ego,
that the man is different from an animal,
that the animal is innocent.
He doesn’t know what is sin, that’s why he is innocent.
Because you know what is sin that’s why ‘you’ are
innocent but you can become the fire of damnation.
He is innocence but [only fire He’s seldom?]. (SM slightly laughs.)
And He incarnates too on this earth.
He incarnated as Jesus Christ, Lord Jesus Christ.
He took His form as Lord Jesus Christ and because He is innocent,
He’s made of that essence of divine nature of God
that we call as Paramtattwa, the highest essence of God.
And that’s why His body is also made out of that
and that is the reason He could resurrect.
By reading Bible which was written by disciples of Christ
how far can you go to understand Him?
Because He was created beyond your thoughts, beyond your mind,
in an unlimited Unconscious.
And how can you with your limited mind understand Him or copy Him.
It is said that even Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesh
cannot reach Him. He is so pure.
He is purity. He is innocence
and He exists at that point
and it is He at every point, every Chakra
He bestows upon you the blessings of His innocence.
Innocence was the first thing created on this Earth.
Before creating anything else it was innocence already there
and He bestows that innocence
by which you get your Self Realization.
On the left hand side of this mechanism
there are seven stratas.
On the right hand side there are seven stratas,
down below there are seven stratas
and on top there are seven stratas.
What are these stratas and what do they build?
The left hand side chakras, the left hand side channel
which is called as Ida channel represents the subconscious,
the subconscious mind within you. You listen to Me through
your conscious mind and put it back into the subconscious mind.
All your experiences go into the subconscious.
That is the limit of your subconscious of present here.
Beyond that gouge is your subconscious of previous lives
and beyond that gouge is the collective subconscious.
When you listen to Me you have got a conscious mind which
receives it at this moment and there is a pre-conscious mind
which takes it to the subconscious.
This pre-conscious mind is on the right hand side.
This also has got seven stratas on this side.
Just now the pre-conscious mind is the future
that you are thinking about.
Beyond that is the supra-conscious mind means
all the ideas about future you have had before,
many lives before. Those ideas are there.
And beyond that is the collective supra-conscious.
So, on the left hand side you have sub-conscious
and the collective sub-conscious; on the right hand side:
supra-conscious and the collective supra-conscious.
Down below are the seven stratas of Hell. H.E.L.L.
Sometimes the words are so small that it doesn’t register.
If I say ‘Supra-conscious’, then people say,
“Ah! Mataji has said ‘sub-conscious’.” But ‘Hell’!
And Hell is a truth. It exists within us.
It is there. And there are seven stratas of that also.
Conscious mind [on Sushumna Nadhi-Central Channel]
also has got seven stratas
which are built in within us through
our different evolutionary processes.
And these are the seven stratas
which are placed here of the conscious mind
and then you go on top of the head into super-conscious mind
which is the subtle mind – is the eternal mind –
the unconscious in which you have to move in seven stratas.
You may say, “Shri Mataji it’s too much!” But it’s not.
You are already built-in for that.
For example if I tell this light, “You have to get enlightened
and cover the whole hall”, it will say, “Oh! It’s too much.” No,
it is built like that.
You have to just press the button. It opens and works
because it is built that way, has been organized that way,
is placed that way that it works.
When we face things that seem difficult we think we have to do it
and that’s why we are worried. You don’t have to worry:
it’s already done
and it will be done also by the One who is organizing it.
Only thing what we have to do is to witness.
The One who has created this universe very well,
the One who has created all the greenery
then human being very well,
He is the One who is going to do this for you
and the time has come as Gavin has said it beautifully
that the blossom time has come and it will work out.
But it’s surprising you know, human beings sometimes
I cannot understand.
When I told that it is going to work out they said,
“How can it be? It has to be difficult.”
Before even starting about it must you sit down with this idea
on your head : “Oh! It’s going to be very difficult.”
I say it is the easiest and the simplest thing.
Being so important it cannot be difficult.
Anything important like your breathing if it becomes
difficult and if you have to read about breathing,
“How am I to breathe?” Now you go in books and see,
“Now, you have to do like this.”
By the time you take the book, you are out.
If you have to read about your Self Realization
then God saves the Self Realization and God saves you.
It’s your right that you are going to get your Self Realization.
I’m not pampering your Ego. But that’s how you have been made.
Even your Ego which you are condemning every morning
and evening was an essential part of this being.
Only ‘you’ the human beings have evolved
the Ego to know something on their own.
So this mechanism was made specially in such a manner
that through your Ego and your Super Ego
you have become an ‘I’ personality.
Like people say, “This is Mister Kumar. This is X, this is Y.”
You become a separate identity from that big One personality
of which you are just separate.
And the consciousness of that comes to you
that you are a separate identity
and you have to see the oneness with that.
And that is what is Self Realization.
Nothing else!
That you become that. Not what you do but is the becoming of it.
Like you say a seed becomes a flower.
It becomes a flower. You don’t – the seed doesn’t go
and read a book, “Oh! I know what it is.”
Or it doesn’t listen to any lecture of Mataji or anything,
it just becomes a flower. In the same way you have to become that
and not just to be brain washed or to be done something else
which I will tell you later how per misuse you can do
in the name of Self Realization.
So many of them are aware, it happened so. They know that.
But what happens you can know.
What is the mechanism? How it works out? Let us see the
positive side of it and then I will tell you the negative side.
There is a Kundalini placed in that triangular
bone that you can see
pulsate. We have a doctor here he will say that, yes,
he has seen it. You can see the pulsation of
the Kundalini very clearly.
You can see the rising of the Kundalini
very clearly with your naked eyes.
You can also feel it coming up. It comes. How it comes?
How it works out is another detailed program
which I may be able to tell you later on
or I have already told quite a lot about it.
This comes up – the Kundalini –
and pierces your fontanel bone. Pierces! What is this Kundalini?
It is a residual force within you. Is awareness
which understands, thinks, loves and organizes, is an energy.
Now we cannot think, human beings cannot think of
an energy that can think, love, organize.
We cannot.
This is the energy that comes up you can see the pulsation.
You can see the bringing of it with your naked eye.
That’s what you can bring here.
It comes up and pierces your fontanel bone
and you can feel the baptism that you become like a child
because your fontanel bone becomes very soft.
I mean, but that doesn’t mean that if you have a soft bone
here – that doesn’t mean that you are a Self realized person. No.
When you enter not on left side or right hand side
but when you enter onto the top,
onto the first strata of the super-consciousness,
then what happens? First thing that should happen
to you is that you become one with the collective being.
“You become”, again I say. It is not lecturing,
“We are all brothers and sisters.
There should be no racism.” All this is lecturing.
I’m not saying lecturing. It’s ‘become’. How?
When this thing enters through this into that subtle form
you start feeling from your hands a cool breeze flowing.
This is described in our scriptures.
If you read even Christ has said, “Something passed out of My
body when somebody touched Me.” [Luke 8.46 transcriber’s note]
But in our scriptures it’s given very, very clearly.
Here, in some of them, for example I would say Shankara .
– Shankaracharya described that as Saundarya Lahari.
He called it as Saundarya Lahari this force somewhere.
He called as vibrations. So many people are talking
of vibrations but they don’t know what they’re talking
These vibrations that flow from your hand are cool vibrations
and also they understand, they think and heal other people.
When you put your hand towards another person
you start suddenly getting a burning here.
Left hand side burning on this finger is
the Vishuddhi chakra, is this one.
Now, if you know the deity who is there
and if you take the name of
that particular deity who is sitting here …
If you know and if you are a Realized soul then only.
If you are not Realized you have no authority.
You have no authority to take to any mantra
unless and until you are a Realized soul.
Supposing I give you some mantra.
You must know it is a misleading
because whatever is said, whatever is the center in danger
or in trouble,
you must get that one.
The one who is not a Realized soul cannot
make out what is the problem, where is the problem.
And the one who is not Realized
if he is given the mantra, his mantra has no authority.
Like if I want to go and see the Queen
I must take a permission. I must have some connection with her.
I should be able to go and meet her. But if I go and meet
her straight and say, “Oh! Queen, come along.”
The way we call God sometimes is most surprising.
You wouldn’t even call
any servant like that the way we call Him,
“God, come along! Do this.
This is my problem. What are you doing for me?”
“I have faith in God” as if we have sort of
we are getting obligations.
As if He is obliged to us,
“Oh! I have faith in God, Mother, then why did He miss it?”
Who has faith? I mean, He exists.
He’s an eternal being. If you have faith in that,
‘you’ are very false fine, not ‘He’. You cannot add to His Dom
Any mantra is given to you just by any Dick, Tom and Harry.
Anyone coming, “I’ll give you a mantra.”
I’m going to tell you about them later on.
All those mantras that are said are for the deities,
were done by these Gurus as I told you
in ancient times for very few people.
They used to raise the Kundalini very gradually.
They used to take it from that seat which is the Mooladhara
– not the Mooladhara chakra
– from that triangular bone and they used to raise it one by one.
For seven years it used to hang into one center
then they would give one mantra, “All right, now, go and get it!
Work it out! Cleanse it! Do it!” Then again another one.
Then again another chakra. All right.
It has been done like that: very slow process.
As in India, you see,
they said that they have to go to Kashi or Benares.
They used to sell out their houses, everything
and they knew that they may never return.
Or even if they go they might take so many years to reach Benares
that by that time they will be absolutely old people
and they would not have energy to return.
Now, if you have to go to Benares only thing what you can
do is to go from here to Delhi and take a plane and go direct.
So ‘that’ time is over and Kundalini ‘now’
can be worked out just like that
because the time has come for you to become.
There were never so many seekers in the world before
I can tell you.
Only people who existed in the name of religion
were orthodox, rabid, horrible people who crucified Christ,
who killed Mohammad Sahib, who tortured Gnyaneshwara, who tortured
Kabira, who tortured of all the things Shankaracharya,
Buddha, Mahavira, Yuri [?], everyone of them.
All these horrid people in the name of religion tortured.
And today we have got this satanic thing
coming out of that hell. They have suffered there,
you see, they were punished
and after their punishment they are coming out.
It’s a double force.
It’s a new subtler method of befooling you people.
In Self Realization you get complete tranquility,
the collective consciousness
and you can maneuver this power yourself.
It is ‘your’ power that is manifested and nobody else.
But as you have been to all these satanic people
– most of you have been, last time I saw it
– and when I told them [that I tried?],
means I’m working very hard, you know it. I’m working very hard
but some of them have really spoiled their path of Sushumna,
the central path.
So that is they have spoiled it that unless and until
they give up all that it’s not going to work out.
If you are truly seeking I’m there to work for you.
You don’t have to pay any money for it. No,
never think of that because this is divine
and divine cannot be sold in the market.
First thing that should come into your head as Christians specially
that Christ has taken a hunter in his hand and hand it,
beating those people.
That’s the only time He really lost his temper
on them when they were selling the religion.
And today all of them are selling it
and you very, very humbly go and bow.
All kinds of these beggars and parasites have come in
this country and all over the western countries.
They are nothing but beggars take it from me.
Worse than beggars they are the worst culprits.
So, this is what Self Realization is
and in Self Realization you get all the blessings of God,
gradually you go into thoughtless awareness
and then into doubtless awareness which we call Nirvikalpa
and then into Self Realization completely.
In that we have some people in India
– they have met them – who are completely Self Realized
and who, sitting down there, can work out
the Kundalini of other people.
They are living in the family.
They have got their children.
They have got their grand-children. And they are working it out.
You don’t have to run away from it.
No extremes are needed, nothing.
It is ‘within you’ and ‘within you’ it is going to work out.
These outside things and these extreme things are not needed.
Just be normal people.
God has created this world for you to enjoy.
It is for your enjoyment, you see,
these blessings that you have to feel through Self Realization.
When the light of the Self flows in you see the joy pouring.
You see it pouring from your head downwards
and you are just drenched.
All your tensions go.
All your problems go away.
The Ego and Superego which he has shown here
as the black and the yellow,
both of them open up
and you see they’re going down.
It happens. There is an imbalance, there is a
– some sort of a – hurt in you.
Sometimes I can say there could a very great wound into you,
could be there are some spies sitting in you,
could be that you are possessed
without knowing that you are possessed.
You don’t know how these people have maneuvered
and I hope I will be able to tell you now
how they have maneuvered and what sort of horrid people they are.
I should take off my shoes perhaps.
So, about these horrid people now.
In India since long,
if you say the origin of so-called tantrism
which is just the position of real tantra
which is Sahaja Yoga, of the genuine tantra.
If tantrism is to be considered
as a genuine stuff then it is Sahaja Yoga.
But these tantrisms – these so-called
– came into being in our country since long.
Ancient times when these Gurus were
having those few disciples with them,
three, four disciples were taken with great difficulties.
But they were, after all, human beings.
They used to be competition with them
and Guru would accept only one out of them
or two out of them, would take them a little ahead
and would then leave them out saying that, “No.
We cannot treat you anymore.
You cannot be helped. You’d better go away.”
Such a useless, half-baked person would come down to the public
and would start a method by which ‘he’ would put up a show against
[these fools?].
This is the beginning I would say.
So he would now sit down and meditate.
Still, you know, as a Mother, I don’t want to condemn all of them.
I will give them a benefit of doubt
and the benefit of doubt is this that when they were concentrating
they tried to lift you into their Mooladhara chakra
which you cannot enter in, which is below the Kundalini.
This Mooladhara chakra controls the sex.
Why? Because it is innocent.
It’s a child and the child as he doesn’t have
sex that’s why it is not contaminated by it.
It is like a lotus coming out of the mud of sex.
In that lotus sits Shri Ganesha.
These people tried to peep into that
thinking that through sex you might be able to see things
and they might have seen – it is My own way of putting it
– not seen completely but the trunk as you see.
And they might have confused it
– still I say – that trunk to be the Kundalini.
When I tried to understand human beings
I thought it may have been because how could man be
just entering into hell directly with all that sex.
It’s too much to Me. So by mistake maybe, that they saw this.
All right?
So first the tantrikas came in.
Tantrikas were the first.
Then we have tantrikas
– basically I’m telling you- these evil geniuses are.
In the fact, you see, you cannot divide them
into all geniuses but you can give
a basic broad outline about these tantrikas.
Tantrikas are the people who use sex
for so-called Self Realization.
Mantrikas are the people
who use mantras for so-called Self Realization.
Then there are [Jakanikas?] who use evil geniuses
to be introduced as evil spirits into human beings
– called as [Janganikas?].
Then Paishachikas are the people who used
supraconscious devils into human beings.
They are over dynamic, overambitious sort of people.
We have got Aghoris who taught them to put uh,
say they can put a uh put a diamond into their hands.
Aghoris. Then we have got [Behunt?]
[Behunt?] are the people who can
do horrible uh, horrible gestures,
you see, they can pull their stomach in, push it here,
push it there, all sorts of things they do.
And we have also [Sexoyo?]. Minimum.
I have categorized them as that
but I don’t know how many sides of things there are
because when it comes to evil
they come and prosper like viruses.
Viruses they are. And they know how to hit you off.
They themselves are destroying, they cannot see you constructing.
They cannot see you evolve. That is one of
the basic reasons where they are out and oldies.
So these tantrikas were started their jobs.
In the Rama’s time, say about twelve hundred years back
there was a Yajna, a kind of a ceremony known as Ashvamedha.
It’s written in the books about that. Even that
– the books – the scriptures they ruined
by saying that Ashvamedha was nothing else but was a sex act.
The Shakti and Shiva,
which is God who is innocent
and His power the Shakti like light and the lamp or the sun
There also they introduced the symbol of sex.
This happened in the sixth century.
It was at its heights tantrism in our country,
a complete bend. was taken.
Say Satjakuna [?] It was to Khajuraho.
So much so they were influence people
that all other scriptures were thrown into the rivers
and tantrism became the scripture of the Hindus.
Thank God, by organized religion at least
you would not allow people to tamper too much with Bible.
Thought it was but not so much. It could have been.
There is so much freedom, that licentiousness to do whatever
you please with that scripture.
To get … Can you imagine? From this scripture they started spoiling
in the sixth century. Now what was the historical background for
that? That was the best time,
best breeding time of these horrible people.
Because at that time, as you too have
very extreme type of orthodox people,
Jainism, now we have a sect of people called as Jainism.
Now, horrid. I mean, all of them are.
But one of them
– horrid things I can tell you – that they believe in vegetarianism
to such an extent! It’s horrid thing to tell you
because – I’ve already told Gavin that for the first time
I’ll be shameless to tell you people –
that they do not want to destroy
even the insects that are in the filth.
To them an insect …
(tape interrupted)
(…) so that lots of bugs can bite him
and take out his blood and they pay him lot of money.
Is a fact. Even today they do sometimes in the villages.
They think it’s the greatest punya, is the greatest.
What you say ‘Tapoyajna’, means?
Punya is a good deed, you see, religious deed, Is to make a man
get inside a hut and bugs must come and they take the blood.
So these Jains – so-called vegetarians, horrid –
they were the ministers you know.
Some way or other they became ministers. So.
And the maharajas – you know the word ‘raja’ is for the King –
were the Hindus.
And Hindus as usual are very indifferent to religion.
Whatever one may say about it,
I agree it is a very great country and all that
but Hindus these days are even worse because now,
they have all become English, you see.
With English education all of them have become English.
Westernized.
They don’t think we have anything in our country.
So these – that time – great Rajas
who are so indifferent to religion, to their sustaining power,
to understand what is in their scriptures, licentious
and permissive like your Roman kings, horribly Rajas,
once they used to put their money to some sort of
an arrangement for all the licentious people around,
so they thought of a very genius method, you see:
build the temple of God
and make all kinds of erotic pictures in the temple.
Can you believe that thing? In the name of art.
If art is pure as people say, why do you need this vulgarity?
Horrible erotic things were created through big competitions.
Now you are having competitions in this country but that time
– of course now you are also becoming tantrikas
as far as erotic things are concerned
– one better than the other.
And they were given special prices, even jagirs
– as they call the lands –
were given to those people – it’s written in the history –
for creating those pictures. Despite that, you see,
despite all that provocations
and despite all that temptations,
you’ll be amazed, the konaraka, that art is departed.
There has been another thing, a simple thing is,
“Not. We’re ‘not’ going to do it.
On a temple we are ‘not’ doing it.”
So these clever intelligent people, you see, they told them that,
“If you do this, it will be good because all the dirt
that is here should be placed there”,
you see, “and inside should be clean.
Outside we must accept to God that we are like this.”
This is a concession. See the brain,
“This is a concession you must make what all dirty things
you are doing you put them out there.”
This was the – this was the historical side here.
And that time these tantrikas were,
you see, absolutely horrid they came.
You have only one Soho. We have Sohos
and Sohos and Sohos in that great country.
You won’t believe when you see those things, you know,
foreigners are surprised that in India
such erotic things are there.
Wherever there is religion, wherever there is a saint,
these satanic have to reach there to destroy all that is pure.
That is their style, their “happiness”.
This is a crucifixion of the purity.
And such temples were created
and those tantrikas then came forward.
They brought about all their women there for konaraka. If
you go there is the Chausath Bhavani Mandir, they call it
“the sixty-four goddesses”. Imagine Goddesses’ temple!
Now what do they do? Now what is the principle behind all that,
you must know. It is a very secretive principle that they use.
They establish the picture of a Goddess
or create a statue of a Goddess in a chapel
and before the Goddess they do nirvicara,
means sex act of sixteen varieties of different types.
Horrible! In the beginning Shri Ganesha gets angry.
They get all kinds of blisters all around. They – they say
that Kundalini is angry. Kundalini, why will She be angry?
It is Shri Ganesha who is angry, but in such a temper
from the right and the left and they get all blisters.
They start dancing, jumping, they behave like frogs,
they have horrid things. They get blasted in the head,
they get headaches, everything they get.
But still they are adamant
because it is said that, “You have to go further.
It’s a terrible task,
it’s a difficult task. These are your
Karmas that are coming to torture you.
You have to take out your Karmas.
Through your sex you do better Karmas or bad Karmas.”
So they go on poor people.
Then, by that, beyond that what happens is deities slip off.
They go away from there. The area is built-in.
The realm of God from there disappears
as light disappears in the darkness.
They work in the night. They’ll never work in the daytime.
In the night they work and then they call the spirits.
You can call them. Last time I told you what happens to
you when you die and how the spirits are there
and what are the horrible spirits
that are hanging around us to enter into you.
So I will not go into the details of that but later on
I’ll tell you all about it.
I’ll tell you each and everything. You note it down.
So they start, they call the spirits.
When they call the spirits – spirits have the lust in them,
greed, they’re greedy, you see, really dissatisfied –
and they maneuver them. They can give them the name of say ‘Rama’,
then ‘Aim’, ‘Hrim’, ‘Klim’, all sorts of names
they can give to these spirits,
these evil geniuses manage them.
And then they put these spirits on the king,
onto his big ministers. And these
people are captured and possessed.
And they say, “We are very erotic.
We are running after – we used to run after only two women,
now we are running after hundred women.” Mad!
They lose all their sense of Self.
They have no understanding of what they are doing.
Like mad they do. Even some saints can be affected
but they get reactions physically.
Saints if they indulge into it immediately they get reactions.
They get reactions in the head, in the body.
And the reactions could be very strong on them.
Sometimes they vomit too much.
So ‘these’ people start putting those horrible
sexes on you, capturing you, taking out your being.
In India there was a tantrika like that
who amassed lot of money but his wife [has pushed?] him throughout
and he built that horrible temple of that Konaraka
[Temple near Puri].
If he had not put any erotic’s there
it would have been a beautiful temple
but with that erotic you feel like vomiting
all the time when you go.
I mean, if you are healthy, you just can’t bear to see
those kinds of bathroom, the way it is done.
Tomorrow they will ask us to watch
these people sitting down there for the morning ablutions!
Filth and filth and filth! The whole place is nothing but filth.
And then his own son defied him, this horrible tantrika.
This tantrika was killed in a very funny manner
which is worth reading how he was killed.
And the son came down and he completed that temple
[In legends the architect’s son committed suicide jumping from the top of the temple.]
but he told the King that, “Your kingdom will disappear.”
All these – all these kings disappeared once for all.
They had no children,
they had nothing and they became just shamble
and all of their temples were covered
with stones, earth and they were just mounts.
Later on the English came there
and some of them excavated and found out.
They found it artistic, I don’t know how
they found it but it was there.
But in Konaraka you will find the whole thing is so vulgar,
so horrid, where the artists – poor things – had nothing to say.
And I met the artists of that place who are living around.
They said, “We are paying through our drones
all these days for what our forefathers have done
and we don’t want to see that.”
Even today in India an unmarried man and
an unmarried woman will never go to see a konaraka.
Now the only explanation they have is this, you’ll be amazed,
that after marriage Indian women are so innocent as that
they’re married quite young, they don’t understand what is sex,
so teach them how what is sex. It is made for the marriage
and only the husband and wife should go there.
This is the only explanation our Indian
artists could find out to give for that.
But we have to accept.
You see, in every country there could be a satanic force working.
Why should we identify ourselves with those horrible tantrikas
and why should we be ashamed of that?
In Khajuraho the other tantric place you will find
there are some places where you find eroticas.
But if you are alert and if you watch,
these are kept in corners somewhere
while the gods and goddesses have
big form, back, very great attachment, such a thing.
So it never comes to your notice unless and until you are
taken to it and shown out that this is an erotica.
But surprisingly most of the foreigners are specially
Japanese bringing their camera from this angle, from this angle.
Why don’t they take their own photographs like that?
What is there to go all the way
to Konaraka to take those photographs?
Shows your search!
Shows what you are asking for!
The way from here people take all the way those big – big – cameras
and go round. They take photographs like various angles they look.
What is there to take photographs? In that what is there to gain?
Sex, animals know, everybody knows, dog knows.
What is there to teach about sex?
You have done so much of mentally that now there will be impotency.
And in there, you know that, in America,
the highest number impotent are there
because of this kind of perversion and ruining
your innocence within yourself.
Beware of it!
This so-called freedom is nothing but abandonment of
your sustenance of your Dharma that is within you. Is built-in.
It is there. It exists. You cannot from,
“Thou shall not commit adultery.” Christ has said, “Not only
adultery but I will say, ‘Thou shall not have adulterous eyes’.”
And you see people, all the time they…
And they say, “We are intelligent.” What did happen?
Where are you looking?
Where are you seeing? Where is your attention?
This human attention built up ages.
So much has been worked out. You have been
brought from that level to this level today.
Where are you getting? Into gutters, into filth, into dirt.
Rise! And see your glory. Have your self-respect.
As a Mother, I tell you that.
And these horrible tantrikas and mantrikas
who are teaching you all kinds of things like putting a mandala
– the other day somebody told Me – and putting your sex there.
What is a mandala? Do you know is the aura of God?
You are showing your sex to God!
Have some brains at least if nothing else.
It’s the greatest shameful thing you are doing
if you show your sex part to God.
Are you all lunatics? Can’t you understand? It’s a ceremony!
I get upset with those
because you don’t know. You will lose
all your chances of Realization.
Your seeking is going to be lost completely, believe Me.
Stand in your own glory. Why should you run after women?
Why should you run after men?
If you are a glorious person, stand in your own image.
That’s the best way you are going to be a human being.
This kind of licentiousness and permissiveness is
going to completely finish that chakra in the Nabhi.
If you see that one has got ten petals which are
built so carefully, delicately, beautifully, with love.
Do not confuse love with licentious behavior.
It is ‘not’.
It’s sanctified love.
I don’t say you become sanyasin, not at all,
I’m against that also, another extreme.
Then I’m going to tell you about sexo-yogis, the third time.
The sexo-yogis start as a people who are
suppressing their sex. They do not marry. (Tape interruption)
They use
– they use the skull of a lady.
They need skulls for that.
To be in the subconscious you have to have a skull.
So they kill people, take out their skulls and keep it with them.
Some people are coming, please open door.
So the – they keep those skulls with them
and those skulls they use it for drinking water,
for eating food, all the time these skulls are there.
Now there is a very good story written by a great writer in
India, Bankim Chandra [Chattopadhyay], is known as Kapal Kundala.
This girl, there was a girl whom a Kapali [Mahadji?],
he used to make her nude, he used to make her dance,
he used to make her go in the see
and used to control his sex sitting before her.
And there are several also, very sexual acts he would control also.
He went on like that and ultimately he wants to kill that girl.
That is the height of complete abstinence
because you kill the person whom you were supposed to have.
Just imagine, what perversion! What brain! What habits!
I mean there’s no limit to this. God has not given you freedom
to break your head and to say that, “Oh, bull come and hit me!”
And this girl was preserved and then someway
or other she ran away and she got married to a man.
He visited her, brought her back and killed her.
These are the Kapali.
If you don’t listen to them,
they will take you to the smashana that is the burial ground,
cut your head, take out your skull and keep it.
They will see to it that you go to the subconscious strata
and they handle you better there.
They would like to die through their stamina.
They do it.
So many of them are doing like that. Even today, you have no idea.
And people are so much enamored,
so much under the obsession of these things are,
that even if you tell them that your gurus are
doing like this and they have found out,
still they will be there to kill you.
Absolutely rabid people. They are possessed,
brain-washed completely.
And if some people should be saved, to say…
I always say that if a sari keeps flying out,
even if you could hold a little bit of it, we can save this sari.
The sanity must come to you to understand
that these horrible methods
are not going to give you Self Realization.
You must know what is Self Realization.
Now some people think that flying in the air,
jumping somewhere is something great.
Which incarnation did? Did you hear any incarnation
[Delete ‘who walked’],
who sat like this and was floating in the air?
Which incarnation did that and what are you going to
do with floating in the air? You are going to
create a problem on the traffic.
These nonsensical things why should you do?
There is in Puna [Shivapur],
they say there is one saint who died, you see,
and there is a stone,
if there ten people take the name of the saint, it can come up.
And you can put a finger, it can come up.
I said, “With that what God should do?” Think of it!
And when I went there I found out
that there was a big spirit sitting there and he said, “I’m going
to sit down here Mother. I’m not going to do [other thing?].”
And the spirit of that horrible fellow
is all the time sitting there.
He doesn’t want anything.
He just want to meet good people and sit down there
and listen everybody’s taking his name,
calling him a saint. When he is not a saint why should
we accept that he is a saint
and be happy with it? Because human beings can do anything.
They have given that power.
And moreover God is powerless before you
because He cannot take away your freedom to be idiots
or to be foolish or to be self-destroying. He cannot do it.
He can only weep and cry, beg on you,
“Please don’t do it, please don’t do it”, but He cannot stop it.
That’s the only problem. And that’s why all of them have taken you.
They have all come from somewhere like spiders.
At least I know fifteen of them.
And three horrible women. They’re all there making money,
making money, befooling you.
Why do you need a guru for telling you a mantra?
Any Dick, Tom, Harry can tell you.
You must see the result, the proof.
What’s happening out of it.
You must think. You are intelligent people.
You understand everything, why don’t you understand this,
“I’m possessed.”
Are you under the complete obsession of such people?
Or perhaps you have paid them so much money that you think,
“Oh how we have paid so much now what,
we should see through the whole thing.”
Like in the drama you go and you don’t like the drama, still
when you have paid the money, then stand.
It’s not that casual.
It’s a very serious thing. You are going into the den of devils,
finishing your Kundalini completely. Now there are
at least twenty-five people among you who will say that.
It has happened to them. I’ve been correcting them.
I’m doing it. They get it back.
I only feel sorry for one thing,
that you have been genuine about your seeking.
You have been genuinely seeking and
I can assure you that I went to America in 1970
to warn on you but that time they were,
all of them had become something special type of possessed.
They would not listen to Me. I told Ravi Shankar. He said,
“Mother you just don’t go near them. They will eat you out.”
That out to have experiences of torn fulsome drugs.
In India how many people have seen the drugs
– ask them, anyone of them ?
Ha! Do they even know what is the difference
between bhang and this and that?
These drugs and all these things were used by tantrikas.
And they are out here. They have brought out that.
Things that go against your awareness
whether drugs, alcohol, anything
is ‘not’ going to give you that higher awareness about
which I’m saying.
Don’t waste your life. It’s very precious.
The most precious and the greatest time has come.
Please respect yourself. And please understand your value.
What you have learned before, find it out and do not waste it.
You have already wasted lot of your time.
Means all these – I told you the seven stratas –
on the left and right have names which I think that time
I have no time to tell you but there are
names and names and names for everything.
Hakini, Rakini, Lakini, Shakini,
like that on the left hand side they have got.
This side is Gayatri and Savitri and all that sorts of things.
It goes on both the sides.
All these are nothing but like resonances.
They throw you from one to another strata.
You are sort of tested in every strata
and when they found you are a gone case you go ‘direct’ into hell.
These are all achieved!
So I have to make a very simple
statement that keep your Self, respect your Self.
Try. If it works with you, well and good. I’m here to work out the
raising of the Kundalini, the bringing it out of it.
You yourself would be able to do after some time
but cleansing is needed and it should never be given up
because there is no way out.
Nanak – Guru Nanak –
he has written at least three-four chapters against these
tantrikas and mantrikas and these paishakshikas and these jains.
In India it’s an abuse to say – I mean I have first time used
these words for that on my tongue –
is an abuse to call somebody like this.
If you say that to someone they will take you to the court.
They are kept outside like lepers.
Kabira has written books after books. These khecharis
and this and that he lashed them left and right,
He was a great poet.
Everybody fought with him, tortured him.
Christ was the same.
He is the one who said not to go towards spirits at all.
This is all spirit’s job.
But you go in London every fifth house is
a spiritualist sitting there,
“Free hypnotics!”
Why do you want to get hypnotized? Why do you want to get
E.S.P – what they call – Extra Sensory Perception?
All these so-called geniuses also,
these prodigies are also possessed.
I’ve seen many prodigies.
One of them came to Me. I told,
“All right, in My presence you calculate.”
She could not calculate even in one
because I put a bandhan to her possession. I said, “You get out!”
I’ve had many such experiences which I can tell you.
Last time I’ve told you
how people who are possessed came to Me and how they leave.
Now there is still time and we can
move into Self Realization experience.
It will – it might take to some people in five minutes
but to some more.
In any case you must have patience. And don’t be angry with you.
Because when Gavin said Ego – I was fired when he said –
because if it is not Ego then the Superego comes,
“We are the worst people, we are the horrible people.
We…” you see, from one extreme to another.
You have to stand in-between. You are glorious.
You are not an aggressor neither
you are taking aggression from anyone.
You stand within your Self and through
that you have your own powers.
You don’t have to depend on anyone, nothing. You just are.
But you have to depend on the deities that are within you,
which I’m going to see. There has been a problem.
They have to be corrected
and you have to know where are the deities, where are they.
In the Sahaja Yoga – modern Sahaja Yoga I may call it –
there is no mantra given.
No. Because every second the Kundalini is going like that.
Now there are people who’ll say,
“This I can tell you, this I can tell you.”
It is here they saw that.
You must have seen she came to Me, She tells Me that,
“Mother I’ve caught that.” All right, finished. Agnya catching.
So nobody is given a mantra but you know where is the catch.
You yourself say.
She herself came and told Me, “I’ve got it caught on Agnya.”
And you know what’s the extreme Agnya catching means,
you know: paranoia.
But she doesn’t mind telling Me because she sees herself
away from herself and she told Me, “I’ve got an Agnya clearly.”
All of them say, “The Agnya is there.
I can see those coming inside me.”
He told Me that, “I can see these entities now coming into me.”
And I throw them away and they have a nice – a nice program.
If you all talk to them, they will tell you their experiences.
Some of them went into trance; I had to take them out.
So many things happen now. People just like you came to Me
and gained.
And you’ll also gain but be sensible about it, be wise. Be wise.
You have to expect gains and nothing else.
Nothing else you can found.
So, may God bless you.
You can go into a little meditation
just by putting your hands towards Me