…only thing to do is to come down as a human
being, to live like a human being, and suffer
like a human being.
And He came down on this earth, to know now,
to know the world that He has created, from
inside, out.
That’s how He came just to save us.
But I mean, he was talking and his Agnya was
such a big catch that I was just saying ki
(that) thing he is talking about itself is
evident in him – that there is no sense
of humility left in him!
The way he was using Christ for that!
And a very horrible Agnya!
And I cleared it out.
And the whole thing was like a…I was thinking
he was putting up an act.
And then the most miserable part was later
on when he said that, “What is your message
for the people of other communities who are
here and what do you say?”
He said that, “We should love our neighbour
and that’s how we must love you.
And it’s for the wellbeing, and that’s
why we had started a thing by which we give
people jobs and look after them."
And the thing all started with a philanthropic
thing, and then it became a union, a labour
union, and then he became a social worker,
and ultimately he ended up with an employment
exchange!! (laughing) And I didn’t know
what sort of a bishop is he and when is he
going to talk about the emancipation of the
Spirit within?
When is he going to talk about the evolution?
And when is he going to talk that we have
to be aware of ourselves?
And – nothing!
Not a word!
What he spoke was this, and so disappointing,
I tell you.
I mean, all the way Christ came only just
to give you jobs?
(laughing) And then they had a man put up
there who talked about how they give jobs
to people who don’t have jobs and how they
create jobs.
So the whole thing became an economic activity!
So, [to] understand God and His humility by
saying that He should come all the way on
this earth just to give us employment exchange!
I mean this is how if you are going to judge
God’s incarnation, I don’t know what you
are going to get out of them.
Because this is a wrong conception you have
about God and His ways.
Absolutely.
And people listen to him, I mean without any
questioning or anything because he was a bishop
elected by all of you, and he was on and on
and on.
So this is, one has to understand, why did
Christ come on this earth?
Why did He come all the way with all humility?
Why did He come as a poor man on this earth?
And why did He, at all, wanted to get crucified
and to sacrifice His life for the people who
were supposed to be sinners?
This is what we should find out.
Not for unemployment or for getting you a
material gain because He Himself has said
that, “A rich man can never enter into the
Kingdom of God."
So to get jobs for people or to get them some…there
was a disabled person, and “a disabled person
should be helped, and that is the job of the
Church."
And that’s what they were describing, that
how they were helping the disabled people
in this country!!
So, because He cured certain people that doesn’t
mean that He came to look after the disabled
hospitals and things like that!
But He came on this earth for a new awareness
being shot into our being.
He was born at a time when human beings had
no idea as to what is the eternal life, what
is the Spirit, what we call the ‘Atma’
is.
They never even thought that there is something
like that.
He was born in a place where they did not
think on those lines.
And though in India, we can say that people
have been thinking about Atma and Paramatma
since long; but they also achieved nothing
because all these so-called religious leaders
of India were busy collecting money.
Then Christ came in, you see.
And they were – I don’t know what sort
of temples they had or what sort of pujas
they used to have, or what ideas they had
about God because He came out two thousand
years ago.
And that same time Buddhism also was spreading
in India.
And all these things, if you see in the collectively,
it is very disturbing to see people using
Buddha in that fashion.
And it was necessary that Christ should come
on this earth to tell them that it is the
Spirit that you have to find out.
You don’t have to worry about other things,
but it is the Spirit which is to be reborn.
You are to be reborn.
You are to be Christian.
And that’s how we came on this earth.
But He could not cross the limit of Bethlehem.
I mean, He was just, we can say of – absolutely
gated into that place because of the ignorance
of the people.
His message never spread out when He lived.
So His purpose was to come on this earth,
on the Agnya chakra, as you know that, to
open it, and to give a new dimension to our
awareness by which we try to understand what
Krishna had said that, “Nainam chidanti
shastrani, nainam dahati pavaka."
Krishna had said that, “The Spirit cannot
be destroyed, it cannot be killed, it cannot
be wiped out, it cannot be blown off."
“Na chainam kledayantyapo, na shosayati
marutaha."
“It cannot be sucked in by any air."
And when Krishna said that people said, “What
sort of a Spirit is that?
Where is that Atma?
What are you talking about?
Which one it is?”
So Christ came on this earth because He is
the essence.
And He showed by His resurrection that Spirit
does not die.
And He showed it very clearly what Krishna
had said, because, you know, He was Krishna’s
son, and that’s how He did it.
But before He could deliver the complete thing
to human beings they crucified Him.
And that is the way they respected Him and
that is the way they came to Him.
Now in Sahaja Yoga also, we must know that
if you go to Sahaja Yoga, it is not [that]
you are obliging Sahaja Yoga.
You see, this is how a person talks today
when Christ is no more.
That, “Christ came on this earth, it was
His humility,” because you understand how
great He was.
I mean, at least, you try to pose that you
understand, then you say like that.
But when you come to Sahaja Yoga, you think
the Sahaja Yoga should oblige you and not
you are being under the obligation of Sahaja
Yoga.
[Part 2]
…conditions about your spirituality through
completely humbling down yourself because
it is the grace of God that must be sought
for.
And somebody’s grace you cannot force it
down.
You cannot demand it.
You cannot ask for it.
You cannot say that, “I am such and such
a big king”, and something like that, “so
the grace should come to me."
No, it may not come to you at all.
Even you may be the highest priest of the
Church of England, you may not get the grace
of God.
To get the grace of God you have to ask for
it, you have to be humble.
It is like we expect to go to the king’s
palace and then we want that the king should
come forward, he should kneel down, and he
should take you by hand and make you sit on
the throne!
I mean, this is something absurd!
We can understand that.
But even more than that is an incarnation.
An incarnation comes down in complete humility,
not to be humiliated, but to make you understand
that an incarnation has come all the way for
your emancipation and for your spiritual growth.
Then you should with great surrendering and
great humility should accept it.
But the general attitude, you have seen how
Sahaja Yogis before coming and after coming,
how they realise how others are behaving towards
Sahaja Yoga.
They have no humility about it.
They are thinking, “Oh, we’ll come and
judge Mataji.
We’ll see how she is.
We’ll watch her and we’ll do this, or
we’ll come and see the Sahaja Yogis are
like this."
They never come with the idea that they have
to receive it out of their own humility, because
they have asked for it, that’s why they
are going to have it.
On the contrary, they behave so funnily.
Despite that, they get it.
Despite that, they get their Realisation.
Despite that, they get everything else.
But one should know that, somehow or other
you should try to tell those who come, now
you’ll be coming down here, you see I’ll
be not here, and they’ll be coming to see
you, many people know about your address,
then you should tell them that, “We have
to realise [that] if we have to get something
then there should be an area created within
us through our humility."
Like if you throw a stone into the Ganges
you do not get any water out of it.
But if you are a pitcher, if there is an area
which can take that water in then only can
you fill in the Ganges.
Now, if you go to the Ganges and tell Her,
abuse Her and say, “Oh, you Ganges, come
along to my house!”
Will She come to your house?
In the same way one has to understand an incarnation
or a blessing of God, or a grace of God.
We have to ask for it and humble down for
it.
They have all the rituals.
For example – if you go to the church, they’ll
say, “Kneel down” and even the priest
would say, kneel down before him.
Though he may not be a realised soul or anything,
this bishop of Canterbury or somebody who
spoke today, he is not a realised soul, his
Kundalini is just frozen.
But the way everybody was very humbled down
before him.
He never deserved it, according to Me, he
never deserves it, but we’ll do that.
But to an incarnation not only that you are
not humble to Him, but we are extremely insulting,
humiliating and we crucify.
We have to see that human nature.
It is such a terrible thing to do and if this
is done often then the wrath of God has to
come, we cannot stop it because the way we
are behaving, and the way we are looking at
it.
Now, think of Christ, how He was created,
as you have seen in the Devi Mahatmyam, the
Mahavishnu stage, how He was created specially
in the heaven, and then how He was brought
in.
You have read it in the Devi Mahatmyam, His
creation.
With all those things which are being done
to Him, all the powers that were given to
Him, and was specially asked to come on this
earth, to live like a ordinary human being.
Say, if you tell a king to go and live in
a shack, or you can say in a place which is
not meant for even human existence, in such
places, if you ask a king to go and live,
it will be very difficult.
But they do it, they have done it.
And when they come here, the attitude of the
people should be completely surrendering;
to thank God that you have done this for us.
Thankfulness.
And the thankfulness is the way to joy, there
is no other way.
We get everything but we never thank.
Grudging type we are.
Today is the day of thankfulness that He sent
His only son, as we say, and he came himself
so many times on this earth, and how we have
been helped by his coming here, his aspect
coming down on this earth.
The thankfulness if you do not have, you’ll
never see the joy that you have – whatever
you have got, whatever God has given you out
of His grace, out of His compassion, out of
His love.
There is not even a second, which you can
spare, but thank Him all the time.
It’s only thankfulness.
And when you thank Him, the waves of joy will
rise within you.
Because we do not know how to thank Him for
what we have got it.
There is no joy within us and we are joyless
people, we are very unhappy.
Whatever we have, we are not happy about it.
So, this is the point is that, Have we thanked
Him?
Have we thanked Him every moment of our lives,
whatever He has given us?
It’s a great thing, the greatest thing,
is that He has given us Realisation, and He
has given us the way of Sahaja by which we
can now find out ourselves fully.
And the another thing is, unless and until
that is done, we cannot perfect anything in
this world, nothing can be perfected.
All your institutions, all your endeavours
are going to be imperfect.
A human being has to be perfected and he has
to get cured and, for that, the only simple
thing is to humble down.
Humbling down is the only way you can get
it.
There is no way of arguing about it, there
is no way of talking about it, or imposing
on anyone – nothing of the kind – but
how much you are humbled down within yourself
is the point.
Always look into your heart, humble down,
humble down, and humble down.
And thank, every moment, every minute.
And that is the key to spark the joy out of
every moment.
Every moment has an ocean of joy in it but
to spark it you must thank for whatever you
have got.
But if you are a grudging type, all the time
if you think that, “Oh, I haven’t got
this, I haven’t got this, I haven’t got
that,” then you can never enjoy whatever
you have.
And that is what is the message for Christmas
for everyone: is that Christmas is a day of
thankfulness because He gave His only son
to you and He came as an extremely humble
person, in a very humble abode, in a very
humble birth.
And that is a thing one has to know, that
we have to be thankful for what we have got,
materially, physically, emotionally, and mentally
also whatever we have learnt.
While He lived in complete poverty, with complete
thankfulness within him.
So may God bless you!
I am very much thankful for this house, that
my children have got it.
I am very much thankful that my children are
all here and they are enjoying.
I am very much thankful that I am with them
and that your problems are solved.
I don’t know how to thank for all this,
your love that you have shown, and all the
beautiful things you have been thinking and
singing, and how you have taken to Sahaja
Yoga and working for it.
There is no end to it!
But you also enjoy it by thanking all the
time.
May God bless you!