the creation of God is going to get its fulfilment
and is going to know its meaning – it is
that great! Perhaps we do not realise it,
but when we say, “We are sahaja yogis,”
you have to know that, to be a sahaja yogi,
how much identified you should be with the
Truth of Sahaja Yoga, and so many misidentifications
which are hanging on to you must be got rid
of.
People call it a sacrifice.
I do not think it is a sacrifice.
If you think something is hampering your way
you try to take out that hurdle.
In the same way, if you stand out from your
obstructions, you will be able to understand
that these obstructions are standing in your
way and they are not your own and that they
are stopping your progress.
So you should get this misidentification out
of your minds completely and try to be more
and more your Self and not a misidentification.
This is one the problems, I think, people
have here.
Whenever I get any complaints or anything,
I understand that still the level of understanding
about Sahaja Yoga is not up to that point.
It is a tremendous task! And for that, if
you are the people who have to come up and
if you are the people who have to fight it,
you have to understand it in its full extent
and also understand where you stand for it:
how much you have to do? how much you have
to improve yourself? Because you are the people
who are going to take the Sahaja Yoga to that
position where it has to reach because as
far as I am concerned, I have nothing to do
anymore.
I have done it.
Now it is for you to receive, you have to
imbibe into it and you have to change the
whole thing; that is your job and that is
why it is a serious matter.
The second point I always have been saying
[is] that, due to ego problem, we are very
much disintegrated.
We are so disintegrated that the connection
with the Divine is never properly established.
As I have said it, that this instrument (microphone)
if it is divided into five parts and all the
five parts are fighting with each other, you
cannot get anything done through this instrument,
through it is connected to the mains.
In the same way if you still remain disintegrated
you cannot get that connection.
For example, people come down here, I have
seen, for Sahaja Yoga; now they have other
interests and there’s other priorities and
other things are there which are very important
for them.
All the time, they are wasting their time
for that, and then they will say that, “Mother,
we are not progressing much in Sahaja Yoga.
” If you decide, as he (Mr.
Venugopalan) has told you that, “We have
to do Sahaja Yoga first and the other things
are secondary,” then only the Sahaja Yoga
can be really established into you.
We’ll have some Sahaja Yogis of a very high
level, I know that, and we will have some
of very mediocre level, some will be absolutely
useless and some would be absolutely thrown
away.
We’ll have all types.
That also I know.
Now it is for you to decide: where do you
come? How far you are going to? If you are
going to waste your time in thinking about
other sahaja yogis and small, small things
and trivial things as he has said it, your
disintegration is going to be increased, you
are going to [be] separated much more because
all this decision is taken through your ego:
“I don’t like it, I don’t do it, I don’t
see it.
” If you could somehow or other see your
ego working, then you can get rid of it.
And that is the thing one has to do; not to
fight the ego.
I never say, “Fight the ego!” But surrendering
is the only way your ego can go.
And that’s why the progress in the West,
as you have seen it, is much less than it
is in India.
Now, take his case, I would say, particular
case of [Mr.
] Venugopalan: he’s really remarkable because
he is a man who is holding a very big position
in India.
Here I see, even if a person is a dishwasher
[and] he comes to Sahaja Yoga, still his ego
is so big [that] even our Prime Minister won’t
have such a big ego as he has! I mean, the
way he will talk that, “I don’t like it,
I do this, this!” I am myself amazed the
way people [talk]! You see, everybody has
become the King of England or what? The way
they talk! This is something one should tell
people when they come here, that, “Don’t
waste Mataji’s energies in arguing and this
and that,” because everybody thinks no end
of themselves here, and that is the biggest
hurdle that they have, when they even come
first time, you find it so difficult! I have
to show all my appreciation of their ego,
all the time, just to satisfy them so that
they come round.
And this is how the progress becomes less.
Now, in his case, (Venugopalan) he is a person
who has been to all kinds of horrible ‘gurus’
and his wife has been also to all kinds of
horrible ‘gurus’ because of another extreme
in India we have, that we must respect all
the saints.
But these days the saints are fake saints,
not only fake saints, but some of them are
devils! So they are not going to say, “We
are devils.
” When they do not say they are devils or
whatever it is, they do not come in their
proper form, these simple, innocent people,
who are seeking God, just go to them, give
their heart, do everything and then they find
that they are devils.
Once they discover they are devils, then they
are surprised.
Then they come back from there, they go to
another guru, they go to another guru, but
the harm is done.
But they get rid of that harm because they
recognise that harm has been done and they
know, what is the Truth is, what is to expect.
I would say it is the blessing of that country
that people know what to expect.
People would not like to go, those who are
really of a very good quality people, will
not go to a man who shows some sort of a a
sensationalisation or some sort of a chamatkar
(चमत्कार) – is a miracle – they
would not go, but they will go to other subtler
people, who are very cunning and they put
up another kind of a show and just say that,
“No, no, this is the way you can achieve
the highest,” and that’s how most of the
sahaja yogis in India also have been – except
for the village people and the district people
– most of the city people have been to some
guru or someone.
But despite all that, they have left everything.
I have told them, “You have to beat them
with shoes.
” They’ll do everything morning till…every
day he does his sadhana (साधना)
for one hour though he’s a very busy man.
Here even to get up in the morning, people
grudge.
I mean, what can you do with such slow moving
people? You see, it is absolutely very difficult!
And this is what I feel that we must understand
that we have a very great responsibility,
very great responsibility in the West, because
this has to happen in London, it has to happen
in England to begin with, and that’s why
you bear a very big responsibility.
You have to evaluate yourself and you have
to evaluate Sahaja Yoga, again and again and
again.
And know that what makes you slow is your
ego – or even superego is there, no doubt
– but ego is the main problem.
I must tell you [that] ego is the main problem
but I dare not say to anyone that, “This
is your ego,” because that will just jump
on to my head.
But try to see your ego, how it is deviating,
because it is your own joy you are seeking,
it is your own property you are seeking, it
is your own that is hidden from you, for which
you have been seeking for ages now; that is
what I have to expose for you.
What is there to argue with a person, who
is trying to give you the highest? It’s
just a waste of energy.
Do not waste your energy onto these things,
onto frivolous things, about finding faults.
Now he has been organising our Delhi Camp,
he is the one who has organised our printing
of the book and all.
I have not known any problems there.
You just tell them that, “This has to happen,”
“Alright!” I do not know how it works
out.
You have stayed in Delhi.
You have seen how many people were there.
Never a problem! Did you hear anybody complaining?
Or anybody quarrelling or fighting among themselves?
Nothing of the kind! You see, this is not
the sign of intelligence either; of all the
time trying to find faults with each other
or trying to blame yourself.
Both things are wrong.
Best thing is to grow in wisdom, we must grow
in wisdom.
We’ll, ourselves, see that we are becoming
wiser and wiser.
Some of you are really very grown up and some
of you still go up and down, and some of you’re
still very low.
So all of us have to get up and all of us
have to go together.
If somebody has also achieved something it
is of no use to Sahaja Yoga, as I have told
you, it’s a collective thing that is going
to work out.
All of you have to work it out and it is so
sweet that you have real brothers and sisters
all over the world today.
When you’ll go there with the full heart
they are going to receive [you] as you have
received him with full heart.
But we all must come up! Come up to a point,
where we can face each other with full love,
with openness, without any worry about anything,
without any fear of anyone; but just [that]
they are your brothers and you are their brothers
and that you have to love them.
That’s only possible when we’ll get out
of our fears here.
Because there is also another side to it that
ego always has a fear; because it aggresses
others it is afraid also because it knows
others can aggress.
So this is a point we have got to think about.
But that never means that in any way despise
yourself, never! You are saints, you must
know that.
You are realised souls! How many there are
realised souls in this world? How many there
are who can raise the Kundalini? How many
there are who understand what is vibrations?
I’m going to tell you, on Guru puja, what
things you have achieved, and how many things
you have got within you, built-in now, which
are working, and how your chakras are awakened
through Sahaja Yoga.
As he says, “Yes, it has happened.
” But what are we doing about it? It’s
is the greatest of the greatest that can happen
to anyone; that you know.
Also you know this is the greatest happening
which was prophesised long time back as the
Last Judgement.
You know that this is the way you are going
to be judged, so we have to work very hard,
we have to work.
It is effortlessly given to you, alright,
but to maintain it, to keep it up to go higher,
we have to religiously work it out with a
very humble attitude – receiving more and
more and more, imbibing it into your being.
Let it trickle into your being, completely
covering it.
Let that joy, that Eternal Bliss come into
you.
I am so anxious for that.
Do not make yourself a small person.
Have a bigger vision, have bigger ideas because
now you belong to the Bigger Thing, the biggest
of all, the Primordial, the Highest, to the
Viraat! If you realise your importance then
you will work it out.
You see, if you see an Indian Sahaja Yogi,
you will be amazed! He sleeps only for two,
three hours or four hours, but he will not
give up his sadhana.
If he can get his full sleep it’s alright.
First thing he sees is, “One hour for sadhana
in the morning.
I have to get it out somehow.
” But sleep? We have been sleeping all our
lives! We have to correct ourselves, we have
to rise, we have to go ahead – to achieve
your own.
That’s the main point is! See your own selfishness,
I am telling! To know yourself is the greatest
selfishness.
If you do not know yourself, all the selfishness
is useless.
As you call a swartha (स्वार्थ),
in Sanskrit it is said ‘swartha’, Swartha
means ‘selfishness’.
If you break it ‘swa’ ‘artha’ – if
you know the meaning of your ‘swa’, means
your ‘self’, then it is the greatest selfishness.
So this is what it is and we are very happy
that he’s here.
We’ll be going to India also, next year
we also are planning to go to India and you
are going to meet [them].
Lots of them may come to Delhi and Bombay.
They are all waiting for you, they are all
planning how to receive you, they are so happy
that so many of Sahaja Yogis from London and
all over will be coming.
And you know how they look after you and how
they are happy and how they are joyous.
And certain things definitely have gone wrong
with us, we know that.
We should understand them because these are
the troubles of our over-thinking and over-reading
and over-domination but we can get rid of
it very easily.
It is just to detach yourself and see for
yourself addressing yourself, “Now Mr.
how are you?” If you say like that, immediately
your attention will go, through yourself you
will see your outer being.
That is very important.
The more you see yourself clearly, the better
it is.
You have to face yourself.
And you do not want to face, you are afraid
of facing yourself, because you have been
aggressing others and you are afraid to aggress,
in a way that is towards yourself.
But there won’t be any aggression because
that’s the perfect state where you see yourself
and neither you aggress anyone nor you are
aggressed by anyone, you just see yourself
clearly.
And that is what you have to see.
Gradually you start seeing your chakras, seeing
your problems, your thing and you know that
how, gradually, it develops.
But everybody wants a quick results.
It’s alright, if you want quick results,
alright, are you like that? If you are like
that you will get a quick results; if you
are not, then be patient with yourself, not
with me, but with yourself, I am saying, you
have to be patient, because there is a problem
with you so you have to be patient with yourself
and not with anybody else – that’s is
the main point.
If you are patient with yourself, this is
a long promised thing which you are going
to get.
But you must learn to be patient with yourself
and not to be angry with yourself, not to
debase yourself or not to aggress yourself
on to others.
It’s a very simple thing, it’s the simplest
thing to do, but because of our complex life
and our complicated thinking we have become
quite twined up into things.
It can easily be got out of, you can just
slip out of it without any difficulty.
I know that you can do it so forget about
all these things like, “My father, my sister,
my brother.
” All these problems will be burnt in no
time as soon as your life runs straight.
Everything will burn away, nothing will be
left but your light and others who will come
to you for enlightenment.
I know that you are going to have a big day
for a Guru puja.
Before that I would request you to prepare
yourself.
I may do something great but I must have a
proper recipient so [for] that you must prepare
yourself.
Think about it – are you loving others?
Are you in love? Are you in love with everyone?
Just to think that you love everyone is so
great! I mean you ask me.
Everybody says, “Mother, you look so young!
How do you look?” It’s because I always
think of how much I have to love.
You see, so much love I have to give to others.
Just think how great it is to love others.
You know how people treat me sometimes, doesn’t
matter, I’ll still love.
I enjoy playing with it.
In the same way you should love, and love
is the thing that is going to unfold beautifully
like a lotus opens out it’s petals and the
beautiful fragrance starts flowing.
In the same way, your heart will open out
and the fragrance of love will spread throughout
the world, it will ring into people.
I know it can happen, the sooner the better
and the choice is your own which you have
to make a choice.
So I’m very happy because such a beautiful
song to hear and just before Christmas which
is a very big thing for me, you know that.
And in the same way we are having another
Christmas now, Christmas to celebrate a new
Christ, born within us.
Let us prepare for His coming and how you
prepare is not by running away from yourself,
not by getting into frivolous things but by
working it out, beautifully.
Cleansing, cleansing has to be done if the
Self has to be established in the temple of
this being.
May God bless you all.