GURU PUJA
Cabella Ligure, Italy
1st August, 1999
Since we have come to Cabella, it is the ten
years completed.
So you can imagine how, in these ten years,
we have been able to progress in Sahaja Yoga.
Now, today we are going to have a Guru Puja.
As I have said, you all are gurus and you
want to worship Me as your Guru.
It is all right.
But the main thing one should understand,
that you have become guru, no doubt, because
you have the knowledge, you have the absolute
knowledge.
And so we can say you have become gurus, no
doubt.
But one has to understand that you have reached
a state where you can raise the Kundalini,
you can give Realization to others.
Also you know what is the absolute knowledge.
To know the absolute knowledge is very important,
and to assimilate is even much more important.
Though we know the absolute knowledge, we
cannot assimilate it that well.
That means we cannot go deep into it.
What is the reason for that?
We have to realize that we have all come out
of the heritage that was the animal kingdom.
From the animal kingdom you have evolved.
So there are so many things of the animal
heritage that linger in us: the aggressiveness,
the domination, peevishness, fear, grabbing.
All these are our inheritance, and they are
within us lingering.
We want to grab things of others’ - not
you people, of course not, but people who
are not yet in Sahaja Yoga.
They first used to grab lands, then they started
grabbing people, making them slaves.
Then they were not satisfied with that, so
they were grabbing kingdoms, jewelry and all
these things.
So just to grab.
They have no legal right, still they would
grab.
It seems, it seems very funny, it seems very
inhuman, but it is there because of our inheritance.
Now there are so many other things, like jealousy.
Among animals there is very little of that,
they don't have jealousies so much as we have;
while we have inherited this jealousy by our
own reactions and thinking.
People get jealous and they want to put down
others.
If they cannot achieve any height, they want
to bring down the heights of others.
This kind of jealousy, when it grabs human
beings, they think whatever is done in the
name of jealousy is all right.
They become very conscious that “We are
lower than another person.
We lack in some talents than another person,”
and they try to overpower that person, because
of the force of jealousy behind them.
Now the trouble is, though we are human beings,
we have inherited so many animal qualities,
like we are ferocious, we are angry and we
get upset, as animals do.
But additional to that, human beings can react
because of their thinking.
They think.
They can think, and by thinking, all these
inherited properties become perverted.
Like a person wants to put down another person.
Then he doesn’t behave like an animal, in
a straightforward way, but he will find out
a device, a method, he’ll think it over
how to do it.
The main problem with human beings is that
they still have inherited very violent temper.
This violent temper has to be controlled,
has to be seen.
When you see something which you don't like,
which is against your will, it may be something
like that, immediately you flare up.
Just now I saw, instead of the camphor, they
had put a sugar candy.
To sugar candy they were putting the matchbox,
you see, they were using a match into it,
matchstick.
It would not take the fire.
They tried and tried, it would not.
So I said, "Let Me see what is that."
So that was a sugar candy.
If it was camphor, it would just flare up.
So the quality of the person is known in the
same way.
If with the slightest provocation, if he gets
into temper and gets annoyed, then his quality
is not very good as a guru.
As a guru we should not flare up, we should
not get angry, we should not try to oppress
others.
"But what can we do, then?"
people will ask.
We have another method, what we call is love.
Love.
Instead of getting angry, if you show love
and compassion to that person, so what happens
that it doesn’t give you any anger, and
the another person, you don't make him angry
also.
Anger begets anger.
If you get angry with somebody, that person
may not retort because he is afraid of you,
it may be that; but in his heart he will keep
a revenge in his mind that “One day I will
show him.
Why should he get angry with me?”
So in Sahaja Yoga, please remember that love
is the only way we can solve the problem.
Now if something goes wrong, say, in the ashram,
if you get angry with that person, what will
happen?
That person will bear a grudge against you,
perhaps.
If he’s a good Sahaja Yogi, he may realize
that it was a wrong thing to do.
But if he’s a bad Sahaja Yogi, not yet fully
equipped to understand, then what he will
do?
He will just feel that “This man has insulted
me.
He has deliberately put me down and all that,
and I should try to take a revenge.”
Among animals this activity is very limited.
I don't think they believe in revenge, except
for a few animals.
They say that if you hurt a snake, it will
take its respite, it will come back on you,
that's what is said.
And this one is something, one quality of
the snake.
But as we have passed through all these different
categories, we might be having some of the
qualities of some of these animals within
us, we may be even snakes anywhere.
If the snake is within us, then anybody who
hurts you, you’ll remember it all your life.
“He has hurt me, so I’ll put him right
one day, I’ll take a revenge!”
If there’s a snake within us.
But now if there's a tiger within you, so
you’ll become very ferocious, at the smallest
thing you'll get angry, lose temper.
Now, this is not a very good situation, that
we are still at the level of animals and our
inheritance is still working in us.
So we have to keep a watch.
We have to be good gurus, and for a good guru,
you have to have a very peaceful, compassionate,
loving temperament.
After all, one has to understand that people
have this inheritance, and some people have
more, or some people have this, or some people
have that.
For that, if you get angry with that person,
it’s not going to help him or help you.
But if you are loving and compassionate and
you explain that person what is the problem
is and what you want to do, I tell you it
will improve, he’ll definitely improve and
he’ll feel your love.
Of course sometimes, sometimes it’s necessary
to also forgive such a person.
Such a person is to be forgiven, absolutely.
In that it doesn’t mean that if he has done
wrongs, all kinds of wrongs, you forgive him
and he goes on still with the same, doesn't
mean that.
“Forgiven” means “forgotten.”
Such and such person has been misbehaving,
so just forget, forget it, completely forget
it.
For a guru it is important, for a Sahaja Yogi
guru.
I must say others gurus were not like that,
they were absolutely, I would say, extremely
hot-tempered, and they used to lose temper
on people.
Once I met a guru and he told Me, “Mother,
You are too kind to them.
And with this kindness You cannot create good
people.
I’ve had enough of it,” he said.
“I had made two people into gurus, and one
of them got lost in the money.”
“All right, what happened to the second?”
“And second one got lost in the women.”
So I said, ”Now it's all right.
If they are lost, they are lost, but if you
can revive them with your love, affection
and kindness, better get around them.”
So the one who was lost… [interruption]
So as a guru, you must conclude that they
are still lingering with their inheritance.
But the second problem is much worse, because
human beings can think.
Of course animals also think, but it is always
conditioning.
Whatever conditioning they have, accordingly
they behave.
But they don't have ego, that kind as human
beings have developed.
So the gurus develop also a very bad ego.
The first ego is, other gurus I have seen,
they told Me that “We have done so much,
we have worked so hard to achieve this state,
and why should we give Realizations to others?”
Or if they have got Realization, then, “What
have they done?
Why should they get Realization?”
It’s become a comparison between their own
state and how they have achieved it, and how
others have to achieve it.
So they make all kinds of different torturing,
troubling maneuvres.
For example, they may make the disciple stand
on his head, give his family up, do this,
do that.
They’ll beat them, they can beat also.
They will make him stay in the water for a
long time, make him stand under, on one feet.
Like this they punish, and the worst comes
to worst, they may beat with sticks or with
stones.
They’re like that.
They don't want to talk, they don't want to
understand what the another person has to
say, or the ones who are seekers, how they
should be treated.
All this anger and all these things might
have been all right before, but after the
advent of Sahaja Yoga you must know it is
not necessary.
It is not at all necessary to give any physical
punishment to your disciples.
Now also the mental punishment to your disciple
should not be given.
Like people start saying all kinds of things
to their disciple; like saying they, I am
saying, say there is a leader, and the leader
finds something wrong with the disciple, then
he goes on saying, “Now you are like this,
your father was like this, your grandfather
was like this, your great- grandfather was
like this, and you are also like this.”
Or some sort of thing that will hurt him.
By hurting a person, you are not going to
help.
Supposing while walking you are hurt, you
can't walk.
In your spiritual ascent also if you are hurt,
you cannot go ahead.
So not to hurt people is very important.
Once you go on hurting others, then you are
not a good guru, you are not a one who is
really being kind and understanding of the
disciple.
In Sahaja Yoga it's a different thing altogether,
because you all have achieved Sahaja Yoga
without doing any kind of penance, any kind
of a guilty consciousness, confessions, anything.
Nothing!
As you are, you got your Realization.
Nobody had to stand on their heads, give up
their husbands, wives, their families, this
thing - nothing of the kind.
As you are, whatever dress you are wearing,
whatever conditions you are, you are given
Realization - it’s a fact.
You don't have to pay for it, you don't have
to exert yourself, don't have to do anything.
Just you get it, sitting down wherever you
are.
After that, this kind of a happening should
prove to you that you have a power of love,
of compassion.
Out of your love you have given Realization.
We never realize that.
Supposing we are anxious to give Realization
to people, we want to go to the villages,
work there and give them Realization.
Why?
Why do we do it?
It is not for any fame, not for any reward
or anything, but just out of the love that
is within your heart that you feel, “Why
am I enjoying everything?
Why others are not enjoying?”
And so you go out of the way to help people
to get their Realization.
Now you have become a greater human being,
and you feel concern.
Others are getting ruined, they are going
on the wrong path, they are doing wrong things;
and that makes you feel very, very upset,
and you want to help them.
And this understanding once you have, then
you will know how to deal with the person
with whom you have to behave like a guru.
Mostly it is not necessary to say anything
harsh to that person.
At the most you can tell the mistakes that
they have committed, but that too in a, such
a soft manner that a person doesn’t get
any shock out of that.
All this thing of attachments also: now somebody
has too much attachment, say, for the family,
for the wife, for the children or someone.
And once they come to Sahaj Yoga, still they
have same amount of attachment.
All right, doesn’t matter.
But how far they will go with that attachment,
how long it will continue is the point.
You should be detached.
If I say, you cannot be; it's a state, it's
a state of mind when you are detached.
But when it comes to doing something for them,
you will go all out to help them.
But you are not a attached person.
Now what is the description of an attached
person?
Attached person is always worried about the
other person, goes on thinking about the other
person, cannot think of Sahaja Yoga, only
think of the people with whom he is attached.
Then he is very sensitive, you can't say anything
to his brother, sister or anyone, otherwise
he jumps.
Attachment is also with the name that he has.
Supposing he has achieved a certain name,
supposing, or some big position, then what
does he do?
You can't challenge him any way, you cannot
by any words you can challenge him, because
he’s so identified with that.
He thinks he’s a big person who has achieved
such a lot of positions in life.
He’s so much attached that he wants also
the guru to pay respect to that attachment.
Now which is the way you can solve that problem?
Supposing somebody is very much attached to
his wife, say for example, then you should
not discuss and argue with that person, not
at all, because he’s still coming up slowly,
slowly up to this stage.
Such a person is not absolutely a perfect
Sahaja Yogi.
So what do you have to do?
If he’s attached to his wife, let it be.
But the Divine will work it out, and he will
realize that what he has been thinking, doing
and taking decisions is all wrong.
And once he discovered it himself, then he
will get detached.
But if you go on telling him anything and
try to argue it out, it will never work out.
So you must understand that as human beings,
whatever we were, also as Sahaja Yogis, we
have problems.
And these should be slowly, slowly should
be dissolved; not by argument, not by saying
things, but by love and compassion.
If you have love for a person, you will be
amazed, ninety-nine percent people value love.
This is the third quality of human beings,
I should say.
First is his inheritance, second is, he thinks,
and thirdly that he values love.
Anybody who loves, the another person values
that love, because he thinks that “This
particular person is loving me; not my wealth,
not my beauty, not my this thing, but he is
loving me.”
And this idea of love, this is something that
will get him completely detached from that
person, easily.
How?
Now it looks very funny that if you like somebody,
if you love somebody, and then you should
get detached.
It’s only possible in Sahaja Yoga.
In Sahaja Yoga your state of mind is such
that you are absolutely detached and absolutely
attached.
How?
For example now, say I have My daughter, so
I’m detached, I never telephone to her,
I am never bothered about her; because in
Sahaja Yoga, you know how is that person.
If the vibrations are right, why should you
telephone?
Why should you talk to her?
Why should you ask for anything?
No need.
Only on vibrations you'll know how the person
is.
And so it will seem that you are absolutely
detached.
But when you will find the vibrations are
showing or are indicating something serious
about that person, what you will do, you'll
put full attention to that, full attention.
You put attention, but not attachment.
So the attachment doesn’t solve the problem.
What solves the problem is attention.
But when you are not detached, then your attention
is attached attention.
It's an attention that is not available to
everyone, an attention that gets stuck, absolutely
stuck into that person with whom you are identified.
Try to understand.
So to be identified with someone is not actually,
what we can say, paying attention to that
person.
And then your attention will work.
If you are of that level, whenever you put
attention to that particular person who needs
your attention, it will work.
But if you are all the time wasting your attention
on a person because you’re attached to that
person, your attention will be tired, it won't
work out.
It's a big, I should say, a paradox, that
if you are attached to someone, then your
attention doesn’t work.
And if you are not attached to that person…
You do everything else: now you have to give
lecture, all right, I’m giving lecture;
then I have to do some cooking, I'll do cooking;
this, that, that and that.
But all the time if you are thinking about
that person, all the time you want to have
connection with that person - it’s not necessary.
That person is all right.
What is there to be so much worried about
that person?
After all, you have to do Sahaja Yoga, you
have to do so many things, you have to raise
Kundalini of so many.
Now you are getting attached to one person
somewhere, it's not a very good thing.
By that kind of attachment your attention
also becomes useless, absolutely useless.
So let the attention be free.
Attention should not be bound by your attachments.
Attention should be absolutely free, so it
works automatically, automatically, and you
will be amazed, even if you do not pay attention,
the attention will work it.
It is such a big thing to have this spiritual
attention, which is nothing but love.
It will just act.
You'll be amazed how it acts.
It's another world I am talking about, not
this mundane world but something higher, where
your attention works, and works so beautifully
that you are amazed how it has worked.
But you should not bound it by your attachments.
If it is bound you can have a very limited
sphere, only the people who are attached to
you, or you are attached to those persons.
That's why identification is not the way a
guru should work it out.
Now there are ten disciples and one guru,
and the guru likes only one.
He thinks this is he is the best, and he should
be encouraged and he should be given all the
possible help.
But that’s not going to help.
But on the contrary, he should say, “This
is already a good fellow.
He has risen already very high, he has gone
very deep.”
So pay attention to those who are not so good,
and talk to them about it that “You have
to come up,” in a very sweet manner.
You have to talk to these other people who
are not yet there, or who are still struggling.
You have to understand them.
You have to notice, what are they doing?
Why is it they are not improving or rising
in their attention?
What is the problem, why the Divine is not
flowing through them?
And you'll find the reason for this is that
people do not have good attention, is because
it is focused on someone all the time.
They feel that this is their responsibility,
that it should be focused.
It's just to give, it's an explanation, it's
just a explanation to say that “You see,
naturally I have to be worried about this,
and worried about that.”
It's just an explanation.
But if you really don't fix your attention
to one person or ten persons only, then your
attention looks after the whole world.
It receives all the information, and also
it gives all the information what is to be
done to correct the situation.
So one has to rise into that state where you
do not get angry, annoyed, upset - no, not
at all.
What happens to you, that you see a situation,
and in that you are not involved.
You see the situation and you are away from
it.
Then you can solve that problem better.
But if you are part and parcel of that problem,
then you cannot solve.
It's like this I was telling, that those who
are fighting, say, cannot solve the problem,
but a person who is not fighting can solve
the problem.
So it’s a very simple thing to understand
that if you are identified, if you are involved
with one person or with one kind of a thing,
then you are lost.
So our attention has to be always free and
can be applied widely, wherever needed.
That is the state one has to reach.
If you reach that state of mind, it's not
I am saying you can do anything about it,
it’s just a state of mind.
Now, how do we do that?
Only through introspection.
Through introspection you will understand
that you need help to solve your problems.
Firstly the problem is how to face yourself,
because you are a little bit shy or maybe
nervous about it.
As the time comes, you'd be amazed that this
nervousness has no meaning at all.
When you try to be deliberate about it, then
it won't work out; but if you are Sahaja,
it will work out.
So we come to the second point, apart from
the attention, that we should leave everything
into the hands of Paramchaitanya.
Let the Paramchaitanya solve the problem.
“This is the problem?
Let Paramchaitanya solve the problem.
We are not bothered.”
So a detachment comes in.
You give the whole thing to Paramchaitanya
to solve, so you are not in it, you are away
from it.
Very, very simple things are there, that if
you understand that we suffer, because everybody
feels responsible for us.
Everybody thinks they are responsible, they
have to do this responsibility for us, somebody
says this responsibility he has to do.
All these things are worrying them, and that
is the reason today we have a very complex
society.
They are suffering from all kinds of diseases
in which only thinking is responsible.
By this thinking all the time, thinking about
one person, thinking about one problem, you
reach nowhere.
At that moment, what you have to do is to
leave it to the Paramchaitanya.
If it goes to the Paramchaitanya, It will
manage, It will solve the problem.
Now I will tell you one thing, an experience.
This time I was in America.
I wanted to have a puja there.
So I said, "All right, let them come for the
puja.
It's nice if they want to come."
Then they told Me that "Mother, we want to
bring presents for You for the puja.
So how can we bring the presents?"
I said, "It's very simple.
Don't bring!"
But they wouldn't listen to that.
They said, "We'll have to bring, and the Customs
will trouble us and do this and do that."
So there was only one building ahead was,
there was another building where they were
having a liquidation sale.
I said, "This is something nice!
One can have a look at it."
So I went in and I found things so cheap,
unbelievable, very, very expensive things
for throw-away prices.
I was amazed how it is there.
So I told them, "I can purchase all these
things.
I'll pay you, but you bring all these things
to Canajoharie."
They agreed, “All right, we’ll bring this
to Canajoharie.”
And they brought all the things all packed
nicely and gave it to Sahaja Yogis.
We had no problem of Customs or anything;
I paid them there.
How, you see, things can be improved by understanding
what is the most important thing: is to love.
But love is truth, and truth is love.
If you have love for somebody, genuine love,
then anything you want to do with that person
will be absolutely obvious, because it will
be truthful.
Anything you say to such a person will be
absolutely obvious, clear-cut, because it
is absolutely truthful.
So when you are dealing with somebody also,
you should be extremely truthful.
Of course, you need not say things that will
hurt him, but you must use such ways and methods
that will not in any way hurt the other person,
which will have an effect on that person.
So this kind of a gurus we need now very much
in Sahaja Yoga, because by Sahaja Yoga has
spread a lot.
So first of all, our temper has to be brought
into proper shape.
A guru has no business, I mean the Sahaja
Yogi guru has no business to lose temper at
all, on any point whatsoever.
If they can really do that much, it will save
our, I mean, so much of worry, so much of
problem, so much of mess we create.
All this can be solved very easily.
But first we must have pure love in our heart,
not love out of some gain or out of some sort
of reward, but pure love if we have, then
we can work it out very easily, anything that
you want to do.
This is a very lengthy thing which can go
on forever.
Because, after all, the gurus have to know
what are their duties and why they are gurus,
it’s very important, very important position
that they are gurus.
And they should use that position for exhibiting
tremendous understanding of their disciple,
and also their purpose should be clear-cut.
People should not doubt him, should not think,
why he is doing such and such things?
It should not be a mystery, it should be absolutely
clear-cut.
All these things I am telling you today, because
today we have completed ten, our ten years
of stay in Cabella.
Cabella has been extremely kind to Me.
They have brought lots of people to Sahaja
Yoga, I tell you, very lots of people.
It is a very far-fetched place, everybody
discarded it and said, "Where are You going
to live?" and all that.
But here only it has worked, and that should
be accepted as a very good indication that
Sahaja Yoga does miraculous things, miraculous.
But the foremost thing is, you must know vibrations.
If you don't know about vibrations, then you
can't do it.
For example, when I first came to Cabella,
everybody told Me, “Mother, very lonely
place, there are mafias around.
Only six, seven houses there.
Where are You going?
What is this?”
They all warned Me.
So I came here, and immediately I told the
Mayor, “I am going to buy it, and tomorrow
I'll pay you the money.”
He was surprised: how can I do that?
I said, "Don't worry!
Perfectly all right."
On vibrations it was.
On vibrations I decided that this is a wonderful
place.
And vibrations helped Me so much that time,
though everybody discouraged Me and everybody
gave Me a very big picture, horrible one.
But still, where is the mafia now?
Gone, finished.
Now, to know about a thing, you have to meditate
and improve your vision, which should be clear-cut.
It should not be something, a vision which
is reflecting your particular ideas about
a particular thing, but it should be a vision
which should be clear-cut.
With Sahaja Yoga, one has to know the protection
of the Goddess is on top of your head.
Nothing can go wrong with you, nothing will
happen to you, it will all work out.
I am sure you will get yourself this experience.
You see, talking about Sahaja Yoga like this
you just get meditative, you just get meditative,
and you feel that one day all of you should
become like that - just meditative.
And this meditative temperament or whatever
is the state, emits vibrations.
It emits and creates path for you, for your
work, for your life, for everything.
You don't have to struggle with anyone, you
don't have to fight with anyone, you don't
have to argue with anyone.
Just try to meditate, and achieve a state
which I’m describing to you, where you get
completely surrounded by love and affection.
May God bless you all.
There's one thing is important to understand,
that you should not go to extremes of everything,
which is also a human quality.
For example, if they are rational, they go
on rationalizing everything, “I can't do
this, I can't do that.”
Something like that goes on.
The second part of it is that they become
very emotional, and they become so emotional
that they start doing wrong things in the
name of emotionality.
You have to overcome these two things.
If you have not overcome that, what's the
use?
What’s the use of calling yourself Sahaja
Yogis?
Minimum of minimum, this much you must do.
Going to the extremes must be avoided.
Keep a watch upon yourself.
If you are going to the extremes, nothing
will work out; you might develop cancer, may
develop horrible diseases on one side.
And on the other side you might become a very
rational person, and no Sahaja Yoga will enter
your head.
So you have to keep the balance all the time.
And with that balance, like somebody is a
Sahaja Yogini and she has done something very
wrong, then you should not become emotionally
attached, “Oh, Mother, what is it?
And we should forgive her.”
No!
You tell her that “You must improve your
vibrations, and must come to a balance.
And once you are in balance, then I will consider
your case.
Then I will say it is so or not.”
But if she has no balance, she goes into rationality,
she goes into emotional thing, and this emotional
business can take you to any nonsensical thing,
as it is a psychological case.
And one can go into very, very wrong things
that they are doing, out of this emotional
thing, you see, like even singing songs that
are neurotic or anything, you see.
All this emotional thing can take you anywhere.
So to be emotional is not needed.
You must love.
And left side is what you can call another
extreme.
One side is, is this emotional, another is
rational.
In rationality you can start justifying anything,
like Hitler did.
He said, “No, this was right, I was doing
was right.”
He took something into his head and now, “This
is right.”
This is rationality.
So both things are to be properly balanced,
and you should see that whatever you are doing
are giving you a proper result.
So thank you very much again and again.
May God bless you.