[Music]
all right
[Applause]
okay
so
thank you
is
[Music]
but you have to
whatever i am
we have had lots of problems in
blind
[Music]
is
starts when
[Music]
but it exists my
resistance i'm very happy to see
so many people here in brazil
in rio who are seeking
[Music]
i would like to tell you
the first thing is
[Music]
foreign
is
[Music]
unless and until you become the spirit
you are going to be there is
[Music]
example
system
[Music]
so
come on
so you can ask who is this
in the same way i have to tell you
that very unfamiliar power
of divine love the member former
individual says
[Music]
which is satellite
and we have come from this
[Music]
we live
absolutely
[Music]
this is what has happened so far
that everybody thinks that this is the
truth another one
this is the truth and therefore
[Music]
is
about moses about christ
[Music]
but once you know the absolute truth
then you realize
that all these religions came on this
earth
[Music]
foreign
is
we have been already described about
the subtle system
[Music]
that works
she has taken all that
you have aspired all that
was your pasta
[Music]
is
now the problem is
that you have to
understand that what life we are having
today
is extremely chaotic
[Music]
you don't know about anyone
so i was telling you about the second
truth that there's an
all-purpose of divine love
though islam
[Music]
there
works out
[Music]
so when this power rises within us into
six centers
it pierces through our own area
[Music]
foreign
you know about yourself
[Music]
there
your awareness it's a new dimension that
you can feel the centers
[Music]
then
i'm
[Music]
so you get rid of your
india we have got four doctors now
who
[Music]
foreign
that's all your problems
[Music]
is
foreign
[Music]
uh
because their lifestyle is absolutely
[Music]
global transformation
is
[Music]
as well
is
[Music]
your attention
you can solve the
[Music]
of god is extremely alert
there is no
who is
[Music]
and you will know whether you want that
truth
or not he was
there are so many people
[Music]
experience
nobody
i've already told you that i cannot
force
[Music]
if
i've already told you it is your own
power
i there's no
[Music]
obligation
thousand
there are many simple three conditions
is this the praise for the source no to
save this
the first one is that
all of you have to be very confident
you must forgive yourself
[Music]
all-pervading power is the
ocean of forgiveness
foreign
[Music]
this
progress
[Music]
but if you don't forgive then
because foreign
[Music]
foreign
sells uh
as we know we have
[Music]
this is to signify that
and also to promise that once you can be
growing
[Music]
now if you ignore
of pure divine
[Music]
now
now you have to take your right hand
on top of your foreign
[Music]
is
you have to ask forgiveness
[Music]
foreign
by
[Music]
foreign
now
on your
[Music]
is
close your eyes and please don't open
them
don't close them very tight
not available
so you have to ask a very phenomenal
[Music]
with spirit
i have told you that when you become the
spirit
you become your guide your master
[Music]
so now please take your right hand
is
[Music]
i have to tell you that i cannot force
the divine your knowledge on you
you have to ask for it
foreign
[Music]
six times
please give me your divine knowledge
this time the prophet
[Music]
says
as soon as you ask for
your important knowledge
this power of kundalini starts right
my
all right so now with your
self-confidence we have to nourish
with upper sectors
superior
[Music]
here
are feeling dangerous my
ill soul to your problems
at the very outset i told you that you
are not responding this mind
this interest these emotions
this ego and your
conditioning but you are a pure spirit
[Music]
foreign
this all-pervading power
of the mind love is the ocean
of knowledge and ocean
of
[Music]
whatever mistakes you have committed
so
[Music]
now
i've already told you that whether
[Music]
but if you don't forgive then you play
into wrong hands
at this moment it's very important that
you forgive
everywhere
[Music]
this is the most important time of your
life and please
don't kiss yourself like nation by not
forgiving
your moment
you know
foreign
not how many times but from your heart
[Music]
i forgive everyone in general
they will go up to others in general
just for your satisfaction
[Music]
so now please take your right hand and
the back side of your head
and to scratch your head as far as
[Music]
possible
please forgive me
you the last center is very important
and that's how you get the actualization
of your background
[Music]
is
please
[Music]
is
you have to now open your eyes
and
foreign
[Music]
if
foreign
[Music]
so where
vibrations coming out of here
[Music]
is
one of the questions
[Music]
is
question
[Music]
is
foreign
[Music]
a
and for that you have to come over
center
where we have very cool
[Music]
me
but you must
[Music]
foreign
foreign programs
[Applause]
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
my
[Music]
[Applause]
um
[Music]
[Applause]
why
[Music]
okay
you