Sahaja Culture and Ego
New Jersey Ashram, USA
October 26, 1985
Today I was thinking of talking, telling you
about the Sahaja Culture.
Now we are formed in dharma, Vishwa Dharma.
But it must have a culture. So far in all
the religions there is no combination of religion
and culture. No religion has. That's why everywhere
you find different cultures. Say in India,
people who follow Hindu religion have different
cultures in different places. They are living
in Lucknow, or say in U.P., they have a Muslim
culture. More Islamic style. They'll eat in
one plate, do all kinds of things which normally
a South Indian won't do, and the South Indians
have a different culture from Maharashtrians.
So even in a religion like Hindu religion
where culture is important, very important,
we find varieties. So the cultures get influenced
by the neighboring cultures or surrounding
cultures, and that's how people get lost.
When you establish a religion like this, Vishwa
Dharma, it's not like any other religion.
It's the real religion within us, and this
reality comes to us because now we are one
with the Spirit. So when we talk of Sahaja
Culture, it is the culture of the Spirit.
Now what is a culture? First of all let us
see what is a culture is. So the culture is
the pattern of behavior we have with others.
Is a common pattern of behavior we are supposed
to have with others. Like in English language,
for example, we'll say "Thank you". Even if
somebody murders, you may say, "Thank you".
Or the person who murders you can say, "Sorry".
On the phone one may say, just if they say
something you can't hear, "Sorry?" Every time,
"Sorry". As if "sorry" is a word so easily
to be used. I mean if you are sorry, why are
you sorry for that? "Sorry?" On the phone
they used to first say, "I beg your pardon?",
was sensible; but now I find everybody, A
to Z, says, "Sorry?" I mean, it has no meaning,
because what are you sorry about? Says "Sorry?"
For everything they are sorry. Or we can say
in English language, when we speak, "I'm afraid".
You see, it's very common, "I'm afraid". What
are you afraid of? The whole world is afraid
of you.
So this is the culture, what we talk of, any
culture as such, becomes artificial, is not
spontaneous, doesn't come from reality. It
has no meaning; sometimes it is pointless,
absolutely pointless to stick to certain cultures.
So the culture of the Spirit doesn't change.
It's universal, and is higher than any other
culture. Apart from that it integrates all
the essences of all the cultures.
So
it emanates from the spirit. Now, spirit has
two sides. One side which you see, the another
you don't see, like the moon. The side you
see is outside with other people, other Sahaja
Yogis, other people, other societies, which
are not yourself, absolutely. The other side
you don't see is the relationship with God
Almighty, relationship with your Mother. If
the other side is not all right, the behavioral
side outside could become artificial, could
become crooked and not Sahaj. So it's the
other way round than any other culture. To
know any other culture what do we go? We see
how they talk, what is their language, how
they speak, how they behave: all the outside
things we get. We must know "thank you" if
we want to know English language, must know
"thank you", "please", all that. But if you
want to know the Sahaja culture, you have
to know your Mother, and you have to know
God Almighty. And the relationship between
your Mother and the God Almighty has to be
absolutely perfect. Then there's no problem.
But that, the relationship, if it is not all
right, you cannot have artificial Sahaj culture.
That is one thing for sure. Artificial Sahaj
culture is not all right. I would say that
India has, in its basics, the culture of the
spirit, India has; because for traditions
and traditions in India, and for ages, people
have been seeking the truth. Spiritually they
are endowed, because of the saints. They are
blessed specially because they have been seekers,
not of material things, but of the spirit.
Specially in Maharashtra, we should say, because
the Kundalini is there always like a magnet.
People are attracted because Shri Ganesha
being the magnet, attracted towards God and
spirit. So they form a pattern, but there
is lot of artificiality in that also has grown.
We must admit that there is lot, lot of artificiality,
falsehood, nonsense that has grown into it,
because the religion fell into the hands of,
spiritual religion fell into the hands of
gross, horrible so-called Brahmins who were
not realized souls. So the whole culture has
become so nonsensical sometimes that you don't
know where to look.
But to have the culture, first of all, culture
is developed through meditation, by facing
yourself. First of all you should face yourself,
how you feel about your Mother and about God
Almighty. First of all, how much liberty you
take of your Mother? How much granted, take
for granted your Mother? She's a Mahamaya.
Even the first "M" is difficult to understand.
So when you start taking liberties, all the
time putting your pressure on Her, all the
time trying to attract Her attention, Her
time, or writing letters eleven pages, all
that, is one side. Another side is complete
indifference to your Mother. So it is to be
known through your heart. You don't have to
talk to Me. I know whose heart is pulsating.
Perhaps I'm the only person who knows really
what you are. You may not be knowing yourself
also. I may not say, but I know you in all
details, out of which I may say little bit,
because I am too gentle to say things. Because
again of Sahaj culture. Because of Sahaj culture,
I cannot say everything to you on your face.
I'm correcting it, trying to correct it, correct
it; if not possible, then I say to you. Then
in that you have to also see how much worshipful
you are. Some people, though they spend more
time with Me, remain with Me, want to be with
Me, it is only when they feel surrendered,
also. So it should not be confused: if somebody
is spending more time with Me, you should
not condemn yourself for that. It's all right.
But how far you are surrendered is the point.
Now, if you are surrendered, how do you see
the surrendering in a person? You see it has
one side and the another is the expression.
Say a person who is surrendered doesn't talk
much to Me, doesn't talk, he listens, doesn't
talk. Common sense, he listens. Even people
who are very good, I've seen when I'm talking,
they'll put in their own words in between.
People who are very good, I should say. So
the surrendering is not full. Then the time,
they become very conscious of the time. Who
has made the time? But the person won't come
directly and tell Me, but tell somebody else,
"Go and tell Mother, She has to go at this
time." I know everything, who tells whom,
who goes to whom, who is telling someone,
who is time-bound. And then I flout it. I
know what time to reach, what is the auspicious
time, how it will work out.
Surrendering has to be to that point, that
you shouldn't worry. I would say Dumahl is
one of them who is a very great surrendered
fellow. When I went there I was very tired,
and he said. "Mother, if You want to rest
You can rest."
I said, "Yes, I want to rest."
So he just left Me alone. I was really very
tired because I had a very long journey, and
then this and that, and then I went down all
the way there. I thought, "I'll lie down,
and sleep off. " Of course, as I know that
everything has to be done at right time, I
just went down. And we had a program of My
reception at one place in a village, and they
were all waiting for Me there. And I was sleeping;
he wouldn't wake Me up. He wouldn't wake Me
up. He said, "Everything will be all right.
Tell them when Mother will come." So there
was sun on, they were all sitting under the
tree, sun was scorchingly hot. They were nicely
having a nice nap under the tree and all that.
All the villagers arrived, everybody arrived,
everything worked out. And when I got up it
was about five-thirty, then he told Me that,
"Mother, I didn't tell You the program." He
never tells Me. If I get something written,
well and good, but, "You were sleeping, I
didn't want to disturb You."
"What's the program?"
"It was at three o'clock."
I said, "Three o'clock. Why didn't you tell
Me? Why didn't you wake Me?"
He said, "You were awake, I knew You were
awake, Mother. It's all right."
So we started off at six o'clock. Sun had
gone down. By that time they arranged beautiful
lights and fireworks and everything, and all
the rushing about was finished, they're very
well settled. And the people from distant
villages had also arrived, and they had organized
them so well, and they had a proper time,
and are very happy that I came late because
sun was not there, so scorchingly hot. By
the time we reached about seven o'clock it
was night and they illumined the lights, and
the diwali like this was put up everywhere,
and they got everything, they had sufficient
time to do everything. Then Dumahl said, "I
knew, Mother, You are awake, and You were
managing."
If one can understand that, then you will
not try to organize Me. You can just tell
Me, "We have to leave at this time." But if
I don't have to leave, I will not leave whatever
you may do. In My own sweet way; you will
never find Me obstinate, but I am. Because
I know what is right is what is right, and
has to be done that way. But otherwise I'm
very calm, I am not bothered. I never organize
you, I never hurry you, I never do anything
that should upset you. Spirit is never upset,
never excited, never hurries, and never is
what you call that "go-go" business. Like
now, we have to go to the airport. You'll
find everybody was like an aeroplane - round,
round, round, round. What has happened?
"Oh, we had to go? We'd.."
"We have to go, all right. So what?"
The whole thing is, all these excitements
and all these things come to us because we
are outside. But if you are one with your
spirit you're absolutely calm, absolutely
calm, "All right, we have to go, all right,
we'll reach there. Doesn't matter." The other
day we had to go for some shopping, I was
trying to buy some saris for Indian ladies.
We got lost. I never bothered them at all.
They were going round and round, and round
and round. And then Danny realized and said,
"I think perhaps we had to leave vibrations
in all these places."
I said, "Correct."
And for about two hours I think, we were roaming
about. Anybody else would be saying, "What's
this? You can't find the place, what's the
matter with you?” Calm. We reached the shop
at the right time, got everything at the right
time, did everything, came back at right time.
Everything was first class, nothing went wrong.
But anybody in My place, I tell you, that
time would have been, "Oh God, this, that."
Why are you saving time? For what are you
saving time?
So we miss the present, and that's one thing
spirit never misses. It's always in the present.
That's the reality. Now in the West people
are very futuristic, extremely futuristic,
and their futuristicness sometimes takes them
to points, say for example if they have to
go by train. So instead of arriving at the
right station, they'll go to the station which
is further on. And then again they'll arrive
at the further on. The train will never reach
them. Sort of temperament they have. So one
should not plan at all anything like that,
that fixes you. But at this moment, if I have
to be told that we have to go at this time,
is all right, finished now. At this moment
I've told, is recorded, finished. All right?
So it's gone into the memory. There's nothing
to worry about it now. Now, present moment,
what are we doing? In a very calm way, witness
it. Witness yourself, now, witness yourself.
"Where is my mind going?" Now somebody who
has to cook must be thinking, "Oh, I have
to get this, I have to get that." Once you
start saying that "I have to do it", you'll
never be able to do it that way. But you said,
"All right, just now I'm in meditation." Every
moment, "I am in meditation." Everything will
walk up to you, even matter, and you'll get
the right things at the right place. You'll
meet right people at the right place. The
other day we were just walking, strolling
around. Whom do we find there? Carolyn. She
just walked out. There is she, I mean I met
her. She said, "Christine is just next door."
I said, "Let's go," and you should have seen
the joy on her face when she came down, and
she saw Me. Beautiful experience for Me and
her, she was so happy. Then we went together.
So when you have so much tied down with your
watch, that means you are not tied down with
your spirit. So a Sahaja yogi, if he sees
watch, then he's not a Sahaja yogi. But the
other side could be that the Sahaja yogis
are never in time where they have to be. Very
common in England. I reach always first, to
open the door. And to clean it also sometimes.
Now, to take for granted things, as you say,
take for granted, that's not the way Sahaja
Yoga is. You have to be alert, alert, absolutely
alert. If you are alert, immediately you'll
know "I have to go now at this time. I have
to do it. I have to get this thing now." If
you have to miss something, you are supposed
to miss it. That's what it is. So, there's
a beautiful thing written down, like they
say, "Jai sei rakhahu tase hi rahun" - "The
way You keep me, the way I am, will be happy."
So, satisfaction towards yourself, your spirit,
is important. Because ego will plan out, "Oh,
we'll go there, we must get for Mother, say,
daisies", we decide. "Must get daisies." You
don't find daisies, you're disappointed. Why
not? These are all My flowers, whether they
are daisies or not, they look so nice. Whatever
you get, you get it. That's the thing wanted.
You know that, that the Divine is working
out everything for you. When you are supposed
to get something else, better have it. Even
by mistake, if I lay My hand upon some things,
like a book or something, immediately I'll
open it out and see why this book has come
in My attention; why this fellow has come
in My attention; why this is happening. And
immediately I find that there’s some connection,
something has to be done, something has to
be said, something has to be worked out.
So for a person who is imbibed with the culture
of spirit, the Sahaj culture, impresses others
by his calmness and relaxed attitude. Relaxation
never means lethargy, by any chance. It doesn't
mean lethargy. Lethargy is against relaxation.
A person who is relaxed cannot become lethargic.
"Relaxed" means a person who’s alert and
calm. These two things for human beings is
an impossibility, because if they are alert,
if they are alert then they're not calm. If
they're unhappy, sad, then they think they
are very, very calm. So this is one of the
things one has to remember, that you have
to witness yourself all the time. Not to condemn
yourself, but witness. Now I said the word
"witness" means "detached". Now what happens
with this, when you start condemning yourself,
you miss every good point. For example, you
have some experience of a sudden height being
achieved. All right? At that point you should
catch hold of it, hold on to it, keep doing,
but don't forget that you may go back, no.
And then wait for another higher moment to
come, hold on to it. That's how you climb
Himalayas. But not that, "Oh Ma. Now it's
all right, but what will happen next?" Then
you are gone down, because you have to face
yourself in the way, knowing what are your
powers. You are a spirit now, you are no more
an ordinary human being, so you have no business
to condemn yourself, or to degrade yourself,
or in any way to feel unhappy. No way. Past
is past. What happened a moment before is
finished. "Now I am going to rise. Now I am
going to rise."
So a person who has a Sahaja culture is not
only spontaneous, but is inspired, is a inspired
personality. A person who is of that kind,
an inspired visionary, then other people get
impressed by such a person that, "See, there's
a man who's inspired, who talks in an inspired
way, in a way that is something very different
from others." Something new he says, new that
is nourishing. Such a personality - like the
other day, you see, we heard the lectures
of so many people, and when the New Zealand
Prime Minister was coming C.P. said, "Now
let's go back, because we'll have a little
tea or something."
I said: "No, you listen to this man. He's
a realized soul."
He said, "Really?"
I said, "Yes, you listen to him."
First everybody was, "He's sitting in New
Zealand, such a little titwit of a country,
what is he going to speak?" You see, they
were moving about, making a… Within two
minutes he captured everybody's attention,
you see, and he was bubbling with everything,
so beautifully, and he spoke all the points
so much different, and so much new and so
much better. C.P. was amazed. He said, "How
do You know?"
I said, "I know, because when I was in New
Zealand I told them he's a realized soul."
And our own Prime Minister is also a realized
soul. You'll be surprised, after our Prime
Minister finished his lecture and all that,
after two or three lectures he was to go;
then he turned round and went to this Australian
[Shri Mataji may have meant New Zealand] Prime
Minister, only him, went and congratulated
him, congratulated him. Congratulated and
said something very close to him. And the
fellow again, you see, flew up into joy. We
see it's all there. And then he came away.
Why? Because one realized soul understands
another realized soul, and everybody was amazed:
why did he turn to this man alone, and went
and congratulated him? So such a large country
like India represented by our Prime Minister,
goes down all the way to a little country
like New Zealand which is nothing compared
to India, and congratulates. And that's a
developed country, this is a developing country.
Is something people did not understand. And
the whole joyous atmosphere both of them shaking
hands created. This is Sahaja culture, in
which you recognize a realized soul, the dignity
of a realized soul.
So when it comes to relating to others, first
and foremost are Sahaja yogis. But I've seen
most of the people are more congenial with
others, and less congenial with Sahaja yogis.
They try to criticize Sahaja yogis all the
time, and I test them. I sometimes say, "All
right. I don't think this fellow is very good"
and all that. But when the other person turns
round and shows compassion and says, "No,
Mother, I think it will work out" then I like
it. I like that. Or else sometimes I say,
"Oh, let them go away. There should be no
more food for them, it's all right." No, Mother,
we've made food for them." So the culture
of Sahaj is to give. Give, and give, and give,
and never ask for a reward. Never thinks,
"What I have to get". After all, you have
got the highest that anybody could get. They
said the three heights a human being can achieve
in spirituality, which you all got in no time.
It's called as salokya, samipya, sanidya.
Salokya is that you should be able to see
God. That you got. Samipya is the closeness
with God. Sanidya is the togetherness, togetherness.
You have got all these three. In one incarnation
you've got it. When Gods incarnated before,
nobody knew that they were Gods. So even they
got it, they never knew. Very few people knew
about them. But even when Christ said He was
the Son of God, who, how many believed Him?
They crucified Him. Because they were not
realized souls. But by giving you realization
I have given you that capacity to get all
these three blessings at one shot. I speak
your language, I speak your style, I live
with your style, and you understand Me. There
is no problem. But with other Gods, imagine
if I were Mahakali today, what would have
happened. You would be all upside-down there
hanging, seeing Me from the other way round.
I don't know what would have happened - or
any one of them.
So the three blessings that a saint is promised,
you've got all of them. But because you've
got them, you don't understand. You take it
for granted. There's no shraddha. With this
experience there should be tremendous faith.
Faith is a thing that resides between Me and
you, in between. Is we can say, the ocean
of joy that is in between. Whatever I emit
to you is that shraddha, and when you are
drenched into it, the joy of that shraddha
makes everything so sahaj. But for that you
must open your hearts. A Sahaja yogi who is
secretive, who is insular, who is jealous,
who separates himself from others is no good.
Open your heart. Give away your things, doesn't
matter. Matter has only one value, that it
can communicate your Sahaj culture. Little
things, you see, I see something that you
have got beautiful, and in My Mahamaya acting
on Myself I say, "Oh, that's very beautiful."
and then they say, "Mother, You gave us this."
"Ah, sorry."
And then I feel very ashamed of Myself, that
this is not Sahaj culture, you see. But the
joy is so much that I can't help it sometimes
I say, "Oh, I - it's so beautiful, this one."
"You gave us, Mother." And the whole rapport
and the whole feeling; I feeling a little
shy about it, and all, they're so beautiful,
so dramatic; so dramatic it is, so poetic.
Only at that point I feel ashamed of Myself.
Of course to be human being you should be
ashamed of yourself sometimes. Otherwise the
drama is not complete. So the whole thing
is so beautiful and so joyous. But that gentleness
towards others and yourself should be there.
Now if you become unhappy and serious, you
are very unkind to yourself and to others.
Anybody who is a serious person, sits with
a serious face, know that he is not a Sahaja
yogi at all. They should be bubbling with
laughter, joy all the time. I cannot be serious
for more than, I think, five seconds perhaps.
I don't know. I try, because lectures should
be serious to go into the hearts of the people.
But there's not, and you can see that even
when I'm getting angry, My eyes betray Me,
and there's a twinkle of laughter in the eyes.
That's how a person should be, and don't worry
what others have to say. You see, the culture
where people are just glum like this, is the
same as the people where they are frivolous.
Now as we can say American culture is to be
frivolous, stupid, you see, I won't be surprised
supposing your Prime Minister tomorrow starts
wearing a sari, just to amuse you. Anything
is possible with them, just to amuse you,
you see, too - for cheap popularity. Anything
frivolous, stupid, they will do. But supposing,
you see, it is say an English old conservative
personality, then a lady might wear a very
official dress with the lines and this and
that, and like a man she might become very
soon, like that, develop a very serious face.
But both things are nonsensical, has no meaning.
You have to be natural, and natural everything
is always bubbling with joy. And a message.
And a message. These flowers are the message
of My coming, writ large on them.
So a person who is a Sahaj culture man should
emit that message to others, people should
see, "Oh, this is the man. He is the sahaja
fellow." You can see that clearly. There's
no seriousness, there's no unhappiness, nothing.
Supposing I have said something that might
be upsetting you, forget it. If you cannot
forget that, then you have not listened to
Me. But "forget" doesn't mean that you do
not act upon it. "Acting upon it" means that
you face yourself and see for yourself how
you have ascended and how far you have to
go, not how you'll fall down. So it is all
the time acting on both sides, as I'm telling
you in My lecture, that on one side you'll
see to yourself as relationship with Me, and
relationship with others. For a Sahaja yogi
it should not matter whether you are in a
palace or on the street.
The first encounter with the first Sahaja
yogis - we have only one surviving, now here
sitting down - they couldn't bear, for them
it was difficult to be in the beautiful atmosphere
of India. The reason is, they were analyzing:
they have no good bathrooms, no showers. But
you have the whole sky. You have all the mountains.
You have all the trees. You have got all the
waters flowing. But you want to have a little
shower, in which you can't even move. Just
an idea, just an idea of comfort. You have
no comforts, if you ask Me, compared to what
we have in India. No comforts at all. I mean,
ask any Indian girl to come and stay, she
will cry. Even I think here the President,
the President has to wash his utensils perhaps,
maybe. What a comfort. There's no division
of labor. Now in our country we have servants,
but "servants" doesn't mean that we cheat
them anything else. They eat the same food
as we eat. They live the same way we live.
But they do different type of work, because
they don't have the same mental capacity to
be the President. The President does some
other work. You have no comfort of any kind,
you take it from Me. Food matter, you get
everything processed food. Imagine, any time
you might be developing cancer due to processed
food. What is your speciality then? Try to
understand. What is the kind of food: it's
not fresh, God knows how it is processed,
how it is preserved, from where it is coming.
Suddenly in London they said that, "Don't
eat this kind of food," you see, "because
it has got something contaminated." So everybody
rushes, you see, to the store room, because
we have to store up all these things. You
can't get at the right…. "Oh it's there";
then you start throwing them out. It's a mad
racing because people think that, "God knows
what we are eating today, is it correct or
not?" So food-wise you are zero. Best thing
is to live in the villages or in the forests,
to get the fresh fruits, wash them in clean
flowing water of a river, eat it nicely and
sit down enjoying the sun.
The comfort of the spirit is the thing we
have lost, and those who seek the comfort
of the spirit are Sahaja yogis, not otherwise.
Comfort of the spirit comes in giving. Say
I've borrowed some money from you, I won't
be comfortable till I've paid you back. Going
further with it, supposing you are caught
up into something, you have got some problems.
I'll somehow or other manage that you'll come
close to Me somewhere, and work it out on
you, clear you out, finished. Till then I
won't be comfortable; though I'll suffer,
I'll have pains, I'll have this, that. As
soon as I came here, left Nabhi was like this
going on. Corrected it. I took it upon Myself,
I sucked it into Me. So they are adventurous.
"Oh I will not touch, I am catching, he's
catching." Finished. But now the compassion
can only work out if you have that kind of
a spirit, otherwise you cannot. It becomes
sympathy.
For example there's one person, Mr. A. or
Miss A. or Mrs. A., whatever it is. I mean,
I'm just talking of a common personality,
and that person is catching. I would say in
an ashram, that person should clear out. But
all the ashramites will catch from that person,
and that person will never be all right. There's
a very nice joke about it. There was a lady,
she wanted to reduce herself. So there was
a machine like a rolling-pin. They said, "If
you rub it, then you will reduce." So she
brought, poor thing, she brought the machine
and she started rolling it. She found that
the rolling-pin became fat, instead of she
reducing. Same thing is in Sahaja yoga. Instead
of Sahaja yogis correcting the others, they
get contaminated. That's why I said, "Don't
have anybody in the ashram." Because you sympathize.
You do not try to correct that person, in
a way that you can correct within yourselves,
suck it within yourself as your Mother does,
and do it. I do it for thousands and thousands
and thousands; you have to do it for one or
two, so you are never bothered. And that's
how you become strong. Not by shunning them,
running away from them or condemning yourself,
or saying that: "We must save ourselves on
the boat." No. Through adventure. "Let's see
what happens". Tamara was telling Me, "Nothing
catches me, Mother, what is it?"
I said: "But who will catch you? Those who
will catch will be hurt themselves."
So what is it, that Bhairava is to be established.
Sidha kala mane Bhairav' - as you have to
establish Shri Ganesha, you have to establish
also Bhairava, and Hanumana on the right side.
If these three deities you establish within
yourself, nothing, nothing on this earth can
catch you. You'll catch it for a while. But
what I find now, I came to this ashram, everybody's
left Nabhi caught up. Everybody's left Agnya
caught up. So then I get the pain. Everyone.
I mean, I have put you inside My body, do
you know that? You are part and parcel of
My body, you are the cells in My body. And
when you catch, I also catch; not catch, but
I really get the pain, but I clear it. In
the same way, I have given you powers. Every
power I have, I have given you. But you have
to develop it and you have to be adventurous.
But on the contrary, once we have ashrams,
everybody settles down, "Oh, now, very comfortable,
very cheap." Very economical, that's the first
comfort. It's surprising, for a Western person,
it is very important that it should be economical,
surprising, affluent people think more of
saving money than the people who are poor.
And English are the last word, save pounds,
at the cost of others. On the contrary if
you go to India, where they’ll be very happy,
they'll invite you in their house. Whatever
they have they will give it to you, "Eat,
eat, eat." They'll force you. They'll be very
happy to give. But in England it's very dangerous,
you see. Sometimes in the ashram they may
not even have food for Me. Really. And if
you tell them, "I know. I know." You know.
Finished. Then what do you say? They already
know it, now what to do? They know.
So with the affluence miserliness grows, and
money-orientation. In India also I've seen
people who get little more money than the
rest become very money-oriented. Money becomes
everything, money becomes the power, money
becomes their life. Sahaja yogi doesn't care
for money. Just.. is the dust of our Mother's
feet. What is money, what is wealth? And when
they do like that, then their money problems
are solved. If you have a money problem, know
that there's a problem. If you are very particular
about money. I am, in a way, because if I
have to give somebody, I remember it. But
I've seen people who are very anxious to tell
Me that, "You have to pay this man so much,
that man so much." That's wrong. That's not
your look-out. That's very, very wrong to
tell Me that, "You have to pay this man or
that man." It's not important. Even if I don't
pay, I pay him. So in relationship with Me,
you are not to tell Me that, "You have to
pay so much money to him, this much money
should be paid, this is what he owes You."
Nothing of the kind. Let the person come and
tell Me. Why are you telling? That kind of
a message if you give Me, you are lost. Or
if you come and tell Me for somebody else
that, "Mother, time is up, we have to go.
Somebody is hurrying You up." If somebody
is hurrying Me, tell him, "Don't hurry Mother."
You must know that your kundalinis were not
raised with just your own kundalini, but something
that is working it out. Something very tremendous,
a big organization. You can't see it, it is
microscopic. You must know, nobody got realization
like that, did they? Thousands getting realization,
what's happening? There must be something
about… Now how can you tell anything to
such an organization? They don't like it.
They know it. Actually they are the ones who
know, not the English. They know what is to
be done.
So your relationship with Me acts as your
culture. So it is a Mother's cult, you can
call it, the Mother's culture. How we are
connected with our Mother. I have seen people,
if somebody is rude to them, they get very
angry. But if somebody is rude to Me they
don't feel angry. It should be the other way
round. Now I'll give you an example. This
Merv Griffin was funny, and both our PRO’s
were very angry. It was natural and very…
I mean, I liked it, but I calmed them down.
And Worlikar of course was on top of this
thing. But the other fellow would not. He
was giving arguments. I was just watching.
I mean, if somebody had said this to his mother...
There's another one there, he never came to
receive Me at the airport. So Worlikar said,
"If your own mother had come, you would not
have gone?" Then one can give explanation,
"Oh, but our Mother is Adi Shakti. My mother
is not, she's helpless." It's not. To show
your respect, to show your love, you have
to go; for your own gain, not for Her gain.
For your own gain. This relationship is for
your own gain. Supposing if you strike oil,
is it for your gain or for the gain of the
oil? If you get to the Source, is it for the
Source to gain anything, or it is for you
to gain anything? Logic, simple logic. So
in that culture, you see, you really thrive
and you become extremely a happy person, a
joyous person. And the expression of such
a person is so different, because such a person,
as I told you, rises above and sees the problems
of others, the decadence of the society, sees
all the problems of the world. Not only that,
but knows the solutions. We are not like these
ordinary people who have racialism, this..
other diseases, I don't know what sort of
diseases they have, I also forget. Racialism
now, it's another stupid nonsense, you know.
What is racialism? God has made somebody's
color like this and somebody's color like
that, and those same racists are trying to
tan their faces.
So in this culture of ours we are not bothered
about superficial things. What we are bothered
about is our inner cleanliness, inner beauty,
but that doesn't mean that you should move
about like primitive people, no. But if there
is inner beauty, then outer beauty comes.
You will never find Me dirtily dressed. You
will never find Me without a sari on, even
when I sleep I wear a sari, because in the
night also I have to work, so how can I go
in My dressing-gown to the other world? So
a person who is a Sahaja yogi has to be an
extremely neat and a clean person, but not
to tell others, but should be himself or herself.
That's one of the things are very important,
because others will see you, like loonies,
who's going to believe you? So the one effect
is from the Mother, you take from the Source,
for what? To be that illuminated quality,
in you, so that others see you as something
great and adore you, worship you.
This is this far we have come, now, how your
personality should be. But now, when you are
dealing with others, know that they are human
beings made by God, not by Sahaja yogis by
any chance. And they will be tomorrow's Sahaja
yogis, may be higher Sahaja yogis than you.
So when we are dealing with others also, talk
to them in a gentle way. Be kind to them.
Of course we are against gurus, against cults,
against all these people. But as soon as they
come, if you say: "Oh, you are a bhoot", the
person will do right-about-turn and go away.
So you are not given this power to be abrupt
or to be arrogant with others, not given.
Now all such people are coming down, calming
down because they see that what helps is your
gentle, kindly, firm attitude. Only after
Sahaja Yoga you can combine all these qualities.
You'll be firm, you'll be alert, you'll be
gentle and compassionate, smiling, but not
making fun of others. So then you become a
personality who is alert: to see what is the
reaction they're having on others, this is
very important to be seen. So now you start
witnessing others. What is your reaction on
others? I have seen many a times, a new Sahaja
yogi comes in. The person is trying to say
something, and the girl starts giggling or
laughing. One should not, at that time, because
the person might think that, "They're making
fool of me, or they're thinking that I'm a
stupid person, or something wrong with me."
That person will become self-conscious, I
won't be able to give realization to that
person. But if somebody is sitting before
Me and I'm trying to help that person, know
that it's a very important moment of this
gentleman's life. We have got it, so what?
When we are pulling out somebody, when we
are helping out somebody, do we laugh? That's
the time you have to be very concerned and
very much serious, to do the job. Every quality
and mood has its own place, like nose is at
its own place, eyes at its own place. In the
same way, all these moods that we have, have
their own places. And that is what is lost
in modern society. So when I am trying to
help somebody, you should be all concern about
that person. How does this come in to us from
the Source? How much you are concerned about
Me? Supposing I am thirsty, you will feel
thirsty. You'll immediately say, "Mother,
I'll get You some water." But you may not
even ask Me, just bring it here, keep it there.
Or just make some tea for Me or look after
Me. Do this or do that. In little, little
things you should watch. The concern is not
in saying something, asking something. You
don't ask. Don't ask Mother, you just do it.
That's how, when you start doing it, you will
understand what you are doing to others. So
the reflection on others, how they reflect
about you also is very important, and you
have to be alert. Suddenly you say something,
and everybody disappears. You must know they
are not yet Sahaja yogis, they are to be brought
in, so you have to very carefully bring them
around. Then with Sahaja yogis, among yourselves
how you behave is extremely important for
others to see. We must cherish each other's
company, we must cherish. To meet some Sahaja
yogi somewhere, "Ah, what a joy it is to see
someone, to talk to someone on the phone."
But because we are so insular, so selfish,
so greedy, and sometimes very circumcised
[should read 'circumscribed'] I should say,
or absolutely engulfed into our past, we cannot
do that, we do not feel that joy, we cannot
adore another Sahaja yogi, we do not enjoy
another Sahaja yogi, we cannot cherish his
company. That means this finger cannot feel
this finger. It's like a developing, what
you call, a disease called leprosy. Nerves
are finished. Nerve endings are not there.
You cannot feel the joy of other Sahaja yogis.
And this is only possible if you get over
your personal interests. When people come
in Sahaja Yoga in the beginning, they have
personal interests, like say somebody is trying
to sell something, so they would like to sell
it to Sahaja yogis. Or they are arranging
something, they would like Sahaja yogis to
do it. See, personal interest, to use Sahaja
yogis for their own purposes. As a result
of that I've seen some people become so insular
that nobody helps them, no work is done by
them; if there's a telephone, nobody will
say, "I'll get it." That's American quality,
they'll say, "I'll get it." Is regarded good.
Not in England, they'll be all sitting, quiet.
Even when they have eaten the food, they have
to pay the money, they'll look this side,
and some poor Indian student will pay for
all of them. "I won't look", they say. "Now
paid." Now they are normal. It's very low-level.
Is extremely low-level behavior.
And this is what one has to learn, that you
have to cherish others, give presents to others.
"You're going there; “Oh, now…"; like
the other day I met a lady, she had liked
one of My rings of emerald. That's My family
ring so I can't give away, you see, I'll have
to ask C.P. and he may not like it, because
after all I have no right on it, I have to
give it to My children, all right? But I found
an emerald somewhere, beautiful, so I kept
it with Me. The other day when I gave her,
she was so enamored. I said, "You liked My
ring, I couldn't give you My ring, so.."
She said to Me, "You mean to say, I would
have taken Your ring?"
I said, "I would have forced it on you, but
I couldn't give you, so I thought of it. I
just saw it somewhere so I got it for you."
She said, "How thoughtful."
But it's all in My head. I, whenever I get
it, a chance, you see, so somebody says, "Oh,
I like it", keep it in mind. Next time, even
a flower. You must cherish their companies,
because it's such a great thing to have somebody
who understands you, your spirit, and they
have the spirit. Such a great thing. How can
you be unkind to each other? That hurts Me
the most of all. And the first thing and the
foremost thing you have to give Me is congenial,
beautiful, loving group, that they love each
other. If that's achieved, that you really
love, beyond your personal considerations.
I mean, of course, in Sahaja Yoga there are
now not many people who try to make money,
but try to make comfort for themselves. They
must have the best room, they must have the
best place, they must have... "I didn't get
this, I should have it, this, that." Try to
do more than others. I know sometimes people
take advantage of you, but they will go out
of Sahaja Yoga very soon. So be sure that
you become generous about it, very generous.
And generosity should start from your own
Sahaja yogi brothers and sisters.
In the culture of Sahaja Yoga we have to have
a full imbibement bubbling through our nerves,
the sense of chastity. That is a must, whether
you like it or not. There should be no bad
intentions about any other person, of relationships
which are not pure. Absolutely pure relationships,
pure eyes without any adultery, adulteration
I would call it. Clean eyes is the basic of
Sahaja Yoga. Steadfast clean eyes, because
your eyes are very powerful. You don't know
how powerful they are. So to make it that
way, to practice, move your attention inward
and towards the Sahasrara. You can. With your
eyes you suck in. Even by looking at Me with
the shraddha, with the joy, you just suck
it inside, My image. Put it on your Sahasrara,
put it in your heart, you can do it. It's
very joy giving. When you put it in the Sahasrara,
then you get the knowledge. When you put it
in your heart, you get the joy; and when you
put it on your liver, then you get the power
of action. From the photograph also you can
do it, suck in, move it. But that is shown
in the way you behave towards others, completely
confident, gentle; no arrogance. Neither the
neck up like that or like that, but in the
center in a very dignified manner.
So in the culture of Sahaj, because the spirit
is the dignity, is the majesty, is the glory
of God, you have to judge yourself. "Did I
say something which is not respecting my spirit?
Did I do something that is not glorious?"
Like I've seen people, when I'm there, they'll
go on asking Me hundred questions. "Should
it be white towel? Green towel? Should I do
this, should I do that?" Why? Because we don't
live with choices. We live with whatever we
get it, and there is dignity in that. If you
start doing choices, it's stupid. In a group
of Sahaja yogis, the food, "What will you
have?" They'll take forty-five minutes to
decide, if you go in a restaurant, because
the first, the consciousness, "We are paying
for it", and somebody will have this, somebody
will have that. The poor waiter will run away.
But why should we have different? It's just
the same. Whatever Mother is having we'll
have, finished. But if not that, at least
whatever everybody is having, "Why have separately?"
Choices are not there in Sahaja Yoga, remember
this word very clearly. Choices of this, choices
of that, I don't like it, I like that. This
is not good, that is not good. Because we
need everything on the level of vibrations,
then the choice is coming. Like, if the vibrations
are not good we'll not say it, but we'll not
have it. But not question of whether green
or red or yellow or white. And that is what
they are making fool out of you. They will
put one name, Cartier, finished. People will
pay any amount for that Cartier. Is any ordinary
stuff, it is nothing special. But you see
that ego, "I've got the Cartier. I paid more
to show that I've paid more, that I've been
a fool." To pay more for something that's
so cheapish; that's what they're playing upon
- remember that.
So you have to understand that when you are
a Sahaj personality, you have your own dignity.
These things do not give dignity to you. You
give them dignity. But that doesn't mean tomorrow
you come like a clown, or like a limbo on
your nose. Of course I must see the other
point always, because it just slips out that
side. When you become dignified, you will
wear always something that is dignified. You
will do all that is dignified. Is automatically
you become dignified. It's nothing artificial.
So dignity that comes, as you see your Mother.
Whatever you give Me in Puja I take it, all
right, but otherwise you cannot give Me anything
else. If you give Me, I'll return it, somehow.
Somehow I'll return it. A person who is money-oriented
cannot have dignity, because you see him like
a beggar. See, if there’s money-orientation
is too much, he comes down to that level,
you can see it, there cannot be dignity there.
A man who is power-oriented is an idiot. He
looks like an idiot. So we cannot become idiots.
All right. So we cannot be power-oriented.
The one who is sort of a romantic or a love-oriented,
is a stupid fellow. He behaves like a stupid
fellow. On the street they go on kissing each
other all the time. "Where are you going?"
"To the divorce case, but last bit we are
thinking of having some kisses." Self-respect
is the thing. Self is your spirit. The respect
of the spirit should give you that dignity.
But in privacy you are gentle with your husband,
you are gentle with your wife. You must learn
how to be gentle with her in privacy, not
in public. That's horrible. Specially in India.
I am told that people go round with that romanticism
and all that. So please, don't do all those
romantic stuff in India, it's very embarrassing
for Me, very embarrassing.
So we cannot do things which embarrasses our
Mother. Once you start knowing that, "This
will embarrass Mother, we can't do this",
automatically you are helping. So when it
is related with Me, immediately, "What will
Mother think of in me? Is this the way to
behave towards Mother?" Immediately you will
get the reward, as that thing working through
you, as if you become that nature. Sahaja
culture is a sahaja nature. Automatically
you will do it. You'll talk in that manner,
you will speak in that manner, you’ll live
in that manner. I mean, I have seen people
who have never known Me, on a trunk call or
a telephone, they recognize. They know I am
something special; if they are sensitive enough.
From My photograph, the way I sit, the way
I talk, immediately everyone asks. The other
day where I went for the meeting with My husband,
everybody was asking, "Who is this lady?"
"Who is this lady?" "Who is this lady?" There's
something in the personality. I talk to everyone
nicely, I'm very sweet. We cannot be slavish,
and we cannot enslave anyone. We have to cherish,
even human beings we have to cherish, because
they are us. Not to despise anyone, not to
laugh at anyone. In the culture of Sahaj,
you have to become an expert: expertise. Expertise
comes through your adherence to your Mother.
Expertise: you all should be an expert, and
who will give you the certificate is your
Mother only - who else? I may not say so,
but your spirit will say that, and not your
ego.
In this short time whatever was possible,
it's such a big subject, culture is; you cannot.
But I've talked to you, I would not say in
a very analytical way, but in a very synthetic
manner. So I've given you very synthesis of
the whole thing. "Analytical" would be one,
two, three, four, five - cut short - two,
three, four, five, like that. It's not like
that. And that is how you have to speak to
people. One, this is so; two, this is so;
three, this is so; finished. You are not Sahaja
yogis. In your speeches if you talk like that,
finished. But before saying something or doing
something, give a little idea where you are
leading the people, so they are not frittered
away, attention is not frittered away. Give
a little idea, as I say, or else while talking,
bring them to a point which is important,
so that they wait in the sentence to come
to that point. But make the whole sentence
look so, that it is going towards certain
points, so always a Sahaja yogi must make
a point out of what they talk, not just babbling,
talking. What is the point you are going to
make? Whatever they do, they have to know,
"What are we going to achieve out of it?"
Now, marriage. "What are we going to achieve
out of marriage?" A family, house, everybody
has, even a donkey has that. What's so great?
We are going to achieve a family unit where
realized souls are to be born, we're going
to look after them in a proper way, and then
we are going to emit that unit into this world,
like a sparkling diamond set in the beautiful
setting of a family, giving light to the whole
world.
So one's life should not be pointless, and
talk should not be pointless, and every moment
should be filled with achievements of your
visions and dreams, slowly and steadily, which
is not at all difficult. If you can get rid
of ego and superego, finished, that's all
- simple as that.
May God bless you all.
Mm.. good.. nice.. relaxed, eh? Relaxed. Witness.
Everyone cleared out, I think. And no more…
one more thing I must say last, as I've said
it before, which I've not said here, no-one
is going to say that bhoot did it, because
such a person will be sent away to the bhoot
clan, not to Sahaja Yoga. Don't put your responsibility
on the bhoots. Either you are a bhoot or you
are a Sahaja yogi, one of the two, you can't
be both.