So beautiful it was,
that you all could come and give me such a surprise.
Of course I love you very much, no doubt.
My love is not mental, is not emotional,
it’s existence itself.
I exist with it. It’s my innate nature,
which I could not enjoy unless and until it is reflected.
It has to be reflected,
and today I felt the reflection in you people.
I was so overjoyed, so very overjoyed.
Everything seems so beautiful.
All these petty problems that trouble you,
and sometimes try to bother Me also,
just disappeared.
You just felt that everybody is so cleansed and so beautiful,
everybody’s ego washed off
and the nectar of the beauty of love is just
pouring into them.
It’s not easy to describe,
that was Nirananda, I felt it today,
complete Nirananda.
To feel Your own joy reflected is something so
boundless that You cannot put them
into the limitations of words.
You have given me the greatest joy today
and a very great feeling
that Sahaja Yoga now will be established very well
in Germany especially.
I always felt about Germany
that it needed a special help
and the way you all have rushed here
is something like a place,
say, in the hand or in the feet, there is some pain,
so all the attention moves towards that, like that.
Germany is a very strong nation
and if you could take them to Sahaja Yoga,
we’ll have that metal within us. It’s very important.
Every country has something special.
The metal of Germany is very important
and if that comes into us, we’ll have that courage.
So may God bless you all for that.