[Music]
and it happened I really saw
there's a difference between vs. iron
mine I saw this
[Music]
how do you uh transfer just like this
I saw so many permutations of
[Music]
and as if every weapon was engaging
absolutely so it didn't they eat open
out it was so hot it was no problem such
an army wasn't no fluctuation as if they
were dancing tonight and we colors I'll
spread out their lighter the center I
thought wrong
to mess with top
[Music]
so dark and alone laughs so now it's
Halloween and they were also emitting
light
[Music]
done
first I'd open up myself then you were
silent and then I think that tremendous
work so much I will miss Theresa vanes
happiness on fetched
[Music]
that
savage that lesson
everything was fetched
[Music]
the Sahara is the blessing of the
heavens I should say it has worked out
so well it's very difficult to break the
sahasrara and when I really broke it I
didn't know that it would be that
successful first I thought is still
premature because there are many
daksha's are still on this street
selling their books and there are many
fanatics who are calling themselves by
the so-called religions they are
following not the real religion of the
earth but gradually it has taken its
roots now let this truth take its root
within yourself through your system and
once this truth becomes absolutely the
light that guides you the light that
nourishes you the light that enlightens
you and gives you a personality that has
the light then only you should know that
your sister arise completely enlightened
by your spirit your face should be such
that people should know that there's a
personality was standing before you
who is light this is how sahasrara is to
be looked after
please close your eyes
as it is kundalini has risen quite high
I feel it but it has to cross through
the last point which is the seventh
Center Collis Ostara to pierce through
the whole of is called as the Brahma is
the brahmarandra where you get your
parties
the real Baptist actualizing it please
close your eyes just don't open your
eyes that's very important part of
sahaja yoga that you don't open your
eyes because if you open your eyes then
the Kundalini doesn't rise about our
chakra which is the sixth Center put
your right hand on your heart don't open
your eyes please but put your right hand
on your heart and ask a question
for those who have not yet caught the
realization fully established ask a
question mother am i the spirit and the
sahaja Yogi's I have to say mother I am
the spirit in your heart you do need not
say loudly cries
[Music]
put your left hand on top of your head
are you feeling little not touching it
keep it higher I am still higher on on
the place where we call it as a value
where the fontanel bone area where it
was soft when you were a child bring it
nearer to the head and see if you are
feeling the whole piece coming up
me but miss
[Music]
you