Now raise your Kundalini. All of you raise
your Kundalini and tie it up so that it's
up there. Just raise it like that. No. This
way. This way you should do it. This way.
It's good. Once more.
In the West, you have grown very big outside,
like a tree has grown very big. But it must
find its roots, otherwise the whole tree can
fall off, without nutrition. So you must know
the knowledge of the roots.
Without the knowledge of the roots, the tree
has no meaning. So this may be a little new
thing for you to understand, but you must
know ... to know the knowledge of the roots
you have to become subtle. If you are not
a subtle personality you cannot enter into
your roots and you cannot understand what
lies in there. So, first of all, I said yesterday,
you all should get your Realisation, and after
your Realisation you can understand this better
than anything else.
Christ came on this earth, but he was only
allowed to preach and talk for three and a
half years of his life time. And in tree and
a half years is nothing. In that, whatever
was possible he said positively, he told about
the future, all that was to happen. He didn't
talk much about the Holy Ghost. The reason
was His Mother was the Holy Ghost at that
time and He didn't want to talk about Her
because the attention of the people would
be on Her and they would have killed Her.
And then he has got eleven destroying powers.
And he would have used those eleven destroying
powers and everything would have been finished,
the whole drama would have been finished.
So He did not mention much about the Holy
Ghost and did not (expect / express / exaplain?)
But logically we must understand that we talk
of the Father and of the Son but not of the
Mother.
How can you have a father and a son and no
mother? That's an impossibility. So, Holy
Ghost is the Primordial Mother.
In the sanskrit language if you go - because
in the Bible you cannot find everything about
Christ, it's very (little/literal) - but you
have to go back about 1400 years back, back
in India people have prophesied about Him,
how He will be coming. And about the Primordial
Mother who was called as Adi Shakti who was
the Holy Ghost.
All description was given and when Her advent
will come what will happen and how to recognize
her.
All this is described very well so many
years back, even about Christ, quite a lot
to described and also we are going to read
it out to you, the translation of what is
written about Christ and then there is a complete
description about His origin, how He came
on this earth and what was the purpose of
His life.
(Ask that gentlemen to come inside. Can
you ? This gentlemen, come inside. You sit
comfortably)
4:02 And what was the purpose of His life
and how He has to establish in this centre
here (pointing to the Agya Chakra), and that
by establishing there he can suck the ego
and superego in you and how He takes you away,
or He washes off your karmas and your conditionings.
All that has been described very well in the
Devi Mahatmya book out of which we are just
going to read a little bit to you about the
adoration.
So Bible cannot contain Christ, because Christ
is Chaitanya, He is Omkara, He is the Logos
as we call Him. He is the Power, and you cannot
describe Him in one little book, when He was
here only for three and a half years and the
people who saw him also were his disciples,
they did not know much about Him. Until he
was resurrected they did not believe Him and
even after His death, I mean His resurrection,
Matthew and all these people were quite disturbed
and upset because you know they were all persecuted
and they, somehow or the other, wanted to
continue the message of Christ in a very secretive
manner.
So today the time has come for you to
know about Him, about what He was - in the
Heaven and how He came on this Earth. All
that we don't have time today but we'll be
just telling you about a little passage that
is written about him.
So first, He is the one who is innocence,
who is an eternal child, and He appears first
on the first chakra of Muladhara, and there
He's called as Shri Ganesh. Where the carbon
atom was made. Carbon. And that is very important
to understand that Ganesha is the symbol of
innocence and Mother Earth is the power of
that deity, Ganesha.
So it was Ganesha, later on incarnated
on this Earth as Christ, and He will be incarnated
again as eleven Rudras, means Ekadashas, or
we can call him as Nishkalanka deity, when
He will just sort out things in a sense that
He will just cut the people out who are not
realised, who are no good, and the rest of
them will ascend in the Kingdom of Heaven,
this is what is the last Ascent.
Now, for this ...
Please sit down, please. Please be seated,
give him a chair or something. You have to
sit down comfortably. You see, it is a thing
that makes... happen something within you,
so you have to be very much restful, that's
very important. Give him a chair if he cannot
sit on the ground. Give him a chair, but be
comfortable otherwise it won't work out, you
see, it is not something that will go into
your mind, it's something that will go to
your being, so you have to be very receptive.
Another thing I'll tell you, yesterday also
I saw, and today also, you should not move
your neck by eating something or chewing something
because this Vishuddhi chakra gets upset at
that time. So keep still, unless and until
you are still it cannot work out. So please
keep still.
So this is the nourishment of the roots of
which we are going to work out, which you
will feel it, very nicely within yourself.