I bow to all the seekers of truth. When Bala
says that I can give you realization in a
split of a second I have to tell you that
it is you who get it. You are built in that
way like a seed; when you put it in the Mother
Earth it sprouts. Whom will you give the credit
-- the seed or the Mother Earth? Without the
Mother Earth the seed cannot sprout and it
does not mean that if you put a stone in the
Mother Earth it will sprout.
So the credit is not to anyone but it is a
process which is built within us through ages
of our seeking. We have been seekers in previous
lives and before that we have been seeking.
Even when we were amoeba we were seeking.
That's how we have become a human being. And
now we have reached a stage where we are human
beings and we are seekers of truth. This is
the epitome of the highest that any human
being can reach where he is seeking.
As a human being when we are born we are quite
aware that we are higher than animals, that
we have capacities much more than animals
have. We are quite aware of our being as a
human being but this awareness that we have
is still not complete because we are still
in confusion. We do not know why we are on
this earth. We do not know what we have to
achieve. We do not know what mistakes we are
committing or this is right or that is right.
A man lands up himself into confusion because
of ignorance. Now this ignorance, as has been
described by all the prophets and saints,
is just a myth, like if you have darkness
here that doesn't mean it exists, but because
there is no light. In the negation of the
light gives you the darkness.
Where is the light, and how do we awaken it?
This question has been very much looked into
by thousands and thousands of people earlier
also, and thousands of years back people have
bothered to find out where is this light and
how do we awaken it. Now this light is within
us because they found it, and the method they
have said also is within us because they knew
about it. But this knowledge was quite a big
secret for many years, thousands of years,
and was not given to people because people
were not ready to accept it and to take advantage
of it. But we should not say that it was not
said. It was very clearly said in most of
the scriptures that you are to be born again.
Unless and until you know yourself you cannot
know God. First you know yourself and then
you will know God Almighty. For example, supposing
we are coming to Birmingham and we do not
know the way, and we get lost. We can come
here, can be brought properly, but the car
that you are driving, you don't know the car.
You don't know how to drive. You don't know
the way. Then how are you to reach the right
place? If everything is missing, how can you
say that you can reach Birmingham without
any knowledge about it? In the same way, if
you have no knowledge of yourself itself,
how can you know God when you have not known
yourself? It is very logical, and extremely
simple logic should tell you that you do not
know about yourself.
People become mad and when they are absolutely
gone cases they end up into lunatic asylum.
But when it starts they do not know. They
get cancer diseases, terminal diseases of
the worst type, and they don't know how to
overcome it. Till they have reached their
last stage they do not even feel it. Suddenly
they discover, "O God, I have this disease."
So we do not know even our physical being
that when it is hurt, when it is in danger,
when it is diseased we have no idea. We do
not know our mental being either.
When we are impressed by other people we start
behaving like them. When they mesmerize us,
we start following them. We are not aware
that we have no mind of our own; we are just
following something that is very aggressive
and that's how we accept it. If you are accepting
something about which you have no idea just
because you are impressed by somebody's personality
or the way he talks or the way he comes to
you, then definitely your mind you do not
know.
Like Hitler, he came with funny ideas. He
told people that, "We are a very great race
and we have a right to kill everyone and to
put the people in the gas chamber." They accepted.
How can you accept such a mass massacre of
people like that? But they did accept. The
reason was they did not know what is their
mind. We do not know our emotions also. We
say, "This is my son. I'll give my life for
this son. I'll do this for him. This is my
daughter. This is my father." But when it
comes to selfishness everything drops out.
So we do not also know our emotions. If we
had known we would not talk like that. Every
moment we are changing our mood from this
to that. Sometimes we are happy with that
person. Then we are very unhappy. Then we
become enemy of that person. We fight for
that person first. We say, "No, this is my
brother," and then we say, "No, he is my enemy."
Why? Because both of them do not know their
mind.
So first we must know ourselves by which we
get the light to know all these things. Now
what is that self? What is that Spirit, that
Atma about which all the great people have
talked? Where does it reside within us? It
resides in our heart. Now when I say this,
you need not accept Me. In these modern times
nothing should be accepted blindfolded. It's
very dangerous. That's how you have fallen
into traps of so many wrong people. When I
say that you should only have an open mind
of a scientist, to see whatever Mother is
saying is true or not. Now the time has come
that God can be proved scientifically. The
science of Sahaja Yoga can prove that there
is God. The science of Sahaja Yoga can prove
that there is self, the spirit. It can prove
all the saints and prophets who came on this
earth told the truth. It can prove that whatever
is said about the miracles of God is all true.
The time is like that. Only our mind doesn't
go to that side. We don't want to know about
it. We don't want to understand it.
Now this is a special time which is described.
This is a very, very special time which has
been prophesized by so many. Every one of
them, those who were great saints, have. They
have to be great saints or real saints, as
we say Sat-Guru [Hindi word meaning True Master].
Those prophets who were real prophets, they
all have said that the time is going to come
when you are going to be resurrected. Mohammed
Sahib has said, "At the time of resurrection
your hands will speak." Very clearly he has
talked about resurrection throughout, but
who is bothered to know that? They all only
want to talk about the doomsday so that everybody
is frightened. Another is that we talk of
the day when you are all going to be damned
into something because you should be all frightened
and you should just go under their clutches
and surrender yourself so that these people
who will be destroyed first are going to save
you.
People have made money out of God. Imagine!
How can you have an enterprise in the name
of God? How can you make money in the name
of God? I mean, how does it go into your logics?
I can't understand that you can pay money.
How can you intellectualize God? It's amazing
the way they are intellectualizing Christ
and believing Paul was nothing but an intellectual.
Why is he there in the Bible? I can't understand
he should not have been there. That way, we
Indians are sensible.
We had Guru Nanak who wrote Guru Granth Sahab.
He has taken all the poets who are realized
souls. Not one is none realized. We don't
listen to people who are not realized, who
are not of a great evolved state. But this
Mr Paul has come inside there, and now he's
challenging Christ and his miracles. What
does he know? He is not a realized soul. If
he's not a realized soul how can he talk about
God? He has no business. He has no right.
None of these people who authorize themselves,
get elected and selected as big Brahmins and
big pundits and big bishops and Popes and
others, they are nowhere near God. They are
not realized people, are they? What realization
have they got? They are just interested in
politics, economics and all nonsense that
is not God's job. But we get into their traps.
Be careful. You are seekers of truth and not
of something that is ignorance. We have had
enough of ignorance. Any person who has any
power will never succumb or compromise with
untruth. That is first sign of a person who
is a realized soul. He is not bothered, even
if you put him to jail, you crucify him, poison
him, do what you like. And this is what surprises
me. How do you like such people and adore
such people for compromising and meek and
taking to all kinds of falsehood? Take the
case of Christ. Did He compromise? Did not!
Any time, He never compromised. What I am
saying about Paul was said by Kahil Gibran.
Openly he said it in his book, "The Son of
Man" or something like that, he clearly says,
"This Paul, a strange man." I don't understand.
He's not a man with a free will. It's true
anybody who is a realized soul can see this,
and all those who follow him are following
falsehood and making others follow him.
I must tell you God is not an enterprise.
Remember that. If you understand that God
doesn't understand money at all. Is your headache.
You better deal with money, not Him. So in
Sahaja Yoga people say, "Mother, what about
money?" I say, "What money? How much money
you pay to the Mother Earth to sprout the
seed? You pay that much to Me. If Mother Earth
can take for her love any money, you can give
me some money." How can you talk like this?
This is ridiculous. It is ridiculous. So there
is no money. That is nonsense. There is no
effort, either. See what effort do we put
in? It's a living process and for a living
process what effort are you going to put?
What effort did we put to become human beings?
Nothing! Effortless! Sahaja Samadhi Lago.
Sahaj is born with you. Sahaja, born with
you.
So what is there for people to put in effort?
It is He who does all the jobs. What work
do we do? In our ego we think, "I have done
this. I have done that." What? A tree must
have died and you make a platform. So what?
Dead from the dead! What else have we done?
Then you make a chair and sit on the chair.
You can't sit on the garden, floor. The other
day somebody was interviewing on the BBC.
Poor thing! You see, they were trying to arrange
a platform and I sat very comfortably, but
he had such aches and cramp. He couldn't even
ask me proper questions because he can't sit
on the platform. He said, "Mother I have never
sat on a platform all my life," because now
he must carry a chair with him on his head.
So one must understand that this dead is going
to make us slaves. What we do is to create
dead out of dead and think, "Oh, I have done
this. We have done that." Can you transform
a flower into a fruit? Can you? One flower?
What can I describe? The glory of God! There's
no words. Just think that every human being
gets a child according to the family. Who
does that job? Imagine! Imagine that child
has cells developed. There's thousands of
cells: some for the nose, some for the eyes,
some for the hands. How it develops automatically
-- Sahaja. What do you do? Spontaneous! Do
you give any treatment to the child or give
any suggestions to the child?
The One who does all these things, how can
you describe His glory? And you challenge
Him. Here we are, like Newton has said in
a very humble way, collecting the pebbles
on the shores of knowledge. That's what we
are. And so we have to know, only thing that
we can become is a drop in the ocean and become
the ocean so that all our angularities drop
out. This is the only thing we have to achieve.
But for that also, God has made all arrangements
so sweetly within us. He has made us so beautifully;
he has created us so beautifully within ourselves.
This is the picture of that tree of life which
is still dormant within you, and the Kundalini
that is the Holy Ghost is described, is in
the triangular bone.
Now this Kundalini has to rise, just like
a primule in a seed, or you can say the germinating
power, and she rises through six centers,
comes out of your fontanel bone area and gives
you the Cool Breeze, from your body, from
your head. For that you need not change your
dress. You need not put up any show. Nothing.
It is something inside that happens. Kabira
has described, "Shunya shikhar par anahad
baaje." On
the silent apex there is the percussion of
Anahata. Anahat is this "lub-dub" of the heart
you feel there. And then when it breaks you
start getting the cool breeze coming out of
your head. If you call it, miracle. It is
a miracle, but to Me it is not. It's all there.
It is built in. There are thousand and one
miracles we see morning till evening. We are
not surprised and this is also the great thing
that God has done, that you all have to get
your Self-realization. The time has come.
This is the time of judgment, a special time,
a blossom time when thousands of you have
to get your realization.
First of all we have to know that we must
get the light within ourselves. Then one can
tell you all about the chakras and the nadis
and everything. Like the light here has to
be put on first, and then one can tell you
about the history and how it came and about
everything else, but very easy to get the
light. Now the other day somebody asked me
a question, "Mother it used to take thousands
of years for people to get realization. They
used to be born again and again and all that."
I said, "That was all right." Because on the
tree of life first there were one or two flowers
only, but today you all have come through
all that. Now that background is with you.
You are just cashing your background with
Me. I am just like a banker sitting here.
But even you feel that you don't have a background.
You have it. You don't know what background
you must have had that you have become a human
being, and on top of that you are a seeker.
You might done some mistakes, doesn't matter.
After all, human beings are only going to
make mistakes. So we are not to feel guilty.
That is one thing I have to make very humble
request that we are not going to feel guilty
at all.
Today, somehow or other, the time has become
very short for Me. Your train times have to
change. You have to go to London tonight,
and I will start the program of giving realization
to you. But there will be some people here
who will look after you, fulfill all your
questions and do everything. They have become
experts and sometimes they are more effective
than Me. Especially in India you see, and
here I find that somehow I, being a very gentle
Mother, people do not take things seriously.
Mother may be gentle but She can be very forceful,
and you all should take your realization because
the power of love is the highest that suits
you, controls you, makes you a higher personality.
We have never used the power of love so far.
We have only used the power of hatred. The
power of love just flows. That is, not to
be seen but to be felt as cool breeze all
around, is called as Rutambhara Pragya -- in
Sanskrit language, is called as the All Pervading
Power of God's love. Is called as Brahma,
is called as so many Nirakaar sakshat brahma,
but all these things are to be felt. It acts
so that you get cured of your troubles. It
acts so that you are mentally a very happy
and a satisfied person that you rise into
joy. It acts through your attention that wherever
you put your attention it cures; it makes
a person innocent.
As Christ has said, "Thou shalt not have adulterous
eyes." Where are those people? Where do we
find those people who have no adulterous eyes?
But you get purified.. Your eyes get purified,
and you have those eyes that when you put
those eyes on anybody he gets his realization.
That sort of a personality you develop. You
are so great and glorified by God. Just achieve
what is inside you. Just get it, manifest
it. But truth has to be manifested on your
central nervous system. Not just talk, talk,
talk, talk, talk. No mental projection, but
you must feel it on your central nervous system
and you have to become your own master.
That's what when happens then you say you
are a self-realized person. It's not that
you do all kinds of bad things and say that,
"Oh I am great." Not so. You really become
embodiment of virtue, embodiment of righteousness
and you lose that capacity to be tempted by
nonsense. Nor do you allow any habits to come
over you. Such a powerful, compassionate personality
you develop and the whole personality beams
with that and you can see it clearly. You
don't become a miserable bony structure, as
they put up of Christ, but you really become
like the one Michelangelo has done -- that
sort of a great personality. When they put
up such a picture know that they are miserable
creatures themselves. Ask them if they can
carry the cross themselves that they can put
up such a picture of Christ.
They have done harm to everyone, not only
to Christ; to all the great prophets when
they lived and when they died. They are still
harming them by giving wrong ideas about them,
by making money out of them, by spreading
hatred out of them. Anything extreme is wrong.
You have to be in the center. You have to
be moderate and it acts and works out. May
God bless you all.
Today I am sorry I won't allow you to ask
Me questions because there's no time today.
I'm sorry I didn't have so much time, but
what we can do is to leave someone here for
you, whom you can ask questions. Best is to
get your realization. That will work it out
and let's see how much time it takes. Actually,
Kundalini takes split of a second to rise,
split of a second. But where? In Indian villages.
I don't know about Birmingham. Let us see
how it works out. But you have many people
here who are already realized souls sitting
and it should take no time for you to be that.
But don't start thinking about it. It is beyond
thought. It is in thoughtless awareness you
have to rise but you don't have to fight your
thoughts. You become thoughtlessly aware.
You become -- again I say you have to become,
it's not just a mental projection or a certificate,
"born again", and behaving like a stupid fool.
Or, "I am such and such guru," wearing his
mala and the guru and the shishas going to
hell, taking two running jumps that way. That's
not it. It's such a funny sight when you see
those people, the chelas of the gurus the
way they are. Just can't believe it. The guru
has befooled them and they have really become
fools and stupid people. So be careful. You
have to become your own guru.
I am just your Mother. I am here to give you
your realization. As far as the Mother Earth
gives sprouting to the seed, that's all. There's
no obligation, nothing of the kind. It's your
own. You have it and enjoy it. Only thing
after this, as yoga has one meaning, the Union
with the Divine, and another is the deftness,
the art of handling this power of God. The
Divine Power, the Divine Laws, this is the,
another meaning. That is in Sanskrit it's
Kaushalam. It's the deftness, the technique,
the technicalities. Not of how to handle a
car but how to handle this power, this great
power that starts flowing through you. You
become like the flute of Shri Krishna, egoless,
and you enjoy that egoless state. That's what
you all are for and you should get it.
May God bless you.
Question from a seeker.
Shri Mataji: Just a minute, I'll tell you
now. Sit down, sit down. It's very simple,
you see. Your question is all right but is
not thought out. But you understand how you
have not thought out. Now just a minute, now
in this light there is a lamp and a light
coming out, all right? Now you think about
your question again.
What is it? What are you asking me?
All right! All right! God is everywhere, all
right? I can't understand what he is talking
about.
Bala: Mother I don't think this is the time
to discuss...
Shri Mataji: All right, you can discuss with
him later on. All right, we'll give you a
full chance. What is he trying to say? Just
tell me. One minute.
Bala: He is saying that the Kundalini is wholly
within the body but God is everywhere. How
can you awaken something which is within?
Shri Mataji: But that I will show you....
Bala: On the assumption that God is everywhere.
Shri Mataji: I mean, God is everywhere. Now
see, it's very simple. I'll tell you. It's
like this. There is ether everywhere, all
right, but how is it that only the radio receives
the programs? Why do you have a radio? You
can receive yourself. After all, ether is
everywhere. It's very simple. I mean, you
have not used your brains at all. When asking
the questions use your brains.
Comment from questioner: "Let the people receive
the"....
Shri Mataji: Now you should not be -- Hello,
sir, you should not be aggressive. There are
many who want it. Let it be. We are going
to give you time. I will tell you all about
it. Why you are for the people? Are you representing
them? How are you talking for people? Who
wants to hear his lecture? Is there anyone?
No one wants you. Please go away. Useless
man, does nothing for you. From where they
come, God knows.
Must be from some guru paid by them. That's
all, nothing else. They earn money and that's
how they manage. They earn money; good advertisements
by some people put them up. Some of them came
to kill Me because you see they are enterprisers.
So, they think when I say, "You can't give
money," you see. In Marathi we say that, or
in Hindi we say, "Pate pe pair aana." You
see, his earnings are hurt. They don't like
Me. It's all right. I'll have to say what
I have to say. I am not afraid of them.
All right, please take out your shoes. It's
not that only I can raise the Kundalini. You
see, ego gets challenged by that. I don't
mean that. If you get your realization you
can give. Actually there's one gentleman in
Maharashtra who has raised the Kundalini of
ten thousand people, but one light has to
enlighten another light. What is wrong in
that? And then another light can enlighten
just another light. But the one that is not
enlightened has to get their light from someone.
In that their ego is hurt. They don't mind
taking dole from the government but if somebody
tries to raise their Kundalini, his ego is
hurt.
Such self-respecting people, I can't understand.
It's a great blessing that somebody's raising
your Kundalini. Where do you get people these
days? They only want to have all your money,
that's all. Who does that? Have you met anyone?
If you have met anyone like Me, please tell
Me. I haven't met one.
It's not that I am something great, but this
is the fact. This is the truth that somebody
has to do it without any selfish interest.
It has to be done. It's a job of a person
who has no selfish interest. It's just the
love, the compassion. So, how can you challenge
that? It is there. It will act and work out.
All right, so settle down little bit. Don't
be upset with this gentleman. It's all right.
They are always there to upset. Only one is
not to fight. Now what you have to do take
out your shoes, simple. What I say, you just
do it and it will work out. Have faith in
yourself. First of all, have faith in yourself.
Forgive yourself. Don't feel guilty. I have
told you before now, "Don't feel guilty. Don't
feel guilty. Don't feel guilty." All of you
are capable of this Kundalini awakening. So,
please don't feel guilty. Just know that everyone
can get realization. Everyone can become a
guru and everyone can give realizations to
others. Is a fact. This has happened. But
if you want to sit on the fence, you go ahead
with it because I have to gain nothing out
of you. Be sure on that. You see, it's a subtle
type of a ego that works in people.
What do you have to give Me? Supposing I say
I want something, then it's all right, but
there's no shop here. It's a temple. In a
temple you have to get something and you don't
go and fight with someone in a temple, do
you? All right!
So now close your eyes. Put your hands like
this, just like this. You don't have to do
anything. Effortless! It's effortless. Don't
fight your thoughts. Don't fight anything.
Just let your attention be loose. Kundalini
itself will rise. You don't have to do anything.
Just have faith in yourself, that's all, that
you are going to get it. Now
one thing you have to do is to remember that
the left hand is for your desire, desire power,
which they will explain to you later, and
the right hand is for awakening of the Kundalini
in the way that it goes into action. It gives
release to your different centers by which
the Kundalini rises easily.
It's very simple thing. So, put your right
hand on your heart. Put your right hand on
your heart. Now, as I said, the Spirit resides
in your heart but God Almighty, the seat of
God Almighty, is on top of your head where
you have a very soft bone in your childhood
called Talu. He resides there. But His reflection,
the Spirit, resides in your heart. So here
you have to say, or ask Me a question with
full confidence again, not counting your sins
or anything, but knowing that you are a seeker
and you are going to be blessed into the Kingdom
of God. With all that dignity as a question
to Me -- you can call Me Shri Mataji or you
can call me Mother, whatever you like -- "Mother,
am I the spirit?" Three times. Three times,
ask a question. You are the spirit, but you
have to just ask the question. There's no
harm in asking. Please keep your eyes shut
because Kundalini won't rise if you, if you
keep your eyes shut. Please have respect for
yourself because you are the spirit. So just
ask Me a question, "Mother, am I the spirit?"
We all have to become that. That is the epitome
of our evolution. We all have to become the
spirit.
Now second position of the hand should be
on the stomach on the left hand side. We work
on the left hand side. On the upper part of
the stomach on the left hand side you have
to say again a question, "Mother, am I my
own master? Am I my own guru," because logically
if you are the spirit you become your own
master. All these great masters reside within
us. So they bless you for that. Now with full
confidence, without feeling guilty, just ask
Me a question, "Mother, am I my own master?
Am I my own guru?" All the great gurus are
there within us. This is a very important
center. Now ask this question three times.
Now take this right hand down on to the lower
part of the stomach, abdomen, and press it
hard a little. This is a very important Swadhistana
chakra on the left hand side and it is related
to the second part of yoga that I told you
-- the deftness, the technique of the true
knowledge. Here I must confess I cannot cross
your freedom. You are free to choose. So you
have to ask that you want this true knowledge
and you have to say, "Mother, please give
me my true knowledge. Give me Shuddha Vidya.
Mother, give me true knowledge. Give me absolute
knowledge. Give me pure knowledge." You have
to say it six times because this center has
got six petals. These are like lotuses and
they have six petals. In the same way it looks
after the aortic plexus in the gross and it
has got six sub-plexuses.
Now please raise your hand again back to the
same position on the stomach on the left hand
side, that is the upper portion of the stomach,
upper portion of the abdomen on the left hand
side, please, again. Putting the left hand
there where it was. Now here again you have
to assert because you have asked for the true
knowledge, so at this center of the guru there
are ten gurus; there are ten masters. Or we
can say there are ten valences human being
have got. So, you put your hand on that center
on the left hand side and you have to ten
times assert, "Mother, I am my own master.
Mother, I am my own guru." That's what people
don't like. They want to be subservient of
somebody who is not a realized soul because
a realized soul never makes you subservient;
he makes you higher and higher. "Mother, I
am my own guru." Say it ten times, please.
Now please do not feel guilty. Even if you
have been to wrong gurus, whatever has happened
has happened. Forget it. Don't blame yourself
for that. Just say, "Mother, please make me
my guru." First of all as you have said it,
now you say, "Mother, I am my own guru." Say
it ten times.
Now raise your right hand. It's like a play,
I tell you. It's just a leela. It works out
so well. Now put your right hand on the heart
again. Now you have to assert ten times with
full confidence, "Mother, I am the spirit."
With full confidence please say. Don't you
worry. Many people think we have to cleanse
this, cleanse that. You leave it to Me, all
those things. You just say whatever I tell
you, please, believing in yourself, "Mother
I am the spirit." This you have to say twelve
times because this center has got twelve petals.
This is the heart chakra, is called as the
anahat chakra, twelve times.
Now raise this hand to the base of your neck
and place it on your shoulder from the front
side in the corner where the neck and the
shoulder meet. Put it tight. This is the center
gets caught up when you feel guilty which
is very badly caught up just now. What is
there to feel guilty? Now take the hand from
the front side, from the front side on the
left hand, front side, not this way across,
front across. [Aside: No. Left hand towards
Me and right hand like this and hold it tight,
yes. This gentleman is not knowing, you just
- this hand like this and this hand like that.
Can you do it, please? Left hand towards Me.
Yes, left hand towards Me like that, left
hand towards Me. Yes, correct and right hand
here. That's good.
Now this is a very important center what we
call the Vishuddhi chakra on the left hand
side. Those who suffer from this center get
all the diseases like angina and rheumatic
heart and all those things where there's a
slow movement of the circulation. So please
say sixteen times, "Mother, I am not guilty."
You have to be pleasantly approaching towards
God's Kingdom, isn't it? You should be pleasant
about it. What is there to be so sad or to
be so gloomy about? So just say, "Mother,
I am not guilty," sixteen times, and if you
still continue with that kind of a thing is
better that you say hundred and eight times
to punish yourself. Please say, "Mother, I
am not guilty." Be pleasant about it. There's
nothing to be upset about yourself. All the
time you have condemned yourself for nothing
at all. Believe me, you have done nothing
wrong that cannot be forgiven by God because
God is the ocean of love. He is the ocean
of compassion. He is the ocean of forgiveness.
What can you do that it cannot wash away these
little specks? Some people say that it is
difficult to forgive but just see what is
the logic behind it. What do we do when we
do not forgive? What do we do when we forgive?
Nothing! It's a myth. We are just torturing
ourselves. So just say, "Mother I forgive
everyone," with your heart in it. Please forgive
everyone. To forgive is Divine, and really,
that's a fact. You'll feel much lighter if
you forgive.
Now you have to put your hand on top of your
head for a while, just for a while, pressing
the palm of your hand on top of the fontanel
area or the soft bone or the talu and press
it in a clockwise manner and move it so that
your scalp also moves in a clockwise manner.
Press it hard. Seven times you have to press
it. Before that you just say without feeling
guilty again, without confidence before entering
into the Kingdom of God that, "Oh God, please
forgive me if I have done any mistakes," but
don't feel any way guilty about it. Just say
it three times.
Now here at the top of the head you have to
cross the gross into the subtle. You have
to enter into the Kingdom of God. For that
I cannot force you. I cannot push you in.
You have to ask for it. So again you have
to say, "Mother, I want my realization. Please
give me self-realization. Mother, please give
me Atma Shakshatkaar." Just press it hard,
seven times.
Now you can take down your hand. Put your
left hand on top of your head. Pay attention
there, about four inches above. And now see
if there's a cool breeze coming out. Keep
your eyes shut. [Mother breathes into the
microphone] You start feeling a cool breeze
on top of your head. Just move it up and down.
Now don't get upset you are not feeling it
-- Vishuddhi. If you are feeling any cool
breeze, well and good. Even it you are not
feeling you should not worry. There might
be heat coming out. First, there's a lot of
heat in the body. Let it come out. Let the
heat come out. You can change your hand and
see if there is cool breeze coming in. If
it is coming you can put down your hand. Little
higher! Move it up and down or move backwards
and forwards. All right? Good. Now put your
hands like this.
Now putting the hands towards Me, you have
to ask Me a question again sixteen times,
I am sorry, "Mother, am I the part and parcel
of the whole? Mother, am I the part and parcel
of the whole?" [Aside: that will work out
for Vishuddhi]. Now I will tell you how to
raise your own Kundalini and keep it there
because it has stuck. I know it has stuck.
Still you may not feel it. Some may feel it.
There are many Sahaja Yogis here who will
help you how to do it. They'll tell you, but
there's very simple which you should follow
every day to raise your Kundalini and keep
it in proper place. It's first of all, just
hold it. You have to put your left hand in
front of your Kundalini, just like this, how
to raise it. That is -- [Aside: should we
give them a bandhan first of all? All right!
Doesn't matter.]
Now you put your right hand here and go on
moving it just like that. Take it on top of
your head. Push it back your head and make
a -- that's it. This is the first way we raise
our Kundalini. Everybody should try because
then they will say, "We didn't feel it. We
didn't have." It's very simple. Now this is
what in the Bible they said that when the
Holy Ghost blessed them they started speaking
in strange languages, means the languages
of the chakras, and they moving their hands
in a funny manner. This is the way because
that's how you raise the Kundalini. Even the
children were doing. I saw them. They are
-- some of them are born realized so they
themselves were trying all the things, so
-- but we are grown-ups, you see. So we are
too much up here.
Now let us be humbled down and take it. This
is the first time we push back our head. That's
one. Again second time. This is, we are raising
our Kundalini. You'll see the vibrations will
increase. Second time. Third time, three times
we have to give, beautiful. Three times we
have to give a knot, beautiful, one, two and
three. Now see your hands. Are they feeling
cool breeze? In the hands, feeling it, yes.
[Mother speaks in Hindi] If it is not coming
you should not be dishonest. You have to get
it. You should not be dishonest to yourself.
You should be kind to yourself and as a result
of that sometimes, you know, people think,
"Oh, I haven't got it. So what!" It's nothing
wrong with Sahaja Yoga. It's something wrong
with you. Either you are egoistical or you
are conditioned. Either you are not well or
there's something going in your minds which
is against, or some sort of a thing that works
out.
I have seen there was a gentleman who asked
me, "Why I can't get it?" He was a very frivolous
man and I didn't want to tell him that, "You
are frivolous." Another one was thinking no
end
of himself. So just see if you are feeling.
Is it so simple? [Mother speaks in Hindi]
Taking the name of Nanaka himself, you see,
such a great primordial master born on this
earth. Just taking his name itself, the Kundalini
rises. [Mother speaks in Hindi] He was the
same as Mohammed Sahib. He was the same as
Abraham. He was the same as Moses. Why are
you fighting? Just see this.
All right, I am sorry I have to catch a train
because there is some sort of an emergency
for Me to go to London but here is Warren.
He is Dr Warren Reeves. I call him Warren
because he is like my son, he -- they are
all My children. He is here to satisfy your
mind. If you have any questions you can write
to him. If you have not felt the vibrations
don't go away. Raise your hands. There are
at least here thirty to forty Sahaja Yogis
who have been imported. Now we have to import
people from Birmingham to London. So there
are so many have come. Please just listen
to them. You can outbeat them in no time.
There is nothing to feel bad and this is how
you are going to achieve, that is being prophesized.
And now you can ask a question, "Is there
God?" Ask a question, "Is the God miraculous?
All the miracles of Christ -- are they correct?"
Real, ask a question and you'll get the answer
as tremendous vibrations. You become a computer
which is living computer. That's how you can
prove everything. Everything can be proved.
May God bless you all.
There are people here. Dr Warren will tell
you about it. He is going to stay on. He has
given realization to I don't know how many
thousands people in Australia, but somehow
Australians are very much in the center. I
must say Australians are very different. English
now think that they have punished Australians;
so now they are great. It's not so. In Australia
great saints are born. So in England also
but we have to become. So the becoming is
the point. We have a very nice center in Birmingham
and I've been coming to this hall I don't
know how many times, and to Birmingham. I
hope you people become the tree. Now the seed
has sprouted but just don't give it up. Become
the tree. That's very important; otherwise
it's just a waste and is a sin against yourself
if you do that. So may God bless you. I don't
think you have questions.