With love
all kinds of creative action takes place.
You see how Raulbai has love for Me and in
this place you all also got new idea of creating
a beautiful thing. And as love will increase,
your creativity will develop.
So the basis of all creativity, of Saraswati,
is love. If there is no love there’s no
creativity. It’s even in the deeper sense,
you see. People who have created all the scientific
things are also out of love for the masses,
not for themselves. Nobody has produced anything
for themselves. If they make something for
themselves it has to become for universal
use, otherwise it has no meaning. Even if
you say atom bomb and all these things that
are created from science, they are also very
protective. If they had not created those,
people would not have taken out their minds
from war. Now, nobody can think of having
a big war. Of course, they are having cold
wars, but that also will gradually stop, when
they will be fed up.
So, all the activity on the right hand side,
of Saraswati, basically has to end up in love.
Starts with love and ends up in love. Whichever
does not end up in love coils up and finishes
off. It just disappears. So you can see that
even matter, which is not used for love, just
finishes off. The basis has to be love. Otherwise
all such matter that we create which has angularity,
which is not fitting into the mass media which
is not appealing to the masses. Of course,
it takes time, you have seen that it takes
time - but it does have that tendency always
to disappear in the thin air as soon as you
find it does not appeal to the masses.
Now this love of, that we talk of, this great
love of God we talk of, we know it for definite
through vibrations. People do not have vibrations,
but still they can feel the vibrations in
a very unconscious way. All the great paintings
of the world have vibrations. All the great
creative works of the world have vibrations.
Only those who have vibrations have been sustained
by time, otherwise all other things are destroyed.
There must have been monuments and horrible
statues and horrible things that have been
created long time back. But they were all
destroyed by nature, and they could not stand
the impact of the Kala - that is the destructive
power of time. So, all that is sustaining,
all that is nurturing, all that is en-nobling,
comes from this sense of love, which is within
us very much developed, but within others
also, who are not yet realized. Ultimately
the whole world has to realize that one has
to go to that ultimate love of God, otherwise
it has no meaning.
Now you have seen in art people have taken
to other methods of appealing to people by
using cheap things and very vulgar things,
just to make people think that this is art.
But this will all disappear. It cannot sustain
the impact of the time as I told you, it cannot.
Because the time will kill it. All these things
have to disappear and already you can see
the result, how things are changing everywhere,
even in the West. So there is no need to be
so much disappointed with the West and to
say that the Western world is a wasteland.
It is going to be alright and it has to be
done. Especially it has done lot of Puja of
Saraswati, I should say, in the West. Much
more than they have done in India because
they have gone to learning and they have tried
to find out so many things. But only thing
they forgot that it is a Goddess, Goddess
of Learning. Everything comes from the Goddess.
That’s what they’ve forgotten. And that’'s
why all the problems have been created.
If there is no Spirit in your learning, if
there is no source of the Goddess in your
learning, then it is absolutely useless. If
they had realized that there is the Spirit
that is working it out, they would not have
gone that far. And that’s what I was warning
the Indians, all through, that you are now
taking to industrial revolution in a way and
to avoid all the complications of industrial
revolution, you must try to know the Spirit.
If you do not know the Spirit you will have
the same problems as these people have. Because
they are also human beings, you are also human
beings. You will also go the same way. At
random you will run and there will be problems,
the same problems as the Western people have.
Now Saraswati's blessings are so many that
one cannot describe in such a short time.
And the Surya has given us so many powers
that it is impossible to tell them even in
one lecture, even in ten lectures. But how
we go against Surya and how we go against
Saraswati, while doing the worship of Saraswati,
is to be seen very clearly within ourselves.
For example the Western people are very fond
of Surya because they have no Surya. But they
go too far with it, as you know, and create
complications within themselves of Surya.
But the main thing that one has to achieve
through Surya is the light within, is the
light within. And if Surya chakra at the Agnya
level is occupied by Lord Jesus Christ then
it is even more essential that the purity
of life, what we call ‘Niti’, is the morality
of life.
Now morality itself has become very much sort
of an argument in the West. People don't have
any sense of absolute morality. On vibrations
of course you know. But they have gone all
against it. Those who are worshippers of Jesus,
those who are the worshippers of the Surya,
of the Saraswati have all gone against it.
Against the powers of Surya, just disobeying
it. Because you cannot be a Surya if you do
not have a proper sense of morality and holiness.
The Surya itself brings light, to see everything
clearly.
So many qualities Surya has got. It dries
up everything that is wet, dirty, filthy.
It dries up all these places, which create
parasites. But so many parasites are created
in the West. Not only parasites, but there
are horrible cults and horrible things which
have come into those countries which are supposed
to be full of light, and in that darkness
they exist. Darkness about their Spirit, darkness
about their own knowledge and darkness about
love. These three things have taken over in
the places where you are supposed to love
light. Light doesn’t mean, light doesn’t
mean what you see with your gross eyes. Light
means from within - the Light of Love. That
one should understand – Light of Love. And
it is so soothing, it’s so sweet, it’s
so beautiful, it’s so enamouring, it’s
so abounding that unless and until you can
feel that light within you - that light which
is of pure love of purity, pure relationships,
pure understanding. If you can develop that
kind of a light within yourself, then the
whole thing will be cleansed. 'Wash me and
I shall be whiter than snow.' This is what
happens to you when you are completely cleansed.
The purest form of nature is within us. The
purest form of nature is within us. Our chakras
are made out of that purest form of nature.
We are the only people who are spoiling it
by our mental thinking, against the same Saraswati’s
power. You are going against Saraswati itself.
Saraswati cleanses all that is impure in nature,
while, with our brain activity, we are spoiling
all that. All our brain activity goes against
pure intelligence. And that’s what one has
to understand - that this pure intelligence,
is not to be soiled by our thinking. Our thinking
can make us so bumptious, so ego-oriented,
so impure, that, we can really eat the poison
and say 'what is wrong with it'? Just the
opposite of Saraswati. If Saraswati is within
us, She gives us Subuddhi, wisdom. And that
is why to worship Saraswati, to worship Surya;
we must have that clear vision as to what
we have to be. What we are doing. What filth
we are living in. What our mind is getting
into. After all we are here for emancipation
and not for just for pampering our ego and
living with our filth that is with us. So
this light has come within us and we should
try to rise above our own mental filth, which
is being created around us.
Apart from that, you have to go higher and
understand that there is, within us, a thing
called ego. And this ego is false, absolutely
false. You do not do anything. Actually when
you turn your eyes here and there, when your
attention is here and there it is nothing
but your ego that is trying to overpower you.
But actually ego is an absolute falsehood
because there is only one ego and that is
of God Almighty, Mahatahamkara.
There is no really any ego that exists. It
is myth. It is a very big myth, because if
you start thinking you are doing everything
- you are doing this, you are doing that - which
you are not doing; then this nonsensical ego
comes in and you start working it out, it
can project in every direction. When it projects
forward, it overpowers others, it tries to
dominate others, tries to kill others, becomes
cruel. When it moves [to the] right side,
it becomes supraconscious. It starts seeing
things, which are absurd, which are foolish,
which are stupid. When it moves left side
then it starts talking - I mean, seeing things
- yourself as a big man, as a big Christ or
as a big Devi or something like Adi Gurus
and 'I am a very great personality' - that
is left sided. When it moves backwards, that
is the dangerous one.
When people become gurus, which are ruining
other people. When their ego moves backwards
then they become gurus, they themselves have
lots of defects in themselves and they try
to pull people into those horrible stuff,
which is described as absolute Naraka. That’s
how, is the movement of ego on all the sides.
Now when people try to use their right Vishuddhi
that is, to talk about themselves, is the
worst of all. Whatever type of ego you may
have, if you start boasting about it and talking
about it, then it encircles, thickens the
walls of ego so much, that it is impossible
to penetrate into that. Because such a person
is completely satisfied with himself and he
believes that he is so. And once he starts
believing into a nonsense like that, it's
an impossibility, is an impossibility to penetrate.
So, when you boast about these things or you
talk big, be careful. You see, you know what
I am, but how many times do I say 'I am that'?
Even if I say once, it makes tremendous vibrations
for you. But how many times do I say so? At
the most if you say something, I say 'yes'.
But I don't say that. If I say it loudly,
I don't know what may happen. The whole thing
might be blasted with that. So, one has to
understand that Mahatahamkara is the one that
acts, that works, that creates. Sometimes
I shout at you. Immediately all the bhoots
run away. Just once I shout. Yesterday, you
saw all the bhoots that were coughing, they
all ran away. Yesterday just I started. So
you should understand that now you are a realized
souls, you can also do the same. Use your
right Vishuddhi to shout at yourself, ‘‘Now
will you please stop boasting, will you stop
talking all this nonsense, will you stop showing
off!'' Then it will stop.
Now this thickening takes place by people
who really are active. Who want to do something
about it, not that they are not active. They
want to do it. But they know only one way,
is to act talkative. They don't understand
that there are inner ways by which you control
it much more. Because they don't want to take
to that, they take to this talking. And once
they take to talking and they talk about it,
the whole power goes. But if they do not talk
about it and keep it within themselves. It’s
alright, you can tell Me about your experiences
or anything, but if you start telling others,
and talking about it too much, then the powers
that you have got will all be disappearing
gradually. And you will just come down to
absolutely lowest level. So one should not
too much talk that “I have this power, I
have this power” or “I see this” or
“I do this,” which is a very wrong thing.
I warn you, don’t try to show off.
Yes, you can talk about My powers. It is all
right. But don't try to talk about your powers.
When it comes, of course, to talk to somebody
who is a negative person or to tell somebody,
then you should say that “we”, not “I”.
“We” have, some of us have felt this power
within us. We have seen people”. It may
be you only, but you need not say, 'I' have.
What you have to say is 'We'. Then you become
the Mahatahamkara. When you say 'We', Yes
some of us', 'we do'. Like in Gregoire's book
also I made it, I saw to it, that he should
not have many 'I's', but he should have 'We'.
'We think', 'we do', 'we'. Means, the whole
collective being, the whole collective organism,
living organism of Sahaja Yogis. So if you
say, 'yes, some of us have got it', that means,
you put yourself down, but put all others
above you. Say: 'Yes, some of us have. I know
some people have this.'
That’'s the way one should do it. Because
if you have to overpower your ego, you must
allow it to spread into everybody else. That’s
how you will make it perfectly all right.
Let it spread. “We, all Sahaja Yogis, we
all”.
But that pride is not there. I've seen that
pride is not there. Still it is very individualistic.
If you start thinking, ''we Sahaja Yogis",
then what happens, that you become one personality,
one organization.
But the person will look down upon other people.
He will see that this person is low, that
person is higher, that person is there. But
he will not think 'We' the Sahaja Yogis, how
beautiful we are. 'We' the body of Sahaja
Yoga, how beautiful we are. So always think
in the words of 'we', so your ego will become
much less, much less, much less. And the same
ego, which looked so funny and absurd, will
form tomorrow, the Ekadesha. Today’s, individual
ego will merge into Ekadesha. But we all must
remember to say 'we' all time.
This is what is today's day, is a great day
for us to change, because the sun has changed
its mood, now. Sun is coming this side. So
let us welcome the Sun, coming to the North
now, this way. And for Australians to say
that though the sun has gone, let us establish
the Sun, the domain of Sun, within ourselves.
Because Sun never disappears from our inside.
So that is how we have to take a mood by which
we should think of one personality, all of
us together, all of us together. And anybody
who tries to be something separate or different,
he will drop out. I will drop him out. Whatever
it may be, it will drop out. So you just don’t
worry yourself, anybody who tries to be singled
out or anything.
Everybody must do whatever they like, to nurture
the whole, to help the whole, to emancipate
the whole. But not to, in anyway, put anyone
down. Always. Because this is not the way
the Sahaja Yoga is. Sahaja Yoga only works
in collectivity. And the one who has developed
this permeating spirit, is a real Sahaja Yogi.
Who has not, is not!
Whatever you may think of yourself, I have
nothing to say. But this permeating personality,
which moves from places to places, whether,
you talk or not. Like your Mother is. Whether
I meet you or not, makes no difference, but
I am permeating through all of you, by little,
little things, also, I am there with you.
So like that, try to permeate into each other
and see the beauty. And you’ll enjoy yourself
the best because that is the biggest thing.
That's the biggest thing that is to be achieved.
Because this ego you know makes you like a
nutshell and you just cannot have a rapport
with that beauty of permeation and just see
how the notes move into each other.
It will be a great idea today, it’s great
thing today [that] we are having Puja in Dhulia.
Like the Dhulia means the dust, dust. And
one day I had written in childhood, a poem,
I remember. Very interesting poem it was - I
don't know where it is now - but which said
that I want to be like a dust particle which
moves with the wind. It goes everywhere. Can
go, sit on the head of a king, or can go and
fall at the feet of someone. And it can go
and sit on a little flower, and it can go
and sit everywhere. But I want to be a particle
of dust. That is fragrant, that is nourishing,
that is enlightening.
Like that, I had written a very beautiful
poem, I must have been about seven years of
age, I remember - 'To be a dust particle',
I remember that very clearly, long time back,
that I should be a dust particle. So that
I’ll permeate into people. Which is a very
big thing - to become a dust particle of that
kind. Whatever you touch, you see, that becomes
{sounds like ‘enwavened’ but I don’t
think that’s a word – “enlightened”??},
whatever you just feel, that has fragrance.
It’s such a great thing to be like that.
And that was My desire, and it has been achieved.
At that young age, I had this idea of becoming
a dust particle and today just while talking
to you, I remembered that I wanted to be that,
and that is what this place is.
And Raulbai is like that. She’s a very simple
woman, very simple woman, and she lives like
a very simple person but she has a sense of
permeation. And now there are so many Sahaja
Yogis, yesterday who came. I am sure that
they will take up, Sahaja Yoga, very well.
And there are lots of Sahaja Yogis from Dhulia
now, and I am sure there are going to be more
people. I hope you have met all of them. Make
friends with all of them. Try to know them
who they are. They may not know English - so
get somebody to translate. Talk to them and
be nice to them, be friendly with them. I
wanted you to meet them for permeation. You
should know who are the people here, who are
in Nasik. Because somehow we never meet the
Sahaja Yogis, you see, who are in that particular
place, and when we go back we have only one
or two addresses. It is not a good idea. Try
to see how many people there are. Ask questions
about them, and all that.
This permeation is only possible when your
ego starts permeating all around, and this
is the way to overcome the problems of the
right side and that is how to worship Saraswati.
Because Saraswati has a Veena in Her hand
and that Veena is the primordial instrument,
which She plays like music, and the smusic
penetrates into the heart. You don't know
how it goes into you and how it works out.
And that’'s how a person who is a Sahaja
Yogi should permeate - like music into other
people.
She has so many qualities, as I told you,
which cannot be described in one lecture.
But one of the greatest qualities of Hers
is that She ends up into subtler things. Like
the Mother Earth will end up into fragrance.
Music will end up into melodies, like that
whatever She creates ends up into something
greater. Matter, whatever She produces, ends
up into aesthetics. If matter does not have
aesthetics then it is gross. Like that everything.
Now you will say what is water. Water becomes
the river Ganges.
These are the subtler things. So the matter
gets into subtler thing because it has to
permeate, it has to permeate. So everything
whatever it is. And the best of all is the
air. That air becomes the vibrations.
So you can see how, whatever has come out
from
this matter, from these five elements, becomes
that subtle thing. Of course, the left and
right side both work it out because the love
has to work on this and when love acts on
matter it becomes that, and
that is how one has
to look at your own lives, to make it
a beautiful combination of
love and matter.
May
God bless you!