Having a Good Tongue
Delhi India, 2nd April 1976
I was telling you about
how difficult it is to be a Mother and a Guru,
because both are very contradictory functions.
And specially for a person who wants to
be in charge of your salvation,
to be the Moksha Dayini,
it is extremely difficult.
Because the path is so delicate and so treacherous
that all of you have to come yourselves, walk across.
And if you
fall this side or that side there is disaster for you.
I am watching your climbing
and I see you coming up
with a Mother’s heart
and a Guru’s hand.
And then I get the glimpses of people falling.
I try to tell them "Come up!"
Sometimes I shout.
Sometimes I pull them up.
Sometimes I love them, caress them.
You can yourself judge, within yourself,
how much I have worked on you,
how much I have loved you.
But how much do you love yourself is the point.
I have told you that for a Sahaja Yogi
the whole thing should be decided by the witnessing power.
Now the witnessing power is silent, it doesn’t talk,
if you are a very talkative person
then it’s not going to help you much.
You have to come in balance.
For the first time in this incarnation I have started talking
and I get throat trouble
because I’m not used to this kind of talking.
So for you people,
it is necessary that you should not talk
unless and until you feel like talking.
And very few sentences, conclusive.
As I told you before, the tongue
is the master of all the organs of distraction.
If you could master your tongue,
you are master of all of them, in a way.
Because everything has to be palatable.
For example, you look at a woman,
if she’s not palatable
then she may be beautiful but you don’t want to look at her.
She decides, the tongue decides, about a person.
If you want to eat some food,
if it is not palatable
then you don’t want to eat that food.
It has to be palatable.
Then a thought also,
a thought has to be palatable.
If it is not palatable, you are not going to have it.
So the deciding factor is the tongue,
the roots of the tongue
goes up to the Vishuddhi chakra,
which controls your ego and superego,
or you can say that
the tongue is reflected in superego and ego in a way.
Through your tongue, when you speak,
one can make out whether you are in the realm
of the ego or superego.
She expresses, she decides.
But if you understand her,
then you know how to handle her.
She’s your friend
and Saraswati Herself resides in your tongue.
If you know how to handle your tongue
then Sahaja Yoga can rise very hight up.
Because when others meet you, as Sahaja Yogis,
they also see how the way you talk,
the way you eat, the way that things are palatable to you.
It is the tongue that decides.
If you are really very much evolved, you’ll be amazed
that if you eat some food somewhere, immediately the tongue
will immediately throw it out.
It won’t have it, if it is something wrong.
If some prasad, so-called, is given to you, which is
given by some wrong type of man,
immediately your tongue will throw it away.
It won’t be able to take it in.
And even if you take, somehow or other,
it’s forced down in the stomach,
still the tongue will inform the brain that throw it out,
and the brain will inform the stomach that – throw it out.
It will be unpalatable.
So the action of Vishnu
in the stomach up to the action of Shri Krishna,
I mean, the same personality,
is all judged by your tongue.
So, you must know how pure,
holy, your tongue should be.
But when you take the name
of your Mother with this tongue,
you must know it has to be the holiest of holiest.
It is very important how you use your tongue.
Those who talk very bluntly
are just the same
as those who talk very sweetly,
to get something out of you is the intention.
As I have told you, it controls ego and superego.
Even if Sahaja Yogis
understand that the witness is also here,
at the Vishuddhi chakra.
So your witnessing powers
will increase and decrease
according to your tongue.
Of course it controls sixteen sub-plexuses.
It also controls the muscles of the eyes,
it controls all these muscles,
it controls the palate,
it controls the teeth.
It controls the ears.
But ears, you hear something you cannot control it.
Tongue you can,
because that is the thing which releases,
which goes out.
With the ear you cannot give anything to others.
That is just one way.
This [tongue] is double way thing;
you take in something and also can throw out something,
it has a double purpose.
It is a very important organ.
And that’s why we have to look after our tongues.
When the Kundalini is rising
that means one thing is there,
that your attention has to become subtle.
From gross to subtle.
But it has to become subtler and subtlest
and then it has to go beyond that.
By becoming subtle only it comes up through the Agya.
Because Agya is just like a hole in a needle.
So it penetrates through that to the subtleness.
Because of that subtleness,
your attention sees everything,
but in a subtle form.
Now, this is a new experience for you.
That’s why you do not recognise what is that.
In a group of Sahaja Yogis,
you can witness these things very carefully and clearly.
There is one person
whose eyes are roving still, around.
He’s a Sahaja Yogi, he’s sitting down,
he’s looking here, looking there, looking that side,
who is coming, who is going.
Of course, this person is still in the gross state you can say,
though he’s got his attention up here
by Mataji’s pulling it out,
you see, and hanging onto it!
But still the person himself is
still dragging outside into the gross.
So don’t bother about that.
But even the person who is now, say, attentive,
you can say attentive, you see, because words are not so precise.
Even if you notice such a person, you’ll find
these two forces in a very subtle way are acting:
one is his subtle ego, another is the subtle superego.
When you become subtle,
suddenly you get also powers of the subtle.
Let us see the ego side of it.
You start feeling, inside yourself,
in a very subtle way, that
you do not recognise that it is ego.
It is too subtle to be recognised.
That you have got powers now to cure.
You start feeling that now you have powers to raise the Kundalini.
See how it goes on segmenting into it.
Then you start feeling
you have powers to express yourself,
because you think that you have learnt Sahaja Yoga,
and now you know the essence of it and you can talk about it.
This subtle ego develops into you
and the fourth type of subtle ego develops
when you see the other person’s superego is developing.
That is the most dangerous.
It so happens that some people,
who’s superego develops now, because they have had
previous gurus, previous problems,
previous…you see
the way they have been following religion, some mistakes and all that.
Because of their mistakes, their superego develops.
You see something happening to them,
say Mr X he finds,
that a superego is coming onto him, some negativity is flowing into him.
So, his ego starts developing against that, a force.
In a subtle way.
Now he calls it a positive force, it is a positive force, sort of,
but he over-crosses it.
When he over-crosses that side,
he decides to push a superego of another person,
he trips over.
He thinks he’s doing the right thing, of course he is doing in a way,
but to a point.
And then he becomes very hot-tempered.
He goes on passing remarks about others.
He says harsh things.
That’s how the subtlest point starts.
To a point is alright,
to a point because
in this I would say Ganesh and
Jesus should be treated as the judging points.
Christ did not mind when he was crucified.
Not only that but he asked for forgiveness for all those.
But if His Mother was even touched by somebody,
he would have taken out his Eleven Rudras and killed them.
That’s the point.
When it comes to your Mother,
then of course,
your ego and superego both have a meaning.
But beyond that,
if it starts directed at every Sahaja Yogi,
then you don’t know where to go,
have the balance.
For example then,
such people, anything done
to them also they identify themselves with Mother
and they think, “No, no, he has said it to me then
he did it to Mother also.” It is not.
You must know where you are criticised
and where your Mother is criticised.
These are two things. That’s why I said judging point is Christ.
When he was crucified, he accepted it,
though he was so much one with his Mother.
But still he could strike that line.
When you are crucified, you are not Christ,
but if anybody says anything against the Mother
then of course.
Now try to understand yourself, now you’re watching yourself,
whatever I am saying you are watching yourself.
It is for your good.
That is how you find, somewhere,
a person who gets a superego invasion.
First of all superego invasion is
very, very deep and subtle. It’s extremely deep.
It comes into you in such a manner,
that you do not understand it.
The other person who is very positive, so-called,
he’ll think that “That person has got a negativity.”
But he won’t know that he’s over-crossing
his positivity towards negativity itself!
Because once you cross this line you go to this side.
Once you cross this line you go to this side.
So immediately you are becoming negative once you cross
this point and it’s the Sahastrara, is the Brahmarandra.
Beyond the Brahmarandra, if you are pushing down,
then you are crossing to the other side.
You are playing into hands of other people.
Now, you must judge yourself and see, “Now
Hello Mr X, how are you behaving now?”
Immediately you become a witness, you see, witness of yourself.
Now how the superego and ego, you see sometimes in
in some people,
sometimes the ego presses the superego
and the superego presses the ego.
I have seen it.
They don’t know whether they are egoistical
or whether they are dominated.
They really do not know,
they cannot decide.
Because it’s such a going on,
wobbling all the time.
That’s why I say, “Baith jao”
you must sit down, settle down.
See for yourself. “Am I settled?”
Watch in yourself.
Even you can feel the force,
actually you can feel the force moving from this side to this side.
You’ll feel the force moving from this side to this,
try to bring it in the centre.
Now, ego and superego,
when they go on like that,
you can say wobble from one to another,
it happens like this:
at one moment you start feeling dejected,
frustrated, fed up with yourself.
“Nonsense! Get out!”
The other moment you sit on yourself,
sit on other people.
You ask other to “Get out!
This is bad! I didn’t like that man,
that fellow came, that fellow caught me,
this thing happened, that thing happened.”
Two extremes you move to.
That’s not the way to Sahaja Yoga.
Sahaja Yoga.
Saha-ja means that you are a witness.
Saha-ja.
It has double meaning.
Sahaja is normally used for a word which is simple.
Sahaj. You are in a Sahaj method,
means you are a witness, you watch it.
Look at these trees,
they are just witnessing,
they are not saying anything,
they are just there.
It is to be.
It is just to be at this point.
Are we that? Every moment, dealing with anything.
Then you will not have any organisational problems.
You have organisational problems
because you are not a witness.
You’ll find two types of people.
One who will say, “I’m suffering too much”,
the others who will say, “No, not me!”
Then they interchange also.
You see, their attitudes interchange, it’s absurd.
But you can just know where to stop it
and become a witness, silent.
After talking for one minute, you just become silent.
That’s the best way, I think, I can say – a practical way.
Is for your tongue, is to be silent.
As far as possible to be silent and be watching.
But some people are silent and brooding,
that’s the worst thing that you are doing.
No! Silent and watching.
Neither brooding, not planning how to hurt others,
and then suddenly your sentences will come out
which would be so filthy, so cutting,
so horrid, so full of venom,
that you think, “From where it has come? Oh God!”
Such silence is absolutely useless.
It should be like a river flowing.
The river has its own depth
and on top it is flowing, it’s just one mast.
That kind of a silence one should have.
Not a forced one but a silence of a witness.
Even such a person is talking inside, the flow of the silence,
you are one with that silence, it is filling you up all the time.
And you can witness that in every leaf,
in every movement of the leaf, you see the silence moving.
They do not speak, but they manifest it.
In the same way you do not speak, you manifest.
Of course, human beings are higher than them because they speak,
but if speech becomes a burden,
a problem, a cutting instrument, it is better not to speak.
Another thing a Sahaja Yogi must know,
that eyes are very important for Sahaja Yoga.
When the Kundalini rises,
then the dilatation of the pupils takes place, because
you have seen the children how their eyes are dilated.
Just gaping at everything, what is happening.
Just gaping, silence, complete.
Silent seeing goes on through the eyes.
And that’s why eyes are very important.
You must learn to fix your eyes within yourself, in your heart.
Humble down, in your heart!
Fix your eyes in your heart!
I say that way, but I don’t know if you can do it.
I don’t know if you can do it,
but if you could do it that’s a very good way of doing things.
Looking at everyone, gazing at everyone,
seeing this, seeing that,
is a very bad exercise for your eyes,
it’s a very bad habit.
Try to keep your eyes low, on the earth, Mother Earth,
watching the lower part of the body than the face.
Because face, if you are made that way
that you can watch the faces is all right
but you are not yet made.
Best thing is to see to the feet.
And your eyes will touch their gross sense, feet,
from where the sensation of vibrations go up,
upward, and the Kundalini rises better.
Actually those who suffer from low Kundalini rising,
if they could rub oil on their feet and wash their feet,
it’s a very good thing.
That’s why Christ washed the feet of his disciples.
I wish I could do that if you allow Me, in public,
because the whole grossness is in the feet
and if you touch somebody with your eyes,
realised people I am saying.
Their feet, most of their grossness will disappear.
And you won’t have that much problem with them.
That’s why Christ washed the feet of His disciples.
You also wash your feet and keep them clean,
so that the grossness drops out.
I have explained
in brief way, but if you want to ask Me questions, ask,
because still I find that the Sahaja Yogis
are not rising as fast as they could.
Because
bringing Kundalini up to this, and up to this is possible for Me,
but taking it back into your gross being, is your own job
which you have to do it.
In Marathi as they say, “Da adi karatza maga paiya” –
I have built the top, the dome for you,
and the dome is now to be supported by you.
I have taken you to the dome,
but you cannot bring it down,
because either you are frustrated with yourself,
by being frustrated what are you going to gain?
Or else, you are frustrated with others.
Just be silent and be witnessing.
As Sai Baba has said, saburi, patience, it comes in.