I bow to all the seekers of truth. It was
a thing of great joy to Me to come to Sheffield
again. Always this name Sheffield created
a kind of a mystery in My mind. The word Sheffield
could be the ‘She Field’ and She is the
Mother energy, the energy within you which
creates this field within you and is in the
Gita. Shri Krishna has talked about the field
that we all have a Pradesh - is the field
but Desh means the field and the enlightened
one is the Pradesh. And that same thing happens
to us when this Kundalini rises within you.
This Holy Ghost which is described in the
bible, She is the Kundalini, She is the Mother.
Actually people don’t know anything about
Holy Ghost and we didn’t give Christ much
chance to speak about it. He could only speak
for three and a half years, is nothing. I
can tell you three and a half years in this
land anywhere in the whole world it’s so
difficult even to convince four people that
they have to seek the truth, it’s very difficult.
Especially in the land where He was born.
It was full of ignorance, complete ignorance.
And in that ignorance to speak about realization,
to speak about second birth, even to speak
about God was so difficult. And He was just
crucified for nothing at all, today we may
have big organizations in His name but when
He lived nobody listened to Him and they crucified
Him. He talked about Holy Ghost but this Holy
Ghost had been interpreted by people in various
ways. They’ve never been able to say what
is this Holy Ghost but logically you can come
to some conclusion yourselves because you’re
all intelligent people.
We talk about the Father, all right, and then
the Son. Have you heard of a father producing
a son? You have to have the Mother. It’s
the Mother who creates the Son. Now why this
Holy Ghost was kept as a secret, never talked
about it because Christ was afraid – not
afraid but was cautious I should say, because
such people are never afraid of anything.
He was cautious to talk about His Mother because
if they had harmed His Mother by any chance,
then He had eleven powers of destruction and
the destruction of world would have come much
earlier than today. He had to play the whole
drama of His crucifixion and that’s how
He had to go through all that.
In that process He didn’t want to involve
His Mother. He didn’t want to explain about
Holy Ghost and He knew that it will be later
on explained. But logically we must understand
what is this Holy Ghost we are talking about?
[A dove?] All right, it’s peace. How do
you get to the peace? Supposing it is the
symbol of peace. Today we see in the world
we see these televisions and we hear, we read
newspapers and we are shattered and so much
of friction, so much of sin. People are not
even worried about what they are doing, to
what extent human beings can go you can see
the way a three year-old child was molested,
the innocence is attacked like this. Why?
Why human beings cannot control their desires
which are so devilish? Why there is so much
of friction in this world? We have to think
about it and we must also think positively
what we can do about it.
Now at the same time there are so many seekers
of truth born on this earth. This is the special
time and that’s why they are born on this
earth. But they are misled, they go to wrong
people, they get identified with wrong people.
When I came here, the person who is organizing
Sahaja Yoga here told Me that, “Mother,
they come, they get their realization and
then they disappear, they start doubting.”
I said, “That’s a good sign, it’s a
healthy sign.”
Let them doubt because the way they jump into
all these horrible things like gurus and this
and that, the way they accept as if they have
no personality, they have no discretion. The
way they jump into even drugs I don’t know,
what happens that we have lost all our personality.
They took to any fashion, to any nonsense
so easily and to reality with such difficulty.
We have lost our discretion that’s what
it is, but doesn’t matter whatever it is
use your brains. Understand that this world
is not created to be destroyed. You’re not
created out of amoeba just to be destroyed
by something nonsensical like drug(s) or some
sort of a guru; nobody has right to destroy
you. They cannot create you and they cannot
destroy you, nor you have any right to destroy
yourself because you cannot create yourself,
the one who is your Creator, the one who has
loved you who has so beautifully made this
beautiful human life is responsible. He is
the one who is so earnest about it that you
should get your realization, that you should
get your second birth, that you should be
baptized in the real sense of the word.
I agree religions have shown funny things,
some thing so absurd that one can start doubting
their credibility. I admit that, but that
is the mistake of human beings not of the
divine. Divine created beautiful flowers on
the same tree of life time and time again
but when the people plucked these flowers
and said, “These are mine, these are mine.”
They became dead and ugly and they are fighting
now in the name of God, in the name of religion.
Imagine, how can you do such merciless, horrible,
brutal things to other human beings but this
must shatter you, this must make you understand
and you should be aware.
Get out of your sleep now and know that you
are the people who are seekers. You have to
be more aware, more understanding of your
responsibility. It is no use standing there
with a banner saying we want peace. How? The
peace has to be within. Human beings are not
at peace. You see in the art you see today
the art has left the Divine behind, the art
has become so, chaotic. The expression of
esthetics are just missing there’s no beauty
in it. You feel the chaotic heart of an artist
being expressed in that what he’s made,
why? Because he has lost himself.
Now it is the responsibility of you people
living in these modern times to become that,
that source of peace, which is your Spirit,
and the Spirit resides within you. It is all
the time there it is the witness of this field
I should say the She Field, the field that
is to be enlightened by this Kundalini that
exists within you but is not enlightened,
it has not come into your attention. The Spirit
has not come into your attention, that’s
why we think this is all talk. There are people
who are so called intellectuals; they say
this is all talk, talk, talk. For a mental
conception it is impossible to tell what lies
beyond it because mind is a limited thing.
You have to go beyond mind; you have to be
triggered into the space to see that. The
evolution has been just like your spacecraft
going into the space. First, the first thing
comes up is the physical being, explodes gets
its accelerations then becomes your mental
being, your emotional being, your spiritual
being and then it has to go to the space.
That is the time today is the space age. When
we talk of the space age you think of the
space, which is beyond this gravity, there
is some space, which is beyond all gravities,
beyond all temptations, beyond all slaveries.
We talk of our freedom, where is the freedom
I just don’t think see. Anybody comes now
and says all right, have this drug for so
much money. We are finished with it. Anybody
comes and says all right, you take up your
clothes this way, live like this, we just
accept without thinking, without understanding.
We have given up the traditions alright whatever
was wrong in the tradition should have been
given no doubt but everything if you give
up then remember we are falling down. We are
coming down we are not going up. When you
are going up you do not give up the staircase.
Staircase is there and you go up higher and
higher. No tradition is so bad is to be discarded
but if it is so it should be discarded but
that is what is the discretion and that discretion
is so much lacking today that people can’t
see that what we are doing collectively or
individually is not constructive.
Now I would say that this is not the time
for us just to sit back on the fence and see
which side we fall. Either you will fall into
hell or you’ll go to heaven. This is the
situation, we are so precariously placed,
I do not want to frighten you because there
is the Spirit within you just to be enlightened,
it’s your own, it is there, it’s your
own property. It’s not Mine, it’s yours,
it’s your own treasure within you. Only
this treasure is to be exposed to you. Now
for that how can you pay? First thing you
must know you cannot pay for it. If I say
that then all the gurus are after My life,
they want to kill Me, they want to do all
those things. You cannot take money for God’s
work.
We sold Christ, you know that. He didn’t
take any money, did He? We have got such a
great personality like Christ and we just
want to discard Him, make fun of Him, say
all kinds of things about Him, intellectualize
Him, organize Him. You cannot touch Him. You’re
still human beings, you have to be the Spirit
to understand that Great Soul which came on
this earth. In the same way any other soul,
which was an Incarnation who came on this
earth, cannot be understood by our normal
understanding, but only a person with that
pure intelligence can see this point that
I’m not satisfied with what I am, I have
to go beyond.
There’s some transformation needed and how
will this transformation take place? We can’t
do anything about it because we have done
nothing to become human beings did we? What
did we do to become human beings? Nothing,
so going beyond also must be built in within
us. The way we became human beings there must
be some built-in process by which we will
become that higher being. Now the problem
at the human level is that somebody has to
talk at human level. Say at the fish level,
one fish had to come up so the others could
follow that fish. At human level, some human
being has to tell you about it. That’s how
Christ came on this earth. I mean we have
a quite a long traditional history of all
these great people came on this earth at different
places, at different times. According to the
time they had to talk. When they talked say,
about the flowers, say they talked that they
are Gods, like Socrates talked about Gods,
like Confucius talked about Gods. When they
talked we have to please our gods we started
doubting. What god’s he’s talking about?
Whatever they saw we could not see, all right.
Then they thought no use talking about gods.
If you talk about gods then it becomes a sort
of a worship of something that is a flower.
We talk about flowers then we think we have
become God and we talk about flower all the
time. But we have to get to the honey. How
do we do it? So they said, “All right, don’t
talk about God, talk about abstract, talk
about the fragrance, talk about the honey
itself.” But how do you become, how do you
get to the honey? By talking about it again
it became a talk and talk and talk. So how
it has to happen that you have to become the
bee, the transformation has to take place.
First understand this simple point that some
transformation has to take place within us
to go or to penetrate into that unknown divine
which we call as collective unconscious. Something
has to happen to us that we have to become
subtler beings. Don’t be satisfied and don’t
self certify yourself that “I’m all right;
nothing wrong with me.” No, nothing’s
wrong with you. Y0ou’re all right, but you
have still to be connected to the mains. Like
this instrument, if it is not connected to
the mains it won’t work. It is as simple
as this instrument that you are to be connected
with the mains and for that you have got built-in
process that has to work out.
It’s nice we have instruments in these modern
times that I can use them as an analogies
to explain to you. For others they had to
use the analogies of the seed that how we
imbed the seed in the Mother Earth and the
Mother Earth has the capacity to sprout the
seed and the seed has the built-in map of
all the trees it is going to create. Now if
you look at the seed do you see the miracle
behind the little seed there? In India we
have huge big banyan trees and if you see
the seed is so small that it’s quite microscopic
and it makes huge big banyan trees. How does
it make? We never wonder. Whatever is the
wonder, the mystery of this creation we never
wonder about it, we never look at it, look
at ourselves, what are we? We are human beings,
these eyes, can we make eyes like this.
We are making computers, but look at this
brain the computer that is within, we don’t
have to program it nothing it just knows.
You know I’m sitting here, I know you’re
sitting here just looking at it. You don’t
have to go through the process of finding
out what is the process of it and then it
moves the whole thing and gives you the program
and out of the program something comes out.
It is there just at the same instant you know
what is it. This kind of a computer is made
for us, why? To be wasted, to be confused,
to be ended up in a lunatic asylum? We must
have the proper value system about ourselves.
First of all we are human beings made from
amoeba to this stage in thousands of years
with great care and delicacy, for what purpose
we must ask the question, why are we made?
Are we made here just to ruin ourselves or
not to do anything just like blind people
going about hitting here hitting there. No,
we are made to become the Spirit and the whole
system is built-in within you. And we have
to go into another realm of our awareness
into a new dimension. Now these dimensions
can be also misinterpreted. It’s such a
dangerous line we are into because these modern
times are full of horrible people.
Like somebody says that “All right, I can
hear voices." So what?
"I can see light." So what?
Or somebody says that, "All right, I feel
like I’m flying in the air, I leave my body."
So what?
What have you got? You are under the control
of something else, you don’t know anything.
Logically you must know what you are doing,
what’s happening to you, what is within
you, you must know each and everything. You
have to know that if I have become the light
then I must have the power of the light, I
don’t see the light. If I see the light
I’m not the light. If I become the light,
then I have the power of light. In the light
you see clearly and that is what you get is
collective consciousness. You can feel another
person’s Chakras, you can feel your centers
and if you know how to cure that, how to improve
that and how to raise the Kundalini which
is a very, very simple thing - because it
is so fundamental that’s why it is so simple.
You can cure yourself, you can cure others
and you can live very joyously within yourself.
This is what you have to have and that’s
how you will realize that we are part and
parcel of the whole. The microcosm becomes
one with the macrocosm. Not by talking about
it by saying about it by mental projections
no, it happens to you, it really happens to
you when you become the spirit, it works on
your central nervous system, you know what
you are and what others are. That they’re
part and parcel of you is known to you on
your central nervous system.
So we come to conclusion that if we have to
become the Spirit what should we do? Nothing.
What do we do when we put the seed in the
Mother Earth? Nothing, but once you become
that then you have to look after it. When
the seed is sprouted, comes out of the Mother
Earth then we have to look after it, and that’s
the point where most of the western people
fail. The reason is this knowledge is not
known to them. Their knowledge is like the
tree, which is exposed outside. They don’t
have the knowledge of the roots. This is the
knowledge of the roots and we have to give
and take. We have to talk about it; we have
to understand that there’s nothing like
India and England two different things. England
I call it the heart of the universe, it is,
and India is the Kundalini of the universe.
The Kundalini has to know England and England
has to know the Kundalini. If it is one whole
body then one part has to know another part.
So all your misconceptions, or conceptions,
or maybe right ideas are all become absolutely
evident, vividly seen because you get the
light of your own Spirit. That Spirit is missing.
That Spirit which is all the time watching
you, witnessing you has to be enlightened
in the sense that the Spirit must enlighten
your attention. That’s how you become the
attention and wherever you put the attention
you act. It’s very surprising, like if you’re
watching the television, watching the television,
it’s unreal and you’re looking at the
television. They cannot act on you and you
cannot act on them because it is artificial.
But supposing there’s a gentleman sitting.
He’s a living body not artificial you are
talking to that person and that person is
talking to you it acts. But this attention
which is a subtler being within you - your
attention - supposing you project it to someone
and it acts for the benevolence, never for
destruction but for the benevolence. When
it acts for the benevolence you are amazed,
how does it happen? How can my attention have
the power of benevolence? Because in your
attention is now the light of the Spirit.
So you become benevolent.
You know the truth whether it is true or not.
How will you know? I was once in Pune and
you see in England they say I’m preaching,
I’m preaching about Hinduism, I’m converting
everybody to Hindus. And in India they say
I’m converting them to Christianity - because
I’m doing both you see, [laughter from Shri
Mataji and from the audience] So they have
a great objection about Me everywhere because
they don’t see the integrated work about
Sahaja Yoga, all right?
So they said that “This is wrong, whatever
She’s saying is not correct because we are
Brahmins and we know about our shastras and
we are Brahmins.”
But they didn’t tell Me all this. They talked
all these things to others and they said,
“We can’t have Her in our hall, She’s
not a Brahmin and She’s in a Christian family
we can’t have Her.”
So the Brahmins, as usual all priests as they’re
always against the truth you see they were
against the truth there also as Brahmins.
I didn’t know all these things but suddenly
I felt and I said, "Whosoever are Brahmins
among you please come forward."
So four five you see very hefty people came
and sat in front like this. I said," Really
are you Brahmins?"
“Yes” they said.
“All right, all put your hands towards Me,
like this.”
They put their hands like this towards Me
and what happened that they start shaking
like this.
I said, “What’s happening? Stop it, why
are shaking?
He said to the others who are there they are
also shaking. I said yes but ask them from
where they come. They said we are certified
lunatics coming from a lunatic asylum [audience
laughs] because Mother has cured some lunatics
so we are sitting here. Then they realized
that they were also quite lunatic [audience
laughs again] because they’re fundamentalists.
If you go to extremes you become lunatic,
I mean lunatics at least can be put in the
lunatic asylum but these people are going
around everywhere, you don’t know how to
control them, all over the world they are
creating such problems every, every country
has them. Somewhere they are very sophisticated
so you can’t make them out somewhere they
are very closed so you know they are there
but some are can be very subtle you can’t
make them out but you cannot make them budge
from whatever they are holding onto.
So this is how relatively first you realize
what is the Truth. With these vibrations,
with the vibrations that flow that you feel
when the Kundalini crosses through your Brahmarandra
as they call it, we can call the fontanel
bone area you start feeling the cool breeze
of the Holy Ghost coming out of your head.
Then also you start feeling sometimes little
late in your fingers the cool breeze coming
in.
Now some people are very proud, "Oh, I’m
not feeling anything."
That’s not a good thing; if you’re not
feeling there’s something wrong. Somewhere
something missing, normally you should. Children
feel it very fast because they’re so innocent,
not yet spoiled by anything. They are not
so egoistical; they do not have these barriers.
Some sort of problem is there that you’re
not feeling the cool breeze. You should because
this is the All Pervading Power of God which
surrounds us, is everywhere and every one
of you should feel that cool breeze.
Once you start feeling the cool breeze then
you become the joy because first of course
you want to try with everything. "Is it cool
breeze? Is it cool breeze? That is cool breeze.
Should I go or not? Let me see now, if it
is cool breeze I’ll go otherwise."
You go on like that. Then you realize this
is the truth, this is the truth, and then
the joy of finding the truth emerges. But
in India it’s just the other way round.
They’re not bothered because they know what
happens. They know; they have the knowledge
of the roots, so they know what is to be found
out. We don’t have to go very far, even,
so near, I mean, few years back we should
say was, we had Nanaka, we had Kabira. They
talked about it very clearly they told about
this so vividly that anybody with any sense
should understand. Especially Kabira who was
such a great poet and such a great incarnation,
I would say the way he talked right from all
these Brahmins to all the hypocrites and everything
he gave them left and right. He was like Saint
Michael with a sword in his hand cutting everybody.
Like your William Blake, he was really like
your William Blake who gave left and right
to all these nonsensical people. He has talked
about it, he very clearly describing Sahaj.
He said, Nanaka has said (???) you can only
get Samadhi through Sahaja.
Sahaja means spontaneous, only spontaneously
can you get it. Then you have got Kabira who
was treated like a (shidule?) caste. Like
a (shidule?) caste he was treated. Nobody
respected him. Then we had Ramdas another
one a great man I’m told, there is a temple
of this Ramdas. I was so amazed that in England
it should come and prosper. They were treated
just like (shidule?) caste by these people
nobody would listen to them. Nobody would
allow them to come in a temple, these great
saints, because they were not be a born in
a Brahmin family; and these great people have
talked, Nanaka has talked very clearly, very
recently they have talked about these things.
Hundred years back only. William Blake has
talked about Sahaja Yoga. He has said, "The
men of God, men of God" - that’s you - "will
become prophets and they will have powers
to make others prophet." He had such hopes
of making England into Jerusalem, but where
are those English? I have still to meet many.
I’ve worked in this country for twelve years,
relentlessly. India I’ve worked very little
but we have thousand fold people who have
got realization in India. They may be poor
but they know what they have to get, to them
to get to their self realization is the thing.
Nothing else matters, they do not intellectualize,
they know already this is it, this is it.
Everyone knows, right from President downward
everyone knows what to expect, but whatever
is our knowledge has been, we have to know
that this outside knowledge whatever we have
has to have roots and we have to go to our
roots. We cannot live with this outside knowledge,
we have to know ourselves. Everybody is talking
about self-knowledge. There have been so many
books, so many things, I mean so much of seeking
is on, that we cannot just avoid getting to
our spirit, we have to get to it but the only
problem where I stumble down is that people
do not have (?). They’re very frivolously
treating the whole thing, those who have got
realization for them the Kingdom of God is
awaiting. They are not only welcome but they’ll
be cherished and that’s what has to be done.
You have to cherish your Spirit, your Self
- you’ve not done it. Only just getting
realization, feeling satisfied about it itself
is not sufficient. “Now I’m realized,
all right, I’ve got the cool breeze, I’m
this.” No, you have to grow. It’s still
a sapling that has to grow, for that you don’t
have to pay anything, nothing. Here these
people, really I tell you, they are working
so hard because they have achieved a certain
height in Sahaja Yoga. They don’t take any
money. They were just like you, they had to
work hard to first establish themselves, because
that is the time where people want to say,
"No, Mother said Sahaj, so all right, we’ll
sit at home."
That is only for sprouting I said Sahaj, but
we have to look after because we have had
conditionings, we have had problems, we have
had physical problems, we have had social
problems, we have had psychological problems.
They are to be attended to and the Kundalini
just goes and raise this energy there. Unless
and until you know how to maneuver it or work
it out, it is very difficult for this Kundalini
to manage by Herself. You have to show the
will. If you do not have the will nobody can
force on you. The Divine is not going to fall
at your feet. "All right, all right, get your
realization." You have to knock at the door,
and these doors are only six - not many. Six
doors which are partly opened out, again closing,
again opening out. You have to just know how
to knock and how to keep them open, finished.
Then you become the light, and once you become
the light you give light to others.
That’s how this world is going to be saved.
No other way out, no other way out. We have
to have transformation; we have to become
the Spirit. We have to be enlightened and
to be the light in the Great Being that is
our Creator, our Preserver and the One who
is our existence itself. All these things
are so simple. They may look bombastic when
we see from outside, but when you come inside
it’s so simple, it’s very easy. Sahaj
also has another meaning that’s “very
easy” - apart from it is spontaneous, it
is very easy. We don’t want to do something
easy. Like if we can eat our food like this
we’ll not, we’ll have to take our hand
like this, and if you can eat in a difficult
way then it’s very good. That’s human
nature. They want to do something like that.
Like some people suggested to Me, "Mother
when You go to India and settle down there,
then we’ll make these people that, ‘If
you have to get realization, you have to go
to Mother. Then you must stay on a mountaintop
where there will be freezing cold.’ Let
them climb up seven miles and then they will
come to You and they’ll get their realization.
Otherwise they will not because their ego
will not be satisfied with given things."
What about Me? I don’t want to trouble you,
why should you? I’ve taken all the troubles;
Christ has taken all the troubles for you.
Everybody has taken troubles, you better enjoy
now. You have to enjoy it; just you have to
get it.
There’s no end to My lectures. I’ve been
lecturing and lecturing and lecturing and
I would say that this subject is so interesting
that all here there are at least 60 percent
people who must have heard thousands of My
lectures. Still they would like to hear more
and more [Shri Mataji laughs as She speaks]
so I would suggest that we finish at this
point, but know that once you become the knowledge
it’s easier to understand what we are saying.
It’s very simple but only thing you have
to become the Spirit.
May God Bless You.
Now I would like to have some questions but
I’ve seen people when they ask questions
they are representatives of some horrid gurus.
Their horrid gurus pay them some money because
they take a lot of money then they pay them
some money. Then they come here as identified
with these gurus. I have to request them what
have you got out of that guru? Why are you
so much enamored by him? Why are you so much
charmed by that, what have you got? He’s
using you. So please when you ask questions
ask independently, freely, I’ll be very
happy to answer you but I don’t like that
you are talking because somebody has told
you something. Whatever you know you ask me
I’ll be very happy to answer those questions
to you.
May God bless you.
Question: You mentioned Christ, you mentioned
the Holy Ghost, you mentioned the Kundalini.
If Christ is the Son, what is the Kundalini?
Shri Mataji: She is the Mother. Christ within
us is the Spirit and Kundalini is the Holy
Ghost, which is the Mother. The reflection
of Holy Ghost within us is the Kundalini and
the reflection of Christ within us is the
spirit. But everybody has played the role.
Like Moses, like Abraham, like Socrates, like
Lao Tze, everybody has played the role to
build up this drama they are all part and
parcel of one being. This one you must understand.
When they said there is one God, he’s not
like rock of Gibraltar. Even rock of Gibraltar
has got different molecules you see but to
ask God is one means, I don’t know, I can
not think of such thing just a one block.
He’s not, He has many aspects and these
aspects are expressed in these different ways.
Of course He’s one, united, integrated,
one; but all these aspects are there, and
this one God is either in the pockets of the
priests or the pockets of the Brahmins or
the pockets of the mullahs or the pockets
of someone. One God.
Question: Does the Kundalini have any relationship
to the Virgin Mary, the physical Mother of
Jesus?
Shri Mataji: It is, very much so. Yes you
asked the same question. She is the Virgin
the (kanya?) but gradually when you come to
Sahaja Yoga you will know the Virgin Mary,
what is Her exposure is, how many times She
was born even in India, what is Her relationship
and how great She is. But why Martin Luther
did not talk about Virgin Mary? I asked My
father who was a realized soul and he gave
a good explanation. He said it was (?) it
means according to the circumstances at the
time, that time suddenly he found that he
has to take the people in a more enlightened
field and he is doing so he wanted Muslims
also to be included, and if you suddenly talk
about the Mother, they may not accept.
So for that he avoided, but actually he knew
that one day somebody will explain. But human
nature is such I must say that if you accept
one flower, you’ll not accept another, and
when they’re dead - not when they’re living,
never, never. When they’re living we’ll
never accept it, we’ll never listen to them.
But once they’re dead then wonderful because
he’s in our pocket, do what you like, it’s
very common.
We had one Gyaneshwara, a great saint in India,
very great saint and they have built huge
big temple for him and he is in a statue.
So when we went there they said, "You cannot
do meditation here."
I said, "Why? What did he do? He did meditation."
He said, "No, you have to do that kind of
a dance they do called (?)"
I said, "But he did not do it.'
He said, "So what? We do this way. He was
another; he was great. We are not so we have
to do this"
So I didn’t know how to argue at with that,
so I said, "Look at the statue. Now you are
in a statue, better come in a form to tell
all these people.” But when he came in form
he didn’t even have shoes to wear. He burnt
his feet on charred grounds. Nobody gave him
water to drink. All the saints suffered.
Any other question please? Yes.
Question: Do you need to believe in God to
get realization, like Buddha didn’t believe
in God but still got realization.
Shri Mataji: All right, Buddha did not believe
that’s not the point - He did believe but
He didn’t say about God. I also didn’t
say in the beginning about God, because if
you start talking about God it creates problems.
That he said all these things because, why,
that’s what I’m trying to tell you. You
see it is (?) the time, that time. What he
thought that the people in India especially
were worshipping a God in a temple, the Brahmins,
this, that. The Brahmins thought this is a
God; they had pocketed all the money and all
those things. So how to bring them out of
it? He said, “Don’t talk of God; don’t
talk of anything. Talk of the Self. First
step is Self.”
He said, “First they will have the Self,
then they will know where is the God.” Of
course in the temple also we have some things,
which we can say are swayambus, which are,
come out of Mother Earth. It is said in one
of the commandments that whatever is created
by Mother Earth or by the heavens should not
be reproduced, but there is something created.
So these temples were all completely monopolized
by Brahmins and these Brahmins tried to rule
the whole country, that’s the thing happened.
So Buddha thought, how to get these people
out and He talked about the Self only and
nothing else. He said, “First Self”, and
I also felt the same way in the beginning.
but now the time is different. Now I would
say that it can go to any extent this stupidity
of these fundamentalists. Like in Nasik when
Mahatma Gandhi returned from England they
said, “You have to go for (? Chitta)”
- means a repentance – “You have to go
in for repentance because you put your foot
on a foreign land.” Imagine! And they would
not allow him to exist. They would not allow
him to exist and he had to do it. He said,
“Now get rid of these mad people.” He
had to do it and it was a Brahmin who killed
him ultimately.
So I mean, it’s a very funny world, you
know and in that world we come and we tell
about something that is truth - which is truth,
which is good, which is benevolent, which
is the thing, but people just kill. I mean
there is no need - at least if you don’t
want to hear, all right. Don’t kill them,
but they kill. Even Mohammed Sahib was given
poison, even Buddha was tortured by the people,
very much tortured in the beginning and His
disciples also went to extremes later on,
not his own disciples but his followers.
So now we have people who beat the seekers
on their back. We had one gentleman, his name
was, he called himself Omkar. He came from
some Llama and he had a broken spine and I
had to work for days together to put his spine
right, and they used a stick to hit him. Can
you imagine? Is it God? Is it religion?
So Buddha and Mahavira, these two persons,
at that time did not talk of God, both of
them. Later on they again incarnated and talked
of God as Hassan and Hussein, as Kabira. And
the illusion was that every time He turned
His feet the carpet turned with Him. They’re
all one; we are only fighting because we don’t
see the oneness. So because of the time they
did speak but they did not cut out, they had
to say, “Stop at this point”, not more
because that was the situation. You can see
that. All right? So it’s logical.
Question: Do you have to do any practices
to raise the force?
Shri Mataji: No, first of all I’d better
do it in a different way that you all get
your realization, first of all. Then of course,
as I said, your Kundalini attends to your
problems. She goes down, so then I have to
tell you how to raise it, how to bring it
back, how to correct yourself. Once you’re
established, you can do it to others. So we
can say it is in three parts. First is your
establishment, like we can say the sprouting
of the seed. So that’s the awakening first
of all or realization as you touched. And
then the second part you establish yourself.
In the third part we establish others. All
right?
Question: (repeated by Sahaja Yogi) Are You
speaking of Kundalini awakening? Others talk
about it and then deliver the goods, is this
what You’re saying? Yes.
Shri Mataji: It’s true. That’s true. Easy
to talk about anything. It’s true when one
need not talk. There’s no need to talk,
it works silently. It is working in all of
you. That’s the right approach, who delivers
the good. That’s right, he said the right
thing. Who delivers the good? We can be satisfied
with artificial things you know, we can, we
can be. Be careful on that point, you said
the right thing. Correct.
Question: As a realized soul how can one help
social problems such as problems in Ethiopia
and so on?
Shri Mataji: Well very much. Now Ethiopia’s
problem comes from two angles, two angles.
First is Ethiopia you know that the Rastafarians.
Have you heard about them? It comes from them;
Rastafarians took to the wrong side. In their
religion itself you are supposed to take the
drugs and with taking drugs where will you
go? Into your collective subconscious, and
what is in your collective subconscious is
so injurious that it can give you cancer.
Cancer comes from the left side, which we
call as the collective subconscious. It can
give all kinds of diseases, which cannot be
cured. Most of the incurable diseases come
from there and also the famine. The trees
will burn. If you want to find out about a
person if it is true or not see the flower.
Flower will just burn off, if there’s a
person who is possessed by the left side,
it will just burn off. The cows will not give
milk, all things will happen in the nature,
and when there are so many people who are
doing this nonsensical thing and having all
the left sided movement of their attention,
they catch onto these and that’s how the
whole thing works on their nature. That’s
one thing. Now a realized soul if he goes
to Ethiopia, by his mere existence there,
the nature may change. If he is of a very
evolved soul it will, even with attention
he can.
Now the second point is, what is gone wrong?
You see this is what you say is the sin, the
sin, the wages of sin is fear, it’s much
more than fear. It acts, this is a sin to
go to these things and succumb to collective
subconscious. Instead of rising higher, keeping
in the center, going to the right and the
left we can call it is the sin but in a very
wider sense of the word. All right? Now this
is one thing that the country has indulged
too much into the left side will be grabbed,
will be definitely grabbed into the power
of negative forces, no doubt about it. Their
trees won’t grow, their flowers won’t
prosper, their children will die. They will
have negative population, they will have all
problems of terrible diseases even AIDS comes.
AIDS also comes from the same area. It’s
a very serious thing and when collectively
people start doing it, you just entering into
the satanic land where everything can work
out. That’s one thing, no use giving them
money, it’s very temporary. Easy money is
the worst thing; you have to give them something
solid, something permanent, something eternal,
something living, which will make them grow.
That’s one point.
The second point of Ethiopia is a very collective
happening, which happened in Ethiopia. I met
a minister by chance from Ethiopia who was
traveling with Me in the train and he told
Me it was a political game. The politics which
is not benevolent is no politics at all, it’s
a dirty game; and when you go to the extremes
you see the falsehood is such a nonsense,
such an ignorance, such a darkness that you
start moving in it you don’t know where
you go till you reach your complete doom;
and when you see that you don’t understand
what have we done, because to move on a slope
is the easiest and that’s how Ethiopia has
landed in trouble.
Third point which comes to Me very important
that applies to all the nations, whether they
are developing or developed, that we don’t
realize that we are part and parcel of one
world. God never created a separate world.
It’s one world. Like one human being it
has a heart, all right? It has a liver, it
has everything but it’s one and that we
are all part and parcel of this. I would say
that Roosevelt once said that poverty anywhere
is a threat to prosperity everywhere, and
when he said that I think he understood the
subtle thing. Anywhere in the body there is
poverty, means if there is any disease is
a threat to the whole body. But for that we
are not yet there, we are not grown up, we
are still so insular, so insular.
Like the other day we had a lady who was English,
I must say, she came, and in My house I have
- because my husband is international diplomat
traveling a lot - we have got things from
everywhere and she only appreciated English
things, invariably even without knowing. She
couldn’t appreciate anything even if for
sixth century, second century she wouldn’t.
So insular, we are all insular, everywhere,
whether it’s Indian, whether it’s English
whether it’s American, we are very insular
people, self-opinionated. We are not global.
Unless and until we become global, problems
of the world cannot be solved. As if this
finger of a leper is affected and then there
is no sensitivity in the whole body. Then
what happens that if a rat comes and takes
away the finger the leper doesn’t know.
So the lepers if you go to a leper home they’ll
say, “Just have the light for us to see”,
but this light when it comes within you see
that we are part and parcel of the whole and
that’s how you grow up into the global personality.
We are still English, British, Irish, Welsh.
I was surprised even the Welsh won’t like
them to be called British. I mean it’s such
a little land like that. Imagine in the heart
if you have cells, which do not call themselves
cells of the heart, what will happen to that
heart? It will collapse.
It is happening everywhere, it’s not only
in one country it’s the same as I said in
every country we are very insular people.
We have to expand and how do we expand, how
do we expand? Through our Spirit. As you can
see the characters of these people they were
global they never talked about one country,
two countries, three countries, they talked
for everyone. This is the third big mistake,
which all the countries are doing and they
are fighting, for what? Why are they all fighting,
why are they having wars? God did not create
wars, did He? It’s not His mistake. This
world belongs to Him and not to us. All theories
they become self-destructive how can that
be called as a benevolent politics? In Sahaja
Yoga we will have the politics of Socrates,
of giving and of not taking. But we have to
have that race raised into that personality
that global personality. Can I do it alone?
You all have to help Me.
Question: She’s no will power whatsoever,
She’s been a drug addict for 15 years, She
just wonder she can….
Shri Mataji: Don’t you worry, it’s all
there it will come back don’t you worry,
all right? Don’t you worry. Love is the
most powerful thing, we have never used the
power of love, don’t you worry.
Question: I followed Swami Vivekananda for
years, advocated stern practices for years
and years ….
Shri Mataji: Now he is dead and gone, all
right [laughter…applause]. I’m sitting
here; I’m your Mother, all right? I agree,
I know, I know all that, all horrid things
forget it. I’m your Mother, all right? If
I can work it out only with My love, why should
you worry about Vivekananda? It’s all right,
forget it, that’s over. You have done it
in previous life. Vivekananda had to do it
in this life but you have done it before,
all right? You all have finished with it,
now you just get your prizes. [Shri Mataji
and everyone laughs]You don’t have
to do anything like that. You see a person
who has to cook who has never cooked before
has to go through all rigmarole. But supposing
your Mother knows cooking. She’s done the
cooking. Come along and have the food, finished.
Why to worry? All right? It’s already made.
You are a seeker, you have been a seeker.
You have done all that many lives, you’ve
been to Himalayas so now forget it, forget
it. Better have it, all right? There are so
many here I can see that kind.
Question: Can we have the food that You’ve
prepared?
Shri Mataji: You’re hungry, that’s great.
Let’s have it, all right? Should we? Now
do not analyze anymore, just have it, don’t
analyze, when you’re hungry you don’t
analyze from where did you get it, what has
happened, how (will) you cook it. You just
see the fun, that’s all. You just enjoy
it, that’s a good idea.
Question: After you die, would you like to
go to heaven or do you wish to stay around?
Shri Mataji: Who I? I die? I think of the
present never of the future. You be in the
present, don’t worry about the future. We
should worry about the present, that’s why
you see Buddha talked about the Self. Why
talk of the future? Doesn’t exist for Me.
Question: Present and future bind together
Shri Mataji: Yes, Yes but you become first
the present, otherwise there’s no binding.
Either you are in the future or in the past,
first of all become the present. There’s
no binding, that’s the chain is missing,
that’s why I’m saying become the present.
All right?
Question: I want to know the answer, are You
going to stay around or are You going to go
to heaven when You die?
Shri Mataji: I’m already in heaven (laughter…
applause) would you like to join Me? You please
join Me in heaven, all right? I’m already
in heaven. I see the heaven around Me everywhere,
only thing you have to enter into that subtle
thing. It’s so beautiful; it’s so beautiful.
All right, now you don’t have to do much,
but as I said we have problems within ourselves.
We have to little bit work out ourselves,
our awakening and doing so you will know also
later on if the Kundalini falls off how to
raise it. It’s very simple, not much. You
have to use your left and right hand because
as Mohamed Sahib has said that at the time
of resurrection your hands will speak, in
the sense that you get your collective consciousness
and your fingertips become enlightened. So
as all the doctors will also say that we have
a sympathetic nervous system acting on our
fingertips.
Now when you put the left hand towards Me,
it represents your desire to be self realized.
So just you have to put your left hand like
this nothing else is to be done - simple,
but in a humble way. If you say, “now give
me realization”, all right, but we have
to be humble. That’s very important. When
we are humble, we are peaceful and the thing
works out faster. So do not analyze it just
get it. It’s simple how to eat the food
I’m just telling you.
Put your left hand straight like this. First
of all it’s better to take the advantage
of Mother Earth so you have to take out your
shoes. You can keep your socks but better
to take out your shoes, because sometimes
they can be very tight and your hats. Anything
tight, which makes you uncomfortable, should
be loosened, that’s all.
Now, just put your left hand straight like
this. Everyone should try to do it, it’s
very simple, it’s not going to take much
time, it’s very simple. Nothing is going
to happen to you but, on the contrary, you
will become at least ten years younger, that’s
a promise. You see a mother when she gives
castor oil, also she has to cover it with
some chocolates. So now this is one of the
temptations for many people must be, but there
are so many other things that I cannot describe
in this short lecture. So I would say that
just put your left hand because this is your
own power within you, which you do not know,
just put your left hand just like this. All
of you please put your left hand on your lap
very comfortably. Now your right hand is the
one, which is the power of action. With this
you act, so you have to use your right hand
just first on your heart centre then because
in the heart resides the Spirit. Then I’ll
tell you one by one, but just now can see
on the upper part of the stomach, in the lower
part of the stomach, then again in the upper
part of the stomach, then on the heart, then
here, then here, then here. I will tell you
one by one everywhere and then on top of your
head here, stretch your hand palm, put it
down there and press it hard, that’s all.
It’s very simple.
Now this all has to be done with the right
hand, just remember this one point and left
hand here. What are these centers? I will
tell you. One by one, you need not remember.
It’s all in the book, but just now you know
that it is to be worked out on the left-hand
side. Because left-hand side is our desire
and we are putting our hand of our desire.
Now the left hand is already quite heavy I
must say, all right, so now. You put your
left hand just like this and at the very outset,
as I’ve told in every Western program, you
have to forgive yourself. You’re not to
feel guilty for anything whatsoever even for
reading Vivekananda. You have to be pleasantly
placed towards yourself; after all you are
the temple of God. So don’t despise yourself,
don’t think low of yourself, forgive yourself
and say with full confidence that you’re
not guilty. This is a fashion also, everybody
wants to say “I’m guilty.” It’s a
fashion, it’s just a fashion. So please
don’t consider yourself guilty for anything
you have done in the past what you think of
the future. Let your present come up and then
you will know that all these were mythical
ideas. The truth has to come.
So now you have to close your eyes. Don’t
open your eyes. There’s no mesmerism going
on, so no need to keep the eyes open. But
in any case keep your eyes shut till I tell
you to open, because when the Kundalini is
rising it’s better to keep your attention
inside. At least through the eyes the attention
goes out, so if you keep your eyes closed
the Kundalini rises much better. Sometimes
She does not rise if your attention is out,
so I know attention cannot be inside, but
when you close your eyes at least it is not
going out too much. So the Kundalini rises
and It sucks in all your attention, like I
can say in My sari if I have the Kundalini
rising like that it sucks in the sari like
the attention, In the same way it goes up
and ultimately pierces through here. It should
happen, you all should certify yourself, nobody
needs certify you. Once you say you are feeling
the cool breeze then you can ask somebody
to see you. If you are not feeling it, don’t
get desperate, you all can feel it. There
are so many here sitting and I’m sure you
can be told and helped. And then once you
get it, you have to help others. That’s
how we are going to work it out.
So now please put left hand like this, right
hand on your heart. Now here close your eyes.
In the heart resides the Spirit, so please
ask Me three times a question in your heart,
not loudly. Please ask Me sincerely a question.
You can call Me “Shri Mataji” or you can
call Me “Mother”, whatever you like. “Mother,
am I the Spirit? Mother, am I the Spirit?
Mother, am I the Spirit?” Now this is a
fundamental question you’re asking to a
computer, which has to give you the answer.
Now this question is followed by another question
when you put your right hand in the upper
part of your stomach on the left-hand side.
You’re working everything on the left-hand
side and press it hard. Now here is the centre,
which gives you the power of mastery over
yourself, the mastery over the divine knowledge,
the mastery over the working of the divine
knowledge. That means you become your own
master, you become your own guru, nobody can
dominate you, nothing can dominate you, no
habits can dominate you. So at this point
you press your fingers dig them down here
you have to ask the second question to me,
Mother am I my own master? Ask this questions
three times please, with full faith in yourself
ask this question: “Mother, am I my own
master? “ This will neutralize all your
useless feelings and everything. “Mother
am I my own master?”
Now please take your hand down in the lower
part of your abdomen and press it hard there
on the left-hand side, keep the left hand
towards me. Now here is the centre, which
is working out the divine technique, the pure
knowledge, the true art of this technique
is worked out through this centre here. At
this centre I cannot force you in any way
that you should ask me for your self-realization.
It should be your own desire free will ask
for it. So here you please ask Me, “Mother,
may I have the true knowledge?” This has
to be said six times because there are six
petals to this center. “Mother, may I have
the true knowledge, the pure knowledge of
the divine technique?”
(Why don’t you do? You’re so young, please
try, it’s very easy. For young people to
be that adamant is not good. But please try,
it’s worth it.)
Six times please. You must learn to listen
and sometimes understand, all right? Now raise
this hand again on the left-hand side, on
the same center of the principle of the mastery
on the upper part of your abdomen of your
stomach, on the left-hand side, And now press
it hard. This center has got ten petals, so
here now you have to help your Kundalini to
rise by asserting the truth, by saying ten
times with full confidence in yourself, “Mother
I am my master. Mother I am my own master.
Mother I am my own master.” Please say it
ten times.
Now again you raise your hand on top of your
heart and put it there with full confidence
here, as this centre has got twelve petals
you have to say with full confidence in yourself
the truth, “Mother I am the Sprit.” You
are the Spirit, so please say with full confidence,
“Mother I am the Spirit.” Believe Me,
you are the Spirit. Twelve times.
You have to know that Divine is the ocean
of God’s love. It is the ocean of His forgiveness
and you cannot do anything that He cannot
forgive. He’s that powerful, His forgiveness
is that powerful, so there’s no need for
you to feel guilty about anything whatsoever,
by that you’re challenging His power of
forgiveness. So now you raise your hand in
the angle of your neck and your shoulder and
push it back towards the spinal chord and
press it very hard. Now this is the most difficult
center in the West. As I said, when you feel
guilty you catch this center and you get all
kinds of troubles like angina also troubles
like spondylitis and so many other problems.
Now press it hard and with full confidence,
you say sixteen times, “Mother I’m not
guilty.” Sixteen times. You have to be pleasant
with yourself; you have to cherish yourself
and not to condemn yourself at all by any
chance. You are not guilty. So please say,
“Mother, I am not guilty at all” sixteen
times. But those who still want to go ahead
with it punish themselves by saying it 108
times. That would be the best. (Shri Mataji
blowing on her hand and rubbing Her hands)
So much heat coming out from there, so much
of heat. “I’m not guilty.”
Put your left hand towards Me, say with full
confidence. Wow, this is the worst hurdle,
I tell you. It’s just a myth; it’s a conception
in your head that you’re guilty. What guilt
can you have that cannot be washed by the
great power of God’s love and forgiveness?
(Shri Mataji is rubbing Her hands) Sixteen
times or 108 times. You do not know how to
love yourself. You’re supposed to be selfish
but there’s no selfishness I think. (Shri
Mataji is blowing hard and rubbing Her hands)
Now raise this hand on your forehead across
and press it on both the sides. Now, here
is the center where you have to forgive others.
I will not say how many times but from your
heart, please say, “Mother, I forgive everyone,
I forgive everyone, I forgive everyone.”
Now maybe you might say it’s very difficult,
but it’s not all because it is mythical.
What do you do by not forgiving or forgiving?
Is nothing, but when you don’t forgive you
play into the hands of wrong people. So just
say, “Mother, I forgive everyone, everyone
I forgive.” This is the greatest weapon
Christ has given us - to forgive. Forgive
everyone, forgive everyone, forgive everyone.
Now for
your own satisfaction you may put your hand
on the backside of your head, backside of
your head. Here is the center where you have
to say that “If I have done anything wrong
against the Divine, please forgive me.”
You have to ask the Divine the forgiveness,
so that there’s no doubt in your mind or
sort of lurking guilt. Say that three times
of from your heart it will work out, but don’t
count the mistakes, so called. Just say that,
saying is sufficient. Saying is the enlightened
chanting, all right?
Now stretch your hand put it on top of your
head, bend you head a little bit forward.
On top of your head, bend it and now rub it
hard the scalp seven times. Here again I cannot
cross your freedom, so you have to say, “Mother,
I want my Realization.” I cannot force it
on you, so just say, “I want my Realization.”
I can only persuade you, but I cannot force
it. You have to ask for it. So please say
seven times, “Mother, please may I have
my realization? Please give me my Realization”
seven times. (Shri Mataji blows seven times
into the microphone)
Now bring down your right hand, put it towards
Me. Slowly open your eyes and put your left
hand bending your head a little bit on top
of your head here, little higher and see if
there’s a cool breeze coming out. With the
left hand you see, not with the right, right
hand towards Me, the right hand towards Me,
the left hand just try to see if you’re
feeling any cool breeze out of your head,
all right? Don’t get upset. If you’re
not feeling doesn’t matter, we’ll work
it out. Doesn’t matter. Now turn it round
again put it here the right hand, see with
the right hand if you’re feeling the cool
breeze. Some people don’t feel it, doesn’t
matter. Nothing so desperately bad. There
is, I can see that. Now left hand again, little
higher, maybe little higher, some people feel
it very high you see, it shoots off, just
see.
Now you may put your hand up towards the sky
and ask the question, “Is this the All-Pervading
Power of God’s love? Is this the cool breeze
of the Holy Ghost? Is this the Brahma Shakti?”
Ask the question three times. Now, such a
lot, all the Sahaja Yogis sitting here. Are
you feeling? Cool breeze? Or what? Something
happening? Now put back your hand, now don’t
analyze it just see in the hands are you feeling
any cool breeze in the hands. All right, little
bit, some feel a little bit; but it’s all
right, the beginning has started. Now most
of you have got the right hands less, so put
the right hand towards Me, left hand like
this towards the sky, it will ventilate. Left
hand like this and now forgive, forgive everyone,
everyone you forgive, just forgive. That’s
the mantra. It will release, left hand up.
Right hand towards Me and left hand up. Now
right hand towards Me. Moving, is it? Slowly,
slowly it will move, right hand is difficult
because mostly we are very right-sided people,
mostly. Yes, good.
Now with the left hand you put towards Me
and right hand towards the Mother Earth like
this. Left hand towards Me and right hand
towards the Mother earth. This is what we
are doing: we are correcting the elements
within us, bringing them into balance. Which
you will know very soon what it was, what
we were doing. You’ll know everything. No,
no left towards Me, left towards Me and right
towards the Mother Earth. Right towards the
Mother Earth. Left towards Me, right towards
the Mother Earth. Mmm, better. All right?
Now all those who have felt the cool breeze
in the head or in the hands raise your both
the hands. All
of you? Practically? The sprouting has started.
May God bless you.