so try to see why we keep so much
if the left side is strong people see if
the back of your is strong if the front
of you is working too much then people
don't sleep so even if I say don't sleep
it means that you put your right arghya
in in working condition that we should
start thinking which is again sahaja
yoga baby so it should be left or right
on the right on the left on the right
again it's not it will be away from
water so in the center you have to be
with right
so now as many of you are already
feeling sleepy put your first thing
should be for all those people who are
lazy is to put their right to the next
seven times a salad
the writer
Oh Ritter all the back on you that's all
laziness is
the first hours against laziness I mean
anybody got a chance to talk to this
with all of our
on the photo
Oh
but now
tonight you have to keep away the
problem but don't sleep formally here
alright informally
[Music]
but a put your eyes right
okay
[Music]