[Music]
this understanding of what you have
achieved in sahaja yoga should
immediately make you realize what you
are and when it all has happened to us
automatically you should be very sincere
about it you must feel that something
really we have achieved or something so
great so we have to be sincere mentally
also we should feel that so this is
first thing you do is to mentally feel
to maintain you feel that it's so
important but the second part is
different where you see something you
know something and you start opening
your heart about it in the second part
you have to open your heart
so the sincerity comes from an open
heart if your heart is not open you
cannot be sincere now what does it mean
that your heart is not open let us see
we are born again you have got your
realization also it is your birthday in
a way but in the growth of your
knowledge and understanding you have not
kept pace with your heart but what is
the reason for that what is it that
keeps your heart like you can discover
very easily that your heart moves the
body moves your brain everything because
if your heart stops everything stops but
if your brain stops hardcore stuff so
heart is the most important thing and it
governs the whole being within you now
this special instrument which is very
delicate which circulates also is like a
stone
how will it pulsate
so when we say enlarge your heart it
means that the stone enos of your heart
has to be melted away how does it become
stony we have to go to the roots of that
it becomes like a stone because the
heart controls the brain as there are
seven auras on your brain in the same
way there are seven auras on your heart
and all those are us and the ones which
control them on us of the wave now on
the brain as you know there are two
institutions of ego and conditionings we
start pressing the brain too much as a
result of all these auras get dressed
so the auras which are surrounding the
heart also the treasure so this
conditioning makes the brain pervert but
it doesn't make it a stone only what
makes it a stone is that if he is born
with some sort of a mental derangement
that he cannot think otherwise the brain
goes on thinking whether with
conditionings or with it it goes on
thinking such a brain
should not affect the heart because
heart affects a brain but the auras
which are manifested from the heart
start becoming dull or disappear so the
auras around the heart are very
sensitive and they feel no use throwing
light on the brain they start becoming
smaller and smaller and that's how the
heart becomes small because they have no
purpose in life them so they start
becoming smaller and smaller as a result
the heart becomes small we call somebody
is really small hearted fellow is a
chicken hearted you know we always say
such a man is a stone hearted person all
these happens because of the
conditionings and the ego of the human
mind and the result is felt but the
heart becoming a stone because heart is
a sensitive thing brain is not that that
is how we do not know how to be kind to
others how to be nice how to be helpful
how to be gentle and how to be
reassuring protecting others all this we
have inherited already we have already
got a stone art when we come to sahaja
yoga and we have a brain either full of
ego or super-ego so now with your
Kundalini rising you can clear out your
head first of all so the sincerity will
come when the Kundalini will move and
touch
Ramananda which is the seat of your
heart and will expand then the heart
just comes back like a king returns back
and start dominating the brain so the
relationship between the truth has to be
fully understood
at first the domination of the heart
although we can say the king hood of
heart is cherished is put down not to
zero and then this brain becomes the
king and he starts ruling us I think I
feel means the brain the even if you
could give up I think I want everything
with your eyes you should say I want
another point this body wants you
separate yourself gradually you start
separating yourself from all such
situations by never saying I want you
say this body this heart
they said you start separating and once
you are separated all these barriers of
ego and super-ego will disappear but as
it is also it's very easy to get rid of
these two it's very easy to get rid of
these two only by raising your kundalini
and breaking here Ramanathan this is the
greatest achievement that you know that
you can break your brahmarandra
make your kundalini get connected with
the all-pervading power that's why I
always say you must meditate and you
must be in thoughtless awareness then it
works out don't pay attention to outside
things so much tasting you should
decorate yourself within yours with
sincerity it nice thoughts about
yourself that you are capable absolutely
capable people and you can use your
imagination you are
intelligence rationality whatever you
think you have to find the way to find
the way again I say to keep your heart
large