you
I wonder if he understand the meaning of
innocence or not innocence is a quality
which is innate which is which cannot be
forced which cannot be trained into it's
just a quality innate quality within a
human being maybe you say that innocent
persons are attacked by the cunning by
the accuracy but innocence is such a
great thing that it cannot be distracted
with the quality of the Spirit in a
sense is the quality of the spirit and
when they spirit within you is awakened
you get the power of innocence by which
you overcome all that is negative all
that is wrong all that is detrimental to
your growth spiritual understanding
whatever is mine is not all means that's
not so
my body my head my everything my but I -
give me the same I
what is I then I is separated whatever
is not mine is I so what remains it's
your spirit somebody gave me this our
limit as it is a very good argument to
work it out and whatever remains is us
and that I taste of our we have received
so you are reducing all these miles
miles miles so the fewer spirit of
innocence we lack
so the idea of a spirit terms of people
think that if you become spiritual I
mean I don't know what people think
about
with ten people but I about spiritual
people is that you have to be something
terrific like a fool or I don't know you
have to be sharp like a fox you have to
be lecture like Freud or something oh
it's not so my desk beautifully
no it is not spiritual person is just
innocent just innocent there's no
intelligence nothing just innocent the
more thing is innocence see whatever he
talks or says comes through innocence it
doesn't have been clicked as such each
year people are off with Rudy daily and
to understanding and realizing nothing
of the time it just has pure innocence
it's so clean which is the way to become
innocent in sahaja yoga we have a proper
method how we can become innocent
it happens through our thoughtless
awareness if you are in the state of
thoughtless awareness then what happens
you do not react do not get involved
into wrong things you do not get
involved into any discussion as
arguments but you just watch and the
innocence within you Rises beautifully
like a lotus rises out of a dirty pond
so whatever may be the circumstances
when you are in thoughtless awareness
you do not react that is the sign of
innocence and people who do not react
keep young they will never show their
age they keep young because to react is
not
a very good thing which makes you get
involved into another person but if you
don't react if you are just watching oh
you're a witness then you don't get
involved into anything you are away from
it and that's how your innocence grooves
and you get very confident I've read a
story about a Chinese king who went to a
saint and asked him that he wants some
boon problems what he said I want my son
to be developed into a person who can
face all kinds of whatever people may do
he should be able to face them soon all
right we leave your son with me
so when the argument started when the
fighting started his son was just timing
straight watching everything thoughtless
of it so everybody from the arena went
back they all went away and they
couldn't stand the innocence of this boy
who was very young and the king was
surprised how his son could face all of
them all their arguments all their
aggression and all kinds of horrible
things I said if anybody says anything
to you you should just be innocent at
that time you have power of innocence
will show that this person who is trying
to dominate you to trouble you is very
much in the wrong I told you innocence
is the spirit and spirit is the English
which cannot be destroyed by the fact is
that it cannot be destroyed by anything
and it can be reestablished through
sahaja yoga you might have been a very
aggressive person you might have been a
very unhappy person you must have been a
person who is all the time disturbing
others maybe but after sahaja yoga you
can make your personality so sweet and
beautiful that not only you can enjoy
but others can also in this scene
essence is something which is absolute
Oreste intelligence it is not that it
works for the purpose some purpose but
this is purposeless it's absolutely
purposeless and thus it achieves that
height of joy because there is no
purpose in anything it sees the futility
of all kinds of endeavors that we have
it just enjoy why people are running up
and down why are they fighting this time
suffer sees that why should they do it
like that some may think they are all
right there's nothing wrong with them
but it's not so in a sense is something
I told you is a innate quality and you
should not deceive yourself by thinking
you are innocent on the contrary you
just put some introspection upon
yourself and see for yourself what have
you been doing so far as far as other
servants what is your attitude see
children how they are source of it
anybody who comes on the stage and runs
about how we enjoy why why do we enjoy a
child running about we don't say he's
gone amok or he's drunk but we enjoy the
child why what is the sweetness of that
child that makes us so happy because
that's innocence
his power is innocence at that power he
is just looking so sweet so beautiful
that it gives us the real joy within so
the second thing is that innocence is
jointly innocence gives joy to people
anything
sets innocently anything done innocently
is very very joy-giving
and in that you you see the person so
transparent so beautiful that you enjoy
that transparency and that sanctified
innocence if you want to have real joy
then have innocent love between yourself
and enjoy it
may God thank
you