Evening program, Avignon, France, 07-07-1990
Give her a chair
otherwise she won't be able to play harmonium.
Ah,
[Hindi]
Can you keep it up there? Ah. On that.
You can move that.
Come on. Have a sit there.
We would like to present you a "Bharood" [Marathi religious song]
by Sant Eknath
It's a song that
in a style that
is designed
to teach people
what will happen to them if they don't behave in a
in the correct way
In this particular song
Sant Eknath is talking about
what happens to people if they're not, if they trick people
badly
if they are rude to them, if they cheat them.
Sant Eknath gives example in particular
of Duryodhana
who took Draupadi and humiliated her in his court.
and it was eventually
his brother, the brother of Duryodhana
drag Draupadi into the court to be humiliated.
And was eventually punished by Bhishma
punished by Bhishma in a dual.
In the same way, Ravana who kidnapped Shri Sita
was duly punished by Shri Rama.
And so on in many cases.
In reality, there are only four
people, that Sant Eknath mentions
who are free from any kind of
problem in his regard.
For example, Bhishma
and
Hanumana, those two are examples.
Sant Eknath concludes the song
inviting us to be
sweet with each other and not to abuse each other.
Otherwise - cause if we do,
then our fate
is a very ugly one.
Give me a microphone for tablas.
When standing, they will wait.
Yes.
So, all of you can sit there like this only.
Patrick!
Yes.
We have another
song for you. This time it's a
village's song, a folk's song
from Uttar Pradesh.
The context of the song is
a group of villagers on a way to a festival at Prayag
in the month of Magha which is January or February.
And Prayag is a place where the two holy rivers of India, Ganga and Yamuna, meet.
So, in the first verse, the villagers are singing the praises of Prayag
where the rivers meet,
and for this reason, it's a holy place,
a place of pilgrimage.
In the second verse, they explain how Ganga comes from Haridwar
which is also a place of pilgrimage because Ganga has come down from the heaven in that place.
So it has come from Haridwar,
which is a popular place of pilgrimage,
to Prayag which is also a place of pilgrimage.
Come here, on the same line. You go a little bit that side.
Ok, very good.
Ah! This reminded me of my own marriage when I went to my
husband's house.
They all used to sing like this only there.
So, it's wonderful, the way they have sung it, absolutely with  complete pronunciation,
everything, it's wonderful.
I was just enjoying it. Thank you very much. And I hope you all have enjoyed too.
The group of students who are sitting in front of you, on the stage,
have been learning classical music
at Garlate house near Milano, I hope you - all of you know
Garlate house.
And they covered about seven ragas.
Among these ragas, they learnt Marva rag
which is the favorite raga of Shri Mataji.
And they will sing what we call the chutta khayal [composition] in ektaal [12 beats].
First, they will sing the aroha [ascending scale]
and pakad [melodic theme] of raga Marva
and then sargam [singing notes].
Aroha is ascend
Aroha is, are the ascending notes of the raga
And Avaroha are the descending notes of the raga.
And pakad are the group of notes typical of that raga,
so that the raga can be recognized when those notes are sung.
And they are singing the chutta khayal in ektaal.
And before singing the chutta khayal,
they will sing sargam.
Sargam, they will sing also in double rhythm.
And chutta khayal, they will sing with alap and taans [first and second part of the raga].
I hope all of you will like it and Shri Mataji will also like what they sing in the present.
Is a prayer composed by Guru Dev Rabindranath Tagore
in raga Bhairavi.
"Antara Mama Bikoshito Karo, antara tara hey"
The devotee is praying to the God that: "Let my inner being be enlightened."
"Nirmala karo, ujjwala karo, sundara karo hey."
Nirmala, you know: Shri Mataji's name is Nirmala, pure.
Absolutely pure.
And "Mangalo karo" "make it holy and make it beautiful".
So, this prayer is being sung
by the students who were studying semi-classical
in raga Bhairavi and this will be the last song.
In a bus and
we had a lot of discomfort
in the sense that we were not feeling free.
But when we came into this wonderful land of Italy,
we were feeling very, very free and we were also feeling very hungry.
Maybe, it has to do something with the Nabhi, I'm sure.
But then, in order to keep my "Sangeet Sarita" members happy,
I was trying to sing a raga which is known as Chandrakauns.
It's a very, very dynamic raga.
And close to that raga is another raga known as Malkauns.
And there is a difference of only one note in these two ragas.
And, as I was singing I was talking to Guruji and I was saying
that if we add this note of one raga into another,
I think we will create a beautiful raga.
And he immediately got up and he started singing
with that additional note and a new raga was born.
Just, just in the bus, a new raga was born.
And then,
we had to give a name and Guruji gave a very, very dynamic very sahaj name:
he called it "Chaitanya Ranjani" [vibrations; to be rejoiced]
which will entertain your Chaitanya.
This is a raga which is going to be played for the first time.
Even in India, my sister will bear me out that this has not been played before, anywhere.
So, you can imagine what's a headache is done to this poor Babamama
who knew very little about music.
He's gone so dynamic that he is creating ragas!
This will be played to you by one and only Guruji on the violin
and our young artist Nasir khan.
Guido, could you please take down completely ...
as it is obstructing the view.
It has to be removed completely.
I was discussing this raga with my
other sister; where is she? I can't see.
She must be sitting on side.
So, she was saying as to: "How could you create this raga?"
And she herself replied: "It is because of your concentration in music."
"That,
that is because you put your heart and soul in something and you will achieve."
So, when you have to have creativity,
your attention is the most important equipment.
So, you put your attention on something and you are bound to create
if your attention is fully on that subject.
Out of the twelve brothers and sisters that we are,
my dear sister is a subtle artist and was blessed with this voice and the gift of music
and we used to have music every day in the house.
I was a very playful boy, but in between, I used to go and listen to this music.
And that has been registered with me and it is coming so helpful now
so that we can transfer this culture of India through this music
to all the Sahaja Yogis.
It's a tremendous feeling.
Now, I will first tell you as to what the two ragas are
and then I will tell you how they have been blended.
So you will be able to appreciate the difference.
First, a very brief introduction of the members of the Nirmal Sangeet Sarita who are on the stage:
Sandesh Popatkar on the tabla.
Then,
Then our Guruji mister Prabhakarji [Dhakde] on the violin.
And, two years ago this young artist Nasir Khan was here, he was then the baby
of the team.
He has lost that status of being a baby because he's become,
he is going to become a father very shortly.
And- but his sitar has improved immensely
over the two years.
And now I will ask Prabhakarji to first play the ragas as they are.
The two ragas.
Now, first, he will play the Chandrakauns.
One minute, the tuning.
Now, this is Chandrakauns he is playing.
Now, this is the original raga, Chandrakauns.
Pakad notation [unsure]
Acha [Hindi]. Now, I'll ask Nasir to play Malkauns.
See the notation.
The only difference of one note.
Now, the new raga. Only the notations.
OK. Now, the "Chaitanya Ranjani" for your Chaitanya. Thank you.
Antonio, people here can come here in the front.
Shri Mataji has suggested
a new name for this raga.
Since this is a gift from the disciple to the guru,
and guru is synonymous of Purnima that is the full Moon,
Shri Mataji says that this raga should be called
"Chaitanya Purnima", that means-
I think this is the biggest award
a disciple can expect from a guru
that She has blessed this raga with a very wonderful name.
Jai Shri Mataji.
You are lucky because Shri Mataji is speaking about you.
All of you.
Chers amis, [Dear friends,]
bonsoir. [good night.]
Thank you.
[No sound.]
Because I wanted to drive in Rome, I wanted to drive, so I said:
"We will take the car."
So we took the car
and as you know that it's very difficult to find parking in Rome,
like in Paris, yes.
More difficult.
So, for about twenty minutes,
we went around, around and around
looking for a parking place.
Twenty minutes later, I suddenly noticed
a small gap in front of the restaurant.
I took my car and I went into this gap.
And in front,
there was a poster of Shri Mataji smiling.
The smile on that poster was very knowing.
I'm very-
I'm very touched and very moved
that
we have been chosen as one of the musicians
to play in this
elated evening.
Indian classical music is based on ragas,
melodies which we call ragas,
and ragas are emotions,
ragas are mood, it's an emotion.
And different ragas have different emotions.
And this evening, I chose to play a raga
called Puriya, raga Puriya.
[No sound.]
Tomorrow is, as you know, we are going to celebrate the Guru Purnima.
And all these artists, whom you see here,
have become such great artists
because of their dedication - of course through the art- but through their gurus.
Complete dedication.
And this is the key of their success:
complete dedication to the guru.
And to master any art,
you have to have dedication and surrendering.
And that's how these people have achieved such heights of perfection.
That they have followed their gurus
out and out absolutely, completely surrendering.
And that is why today I'm happy that we have so many artists here, especially
such a great artist
of such fame before you.
But if you ask him, he 'll tell you that
he had to go through penance
to master this art.
And his own father is his guru.
So what a difficult situation must be for the father or for the son.
But as far as the art is concerned,
there is no compromise.
In the same way, as fas as spirituality is concerned,
Maybe, your guru is your Mother, but still,
no compromise.
So, may God bless you.
Thank you very much for appreciating him so much.
Actually,
it is a tremendous speed, you see
the speed with which and the balance.
Balance and the speed.
We are living in an age of, we are living in an age of a jet, you see,
we're living in an age of speed
and in that speed, we have to keep the balance and the rhythm.
That's what you have to learn
is to keep the balance and the rhythm and then you have to come to the first beat,
that is the Spirit.
So, how you are bound, may go anywhere with any speed,
keep the speed, keep the balance
and come back to the same
first beat which is the Spirit,
is the- that's how it works out.
And the speed with which he is playing, I tell you, this is a
very great, modern also, a kind of a blessing
that there is a speed in the atmosphere.
And everywhere there's speed and -
but in that speed to have the balance is only possible
when
you practice what you call "riyaz"
is quite deep and you do it with your
whole attention and whole heart.
Then only,
otherwise it's not possible such a speed that he has.
What a tremendous speed! [Hindi]
Speed [inaudible] - you see,  have you noticed the speed with which he was playing?
And have you noticed the balance that he had?
And how he was rhythmic?
Rhythm, he never missed, you see, he's very  good
as we call it the [inaudible]
like.
So he is, tablavala is another -
Tablavala is very sahaj Mother.
Sahaj!
And he is absolutely relaxed
and he is playing so well. He's beautiful.
And that is what kind of a tablavala you need for a music like this
where
he has to be most unassuming and he is supporting
all the time the artist, should be the point.
I'm very happy you all are enjoying it so much
and that you are appreciative of it
cause, after all, it's a -
we have been brought up in this kind of [inaudible] style.
In my family, from my childhood, I have been earing nothing but classical music
and all my life.
I've never known even one minute in my house
then where the music is not there:
somebody singing in this room or somebody singing in that room,
whatever may be the situation, there is music on.
So, for my ear it is tremendous but to my heart also.
And the way he has played, I must thank him very much on your behalf.
From his heart, he has played, from his heart.
It's only to her presence that this can happen.
You all know this also.
"Avion" [plane] means "air" isn't it? "Wind" in French.
"Avion" is wind.
He says it is "guide" "avion" is "guide"
No, "avion", "avion".
"Avion"?
Is what?
"Avion" is airplane.
Airplane. There's a lot of "avion" in the Avignon.
If you see, the sitar he has got
a rakhi to it, you see?
You all know what is rakhi is.
So the sitar is his sister.
And the sisterly love is the purity of love,
absolute, pure love, you see.
And the sister is the protector of the brother.
So, this is how they tie rakhi to a sister, you see?
I hope you have noticed it.
[Hindi]
There is a circus on
and it's a nice contrast to see the difference between the two.
This is the raga which is called as Durga
as you must have heard it before also
and it's quite a difficult raga and
also it is only with the five notes it is played
and there are very few ragas like that.
And one of them is Gunakali raga.
which is also played with the same style.
And I was surprised that
in certain countries,
they only know one raga.
Like Bhairava, it's a - it's the only raga they know in Iran.
Whether it is morning, evening, afternoon,
they sing just that one raga is Bhairava.
And I was surprised, I heard Gunakali in Japan.
Ah, ah.
Japanse have only idea of Gunakali, I don't know how they got it.
But only Gunakali nothing else.
Absolutely.
Absolutely. That's all. One raga they are masters.
They are mastering that raga.
One, but morning, evening, [Hindi]
And in a way, these ragas are morning ragas.  [Hindi]
Bhairava especially is a raga
all the time they sing without any discrimination.
But this is the time for Durga really.
Just before awakening,
the mother is calling that: "Get up now and meditate."
Ah!
How beautiful it is, just see.
Now, their last raga is Bhairavi.
It has to be played in the old
traditional ways and
it's a raga that is in praise of the power of,
we can say,
of the Spirit.
Because it is a- it has such beautiful notes and
[Hindi].
Notes which are - it's a complete "sampurna"
it's a complete "aga" it's a "Purnima". Hey?
[Babamama in Hindi]
All the twelves notes are in it. So, you see,
it's such a complete raga and it has to be played in all due respect to it.
And it is a ragani Shri Mataji.
It's a ragani regarded as you see, because
Now, as you know that the heart chakra has got -
heart chakra has got twelve petals.
And the Durga resides on the heart chakra.
Now, the Durga's qualities are that she is protective of her children.
She's very gentle, very soft with her children.
And she is extremely horrifying to the crooks, to the satanic people, to the negative people.
So, in this raga, I think because the-
there are - it's spaced out,
the notes are spaced out.
So, either you could play it slow or you could play it fast.
Nothing in between.
That's why it is on a Durga style, you see.
Either she's extremely gentle
or she is extremely horrifying.
So, because she has a double function, is one is to look after her children
and another is: protect her children from the devils.
So she has to be very quick about it
to fight them and to, in every way, to frighten them
and to be alert about them.
So, in the second part, you all became very alert I saw it.
The first part, you were having a lullaby
because it was the mother's love that was playing.
But the second part, you became alert
because she has to fight.
Now, this is such a nice raga
because it gives you a better sense of security
within yourselves.
Will give you a sense of security.
And also as you know, medically that it's important to build up this chakra
because that gives you antibodies created more
so to fight all the diseases, to fight all the foreign things
which try to attack us.
So, this raga is so apt, absolutely apt
for today's atmosphere and for today's need,
that we have to have the security of the Mother and the protection of the Mother.
And that all the evil forces must be finished from this world.
And that's how this raga has a very great significance
and I thank you very much for feeling this raga,
see.
This is the now last five minutes he would like to play,
he asked the Bhairavi
which is a complete raga as you can call, is the complete Purnima.
All the - all the notes are there.
And it is played in various ways, is in various styles and
is used for so many expressions of
your feelings and things.
But in this also, there's a beautiful one of a song as you know
Dayani Bhavani is the one
which is a song about the Mother Goddess.
And in this [inaudible] there's a little mixture in the-
I don't know if it is an
absolutely pure Bhairavi or not.
[Hindi]
It is to be played absolutely in Shuddha Bhairavi.
It should be played in absolute Shuddha Bhairavi.
[Hindi]
It is to be played absolutely in pure Bhairavi.
This is the best way
because Bhairavi is the name of the Goddess.
So, that will be the-
[Hindi]
So, this is the purity of it, purity of it creates that
feeling and that-
I mean it awakens that Deity so that you get that effect with the Bhairavi.
Ah! She, my sister is accepting that they may make some mistakes in the Shuddhata [unsure].
Which I detected, you see, I'm not such a musician as you are,
but I did detect that there's a little bit [inaudible]
Indian music has such a lot of freedom, I mean, such a lot of freedom.
Ah! You can do what you like with it but
only thing that you have to keep to the ragas
and you have to keep to the "swaras" [notes] and everything and
it cannot just go crazy from one to another like that.
So, it is like a big aeroplane which is going in the air
with everything completely fixed properly, you see, so it can go anywhere.
Unless and until you it's fixed by its own maryadas, it cannot go.
So, that has to be there. So first, the ragas are built.
And built in such a way that they are absolutely perfect.
And then you can go wherever you feel like, nothing will happen.
[Hindi]
Then it will become jazz Shri Mataji.
Jazz. Or even worse than that, could be.
Ah, ah.
First, he will play all the twelves notes which are moved in Bhairavi.
And then you see how he keeps to them.
He keeps to that mood that way.
Woah, wah.
It's the heart chakra. it's the heart chakra of Shiva.
Surrendering.
The surrendering, you see, as Islam means "surrender".
Islam is the "surrender".
He's been calling [inaudible].
Now, this is the call  [inaudible].
What an enjoyment! What an enjoyment!
Tremendous!
Please, be seated.
I have to especially thank him for one thing
that he has now prepared really for you,
the Guru Purnima for you.
He's worked it out really very well.
I can see that, I can feel it.
It has worked within ourselves that depth and that beauty.
And now with music, you see, it's this excavation within ourselves, you see.
Facing it within yourself.
All these things with music become
not only harmless but also so gentle,
that you don't feel that it is happening.
It just works.
You see, the- like very gentle waves you see, it works within you and
you start developing that personality which is very important
for a function like Guru Purnima.
And the beauty and the joy
they all work it out so beautifully that you don't feel that it is all working,
but I know it's really.
But, supposing, if I say something as a Guru, maybe I may hurt you.
You may feel upset and you also may feel facing yourself
a little bit, sometimes reluctant maybe diffident.
You might feel little sort of dejected or depressed.
Or you may feel sometimes also if elevate you
you might feel egoistical, you see.
So the words could be, could not render service as properly as the notes can
because the notes just penetrate within you
and work it out so smoothly  that you don't feel it's working there.
It's working no doubt.
It's like mantras it works, like mantras only.
And when it's enlightened notes, it has great effect.
I haven't brought you photographs
where, when you are playing before Me,
you go into complete lights.
I have got those photographs with Me.
Of course, also we have got  the [inaudible]
And we have got photographs, now, tomorrow we will be able to show you,
where the lights change their forms,
how through vibrations, how they change their forms, you see.
And how the vibrations work it out, you see?
But the, even the notes are used by vibrations as "vahanas" [vessel]
The notes are used and the notes
take the "vahanas" position
and they penetrate.
When there is somebody: you are singing before a Realized soul
or an evolved personality,
then the Chaitanya flows within you.
But notes are very helpful, I've seen, the beautiful notes,
and in harmony, you see.
It's so much in harmony with you,
that you don't feel the penetration.
You don't feel the injection, you don't feel the going within you.
Just it works and it just moves and
I was seeing your brain also opening out quite a lot
because the heart is so much connected with your brain now,
you are integrated.
So it's wonderful and you are all becoming thoughtless
and beautiful.
I think you all have enjoyed his things and we have to thank him very much
because our Guru Purnima day that he agreed to come
and has done the job halfway for Me.
I'm thankful to him that now, even if I say something, you won't feel hurt.
It is nice to be a Mother.
Mother is a very easy thing, it's to just to express your love and
the children are nice.
But for a Mother to be a Guru is the most difficult task.
And that, if I have to do, a Mother to be a Guru,
then I think this preparation is a very good idea because
first of all, now, you are smoothed out
and you are much better
so it's all right, as a Guru I can tell you some things.
Otherwise, for a Mother to be Guru is the worst thing that she can do
and to act as a Guru but sometimes, you have to be corrected.
But I think this one has created a beautiful atmosphere and I am very thankful to him
for this preparation
of your minds and your brains.
We are very honoured and, as I said in the beginning, I'm extremely honoured.
And, of course, it's very difficult to use words
on how I feel at this moment.
Because to be invited to play for Guru Purnima
is a great blessing for us.
And it's your blessing and it's a great honour and
we would have been very disappointed if you had not invited us to play today.
I was anxious that you should be invited actually.
Thank you.
That you should be here and you should do this
because you see, if you have seen the mid-career that you do
with that you were pulling the strings of their hearts, I could see it clearly
the importance, you see.
Some or other, I thought I can work through you better
than through my own words directly.
It's an indirect way of working out things like this
and you have been very, very helpful,  cooperative.
I'm thankful to you for this wisdom.
So, I don't know how to also
say something about
Indian music.
But I can definitely say
that the way you are appreciating Indian music
is really very creditable.
I just can't understand really how you people are so much appreciative of this music.
I'm just- it's the Spirit
or whatever you may say
it's something remarkable and even the artists are so enamoured by that.
To see such a -
Absolutely.
Absolutely. They're having rapport and all that.
They are very much enamoured by you.
Wonderful.
And they are very thankful to you the way you are just following every note and every movement
with such intense concentration.
But it's your blessings Mataji, it's your blessing that this whole atmosphere
Yes.
worked out like this.  Otherwise...
Really more for - I don't know whom to thank. You or their aim.
But I think it is mutual thanking is needed
because you were enjoying him and he was enjoying you.
Otherwise, it would not have been possible.
Without a proper audience, artist also doesn't get the encouragement to play so well.
[Hindi]
Audience has to have a rapport otherwise
You have not put anything for the Russians so far here?
There are too many there, it seems.
Just simple thing like that.
Moscow and then Kyiv.
Moscow, Leningrad.
Kyiv also.
[Hindi]
A little gift for him from you all.
Only what I can tell him is to keep the music on.
[Hindi]
So, now for- what should I say?
"Good morning" to you?
I think still that will be about -
till twelve o'clock you can have rest.
Then we'll see you. All right?
May God bless you. Thank you
[Hindi]