I’m just trying to remember if I had a more
fantastic birthday than this!
Where words do not come, there the joy
cannot be expressed.
When it becomes so deep, that there is no movement.
This is a great country.
4.1
Australia has been created
for a special purpose in Sahaja Yoga.
This is the Mooladhara chakra, where resides Shri Ganesha, of this world.
How important it is to keep this centre awakened within us.
The information about my coming
can only be broadcasted from this centre.
Then the world Kundalini is going to rise.
When you are putting your hands towards me,
then the divine love passes through
your fingers,
goes down through your Ida and Pingala
and informs Shri Ganesha about my presence
and then the Kundalini rises.
So today, we should say, is a great day
in the history of divine work,
where I came to Australia.
They asked me, “Was there any incarnation
in Australia?"
"Did God visit Australia in human form?"
I said, “It’s not easy to reach Shri Ganesh!”
Even Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesh could not reach Shri Ganesh.
And you know that he is placed like a lotus
where all kinds of people who are insulted,
tortured, ignored, are saved.
Here he really decides whom to save
from hell, and whom not to save.
God’s decisions are very different,
they are absolute.
Human decisions are extremely cruel
and blind.
And today you find so many saints in this
Mooladhara.
This is the work of Shri Ganesh.
He has called you on this great chakra
where Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha
also cannot enter in it
that you should stay here and grow
into beautiful saints
of very great magnitude in spirituality.
Such glory is to him, is such a fortunate thing,
and such a blessing,
that even Indians could be jealous of you.
One has to see how Shri Ganesha acts within us.
It’s very important to recognise him,
37.1
to understand him and to imbibe,
otherwise, you will be wasting all His
energies staying in this place,
living in this place, so close to him.
And though he is the giver of wisdom,
I wonder how many people understand
the word ‘wisdom’.
Wisdom is the centre of gravity within us
which gives us the fulcrum on which
we rotate,
by which we realise that we are inclined
to the left or to the right.
This fulcrum we have to be aware of,
because otherwise we will not know
how far we have gone.
Not only [that], but we should know that it is so much
the centre of gravity and our fulcrum - so close.
Because if your centre of gravity and
fulcrum are separated
50.1
there’s no integration.
You can be ruined completely.
So wisdom means this integration between
your understanding
and the understanding of Shri Ganesha, within you.
For example, we go to extremes, extremes of behaviour.
I would give you a very simple example:
55.1
I was going to Hong Kong
and the lady who organised it,
she telephoned to me again and again
and she told me that, “A big batch of people are coming to receive you
and you are going to be on the television
from the moment you land..
and this is going to happen and that is going to happen”.
Every day spending so much money.
Describing to me the scene
that I’ll be a “hot news” and all sorts of things, you see,
61.1
encourage lots of people to come and see you
And she was on and on and on.
And also, she told Dr Warren
except for giving the newspaper [advert] she didn’t
have to pay for it.
It was going too far.
At that juncture, just it was not necessary
to go to such a limit and plan it out that there will be people coming
inside the aeroplane to receive me
68.1
makes no difference to me!
And there would be a car waiting near
the aeroplane just to receive me.
I don’t know! I don’t know who was waiting
where, at every point!
And when we reached there, it was six
hours late
and I told Warren, “It’s all going to be a fizzled out, take it easy!”
And the plane just deposited us in Bangkok!
73.1
There was no way – six hours.
And we had to take another plane
in which nobody came in
no car
nothing.
We went down looking for her, couldn’t see
her.
Telephoned to the hotel, they said, “No arrangements thrown.”
Warren thought, “Mother has gone to another extreme now!”
Quite worried that there’s no one to receive us at the airport in Hong Kong.
It’s all a joke
Going to extremes has to be corrected in you as well.
because if you get successful with your this kind of planning,
then you’ll go on doing this kind of artificial planning
and not the planning of the divine.
The divine has its own plans
and we have to feel the plans of the divine.
It works it out. You are just an instrument to work it out.
So if you try to do something of your own,
something too much,
then who is going to suggest the balance - is Shri Ganesh
And that balance, once it’s established in you
you know how you should balance yourself.
90.1
Now, there is no alternative
for Sahaj Yog, no alternative.
91.1
One must know.
Everything that is living has no alternatives.
For example, if a mango tree says that,
“I will create a pomegranate,” it cannot!
There’s no alternatives. Whatever is there, it has to see and enjoy;
but not to force its way on it.
This is one of the things we have to understand
to establish our wisdom.
Because of our concept, our idea, our anything,
even about God for example, about our achievements itself,
can be absolutely wrong if you have no wisdom.
But in nature, if you see, those who grow
are never bothered about what shape
they are going to take, do they?
Does a tree measure itself up to know how
many dimensions it is going to grow?
It grows as much as it can
104.1
slowly, steadily
in coordination with nature itself.
Like that, the wisdom is the one that understands.
It is an establishment, is a state of mind.
We can say it’s the state of being, when you become wisdom.
Such a wisdom outside, also expresses so beautifully.
Such a wisdom gives you a gentleman and a gentlelady
only in a personality which is settled down.
If you are frustrated
112.1
and if there’s a problem
if you are unhappy, if you are suppressed
any extremes will not allow this flower of wisdom to grow.
So even in frustration you have to look back,
you have to stand back and see for yourself,
“Why am I to be so frustrated?”
Count your blessings one by one.
118.1
I’ll say again, count your blessings one by one.
Once you start counting your blessings,
you will find in such a short time, where are you.
Now the extreme projections of the mind can take you to:
“I’m not going to face!” and you would like to do it.
But in wise projection, you can see this, that you are what you have to be.
You are saints.
You were born to be saints in this great country.
You are specially blessed people in the heavens,
and are sent on this Earth to do this Maha Yoga, to spread it.
You have achieved that state.
And if you are saints, you should not be bothered as to a few things like,
“Oh! I haven’t got a suitcase” or something
sort of a thing like that
which you have never been very much bothered before.
Can you see that?
133.1
Any kind of extreme behaviour
For example, for materialism you people are not so bad
in the sense that you understand the value
of aesthetics.
But in possessiveness let us take the wise
path, the wisdom
logical, it has to be logical
137.1
What do we possess in this world?
Just think of one thing that we can possess!
Except for your own Spirit, you don’t possess anything.
Except for your evolutionary development, you don’t possess anything.
For example, now you are a saint you’ll be born a saint always
this is what you possess
142.1
The rest you don’t possess
It’s logical, logical.
You need not to be realised to understand what I am saying.
So why should we worry about our possessions?
When you leave this worry, this is another wisdom,
this is the higher wisdom
which you develop within yourself.
And if we leave our possessions, our material problems are solved.
‘Leave’ doesn’t mean you throw them in the sea,
but the attachment to it dissolves
149.1
It is solved.
149.2
Let me give you an example
Like Kay lost her travellers’ cheques
150.1
she did not know, she was not knowing
Suddenly one man bumped into her.
151.1
I was with her.
He said, “Imagine, I never knew I was going to meet you!”
He said, “I went to a particular cashier or somebody"
And he said “Do you know this lady? I’ve got her travellers cheques with me.”
"And here, suddenly, I bump into you!”
How the news has been organised, in the nature you see,
when the flowers bloom, how these bees come all the way.
How the birds fly all the way from Siberia to Australia?
What wisdom, is that magnetism in them
159.1
the magnetism that is in the Mother Earth
which tells them, “This is the way you have to go.”
So we have to see to this magnetism within us:
What makes us magnetic
is not what we could have, what unnatural
things we have
but what naturally we have achieved within
and we are not afraid to express it
In fear you are never aggressive
but even in fearlessness you are never aggressive
In fear you might say that you are not afraid
but you could be aggressive
When people look very frightened, if you push them
to the extreme of fright, they can come back
But if you are fearless, you are innocent
172.1
you are just standing and watching
Fearlessness never means aggression
So the confusion of our own concepts
can only be cleared out
if there is light within us.
For us, if somebody is aggressing us, then we think
[that] if we do not aggress the other
person, we are frightened
then we are useless,
178.1
we are weak, we are weak people
so we should fight back.
179.1
Even when you are fighting back, you are weak people.
If it was not so, what is there to fight
back?
In fearlessness you become the witness.
You see the joke
joke behind all this extreme behaviour of another person.
And also you know the technique, kaushalam.
Yoga also means kaushalam, it means technique
184.1
how to manage the show
by which his action doesn’t trouble you
185.1
if you want to.
If you don’t want, you can even take
the action upon yourself, to prove it
that, “Whatever you are doing is a little
silly and stupid.”
Like Christ getting Himself crucified.
It was a wise decision to do
because if you have to prove that life is eternal
the best thing is to die and show.
And to be [done] publicly, so that nobody
should say that he was not dead.
Still there are many people who are saying he was not dead.
Still there are people who are talking this: “He was not dead.
He was alive. So he got out of the place.”
Because they don’t know how to explain!
So he had to die publicly
and then his resurrection was to be seen
by many people.
This drama had to be performed
for you to have the wisdom to know that life is eternal.
It doesn’t mean that he was weak, by any chance.
So the idea of our aggression, or our suppression
Both come from either fear
203.1
or some sort of a satanic pleasure
203.2
to oppress others
So wisdom lies in seeing yourself also
See how wisdom is so important!
Throughout if you find, in every chakra resides pranava
is the life of every chakra.
Because it is the wisdom that tells you whether you are in the chakra or not.
So how wisdom is [so] important
209.1
that you even become a sakshi if you have wisdom
otherwise you cannot
You become a witness only when you have that focal point
211.1
adjusted to your centre of gravity
That is wisdom!
When people tell me about somebody who has harmed them
they paint such a dark picture of the whole thing
as if it was another war that was fought.
Then you go and listen to another side,
they paint another horrible picture
of this side.
Between these two pictures you stand.
You find the one is reflecting the other,
the other is reflecting the other.
There is no end to it, it’s eternally going
on from this to that, to that to this.
How do you end it up?
Only by your wisdom, by understanding it’s an illusion.
The main thing is the mirror on which it is reflected,
It’s just an illusion that is appearing, and we are worried about it.
The whole illusion will drop out as soon as you just see the mirror
and don’t worry about the reflections.
They’ll come and go: it is for you just to witness it, that’s all.
It’s not..the mirror is a mirror, which is a solid thing,
and all the reflections are illusions.
That’s how we miss all the sweetness of our own being.
Wisdom lies in understanding that you are the Spirit.
You are not all these illusions. You are the Spirit.
232.1
You are the Spirit.
The attention was, as animals, was on food only, you can say.
You were aware of food, nothing else but food only.
This grows higher and higher in awareness,
then he came up to a point where he started thinking that
he is the prime minister
237.1
or he is an actor or an actress
and this and that and so-called things they have achieved.
Or maybe they start thinking - oh, they are atheists
agnostics and all sorts of things, you see.
240.1
Communists!
240.2
And specialists!
It’s a drama going on!
241.1
They are wearing wigs after wigs.
If they like this wig they’ll wear this, otherwise throw away!
This has killed the romance completely!
You start loving the wigs of a person!
And wigs can be bought!
245.1
They could be exchanged.
If you go into the market, you can get about ten types of wigs.
Supposing you say, “Oh, I like this colour for the hair,”
so the lady will go and wear that and come out
and then you’ll like her for the wig that she has got
Then another may wear the same
Or this same lady, who looks nice with one wig,
could bore you completely!
Because there’s no living dynamism, that charisma
Every moment is so beautiful
254.1
It breaks into new waves
of such beautiful colours and beautiful music.
That’s all lost with these bought images.
Every minute the image changes, with a living personality,
into tremendous beauty.
258.1
But the first point is the wisdom
to know that our images cannot be purchased
or bought or created or made.
260.1
They evolve!
So we have to only see to our evolving force..
are we nearer it or are we out of it?
Are we moving with our evolving force
Of getting ourselves crucified
264.1
with all these artificial misidentifications that says that,
You are this, you are that.
265.1
You are nothing but a seeker.
It’s a category, I have told many-a-times
266.1
that you are a seeker and you have to seek
Now, what do you seek? Is your Spirit.
And once you have found it, establish yourself on that.
268.1
That’s what you are!
And to know that you are that Spirit itself is so satisfying
is itself emitting wisdom in you
270.1
Which is so joy giving
and is nothing but love
271.1
It’s love, I tell you!
I mean, I cannot go beyond this.
There’s no word in human language to say
what is love.
To me it is nothing but silence.
274.1
Everything stops at that point.
This feeling within yourself, where the wisdom is becoming love,
and love becomes wisdom.
276.1
that’s the real integration of life.
Open your hearts!
277.1
Allow Shri Ganesha to be settled in that
That innocence which enhances everything.
Look at the little ones.
279.1
How they came forward to give me flowers.
Every step, every movement was so joyous
was creating such a beautiful, delicate ripple in my heart.
And it’s written as history for me,
to see these little, little sweet, innocent Ganeshas coming forward
And the wisdom becomes so powerful
that you know the source of love as Ganesha in you.
For him, he did not know anybody else but one
286.1
That which is the source of love.
Never questioned, never argued. No alternatives!
No new ideas came to his mind.
288.1
It's just taking in.
Working it out within yourself and the whole thing just works out.
The more you enter into it, you will
understand that you have really entered
into the Kingdom of God where he looks after everyone.
You want a house? All right, have it!
What do you want? You want that? Alright!
You have a problem? Have it.
It’s all God’s, the own thing. Who owns it but God?
He is the One who owns everything and He’s
the One who enjoys everything.
And he wants you to enjoy everything.
Only through the power of your wisdom that you can achieve it
Today, You all have to show a part of that achievement in your wisdom
in which there is no artificiality. It’s so natural.
But natural doesn’t mean baser. Some
people think to be angry is also natural.
But you are a human being and
a Sahaja Yogi.
Whatever is natural to a Sahaja Yogi
is not the same as whatever is natural
to a buffalo.
We have nothing to learn from them,
they have to learn from us.
So whatever is natural to a Sahaja Yogi
has to be learnt in the school of wisdom.
Not by any rules or anything
that I say, “You don’t do this,” and, “You do this!”
“You are not to do like that.” “You are not
to do this way!”
Even in the hand if you see: this portion is Australia.
Now just see: this portion is the source for all the fingers
is the connecting point, this is your point
312.1
But it doesn’t say anything!
For example, this thumb means something,
this finger means something
314.1
this means something
but this doesn’t say anything, doesn’t do anything.
But without this nothing exists.
If it is cut out here, you are paralysed,
all the movements are finished, you see.
This is the connecting link with the divine
and the guiding link.
This only tells which finger to move
319.1
where to take, how to contract which muscle.
All of this is controlled in this portion.
The day will come when the information
will reach the whole world
through the awakening of Ganesha in my children
322.1
the Sahaja Yogis in Australia.
And the whole world is going to get the blessings coming into it
Of course, you know that Kundalini is in India
and only then the Kundalini can rise.
But one thing you have to remember
is that you are really placed at a very pivotal point here
and that the responsibility is too much on you.
And the responsibility is to keep the whole atmosphere pure
and send forth all the fragrance of the lotus.
Though maybe you will feel you are surrounded by all the mud and everything,
but still you have to be very strong lotuses.
For the whole world you have to come up
and send forth that beautiful fragrance
of announcement that the Blossom Time has come.
I was asking for the river’s name
335.1
what’s the name of the river
I wonder if you thought about it
336.1
See, the river’s name is ‘Parramatta’
‘Para’ in Greek means ‘above, beyond’ should be Para
And ‘Mata’ means ‘the mother’
338.1
Your river’s name itself is Parramatta.
It’s a Greek word and how the Greeks
have known this word ‘Parramatta’?
This river had to be here, the Adi Shakti itself only, had to be here
to bless the Ganesha all the time which has to do the work.
He’s the one who sorts out
342.1
The Lambodara!
The one you will see in the Sistine Chapel, very well pointed out.
It’s a huge big stomach.
344.1
It’s really an Australian character, personality,
standing there, sorting out people,
throwing left to the right.
It’s so beautiful, I wish you could get
that picture some time.
And you will be surprised – it’s an
Australian. you can see it perfectly -
it’s Australian character.
That is Christ, absolutely an Australian
body, standing up.
I don’t know how Michelangelo could see that so clearly
that he had to be Australian like that.
It has been so beautiful to come down here.
So beautiful.
It’s blissful for you maybe, but for me it’s nothing but complete joy.
complete joy.
I had told that I will not do anything
after three years time;
I will just settle down
355.1
because the saintly person is not supposed
to move from places to places, they must settle down,
they must have their own round pillow that’s called as takiya,
and you are not to leave that.
But I am a Mother who is moving all over.
And can you imagine, I’ve been all over
the places, but never to Australia before.
So to come here first thing was so great
that even,
today I have not been able to put
all that into words.
May God bless you all.
You are really the Ganeshas, the amount
of food you have.