Today again is
a new year's day. Every new year comes, because
we have to take to something that is new.
It has been so arranged that the sun has to
move for 365 days and again a new year has
come.
Actually the whole Solar System is moving
in a spiral way. So, there is definitely a
higher, higher state of this Solar System.
Every year it is rising higher in a spiral
way. So it is not only that it is because
365 days have passed, it is because it has
moved a step forward, higher than what it
was.
Now, we can see that in awareness, human beings
have definitely risen much higher than what
they were, say, about 2000 years back. But,
the first system that started the whole Universe
was the first model, you can say was created.
And that model has to be perfect. And that
was a perfect model which then started perfecting
the rest of it.
So that is the perfect model which is in the
principle of this ascent. And that is working
out this ascent. Now, the perfection of the
rest of the universe takes place in various
directions.
But today we have to consider the Mahalakshmi
Principle. The Mahalakshmi, as I told you,
is a perfect principle. It's a perfect principle.
It's perfected. It is born as perfect, will
remain as perfect, will be always eternally
perfect so that it is not necessary to be
corrected.
Now this Mahalakshmi's thing I am discussing
here because you may be able to go today to
see the temple of Mahalakshmi. Now the temple
of Mahalakshmi when you go there, you have
to know that this deity has come out of the
Mother Earth in this particular place. That
means this place has got a capacity to give
you a force. You can say, an additional force
or an intensive feeling of evolution. If you
are sensitive enough you can see that, you
can feel it and you can do it. But, if you
are not so sensitive, you are still so conditioned
and still outside, that may not work out.
I mean all kinds of things can be done, but
if somebody wants to remain a stone you can't
do anything about it.
So this Mahalakshmi principle is working out
in this place Kolhapur. Normally, this place
should be very, very warm because of its position.
But even in summer this place keeps very cool
because of the vibrations from the temple
that is emitted. The people in this place
may not be so aware either. We cannot say
if they are aware because, as negativity has
to come forward, there are lots of sugar factories
and lots of alcoholism going on here.
But we have to take the best advantage of
every place which is created specially for
a particular purpose. So, it is a pilgrimage,
in a way, that we are here. That we have to
look after our Mahalakshmi Principle of our
ascent. As you know, this ascent starts at
the Nabhi and is surrounded by the Guru principle.
Now the Guru Principle within us, if it is
absurd, if it is juxtapositioned, placed in
juxtaposition where, if it is not properly
embedded within us, if it is not emitting
through our character and behaviour, Mahalakshmi
tattwa cannot be strengthened.
Mahalakshmi tattwa is strengthened through
Guru principle. Now we are lucky today because
there was the birthday of Datta, Dattatreya,
just the other day, when we had the puja,
and today is this Mahalakshmi puja. So two
things together we have got together. First
was the Datta puja and today is this puja
of Mahalakshmi. So, to have the Guru principle
all right, we must make our dharmas correct.
Now these dharmas, as I have told you many
times, are ten, and we should look after these
ten dharmas in a very careful manner. These
are expressed outside, but whatever is inside
comes out.
Now I find, when you people talk, and you
say things, I know that this person is negative,
that person is definitely positive. There
are so many ways of expression of positivity.
But how I know that, I cannot tell you, because
I just don't know how to tell you that. But
I just know that such a person is definitely
positive and such a person is negative. The
positivity lies in understanding why are we
here. First of all, why are we on this earth?
Why are we human beings? In understanding!
What are we doing about it? Why are we Sahaja
Yogis? What a Sahaja Yogi has to do? What
is his responsibility as a Sahaja Yogi. Then
he moves forward to understand -- why Mother
is so kind to me? Why have I got vibrations?
Why am I among very few who have got this
special blessing, the special knowledge of
vibratory awareness. And then to ask yourself,
"What am I doing about it? Am I still very
much embedded in my cheapishness or in my
childishness, in my stupidity, in my harshness,
in my aggressiveness?"
We always see these things in other people,
not in ourselves -- so we are not Sahaja Yogis.
We should understand at that point. When we
start seeing these things in other people,
then we are not Sahaja Yogis. We should see
in ourselves and emit pure compassion to others.
But always people see that it is in another
person this exists. Whatever I may try to
say they always see in other person. Now supposing
there's a negative person among us, you need
not be compassionate to that person. On the
contrary better be away. Get rid of that person,
as far as possible don't have anything to
do [with them]. Is a definite sign of great
compassion to yourself, if not to others.
Better not have anything to do with the person
who is negative, if you have to come up. He
may be your brother, sister, anyone. But try
to be away from a person who is not positive.
It causes lots of problems. I have been telling
you this, and I have been requesting you,
but the conditioning is such that, still though
you have become a Guru tattwa, you don't understand
that you have to be detached.
For the Guru there's no brother, sister or
any other relationship except for the relationship
of the Mother. There is no other relationship.
One of these principles are to be understood.
Very important I feel is for all of you that
-- our relationship is only to Mother and
to Sahaja Yogis and not to any relationship
which has come to us, whether through Sahaja
Yoga or whether through anything else. Now
this I have been explaining because our Mahalakshmi
Tattwa is not all right. That's why we get,
sort of, frittered away, lost, into these
things. And the Mahalakshmi tattwa has to
be like an ascending force all put together.
Like my father used to give an example. That
supposing you have collected lot of wheat
and you spread it on the ground, it will be
all lost. It will be spread out like this,
this side, that side, it will be all lost.
But if you put it in a bag, it will rise in
height. Naturally! It will have those maryadas.
It will rise and it will go higher and higher.
In the same way this principle of Mahalakshmi
can spread just across like that, and can
just destroy all that Mother has given us
and all that we have had all these years,
only by spreading it out.
Now to collect it inside, is to pay attention
to yourself. First of all, try to clarify
your ideas and your understanding in [the]
brain. Is important, because Mahalakshmi tattwa
ultimately works in the brain. Is the enlightenment
of the brain, is done by Mahalakshmi tattwa.
It gives you the Sat, the Truth, you see.
So in the brain you must clarify. Reach logically.
Logically you must reach the conclusion, "I
don't have to do these things, I have to do
these things. I have to ascend. This is why
I am here. Why I am here? What am I supposed
to do?" Now logically you convince your brain,
first of all. This is very important now,
after realisation. Because if logically your
brain doesn't understand, it will always be
cheapish, childish, indignified or could be
harsh, horribly oppressive. It could be one
of these.
So, in Guru tattwa, there are ten elements.
Five of them deal with the weight. Weight.
Guru is the weight you see. Weight of a person.
How much weight you have got? The gravity,
as we call it. Person has a gravity. When
he talks how much balance he has got. See
in Indian Music, we call it Vazan, means the
weight. The weight of the person, means when
he is dealing with himself or with others,
how much weight he carried. In English also
they use this -- weight. How much weight he
carries with others? Means, how much he can
really impress others? If you impress too
much, all right, then the person will say,
'Oh, it's too much.' That is the very big
quality with western people is, "Oh, that
is too much!" That's because they have an
idea, you see. This is all ego oriented. That
is too much. If you tell them too much, "Oh!
that is too much. She is too much. I do it
slowly, slowly. It is too much for me!" Is
very common, is very common reaction. So how
much weight you have.
And the second one is the quality of magnetic.
Two things. Magnetism. First is the quality
of weight. That's how much dignified you are.
How you talk. How your language is. How your
behaviour is. You should be humorous, but
sometimes, even with me, I find people talk
in a very funny manner. I just don't understand,
how is it that always they say the wrong things?
I mean, even if they have to say one sentence,
they'll say a wrong thing. Is absolutely with
them. It is also Vishuddhi, which is also
Nabhi, comes from Nabhi, because you must
know that Vishuddhi Chakra is the ascent of
the Nabhi Chakra.
So what happens, that a person whatever he
is, is expressed through his language, through
his behaviour, through his face, through his
nose, his eyes, everything, through the Vishuddhi
Chakra. So the ascent of the Nabhi is expressed,
shown, through the Vishuddhi Chakra. Now whatever
you have in the Nabhi is shown here. Supposing
now, a person who has the Mahalakshmi tattwa
properly developed, such a person will have
a way of dealing with another person where
he will have the weight as well as the understanding
[of] how far to go with the person. How far
to carry on with the person. How far to talk
to a person. How far to think about it. How
much importance to be given. That's one point,
is very important.
And the another point is that -- how much
magnetism you have? So you reverse back to
yourself. The magnetism is a magic, is a magic
of a person. A person is magnetic because
he has certain magic. Now this magic is, comes,
from your own personality. From your own personality.
The basis of magnetism, on the left hand side,
starts. And that basis is Shri Ganesha. Shri
Ganesha is the basis of that magnetism. So
you're innocent. Innocence is the best way
to have that magnetism. Magnetism you cannot
express in material way. It's not a material
stuff but it is something abstract, comes
from your quality of Ganesha, Shri Ganesha.
Such a person is magnetic. Magnetic means
that such a person attracts other person because
of the weight of the person, because of the
quality of the person such a person attracts.
But does not attract for lust, greed and nonsensical
things. But attracts another person because
of the fragrance of love in the subjects.
Now it is always confused. Confused!. Because
it's such an abstract thing so one must understand
it in a very subtle way. What is this magnetism?
That one should understand. You see, there
some gestures people use artificially. Which
normally they have been using just to attract
other people, the way they walk, the way they
dress, the way they live. All these things
are of no use. It is something so inner, that
fragrance is so inner which must be developed.
But in Sahaja Yoga I have seen, people just
don't bother about it, just don't bother.
They think the way they have been living,
the way they have been this...say, if they
are English, they are English, if they are
French they are French, if they are Indians
they are Indians, if they are from Kolhapur
they will be from Kolhapur. These ideas first
must be curbed off, because the fragrance
spreads everywhere whether you are English
or anyone.
So the fragrance of a person develops through,
first of all, the Ganesha principle within
you. Ganesha principle is to be first of all
seen to. Now a Ganesha person is not a person
who is absolutely a remorse type or a person
who is such a gone case that even if you beat
him up and make him into a complete minced
thing, he will bear it. It's not like that!
It's not that. On the contrary the quality
of magnetism is such that it attracts you,
to a point where you are not disturbed. Now
this is a very important point we should know.
You see, if you have other loves, love like
carnal love and all other love you have, then
that love you may attract the person. That
person can destroy you and it destroys you,
always. But this attraction does not destroy,
does not destroy. The attraction is up to
that point that you are not destroyed, because
you being much higher, much deeper and much
weightier, you cannot be destroyed by a thing
that you are attracting. Always the greater
magnet attracts the smaller magnet. And that
is what one should understand. This magic
and this karishma, the charismatic temperament
of a person comes by, first of all, the Ganesh
tattwa, innocence. And secondly by complete
dedication and devotion.
Those who are completely dedicated and devoted
to Mother. Not to anything else. Ganesh tattwa
again. Not to your wife, not to your husband,
not to your sister, not to your country, not
to anyone but to Mother. Complete dedication
gives you that charisma, or that attraction.
In Sahaja Yoga such a person becomes really
attractive and such a person has ??????.
Now some
people think that if you are a very passive
person and if anybody says anything to you
and you don't mind, sort of a person you are
charismatic. It is not. People like you because
they can dominate you. They like you because
they can dominate you. Now if you think that
by your aggressiveness and by your shouting
and by your screaming at these people, you
will achieve that charismatic temperament,
you cannot. You cannot achieve that height.
So how do you achieve it? By becoming more
innocent.
Now how innocence develops in a person is
by not thinking about it. Like, you see, somebody
asked me, 'How do you manage your Income Tax?'
I said, 'By having no income at all'. Then
they asked me, 'How do you solve your car
problem?' "By not having any car at all of
mine." They said, 'What about your house problem?"
"By having no house of my own."
"Nihi, Nihi." Everything Nihi for me. Then
how do you solve your this problem? By not
having it, just have -- "No, not have it!"
Don't take up headaches upon yourself.
See when you take up headaches upon yourself
then only the innocence is reduced. That headaches
like this, that "This is my shawl, this is
my sari, this is my thing, this is this, this
is this, this is this". But only one thing
is that "This is my Mother and I have to proclaim
Her", that's all.
If that is the way it is, then innocence starts
rising like Shri Ganesha, and by having no
other headache. "This is mine, that is mine."
This 'mine' business causes the problem, I
think. Personally, I think this must be the
reason. That this 'mine' business. 'This is
mine.' Because whatever is mine. Somebody
told me, this is very good argument he gave,
"Whatever is mine is not I", means that is
not Sahaja. My body, my head, my everything
-- 'my'. But 'I' He gave me this idea -- 'I'.
What is 'I'? Then 'I' is separating, Whatever
is not mine is 'I'. So what remains is your
Spirit. Somebody gave me this argument. I
said "Is a very good argument to work it out".
Then whatever remains is the 'I' and that
'I' is the one we have to see! So you go on
reducing all these 'mines', 'mines', 'mines'.
So the pure spirit of innocence will rise.
So the idea about Spirit also, people think
that if you become spiritual -- I mean, I
don't know what people think about spiritual
people. But the idea about spiritual people
is that you have to be something terrific
like a bull or I don't know. You have to be
sharp like a fox or you have to be intellectual
like Freud or something. All sorts of ideas
people have. No, it is not! Spiritual person
is just innocent, just innocent. There is
no intelligence, nothing. Just innocent. The
whole thing is innocence. See, whatever he
talks or says, comes through innocence. It
doesn't have intellect as such, which here
people have through reading and through understanding
and by analysing. Nothing of the kind. It
just has pure and simple innocence. And it
all works out very well. It is so clean. It
just says what it knows and what it knows
is the highest.
So this deconditioning has to be brought within
us. But you should not discuss it among yourselves
also. Once you start discussing then you also,
you see, it becomes sort of a theological
argumentation. There is no theology about
it. It's very simple. It's the simplest thing
is to be innocent. But the innocence is lost.
Why? Because our attention is in different
way, we are attentive to other things. We
are looking at other things. It's so simple,
you know. Today I was thinking I have to buy
three nine-yard saris. A simple question as
it is, because there were three ladies who
wear nine yard saris and I had to give them
three nine yard saris. That is all. I just
thought of it. All right. I came here, I saw
very nice saris being put here. So I asked
her, 'Where do you get?' She said 'You get
it here'. I said 'All right'. So you go and
buy these three saris. No analysis, nothing
of the kind. It just came into my mind that
I have to buy three saris, finished! The answer
is here. So even the atmosphere is so innocent,
the whole situation is so innocent that the
solution is presented by innocence to innocence.
Innocence works out in everything, you see,
because everybody has little bit of innocence
in every one, isn't it? So you can...it's
like a fifth column, you see. The innocence
is a fifth column within you. So if any person
is innocent, you see he'll work on your fifth
column and will make you all right. When you
give bandhan to others, what happens, you
actually bind him by your innocence and the
poor fellow doesn't know. He has his innocence
within him, you capture that innocence, that
is all you have done, that's how you manage.
It's very simple to work out things. Only
principle, the tattwa, the whole thing rests
on what? Tattwa is nothing but innocence.
So try to develop this by all these things...
"Ya neti, neti wachane nigamor awachus" By
saying "Not this, not this, not this, not
this, not this," to all your thoughts. "Not
this not this, not this, not this". You reach
there. 'Not mine, not mine, not mine, not
mine". And that is how it is.
And you see the whole material world is now
attacking the innocence, because they are
frightened. You cannot attack it. Innocence
cannot be destroyed. It cannot be destroyed.
Innocence is something [which] is all pervading
and it cannot be destroyed. So whatever people
may try, it cannot be destroyed. But it can
be covered, it can recede, but it cannot be
destroyed. It will act it's own way. So try
to develop that innocence which is the basis
of Mahalakshmi Tattwa, we should say, or that
is essence of Mahalakshmi tattva.
So the outward things, the weightage, the
weight, the dignity, the behaviour everything.
It is outward thing and the inside thing -- the
tattwa, the principle, on which it is based
is innocence.
Now if, with this, if we understand Mahalakshmi
tattwa within us, how it has to work out.
It's not intellectual! Again I would say that
I don't want you to project your intellect
into it, and to find out, but just remain
where you are and you will find the answers
just coming to you..automatically!
Just don't project your minds into it. Just
you'll get answers to every question, just
like that. Because innocence in everyone is
the simple answer where all the complications
drop out. The innocence is that. And that
is what is the love of God, is the love of
God.
So don't confuse this with love, with all
your nonsensical love ideas you have about
people and identification, misidentification.
This is pure love within us, the purity, the
innocence which is love and which is life
itself, we should say. It is a part of that,
the Prana Shakti. But Prana Shakti is not
Mahalakshmi.
So Mahalakshmi is the essence and essence
of everything, Because if creation has to
take place, also, if desire of God is there,
and if there is no Mahalakshmi tattwa, then
what is the use of having desire?
Supposing, even if you have creation, and
you do not have the Mahalakshmi tattwa, how
will you work it out? You cannot work it out,
You have to have Mahalakshmi tattwa. Because
they do not have any meaning.
So outwardly it is Mahalakshmi tattwa, but
inside, inside is, we can say, there are three
cores. The first core is Mahalakshmi tattwa,
outside to look at, you see the growth, all
right. Then inside is the creation, that is
all the elements being created and all that.
But inside that is the desire and inside the
desire is the half one, you can say, is the
Ganesha. So this Ganesh tattwa ultimately
overpowers everything and permeates everything.
And this is, I would say that, don't think
about it. Just allow your innocence to grow,
Simple innocence.
And your dignity. That's very important to
have your dignity. Like some people think
if they wear torn clothes and walk about on
the street, and all they are big sanyasis.
It's wrong. Why? You are not being dignified
and God has given you so much, why should
you try to show that you haven't got anything?
Just to show off that you haven't got anything
God has given. This is just a sort of thanks-giving
to God that, "God you have given me so much."
You have to wear the best. Like in Puja, if
you see, the ladies here wear all their nose
rings and all their ornaments and everything,
in the temple if they have to go. Everything
they wear! And in the same way, men also wear
their very clean dresses, very clean things,
whatever they have, they wear simple, clean
dresses, whatever they have. But no ostentation.
It is just a thing by which you express. The
God has given you this. 'O God! I thank you'.
It is such a great day today to be, in the
new year, on the new year day, to be here
on Mahalakshmi's place of Kolhapur. And this
is also called Kolhapur because Kolhasura
was killed here. Kolhasura was a horrible
fellow like a fox and he was born again. Now
he is again dead. Thank God!
He was here and now he's...Kolhasura died.
You don't think about it, again your mind
goes out. Don't think about it, I will tell
you about it. I have deliberately avoided
the name. He was born again and was pitched
out. So this is the place where Kolhasura
was killed, where this was established, so
Mahalakshmi incarnation came in and that is
how this place has a special value, that we
have come here for a pilgrimage and let us
be in a humble way. Think about it.
Actually these things could not take place
in the West because even if they had come
out of the Mother Earth who would have recognised
them? Who would have known about them? Who
would have respected them? Who would have
worshipped them? That is why it did not happen
in the West too much. But it is there, little
bit is there, no doubt. But here now we have
these, all these, temples and the attack on
the innocence has come from tantrikas. And
so the tantrikas entered all these temples
and they tried to establish themselves. But
gradually they are being neutralised and cleaned
out. These tantrikas have gone into every
temple of all the Goddesses. And they will
be gradually all out, straight out.
So this is the attack that came through and
that how these brahmins came down and settled
in these places. So-called brahmins. And tried
to preach about all tantrik methods and things
here, in the temple, and they really spoiled
the atmosphere here.
So may God bless you all.
I want you people to develop concentration
of mind so that you rise above all other misidentifications
and get identified with the Pure Spirit, through
your Mahalakshmi principle.
May God bless you.