Today we are here to celebrate Krishna Puja.
I went to America and they wanted Me to have
a Mahakali Puja. But I said, “No, let Me
talk about Krishna only.” Because we have
to first realize what is the strength of this
Puja, how are we going to establish Shri Krishna
within ourselves.
He Himself has said that “Whenever there
is a downfall of dharma.” Dharma doesn’t
mean what we understand as Hinduism, Christianity
or Islamic nonsense - it is not. Dharma means
our primordial taboos that are built-in, in
the human beings. About these, I think aboriginals
knew better than we. But then what we did,
we dominated them and also they had to change
their style of life. The primordial taboos
are only understood if people are trying to
understand oneself or else whatever has come
to them through tradition.
Now, sahaj dharma is little bit different
in the sense that it’s much higher than
the sahaj ideas that we talk of, but it’s
much higher than even what Shri Krishna said
or Shri Rama said. First, Shri Rama thought,
best is to give them disciplines. People should
be serious about life, have full idea about
their own being, they should respect themselves.
All these things were written down long time
back. Also, people, basically when they were
good people, they understood that whatever
is bad for us, we should not do. These are
primordial taboos.
Now, these primordial taboos are built in
within us. Now, supposing I say, “Don’t
drink.” You will go and drink. If I say,
“Don’t tell lies,” you will tell lies.
It’s the human nature, you see, is to go
against primordial taboo, because they think
now they have freedom, freedom to do what
they like. You are free people. Actually they
are not. They are under the spell of all the
kinds of allurement, you can call it, or temptations
which are against human life. And it’s very
natural to be a person of dharma. Small children
mostly have it.
For example, I’ve seen children, they feel
very shy to take out their clothes - even
small, small boys, I’ve seen. They won’t
take out their clothes in the presence of
others; they feel shy. So, all these are described
like, Ya Devi, Sarva Butheshu, Lajja Rupena
Samsthita. So, you should be shy; you should
be humble and respect your body, it’s very
important in these modern times. Exposure
of body is regarded as a great achievement
of women. They are trying to become aboriginals,
you see. That time they never had these ideas
and they were not so confused, you see. So,
even if their women were scantily dressed,
it didn’t mean that it was some sort of
a sex or some sort of an attraction for men,
or men behaving in funny manners to show that
they have a special attraction for women.
I mean, why should you? It is absolutely absurd
that men should be attracted to women and
women should be attracted to men - and on
the road, on the street, you go, you see,
just that going on! This adharma is the worst
I think, for it’s a curse. Because after
coming to Sahaja Yoga also people start doing
this nonsense, you know. They should all go
to lunatic asylum, I think, they are no good
for Sahaja Yoga. But dharma gets established
as soon as you have the light of the spirit.
At the time of Shri Rama, He had to put down
A, B, C, D, E, F. At the time of Moses, also
He had to put down Ten Commandments. But Krishna
thought the other way round - to establish
a dharma of pure love - pure love. So, because
He wanted that Shri Rama’s taboos were forced
on people, just like Islamic, just like Christians
- never works. So, He thought better to ask
them in their freedom, they must develop pure
love. Radha, who was with Him as His power,
is called as Alladhadayini. She’s the one
who gives joy - pure joy!
So, all these limited type of attractions
end up in trouble. Now, drinking is against
you, you know that. Today they are talking
about tobacco, tomorrow they’ll talk of
drinking when they will find so many people
suffering from horrible livers and dying.
Then they will taboo it. But it’s a natural
taboo for your body. If you do something all
the time which is not good for you, for your
good life, you are becoming adharma.
This is to be understood very clearly that
the sahaja dharma is that you are just free
- complete freedom from lust, greed and all
nonsense. You’re above it. You’re above.
This sahaj dharma is above the dharma established
by Shri Krishna or by Shri Rama, because you
have reached that stage. Is in complete freedom
you have to be dharmic. Whatever is not good
for you, you should not do. I don’t have
to tell you that you don’t do this or you
don’t do that. Whatever I say may not be
acceptable, but immediately your vibrations
will tell you.
This is sahaj dharma. In the sahaj dharma
you get rid of all kinds of, as they say:
kaama, krodha, mada, matsa, lobha, moha. Means:
lust, anger, attractions, then greed. Greed
- that’s very important, greed. Greed. And
attractions. Now, if you understand how people
are greedy, greedy for what? This America
is dying of consumerism, you see. Now, see
the trick of the trade. In America, you can
borrow any amount of money from the bank,
no problem. Now, even if you don’t borrow,
they’ll send you a letter, “Why don’t
you take twenty thousand checks we are sending
you, why not have it? Ah, very rich you’ll
become, you see – it’s very nice to take
the loan.” I was told some people used to
come to Ganapatipule after taking loans. I
said, “Stop that nonsense!” So they take
the loan and then they come to Ganapatipule.
All the time their mind is: ‘How will I
pay this loan, how will I manage?’ All the
time the attention is distracted, even when
you want to do something good to yourself
of coming to Ganapatipule.
So, such a mind is not free. The free mind
is that which has attention completely enlightened
by the spirit. But problem is we are still
rising out of this human bondage to a higher
life of realization. And when we are going
to that level, we have to realize that we
have to give up all these shackles, all these
horrible things within us. Like a bird, when
it is born out of the egg, shakes out all
the parts of the egg. Your brothers, your
sisters, your father, your mother, your husband.
Everybody - they try to put you down. Now,
if they are drinking, they’ll say, “Come
along, you better have something to drink,
you are not social, you are useless, you are
not up to date. What is this nonsense?”
That’s how a fashion starts and this collective
action of fashion didn’t come from Shri
Krishna and not in Sahaj.
In Sahaj, you are absolutely free from all
these nonsenses. If you want, you can wear
a good dress, if you don’t want you need
not. You are free. You are free from money
bondage. This is very important. Money bondage
is another thing. I know some Sahaja Yogis
who came to Sahaja Yoga trying to make money
out of Sahaja Yoga. You came to Sahaja Yoga
for what? To get out of that money bondage.
In the sahaj dharma, to you money is nothing
but the dust of your feet. Nothing so important.
Then, we have such a collective sense of accepting
nonsense. That has to be dropped out, specially
in America, I was surprised. Also in England.
A fellow came as a hippie. His hair were looking
like some monkey. Monkey is better I must
say. I don’t know like what, all put together
like a, you can say - there is nothing to
compare, I tell you.
So I asked him, “Why are you having such
hair?”
He said, “Because I want to be primitive.
Now, we have to get to the primitiveness.”
I said, “But your brain is modern, what’s
the use of growing your hair like that? You
think you can become primitive? You cannot!”
Then afterwards I learned that he died. Another
one like that came and he didn’t die, but
went to lunatic asylum. Like that I met many,
but why do you do it? Because that’s the
fashion.
Now Italy, you know, is prospering because
of all kinds of designers. Now there is a
joke about the ouveau riche people, in Russia especially.
Russians are not like that, normally. They
don’t accept something because it’s a
fashion.
So, one fellow said that “My God you lost
your hand in that accident!”
“Doesn’t matter, but I lost my very expensive
watch from Switzerland.”
“Really? What?”
“It was a Rolex.”
Doesn’t matter if the hand is gone. The
Rolex is gone - Rolex is the fashion.
So these are ouveau riche people who have money.
(Dog is on the stage)
Come along. Come along. Sit down. Sit down.
Now, go down.
They (the dogs) don’t form any fashions,
I have not seen dogs taken to any fashions.
Monkeys taking, I mean, supposing, you see
the Italian designers make something special
for them, they won’t think much of it. Maybe
their masters might buy, but not these animals.
Now, we don’t have to become animals of
course, but we don’t also have to become
slaves of fashions.
So there are some shops which are very expensive.
Why? Because they are designers. So you move
about telling everybody, “See, I am wearing
this thing from a designer shop, this is from
designer shop.” That means, what about you?
You have no sense of designs; you have no
sense of understanding what you need and what
you don’t need. And nowadays most of them
are in jail also, sorry to say, but they have
money and they have made money by befooling
you.
Specially in America I was surprised that
they were selling most of the things which
were coming from Italy - designs, Italian
designs, written that Italian design so they
were buying it, Italian design. I was surprised
that such artistic things they create that
are available everywhere, such beautiful things.
But what they believe in is some sort of a
group madness, everybody wearing the same
kind of design is from this or that. This
is not sahaj dharma. You are not slaves of
anything. You are free people. You have not
to accept any design or anything. Ah, it is
there, is there! Let the stupid follow that.
We are Sahaja Yogis.
Now, this also prevails among people who are
supposed to be sadhus, they all dress up the
same way. How can you make out who is who?
In Sahaja Yoga, we don’t want you to dress
up the same way, look the same way, cut your
hair the same way. No. You have to be individuals,
because you are free, but that doesn’t mean
- freedom is always supported by wisdom - that
doesn’t mean that you do what you like.
All kinds of funny things happen when a person
doesn’t know what is the light of the spirit.
In the light of the spirit, you don’t get
involved into this kind of collective madness
that is going on. We are so collective in
mad things. I wish they could be collective
more in wise things.
Wisdom is very important, and a joy-giving
quality of Radhaji - alladhadayini shakti
- has to come within us. Means, when we meet
another person in the collectivity, another
person should feel happy with you. So He taught
the dharma of love. Love is not there if you
discard because he is black or because he
is brown, because he is white. It’s very
superficial - what is black, white and yellow?
I don’t understand. Here they go to the
sea shores to make themselves black and there
they say, “we don’t want to have any blacks,”
specially for Americans. I think this kind
of separation I found there, among the blacks
and the whites, I really wept.
I went to Harlem. Sahaja yogis said, “Mother
will you go to Harlem?”
I said, “Why not, I’m black. If you call
Me black, I’m black. If you call Me white,
I’m white. If you call Me yellow, I’m
yellow, so I’m going.”
And there I had a lecture, you know, so many
people were there, really I cannot forget.
It is one of the most famous place that there
is built in that hall and the same hall is
built in Australia where I had addressed many
people. I thought, just look at this! They
said, “Mother, the Australians copied from
us.” Now, these people, so sweet, so beautiful,
I tell you. I could see their heart, I could
feel it and the fellow was trying to compare,
after My lecture he just came, he hugged Me,
kissed Me. I mean, he would have even minced
Me, little boy about twenty-two years of age
- such love he felt. And he said, “Mother,
next time You come, You are going to come
to Harlem.” But I am told that hall is closed.
So the Americans system somehow or another
goes against democracy, not only against democracy
but against what Abraham Lincoln wanted. They
had such a great man there and there is a
little street I saw in his name. Of course
in Washington they say they have some nice,
beautiful statues. But otherwise his principles
are finished; his ideals are finished because
somehow or other, some people came and wrote
against - England especially - against the
black people. What business they have to write
against something that is created by God?
If there are the same colors everywhere, they
all will look like military people. They have
to have different colors; they have to have
different hues. See, look at the trees; look
at the flowers. Look at the different hues
the sky has, just to make us happy – alladha.
What gives you happiness is variety. Variety
is a sign of beauty. If there is no variety,
it’s so boring I tell you, so very boring.
But they are very proud of it and they think
no end of themselves. They think they are
very great people; they have a sense of superiority,
because they have a certain type of nose or
maybe certain type of lips or maybe certain
types of hair. Such stupid things they are
and you join hands with them? How can you
join hands with them? You want your freedom?
Then be a free person. In the freedom you
have to have variety, very important.
I would say that now the Sahaja Yogis who
are going back to America should have a new
style of drive; go to the black people. I
was very happy to see the South American seminar
that they had taken specially to aboriginal
people. They went and met them. I have met
them also and I was so surprised that they
immediately said, “Mother, You are spiritual,
we know, but can You solve our problem?”
I said, “What’s your problem?”
“Very simple, we have a land – all right,
then - very little land, five, six acres of
land that belongs to us where the sage grows.”
Sage is a kind of a, according to them, is
a holy plant. All right. “Now, we always
meet, all of us, there for different festivals
because we regard that land as a holy land.”
They know so many things, you know. This is
a holy land; there were vibrations for that.
So they always used to meet, so natural.
“So, what has happened now, what is your
problem?
“The government has sold this land, this
American government, to an Indian.”
I said, “To an Indian?”
“Yes, so can you request this Indian to
return it to us, we’ll pay him the money.”
I said, “What’s the name of the Indian?”
They told me the name, I said, “My God!
He is a Sindhi, Sindhi! He won’t leave you
even one single pai, is he going to give you
this? I’m sorry, I may be divine or I may
be anything, I can’t help you.”
But I was surprised nobody raised a voice
against it. They should have raised voice.
They should have told the government, “Please
return their land. Why do you want to have
it? Why want to grab it?” As it is all the
Americans are immigrants. They don’t belong
to that place, that they were not owners of
that place, that ground - they are immigrants.
So they have no right to keep somebody’s
land like that and then to think they are
superior. It’s very nice, somebody enters
your house and thinks he is very superior
and drives out all the people of the family.
That is what has happened in America and just
opposite is sahaj dharma. With sahaj dharma,
you take people into your heart, you love
them. Your love flows all the time; your compassion
flows all the time. To Me it’s a problem,
this body is more compassionate than Myself.
I don’t even think of compassion and this
body just grasps everything. It wants to solve
the problem of others, but I don’t think
you can have that kind of a body, you shouldn’t
have. But, at least you should have a heart
which is open.
You see on the street somebody who is a dark
fellow. I like about the black Americans that
once I got down in one airport, so one gentleman,
black gentleman, “Hello darling, how are
You? How are You here? Very happy to see You!”
“I’m happy to see you. How are you?”
Then once I was traveling in - what was the
airport? Ursula was with Me. So he looked
at Me, one fellow, very tall, hefty, fat,
you know. He said, “Ah! Are You back again?”
I said, “I’m back. You know Me?”
“Of course, of course, I know you.” He
had never met Me, I had never known him. But
I felt happy, I felt very happy. That’s
the best way to meet people.
Supposing you are walking on the street, you
see some black gentleman going. It’s a terrible
life there, I tell you; it’s a terrible
life for them. I’ve known, I’ve read books
on them, I’ve cried and wept and I felt
very sorry. So, as a Sahaja yogi, you should
just jump at them and you should say, “Hello,
how are you?” Shake hands with them. They
won’t cut your throat, I can tell you this.
In criminality, I don’t know who is more
criminal in America, whether they are the
blacks or the whites, competing. But, if you
are kind and if you are loving, you can remove
that part of criminality which is within them
because hatred can be only washed away by
pure love.
But people think they are very cunning, very
superior - in cunningness, of course. Otherwise,
what is their superiority? Only this complexion,
this white complexion is the worst of all.
I was very fair, very fair, till I got married,
or for some time, and then I started becoming
darker and darker. Because white complexion
gets all kinds of, see, the light you put
on Me, I absorb, I get a black spot. So it’s
not a very great thing to be white, I don’t
think so. It looks very funny and pale and
joyless. But no use going to the sea, making
your body, I think brown - brown, not so black,
brown and then suffering from cancer of the
skin. This kind of stupidity is also very
much fashionable.
Now, in collectivity, how much do we get impressed
by these we should be on the watch. I saw
My granddaughter was wearing a sleeveless
dress.
I told her, “Better you shouldn’t wear
a sleeveless dress.”
She says, “It’s very hot, I feel very
hot.”
She’s young. I said, “But see, these are
two very important chakras. If you expose
them, then you’ll have problem.” She doesn’t
like to wear dresses which are above the knee,
but she says people wear even above the knee.
I said, “Knees, they are very important
chakras, we should keep them clothed, otherwise
if they are affected, we’ll have knee trouble.”
Immediately she changed, immediately. “Mother,
I’ll wear blouse from inside and something
from outside.” Immediately. Because she
knew this is a natural primordial taboo that
we should not expose ours - these two chakras
and these chakras. But, nowadays, the more
you have long legs, I don’t know, they have
shorter clothes. And I don’t understand
what is in the legs, the whole beauty is in
the legs or what?
So, I’ve met one lady who traveled with
Me. She was wearing a burqa because she was
a Muslim. And by the time we landed in London,
she took out the burqa and the dress was much
above the knees. I said, “What kind of Muslim
woman is she? She’s worse than even Christians
because they wouldn’t wear such a thing,
you know, to come out of the aeroplane, you
have to come down on the staircase.” No
lajja, no shame, nothing, shamelessness!
So, sahaj dharma is that you have shame, you
have sense of shame. What you talk to others,
what you say to others, how you behave towards
them, in the sahaj dharma is alladhadayini.
If something is not alladhadayini, keep quiet.
Don’t say. What is the need? What is there
to be sarcastic? Showing off your brains in
your sarcasm. It’s not a sign of good breeding
that you talk sarcastically to others in a
sharp way. But if you talk sweetly, what’s
the harm? This sweetness comes from Radhaji.
Now, of course they have misused Her and made
Her into a sort of a Romeo-Juliet business.
It was not that. She was a very pure woman
and She was Mahalakshmi. So, to be a Mahalaksmi,
after coming to Sahaja Yoga, you should know
that you should dress up in a way that’s
perfectly all right. Once I remember, I was
in a big party and one gentleman came and
he sat down, “Aaaaaah!”
I said, “What happened?”
“What a relief, Mother, Mrs. Shrivastava,
to see You. See these women, I’m fed up.
But You came, I felt such a relief.”
I said, “What is so relieving?”
“You are so serene.”
So, women are serene in sahaj dharma. They
are not stupid, frivolous, laughing at anything.
That’s not the way for a woman. Anything
happens, they must laugh. I mean, there is
something laughable, all right, but some things
are not even laughable, they'll laugh. That’s
not the way. That can be ridiculous also,
can ridicule others. But laugh of appreciation,
laugh of enjoyment, is so pure and creates
such beautiful atmosphere. I think the whole
ecological problem is in our brains – [Hindi
words]. It is not outside. It is inside us,
which is reflected outside.
In Ganesha Puja I’m going to tell you how
we are so closely related to Mother Earth
and how the Mother Earth and the atmosphere
reacts to our behavior, to how we live. In
the sahaj dharma, you give up lust and greed
very easily, that I know. I mean if they can’t
even give up that, then they should not call
themselves Sahaja yogis. The first thing you
give up is lust and greed. I find it among
young people now, that those who come to Sahaja
Yoga become really very free people. They
don’t run after women. Women don’t run
after men. They are together, they sit together,
talk together, laugh together, but it is purity
that is here. In the Koran it’s described
that “When Kiyama will come, beautiful women
and beautiful men will be there, but they’ll
have no lust and greed, they’ll be pure.”
Is today, you can see that that lust and greed
is finished in most of it, most of you. Automatically
it is finished and now you can see for yourself
that you’re free of this bondage.
Then our marriages are coming tomorrow. In
the sahaj dharma, first thing is very important
is forgiveness. If somebody cannot forgive,
then he cannot be a Sahaja yogi. Forgiveness.
How this forgiveness comes in is by forgetting
the past. Otherwise you’ll go on saying,
“This person tortured me, that person tortured
me, he was very mean to me, he was that to
me, he did this to me.” Shows that you are
not of that caliber to understand Sahaja Yoga
- because you cannot forgive. What is there
to remember? The present is the best. Now
if you are sitting here with Me, enjoying
the alladhadayini shakti, that time if you
are thinking about the past, shows what? That
you are not of the caliber. To be the caliber
of Sahaja Yoga, you should be free of your
past. Finished. There's no need to confess.
I know after Sahaja Yoga many people wrote
letters to Me of confessions and I just said,
“Baba, just burn these letters. I don’t
remember. I don’t want to read anything
about anything.”
So, there should be forgiveness. If there
is forgiveness, you’ll be surprised, you’ll
feel very relieved and your married life will
be very happy. But if you try to remember
something – all right, some marriages are
really, really very difficult, all right,
so you get out. In Sahaja Yoga we have allowed
complete divorce, but must be with some reason,
not because you think something is superior.
Now we have banned many countries from where
we don’t want to have girls or from where
we don’t want to have boys. What is the
reason? With experience we have learned, they
are not marriage substance. Now, then better
not marry, and if you marry then live like
an ideal Sahaja Yogi. Also, if you are a Sahaja
Yogini, then you can carry on very much better
by forgiving all the time.
Every time, when people tell Me, “My Mother,
You see You must help me.”
“Why?”
“Because, You know my husband doesn’t
give me any money.”
I said, “Give him up. I don’t mind. He
must give you money. Why doesn’t he give
you money?”
If you talk to the husband, he’ll say, “Mother,
she’s very extravagant.”
I said, “You better give up Sahaja Yoga
both of you and do what you like.”
In sahaj dharma, the husband-wife’s relation
should be really romantic, should be really
beautiful. It is not, you know, we talk of
love and all that here, very rarely people
fall in love and carry on with it. It’s
a blessing if you really get that kind of
a feeling. But mostly it is a curse. So to
fall in love is very good but that doesn’t
mean you forget that you are a Sahaja Yogi.
In that, Sahaja Yoga helps a lot, I think,
in your married life. Same dharma is for your
children, that you bring up your children
not troubling them too much, but into a free
land. Let them use their wisdom. Sometimes
I know children go astray and try to follow
wrong things. Then you must correct them,
you must tell them, it’s your duty. They
were not born out of the trees but they were
born here, from the parents. So it’s the
duty of the parents to tell them that this
is wrong and this should not be done. It’s
a very wrong thing, you should correct them
and that correction should be in a Sahaj way.
I’ll tell you an example. I had a problem
once with somebody coming to Me and saying,
“Mother, I can’t do without smoking, I
have to smoke.”
I said, “Better smoke then, but you can’t
be a Sahaja Yogi, because smoking Sahaja Yogi
is a funny caricature, you know, I can’t
think of a Sahaja Yogi smoking. How will I
look if I start smoking like that?”
“Ah, horrible.”
I said, “Then if you are My son, you cannot
smoke, it looks bad.” He gave up smoking,
can you imagine?
So, dealing with children, always make yourself
an example, yourself part and parcel of that
event. So the children don’t feel, you know.
This is something that I have talked many
a times. Children is one thing, I tell you,
they can give up everything but not your love.
If they know you love them they will not accept
anything that will make you not love - not
love them. This is for definite, because children
are the best people who know about love.
Of course, I don’t know, I feel that in
English language, I didn’t see many books
about children written beautiful, beautiful
things. There was one book that was published
when I was in London: The children talking
about the politicians, and they published
I think, 5000 books and that very same day
it was finished. So, talk to children, talk
to them. You’ll be amazed, they are full
of honey. They have such nice, nice things
with them and when they talk like that, then
you are amazed how they say things, how they
talk of Sahaj, how they are expressing their
spiritual strength.
Now, we have many very good children and also
they are absolutely Sahaj. One boy came and
he just prostrated himself before Me.
So, I said, “Why you did it?”
“No, I was getting cool vibrations, Mother
from You, so I did it.”
“Is it, you like it?”
“Of course!”
“More than chocolate?”
I was surprised. “What? You eat them or
what?”
“No need to eat, no, no, you feel so happy
inside and I feel, Mother, You are putting
Your hand on my heart and trying to console
me.”
Surprised. “And where is your heart?”
He said, “Here, here is my heart, I feel
it here.” Just imagine, what love and what
understanding of Sahaja Yoga! For these little
children who are below even five years.
Now, you are all grown up children of Mine
and I want you to know all the beauties that
are within you, that you have to enjoy. First
of all, learn to laugh at yourself. That’s
the best way to enjoy yourself, you know.
And not to spend much time on the mirror,
in the mirror, that’s another way. You spend
too much on the mirror, then something wrong
with you. I think, personally, that it’s
a kind of a possession maybe. So, what you
should see inside, “Are we sahaj dharmis?
Mother has established sahaj dharma, much
more than what Krishna wanted to establish.
He wanted to establish the dharma of love
which of course we have, but apart from that
we have so many other beautiful facets and
such beautiful things within our personality
that we have forgotten to enjoy.”
So, the attention should be on your own qualities,
on your own personality, and then you’ll
be amazed how your personality is giving you
joy, giving you alladha, giving you so much
of patience with others.
To Me the whole thing looks like sometimes
a joke, because nothing so serious. It’s
not a Rama’s type that you have to be serious.
I don’t have to kill anybody. I don’t
use any weapons in this lifetime. Without
weapons if things are solved, what can you
do?
But you must try to see the beauty as Sahaja
Yogis. You should be sensitive to see how
you have been helped, how you have been guided,
how you have been blessed. This is sahaj dharma.
If you cannot know that, then you live on
a very low level. I mean, it’s not fault
of Sahaja Yoga, but it’s your style, you
are not sensitive. Supposing somebody is not
- does not burn his hand. So what will you
do? He has no sense, he has no sensitivity,
he cannot feel. He can drink, he can smoke,
he can do everything and still he's existing,
all right. Must be a rakshasa, I think or
I don’t know what to say.
So, we have to take example from other good
Sahaja Yogis and not from the bad ones and
how do we proceed in enjoyment - which is
a ocean, just a ocean. For example, now, I
came, everybody was trying to fan. But also
in the West another problem is they like to
live in hermetically-sealed rooms, hermetically-sealed
cars, they are very afraid of draft, I don’t
know, as if they’ll be blown away or what
will happen to them. They don’t want draft.
I mean draft is not coming from some iceberg.
So, they don’t believe in the fresh air
at all and that’s one other reason that
people are very suffocating sometimes, you
know, they just suffocate. They are used to
a suffocating life.
Once I was in India, I was very hot, so somebody
was driving Me, but the person who was there
was from Western country. He said, “Don’t
open - don’t open the window.”
I said, “Why?”
“There’s a draft.”
I said, “In this country, in India people
live in the open - what is a draft? What draft
you are talking about?” You can’t open
the door, you can’t open the window, you
can’t open anything, if you open anything,
they’ll be all dead, you see – as if.
So open yourself!
As it is about the nature, also it is in their
private lives. They don’t want to open.
If somebody comes to their house, “Oh my
God, now we’ll have to share the wines,
we’ll have to share the foods” They cannot
share. They cannot share. That is most uncollective.
But in India, I must say, people have a good
sharing capacity because they are still primitive,
they are still primordial, yet not gone out
of the way to satisfy their own ego. But I
think somehow or other in India, people like
to share. If you want to please any Indian,
you tell them, tomorrow I’ll come and have
food with you. His wife will jump. She’ll
say, “Now what do you like, tell me, what
food do you like?” She will jump. But otherwise,
what happens, as soon as you say he’s coming
for food, the wife will say, “No, no, I
am going to my mother.” Immediately she’ll
have a program. I just don’t understand.
They’ll have beautiful houses, very clean,
very beautiful, everything, but if somebody
comes to their house, they get a shock as
if electricity has entered. So, for whom is
all this?
To show off, they will borrow money from the
banks. Even Indians in America they do. They
want to have three Mercedes, four houses - for
what? Borrowing money with borrowing money
they live. Sahaja Yogis have not to borrow
any money. There’s no need, you can do away
with things. Why to have so many cars? Nowadays,
people don’t even walk at all. We used to
go to our school, My father had a car in India
- nothing doing. We had to walk. We used to
climb one mountain. It was about five miles,
the school - every morning. Then in the night,
in the evening, the car used to come, and
I would walk with My bare feet, because so
much vibrations and on the chappals, I thought
were cutting my vibrations, so I used to have
chappals in My hand and walk. One day we had
a new driver, My father sent him. He said,
“How will I know who is the daughter.”
He said, “Any girl with the chappals in
Her hand is the one whom you have to bring.”
So, it is to enjoy your nobility, to enjoy
your generosity. It’s very important. And
not to side with anyone. You are not identified
with anyone.
It’s much better now, I think, because since
you have taken to sahaj dharma, I’ve seen
English will tell you what’s wrong with
English. Swiss will tell you what’s wrong
with Swiss. Indians will tell you what’s
wrong with Indians. Actually, I learned from
them. I don’t know these things are there.
Russians will tell you what’s wrong with
Russians. They immediately start seeing, “What’s
wrong with us? Where do we lack in this?”
Because the collectivity of being in one country,
say as an Indian, we see now, what’s happening
in India, all corrupt, horrible, this, that.
So, I said, “All right, if you don’t like
India, why don’t you go somewhere else?”
No, no, no, that - we will stay here, but
this is a very corrupt government they are,
it’s very bad, this, that. Anywhere you
go, you will find immediately they see - because
you don’t know they are now chosen to change
their country.
I’ve taken up many questions now, of India
and I’m going to start working on that level.
We've already started, in a way, for the destitute
women, then for other type of poverty and
all that. Just by saying, remove poverty,
poverty cannot be lost. You have to have feeling
for the poor, then only - but you get with
more that feeling because you are an Indian.
You are an Indian, so what? Your own brothers,
sisters starving. You get that very deep feeling
within you if you are a sahaj dharmi.
So, this is the new dharma we have established
now in this world. A new race, with a new
dharma, which is much above - even Shri Krishna’s
vision is coming true. He describes in the
beginning. I think, He was not a good salesman,
because He describes the best first. You see
the salesman first will start from two rupees,
then go onward to two thousand. But He first
told us that you have to become Sthita Pragya,
means Sahaja Yogi - and then Shri Krishna
was asked a question by Arjuna, “What is
a Sthita Pragya?” Then He describes a Sahaja
Yogi, that He describes before, first chapter,
second chapter is that, now. Then the questions
start. You know, Arjuna was a great questioner,
I think.
So, he starts asking questions, “Then what
about this and what about that and what about
that?”
So He goes on explaining to him that “You
see, this is all just a maya, this is all
an illusion you have. Get out of this illusion.
If once you get out of this illusion,” because
Arjuna said, “They are my relations, they
are my teachers. How can I kill them?”
So, Krishna says, “Nobody is killed.”
He said, “Nobody is killed, but they are
being killed because they are not following
the satya dharma, so it’s all right. What
is your brother, what is your sister? They
are not following the satya dharma, so you
have nothing to do with them. If you can correct
them and help them, it’s all right, otherwise
forget them.”
First, deal with people who are straight.
Like we should say that we must deal with
people who are simple, innocent and then you
can take to difficult people when you are
that good. Otherwise you’ll come here saying,
“Mother, I have caught this, I have caught
that.” So, in sahaj dharma, you being the
spirit, you also know about others, very well
and you can make it out, who is who, what
chakras they are catching.
But the trouble in America, I found that Sahaja
Yogis used to, just could go and tell somebody,
“You are catching on this chakra.” Now,
he has come for the first time and you tell
him, “You, you are very egoistical.”
He says, “How do you know?”
“Your Agnya is catching.” Maybe, his own
Agnya might be catching.
Is this the way to receive a new person? Is
this the way to talk to a new person? See,
on the contrary, you should say, “Come,
sit down, very nice, you are very great,”
see? Because they are still ignorant, so they
like some sort of buttering, as you call it,
you see, we call it chaplusi. Then, gradually,
because you are doing this just to make him
a Sahaja Yogi, because you love him. Basically
that is the reason. But as soon as somebody
comes in, if you tell him, “This is wrong
with you, that’s wrong with you.” This
is not a pope’s business where you go on
telling people what’s wrong with them, go
and confess to all these silly people. It’s
not that. What we have to show that you have
fallen in love with that person; you are nice
to that person because you like that person.
Then gradually you pull him up. But as soon
as he comes you give him one shock, so finished.
How can you have good relations?
Americans have to learn this. I don’t know
why Americans think they are very superior
people. I tell you for wisdom, I would not
say they are so good. It’s completely lacking
– wisdom in them. And they misunderstand
people very fast. Start judging others, is
not the way you can have sahaj dharma. Sahaj
dharma is: you are your own. You are in your
own, you are in your own realm and in your
happiness and joy. Where is the time to criticize
others?
So the best thing is to show your maximum
love to everyone. In that love you should
not show your pity, but love which is, again,
alladhadayini. This is the message of Shri
Krishna, but I don’t know how many understood
it. Now, what you find those who are following
Shri Krishna like Hare Rama people, they are
really beggars on the street. He is Kubera,
and his disciples are all beggars, can you
imagine? Does it add to His glory as a Kubera?
So, Sahaja Yogis are not like that. Should
be generous, should not bother too much about
yourself. Should not all the time think about
yourself, but think of the collectivity, how
you behave. Collectivity is not to bring - force
people to come to Sahaja Yoga. Once they come
to Sahaja Yoga they will know the joy of life
and you don’t have to tell them anything.
Nothing has to be told, just silently it will
work and they will feel your love.
You see, love is something so great. It not
only helps others but it also helps you. It’s
so joyous to give realizations to others.
But if you start telling, “Your this chakra
is catching”, why you are giving realization?
If you don’t know how to give realization,
better not do it. So, to criticize is not
the way we can enjoy love. Ah, of course you
can pull legs of each other sometimes, just
for fun’s sake, but not to harm, not to
torture, not to make that person fall. You
are all sahaj dharmis, you have accepted sahaj
dharma and in sahaj dharma we have to have
pure love of the heart, not hypocrisy - and
sensible life.
Now, this pope is against abortion. I’m
not. If a woman is suffering, let her have
abortion. The one who is living is more important
than who are not living. If somebody wants
to have abortion, that child can be born again.
According to us, nobody dies permanently.
Whatever it may be.
So, this is one way they use it for propagation
of human beings. Like they say the Muslim
women are like a factory. They go on producing
more children, more children, more children.
So there are more voters. So the pope knows
that. That’s why he says, abortion, no.
Christians should not abort, because then
there will be less Christians to compete with
the Muslims.
But in Sahaja Yoga, we don’t have such funny,
radical, nonsensical things. We have divorce,
and we have also abortion, which is important
to understand that these are all taboos which
are there. But not for people who have to
get out of the troubles - you have to have
it. And that’s how it works. But to be very
frank, we don’t have to do abortions, it
is achieved by Paramchaitanya. Paramchaitanya
does for Me. I don’t have to. I don’t
have to do anything. It’s Paramchaitanya.
It’s nice, because it knows what is to be
done, how to achieve it. And sometimes you
are in trouble, then know that you are not
leaving things into the hands of the Paramchaitanya.
If you leave into the hands of Paramchaitanya
things will work out very well.
So, to understand Sahaja Yoga, first and foremost
thing is, how much you are enjoying yourself.
How much enjoyment you are giving to others?
For that you have music, you have this, that.
I was saying that today I won’t speak much,
but, somehow, with Shri Krishna
you can’t keep quiet. He played murli, basuri,
flute. Look at Him. I talked to Him, but He
just played murli. He didn’t talk so much,
except for the Gita, you won’t find Him
talking. And those who read also Gita are
horrible people, I tell you, I have met - those
who read Gita. They don’t understand what
is Shri Krishna’s dharma is. If they don’t
understand Shri Krishna, how will they understand
Sahaja Yoga? So, for all of you is to practice
on love, on forgiveness, on appreciating others,
on giving joy to others.
Some of the Sahaja Yogis have been very kind
to Me also. Once I went to the shop to buy
a sari for Myself and the sari was very expensive
for My purpose. So, I didn’t buy. Said,
“Let it be. This color suits Me, all right,
but doesn’t matter.” I didn’t have so
much money to buy. So, that Sahaja Yogi bought
that sari and on My birthday gave Me - and
really, I could not see it, because My eyes
were filled with tears. Just a small thing
like that. Normally I don’t expect you to
do anything for Me, no. But small, small things
make you so happy. But even if you do this
to somebody, may not understand, may not realize,
may not feel it. But if you are a Sahaja Yogi,
you will.
So thank you very much for all this that I
have said to you, try to enjoy yourself and
make others enjoy you.
May God bless you!