1984-0708 Public Program 1 at Ilford Town Hall. Ilford (England), To Know The Truth
I bow to all the seekers of truth.
In the previous two lectures I told you how to understand the experience of truth.
In the first one, we came to the conclusion that if we have to feel the truth,
it’s not our only mental acceptance that it is truth, or our mental projection that it is truth,
but you have to feel it on your central nervous system.
In the second lecture I told you that when you feel the truth through your central nervous system
in your evolutionary process, then you become something.
You become, you become is the point. Is not that you think you are like this or like that,
but you really become something. Like a flower becomes a fruit or an egg becomes a chick.
You have to become something in your awareness, and this new awareness is the awareness of collective consciousness.
Where you can feel yourself, what’s the problem with you and you can feel others, on your fingertips.
This is a very good English idiom they use, on your fingertips.
I mean somebody must have thought of Sahaja Yoga when they formed this I am sure.
To use this, you should know it on your fingertips.
Now what does that mean? We have never thought of it, we always say so, we should know them on our fingertips,
but actually you feel them on your fingertips.
The different centres within you and the centres in other people.
As hot or cold, may be as heavy, burning; this you just feel it. You can feel it, others can feel it,
children can feel it and everybody feels the same, because truth is absolute and is for everyone.
Whether you have a different caste, community, race, religion, nationality,
all kinds of superficial things, which divides human beings, everyone feels the same.
For example, supposing you put a finger to this, (Candle flame) you are going to feel hot.
Because you have a different hair style, you are not going to feel something different,
it’s like that. Truth has to be that way, and that is what is the experience of truth.
And once you know you have to know the truth and nothing else but the truth.
When you decide in your mind and be honest about it then when you see it, it is very obvious.
It has to be obvious, it cannot be secretive. It cannot be, it has to be obvious, apparent,
absolutely known to your central nervous system.
So you know the absolute as I told you. Like a computer you start working, you ask any questions,
absolute questions and the answers come to you, as cool vibrations for yes and as hot vibrations for no
and sometimes the vibrations stops to say that absolutely no.
But it can be some blister sometimes a little bit, to say that it’s satanic.
And you can decode it yourself and see for yourself.
This is the second phase where you start knowing about others and knowing about yourself.
So you become connected with the Absolute. Absolute, means there is no question about it,
absolute means there is no doubt about it, absolute means it is single.
Today I have to tell you about what actually happens when this force called Kundalini within you
rises and gives you self-realization. Actually within your self what should happen?
Nobody tells you these things, I mean, they’ll say you are to be reborn, so you have a sort of a certificate,
twice born, reborn and you go about, when it’s not like that.
Supposing a monkey puts a sign-board on, “I am a human being”, does he become?
If we just say we are this, we are that, you are not.
For example we say we are Muslims, we are Christians, we are Hindus, we are not.
Because you have formed a group, you call yourself something, or something that you are not.
It’s just your own idea. How are you a Hindu? How are you a Christian?
What all these religions have said that you have to be born again.
Every religion, Jews have in a way said it too,
but the problem is that we don’t do what is told to us, we just form a group.
Group can be made out of anything nonsensical like, I met some other people the other day
and they told Me our group is called as Knives and Fork.
I said “What’s that group?” Knives and Forks, yes very good group,
so I said, “What is that?” “Because we put our knives and forks in a different way than others.”
I said ” But what’s the use?” “No, we form a very strong group.” “For what?”
“We can form a political party tomorrow.”
I said, “All right, go ahead with this kind of a nonsense”,
But it is nonsense, all this is nonsense. What is sensible is that
we have to become something more than what we are. We are human beings,
we have to become more knowledgeable, we have to become the knowledge.
That knowledge you cannot get in the libraries or from the books.
How do you grow into that knowledge is through this Kundalini awakening,
through this happening that, this Kundalini rises within you
and pierces through your fontanel bone area giving you the real baptism and not the artificial one.
The reality again. Supposing somebody doesn’t get it, all right, so he comes back on Me,
“Oh I never got it Mother”. Something wrong, he should get it, should get it.
Because we cannot give you a false certificate, you cannot give yourself a false certificate.
But it is very common as you see in this world, that when you listen to people who are religious,
you find they are horribly fanatic, funny, stupid people.
I mean if you want to hear about each one of them you should go to the opposite party.
Like if you want to hear about Hindus go to Muslims.
If you want to hear about the Muslims go to Jews and
if you want to hear about Jews go to say Muslims or anyone, Christians, and they’ll tell you.
So there’s nothing universal opinion about things.
It is surprising for a person who wants to see the truth in every religion,
he cannot understand why people belonging to religion, when God is only one,
why there’s a fight going on. Why this world is divided by, even religious leaders are dividing the world.
It is very amazing. So where is this religion? And what happens to our religion?
When we get our self-realization, we become the Self, the Spirit and the Spirit is untarnishable.
It’s untarnishable. You cannot cleanse the soap, can you?
But the quality of Spirit is that it cleanses you. First is it cleanses you.
Just like a Mother lovingly cleanses the child who has fallen somewhere in the road
and cleanses the clothes and makes the child absolutely neat, tidy, clean
and with great admiration looks at the child;
in the same way the Spirit bathes you with it’s beautiful blessings so that you cleanse.
And the second thing it does is to give you light.
Now the light doesn’t mean electrical light, it doesn’t mean the light you see inside.
What does this light means is your awareness itself.
Your awareness itself becomes a higher awareness by which you start seeing things clear cut.
Like I know somebody who came to see Me before Sahaja Yoga
and he met Me after say a month, he was a changed man, I could not recognize him.
So I said what has happened to him? He came to Me I asked him,
”How are you?” He said “Mother I am fine.”
He used to look very old and haggard and absolutely frustrated. I said “What has happened?”
He said “Mother you know, when I got realisation, suddenly I felt tremendous compassion for everyone
and I had an enemy that was my uncle and I hated him from the bottom of my heart,
and I used to think he has killed my mother, and I could not believe that he has not killed my mother,
so many people told me but still with the hatred I could not get over it.
I had insulted him, he had insulted me and if somebody had given me freedom with
a dagger I would have gone and killed him. I hated him from the bottom of my heart.
And all the time I thought of killing him, doing this and all the nasty things I could think of.
My whole mind was pre-occupied.” “So what happened?” He said,
“Next day I started seeing his good points, I said no he is a very generous man.
I have been nastier that he has been, suddenly I started feeling it, that feeling of love,
compassion and when I said uncle, I forgive you completely,
the blissfulness crawled upon me, that’s the first time I’ve felt the joy of my spirit.
I had said this before also but I had never felt it,
but first time when I said this I felt it and that bliss was so great and that joy was so great
I said now I must have it at any cost.
So next day I saw him at a race, he was a great race goer also, a very rich man.
I saw him and I just embraced him. I couldn’t help it. He was surprised, he looked at me,
he said come and have tea with me, and we are great friends now.”
So all that wrinkle, all that horrible anger and all that has gone away
and this divine, serene face was showing its beauty there.
But he said “I have done this before, I’ve tried to forgive him, I told myself,
I told many a times that he’s not killed my mother, I should not hate him.
I tried to convince myself, but still I could not forgive, I didn’t have the power to forgive.
But when I got my self-realization, suddenly the power came to me,
in such a gush. I have become powerful Mother.”
In the Sanskrit language it’s called the word Samarth,
Samarth means powerful but actually means Sama-Artha, it means equal to your meaning.
Equal to your meaning, means you become your Self. Samartha.
When you become yourself, you become powerful to fight your weaknesses
and you automatically do it without any trouble, spontaneously. Very easy it is to forgive.
Not only this, so many things there are which you just do without any difficulty.
It is very difficult before realization for a person to think that to part with your little bit of two P’s that you have,
even that is sometimes difficult. You think ten times, calculate it, all right,
if I give two P’s now how much will I get, three P’s or five P’s, all right
if I get three P’s no good, five P’s is all right; but after realization you just give.
You just give, you like to give, you love to give, you want to enjoy the giving capacity of yourself.
So far the acquiring, acquisition and also the capacity to preserve,
keep everything to yourself becomes a giving capacity.
And as a result of that, what you find, you are filled in.
Every sort of thing, every sort of material or physical or anything that is needed to make you happy
just comes down. From where, how, God alone knows because it’s only God does the job,
it’s God’s work. So the power to stand up against evil, against injustice,
against wrong doing just changes your priorities completely
and you become a powerful personality. Like Christ when He saw the prostitute,
Mary Magdalene, being stoned, He saw the disciple Mary Magdalene in her.
He stood up and He said, “Those who have not sinned can throw stones at Me.”
That character, that strength that stood up there,
and nobody could even think of throwing stones at Him.
This powerful personality which is compassion, which is righteous, which is virtuous,
starts shining through you. It’s not a quarrelsome dominating power in which we believe.
According to us a powerful man is the one who can dominate the whole world.
The power of love we have never exploited, never.
All our enterprises, all our worldly affairs, political, economic, are based on hatred.
The power of love in it’s purest from is the most powerful thing
and that is going to emancipate the whole universe. There’s no other way out.
It doesn’t mean your carnal love or your nonsensical ideas of love, it’s not, it’s pure love.
The pure love is that kind where the sap rises in a tree
and gives nourishment to all the parts of the tree and goes back. It’s not attached.
If it gets attached to one flower, the tree will die, the flower will die.
So this is the power which empowers you, nourishes you, soothes you,
consoles you, relaxes you and leaves you powerful.
That sort of a power is to be felt if it is the experience of truth.
But we have never tried to understand love in its own truth.
The reason is we were not realized people. When we are blind, we are mixed up.
We can’t make out one from another but when our eyes are opened out
we understand the true love. And this is what people have exploited, many of them,
many so called gurus and these people who talk of God have exploited
this side of love by teaching dirty things to people, debasing them, using their weaknesses.
Saying that if you do this kind of a weakness, then you will reach God.
Love that makes you a slave cannot be love and that is what it is, the love that is divine,
is the love of God that starts flowing through you, you become the medium, as you call it,
of that love. A powerful medium. But you know how to manoeuvre it.
You know everything. It’s not blindly, I have seen some people, oh we are in love, you see going on like that, no.
You know everyone. You know ins and outs of everyone and of yourself also.
I have seen many people coming to Me and saying, “Mother please save me from this Agnya.”
Now in our language it is this Agnya, but actually it means ego.
You can see your ego clearly once you get realization and we say oh God what is this?
That’s not me, I am not ego, oh that’s not me, I am the Self, I am the Spirit.
So this separation takes place within yourself, with your own understanding that,
you are not this body, this mind, this ego, this superego but you are the spirit.
And the more you grow into it, a beautiful personality of a character, which is not a character,
sometimes people think if you are very meek, is he compromising,
such a character will never compromise, is a terrific character.
It would never compromise with anything that is not the truth. It cannot by temperament.
But is very kind and compassionate, forgiving.
Gives lots of chances because there’s that inner urge to save others, to save others,
to help others, to get them to the right thing.
It’s like people who are standing on the brink of a disaster,
or people who are on the bank and see the people getting drowned and trying to pull them out
with all their effort. But they don’t want to compromise as to jump or to leave the banks that they have got.
Such a character you develop then and this character is felt by everyone.
I have known many Sahaja Yogis first who came to Sahaja Yoga,
their own family people were angry. Now you are following another Guru,
this is another cult, this is that. But then they found out that they are giving no money, nothing,
and they are flowering. In every way they are beautiful, they are becoming better and better people.
Righteous and virtuous people, powerful people of great character
and they are amazed you know. How do they become?
And they become very intelligent, they don’t do any stupid things, they just don’t do it.
Even a little child knows it’s stupid. They don’t do stupid things.
They don’t do nonsensical things. They are dignified and they don’t take to cheap entertainments.
The depth that you feel in the poets, in the great musicians, becomes their own nature.
When they talk, when they walk, any rapport with them, you can feel the depth of their spirit.
They become very knowledgeable suddenly. As I told you last time these journalists asked Me
“Mother have you got all scholars?” I said “Scholars, what.”
“All scholars are Sahaja Yogis,” I said “No, at the most one percent may be,
who have been great headaches to me, the rest of them are simple people.”
Simple people are the best and this is what is true,
that those who get realization start feeling the knowledge which is absolute.
Seeing the knowledge, knowing the knowledge.
Like if you see, say, this pillar, you just look at it, you say, oh very nicely done painted this,
somebody might say it should not have been this color, that color.
But a Sahaja Yogi doesn’t see this pillar as to how aesthetically it is and all that,
but immediately he’ll say it’s beautiful. You’ll say why? It gives vibrations.
The whole aesthetics are worked out through vibrations.
All the beautiful things, as I told you last time, of the world have vibrations.
Real beautiful things have vibrations. Like Mona Lisa I told you the other day,
if you go and feel her vibrations, she has vibrations.
Now the one who has made her has put his joy into her and she emits vibrations.
And that is the thing that gives joy to you because you are at a level where you can feel those vibrations.
You start feeling the physical side of yours, you understand you have a physical problem.
Immediately you know you have a physical problem, you know where it is,
how to correct it, how to cure it. I have seen many people who come to me,
Mother cure my cancer, but they don’t come to Me before they get cancer.
If they had come they would never have got it, but they had no time, at that time they had no time.
But when they get cancer I have no time either. It happens always.
Of course they are to be helped, cured, but why not come as a prevention to all those diseases
which has no meaning. It is unnecessarily so much accepted that health is first of all.
Then there is nothing to worry about health if you come to Sahaja Yoga,
you don’t need any doctor, sorry for the doctors, I am sorry.
And this is what it is to be understood that physically you feel absolutely fit.
You look fit absolutely. You look marvellous.
Then when you start expanding yourself you start feeling your own mind.
The peace, the bliss of your own mind.
Many a times you’ll find there is no thought but the joy is just bursting in
and you just think why it has happened. Suddenly, how do I get this?
Gradually the state of joy starts increasing in its frequency and you become joy.
That is, one has to achieve, to become the joy is important.
And once you become that joy it’s not a duality, it’s not a duality.
It’s not a thing in which you feel the happiness and unhappiness but you feel the joy.
Joy is a witness, it’s a kind of a power of a witness which sees a drama,
by seeing the drama, whether tragedy or comedy, it’s at a point where it is just a witness and enjoying it.
In the same way you’ll see so called comedies and tragedies of your life
and the futility of your nonsensical endeavours and you’ll laugh at it, oh that’s it, that’s me.
For example in Romeo and Juliet, Shakespeare has tried to show the futility of all those egos.
According to Indian standards he was Avadhotta, as they call it, a person who was realised
and was a very evolved personality. And if you want to see how Romeo should get his realization
and how he should feel that after all that happened he should laugh loudly.
She gets realisation, oh what a fool a stupid thing I was.
Shakespeare did not show him getting realization he kept it for us Sahaja Yogis to see it,
but should have seen to it that Romeo laughs at himself and makes fun of himself,
oh stupid Mr. Romeo, now you better settle down.
But he showed and very cleverly if you see in all his Macbeth or any of his dramas
that he has tried to show the futility of our ego, our enterprises,
we think that is very important in life.
I would say there are so many great writers in English language,
which I cannot name them in a series, but I have read them.
Somerset Maugham, I would say was another one. I was very much impressed by his writings
and read most of his novels because he was very much there.
Cronin for example is another one I would say who wrote Citadel was another great person who
could see the drama of stupidity. Leave alone your great poets like William Blake and all those.
But all that was to show that there is a higher being you see, which sees all this,
and giving you a drama of yourself, projecting it through you.
That this is what you are, you see, see yourself.
That’s what they did and despite everything we’re lost. We are lost quite a lot.
We have to become the same like Shakespeare to see the drama,
like Somerset Maugham, we have to become the same.
To see the drama, we may not write a book, doesn’t matter,
but the capacity to see the drama, that’s what we develop.
We need not write, we may not have the flare of a pen to write but we see it the same way as they see it
and that’s the mental capacity to which we rise with self-realization.
I have seen very stupid people absolutely calling themselves gurus,
you look at them and you don’t know what to say, you see.
You have to look at stupider persons to stupider, that person, what you say, stupidest person,
in the presence of such a person, because he looks at you, you see,
and you understand he is stupid and you don’t know what to do.
And you get frightened of such a person you know and you don’t want to hurt his feelings you see,
so you look the greater stupid person and then he gives you a big lecture,
on something very stupid. But then you find that person you see,
big newspapers you see like Times, publishing such a stupid man there.
Just imagine, this is what we have done to Shakespeare, to all our great writers and everyone,
we have reached that state that we cannot even see the stupidity.
Our brain is stunned because we have been asking for sensations,
with all these electrical sensations in the brain we are stunned.
Which opens out, which completely opens out and you start seeing, through and through,
the mockery of all this kind of seriousness and the hypocrisy
and the way people who are stupid try to give you stupid ideas.
And once you are realised you laugh at yourself,
oh God I was so stupid, that’s what should happen.
If that does not happen your self-realization has no meaning, it has no meaning.
The righteousness and the virtues become part and parcel of your being.
It’s not that you have to be told anything, you just shouldn’t do it.
It’s beyond your self respect because you respect your Self, you respect your Spirit.
How can you do such a thing? You cannot despise yourself can you?
You just become virtuous. You may be kind to others even if they are not virtuous,
you can be nice to them, you can forgive them but as far as you are concerned there is no compromise.
And you enjoy your virtues, you enjoy your magnanimity, you enjoy your generosity.
People will tell you, stupid fool, you go on distributing things what are you doing?
And you laugh at them. As Lao Tse said, somebody told Me this saying about Lao Tse,
another great incarnation of the primordial master,
that when a wise sees the way, he respects it and says this is the way.
That’s the sign of a wise man and a mediocre who is half way this way and that way
when he sees the way he waits for others to go into it,
and when the stupid sees the way he laughs.
But when the wise sees the stupid in himself he laughs.
So that power of wisdom starts shinning through you, you become a wise, righteous, virtuous man.
And such a balance you develop. I have known people who are honest, you see, so called,
now they go to such an extreme of honesty, that for honesty’s sake they’ll kill their father,
kill their mother, kill everyone.
But such a balanced and integrated person you become
that whatever you do is good for your spirit and for the spirit of others.
In Sanskrit the word is Haitha [BEST GUESS],
what ever is good for your spirit and for the spirit of others you do it.
And that is the right thing to do, and that’s how you become a righteous personality.
That’s the religion within you that gets awakened. Nobody has to tell you your religion,
you yourself become your own master, your own Guru, and by which you determine yourself,
now Mr. you can’t do this. No you can’t. So you become your own police commissioner.
You don’t need any outsider to tell you.
You are on your own guard because if you do something like that your vibrations will disappear
and then you don’t like it, don’t like it. Then you feel uneasy.
Nobody has to have you as a Guru, there’s no need you become your own Guru, is the best way.
And that’s how you solve the problem of becoming better by others,
is very difficult but yourself becoming better, by your own understanding and urges,
it’s a thousand fold happier and strong.
So the third thing that happens to you, that you become religious, you become the Guru, yourself.
Nobody has to tell you because there is a natural valency of ten within you
which starts balancing you, and you become one and enjoy that balance.
As you enjoy a balance of colors in a beautiful photograph,
in the same way you enjoy the balance within yourself. You enjoy your personality,
you enjoy your being and you enjoy to be the Self.
And those who are on the same level, you just enjoy each other.
This is the first time you enjoy other human being, as if you are enjoying a flower.
The fragrance of that personality is spiritual fragrance, is so beautiful and attractive.
Without any lust and greed in it but just enjoying the company is real perfect bliss.
Thank you very much. May God bless you.
END