Interviewer: Is this your first visit here?
Shri Mataji: Oh no.
Interviewer: No?
How many times have you been here before?
Shri Mataji: Beg your pardon?
Interviewer: How many times have you been
here?
Shri Mataji: I haven’t counted.
Must be how many times?
From 1974.
Interviewer: Right.
Shri Mataji: Practically every year.
Sometimes I missed one or twice.
Interviewer: And what is the main emphasis
in your teaching?
Shri Mataji: To convey that within us lies
a power which we call as Kundalini in the
triangular bone and when awakened, it passes
through six subtle centres through our spinal
chord, our brain, ultimately into limbic area
and pierces through the fontanel bone area
which was the soft bone in our childhood.
This is the actualization of baptism, actualization.
And this power within us is the reflection
of the Holy Ghost.
Thus you get your second birth, that’s how
you are twice born.
Interviewer: Oh I see.
Shri Mataji: Yes, born again.
Interviewer: And everyone has this?
Shri Mataji: Beg your pardon?
Interviewer: Everyone has this?
Shri Mataji: Everyone everyone has.
Interviewer: And how do people find it?
Shri Mataji: I knew about it since my birth
I think.
Interviewer: And what about the people you
teach?
Shri Mataji: Beg your pardon?
Interviewer: The people you teach, how can
they find this power?
Shri Mataji: (Unclear) They feel themselves,
the cool breeze on top of their heads.
And they feel they are connected with this
power because they can feel it on their fingertips,
also this power.
Interviewer: And the groups you speak to,
what sort of people are they?
Shri Mataji: (Unclear) Are conditioned people.
Or sometimes ego is there also, lot of ego.
They are not open-minded like scientists are.
And they are conditioned by different faiths
and blind faiths.
Interviewer: I have some information here
which says you have an emphasis on the spiritual
importance of women and their role.
In what way, you know how are women important
in this way?
In establishing the balance of society.
Shri Mataji: Because women are the potential.
Men are the kinetic energy and women don’t
know how powerful they are within themselves
and they try to compete with men and get frustrated.
Interviewer: And how are they powerful in
this way, different from men?
Shri Mataji: Because they have forbearance,
they have lot of forbearance, they are the
preservers of society, they are the preservers
of family life and they create beautiful children.
Motherhood is a sure thing, fatherhood is
uncertain isn’t it?
Interviewer: And so you’ve travelled the
world have you, speaking to people?
Shri Mataji: Yes, I don’t know how many
countries, I travel.
I’ve been to Russia, to all the Eastern
block people.
They seem to be very much clean about it because
they are not so conditioned and in our freedom
we have lost many things which were important
to us.
Interviewer: Such as?
Shri Mataji: Such as chastity, innocence,
simplicity, respect.
Interviewer: And how can people get these
virtues back then?
Shri Mataji: Once these centres are awakened
and nourished you feel physically all right,
mentally all right and your attention is filled
with the light of the Spirit and thus you’ll
see what is spirituality is within yourself
and you understand your beauty.
And then you enjoy your virtues, you become
religious, it’s not a question of saying
I’m this religion, that religion, you just
become religious, you become.
Like one may follow any religion but can do
any sins, they are equally the same, there’s
no difference, it’s just a brand.
Interviewer: The recent Gulf War what sort
of effect has that had on people as a whole?
Shri Mataji: At least one thing is that fundamentalism
is a very dangerous thing.
Any religion that gets exclusive can be very
dangerous.
In Sahaja Yoga you realise that all these
prophets, incarnations, saints were born on
the same tree of life or of spirituality and
we have plucked them, saying this is mine,
this is mine and we are fighting with those
dead flowers.
Interviewer: So how can people be helped through
your type of teaching?
Shri Mataji: Because of this happening you
get completely integrated within yourself.
Also all these centres which are within us
were created by these great incarnations in
the evolutionary process and they are all
lined up together.
Thus we realise that if this Kundalini has
to pass through we have to put them into the
same garland.
It’s a happening.
Interviewer: And how long have you been teaching
this?
Shri Mataji: I started in 1970.
Interviewer: And how long did it take you
to come to this.
Shri Mataji: No I started working out with
one lady to begin with in India.
Then as my husband got elected to a post,
as you must have heard about, he was the Secretary
General of the International Maritime Organisation
U.N..
I went to London and I started with seven
hippies.
They were hippies but very well educated professors
and lawyers and things like that but had become
hippies just for seeking the truth.
I had to work very hard on them but they are
the foundation of Sahaja Yoga.
And that’s how then one of them went abroad
to some other place, it started spreading.
England is a, like a heart of the universe
because everyone comes there and they carry
to their own country.
Interviewer: And which countries have you
been to ..
would there be so many that you ..
Shri Mataji: Yes, I have been at least to
forty five countries.
Interviewer: Really?
Shri Mataji: Yes.
Interviewer: When you were working with these
people how long did it take you to come to
now, to what you understand?
Shri Mataji: About what?
Interviewer: Your teachings.
How did it come together?
Shri Mataji: I see a great future, a new race
is coming up.
They are devoid of all addictions, devoid
of all diseases, devoid of unchaste things,
devoid of things which are wrong like they
lead a very nice married life, have nice children,
absolutely angelic I would say.
I don’t have to tell them anything, they
are on their own because they have evolved.
This is the last breakthrough of our evolution.
They are beautiful people.
We have seventy five to eighty marriages every
year, all international, and except for one
percent, they are all very very successful.
Interviewer: And do you intend on continuing
to travel, how long do you think you will
be travelling for?
Shri Mataji: I can’t say, already I am sixty
eight years of age.
Can’t say, as long as possible I would like
to travel because somehow they like me very
much everywhere I think.
Interviewer: And you obviously enjoy travelling
and speaking to people about it.
Shri Mataji: Yes.
Interviewer: Why do you enjoy doing it?
Shri Mataji: What?
Interviewer: Why do you enjoy travelling and
telling people about this?
Shri Mataji: It’s so nice to see so many
getting the meaning of their life, so many
getting rid of their problems and man-made
nonsense that they have on their heads.
Also they are capable of giving Realizations
to others.
And also if you give vibrations to your agriculture
it improves, to animals if you give it improves.
Also it solves ecological problems because
they become so wise.
We have to worry about the emancipation of
human beings as a whole, as a whole because
we are one world and they all feel they are
citizens of the universe.
And the love they have, respect they have
for each other and the silence they enjoy
shows that we’ll have no more wars, no more
problems and we’ll always abide in the beautiful
realm of kingdom of God.
It’s the greatest satisfaction anybody can.
This cannot be given by money, power, anything.
When I leave one country I feel very much
wrenched, as if my heart is being wrenched
because I feel that I am leaving all of them
there, but when I reach another country I
see again beautiful flower-like faces.
This is what all the incarnations wanted.
We have no organisation as such, I have no
secretary, nothing.
It’s like a stateless state you can call
it.
And we have no problems, we just enjoy that’s
all.
Pure enjoyment.
Interviewer: Thank you very much for your
time, it’s been very interesting, thank
you.
Shri Mataji: You are so intelligent I must
say, I thought you are a little girl, she’s
very intelligent.
Yesterday I was in New Zealand talking to
the interviewer, with the gentleman interviewing,
he felt the cool breeze in his hands immediately
and he came to my program also.
Interviewer: Thank you.
Shri Mataji: Want to take a photograph?
(Unclear).
Sahaja Yogi: She’s got it Shri Mataji, she’s
got it.
Shri Mataji: She’s got it.
First time
I met (unclear) in Australia.
They cannot see subtler things, that’s the
trouble is.
And they also find it’s not so sensational.
It’s the most sensational thing don’t
you think so?
It’s for the betterment of the whole world,
the most sensational thing.
It’s a silent revolution, peaceful revolution
that’s coming.
Has to come after all.
We are waiting for a shock all over.
One thing you must see that for all such things
you cannot pay any money because you always
have these from my country or from other countries.
…..
(unclear).
Don’t go near people who ask for money,
that’s the point.
You cannot pay for all these things.
Formerly I used to pay for my travel everything,
… (unclear) I used to pay.
But now they have said Mother we’ll look
after that, aeroplanes.
All right (unclear) I can’t take money for
that.
It’s invaluable.
And you know Christ never took any money,
nobody took any money, now this new type of
people who have come are already described
in the Bible.
One should run away from that, one after another
they are coming to Australia.
Whenever I came there was this Rajneesh was
there, (unclear) was there, (unclear) was
there and people are so much attracted to
them because they think they are paying.
Wrong idea.
And then they disappear.
Any person who has interest in Rolls Royce
and this kind of thing, how can people (unclear).
They don’t think about it, they don’t
think.
It must be told very very clearly to people,
don’t pay a single pai.
And you must know the accounts, that’s the
point.
Now if I am here, acually I don’t know how
these people organize, it’s among themselves.
They know (unclear), they pay, they do what
they…, I mean say for example they have
a program here they pay for the hall and they
know all that.
I am not interested in that.
Interviewer: Yes well thank you very much,
very interesting, thank you for your time.
Thank you.