Today is the third day of the Moon. Third
day of the Moon is Tritiya, is the special
day for the virgins. Kundalini is
the virgin desire. It is virgin because it
has not yet manifested itself. And also, on
the third center of Nabhi, the virgins appear
as shaktis of Guru.
As we have got ten Gurus which we regard as
the main Gurus they all had either their sister
or daughter as their shakti. In the Bible
it is said that, in the Old Testament, that
the one who will be coming will be born of
a virgin. And then the Jews would not accept
Christ so they said that “It’s not written
as virgin, it’s written ‘the girl’.”
Now in Sanskrit Language ‘girl’ and ‘the
virgin’ are one word. We did not have 80-year-old
girls as we have nowadays.
So the virginity of a woman meant that she
was a girl who was not married as yet or who
has not met her husband so far. That is the
essence of purity, which was the power of
the Guru Principle.
So, for a Guru who is in charge of leading
others into enlightenment, has to know that
his power is to be used as a virgin power
of pure power. A Guru cannot use this power
in a way an ordinary person can use. So his
relationship with his disciples whether they
are boys or girls has to be absolutely pure.
The purity should be of such a limit that
a Guru should not accept anything from the
disciples. About this, lots of things has
been written by many saints especially in
Maharashtra. Also Kabirdas and Nanaka have
clearly talked against the people who have
relationship with their shishyas, or disciples,
either with greed or with lust. They have
called them as rakshasas. In the same way
the people who are today, supposed to be the
leaders, the Gurus, in Sahaja Yoga, have to
remember that their relationship with their
disciples has to be of complete purity and
virginity.
In the olden days it was all right that people
did not know about the punishments that can
fall upon such a person who uses his power
as a Guru for his own gratification. But today
at this time when at this time…(Mother tells
off some children in Marathi for disturbing)…The
punishment that
can take place in those days of last judgement
could be very serious and as a Mother I have
to warn all of you, those who have started
their centers or those who are becoming Gurus
as leaders that you have to have a very detached
mind and clear cut understanding within yourself.
You can not mishandle money. You can not misappropriate
money, you can not use anything for your own
purpose which belongs to the collective. Nor
could you use anyone for the gratification
of your lust. If you have any such weaknesses
is better to get out of Sahaja Yoga for the
time being and come back when you are better
off.
There is no place in Sahaja Yoga for impure
people. Purity is to be worshipped out and
out.
As we say that in the West there’s sin against
the Mother. People don’t value their chastity
but in the East, specially in India, people
don’t know that they have to be absolutely
honest as far as their money is concerned.
They fall into traps, into temptations and
then they get a very severe punishment, not
through Me but through the wrath of God almighty
because this is God’s work we are doing.
And the worst thing could be that we seek
power. If not these two things, we seek power
in Sahaja Yoga. To them it becomes like their
own domain and they start using, asserting,
their power over others. This cannot be possible.
It will not work out.
Those who will try to dominate others just
for the satisfaction or their own ego will
suffer a lot.
Now the fourth type are the people who try
to put their conditionings on Sahaja Yoga.
Like somebody who is a Hindu and he is fasting
say, most of the days they fast, I don’t
know which one is fasting. So he’s fasting
say, on a Saturday and he tells people that
see now, I have to fast on Saturday because
after all, you see, I have been fasting for
all these days and all that. Or who has got
conditioning, like, I would like to marry
only a foreigner if I am a foreigner or if
I am an Indian I’ll marry an Indian. All
such conditions if a leader tries to put forward
and saying that, “Mother said so,” he’ll
be doubly punished.
We are belonging to the True Religion of a
true, pure universality. None of these artificial
things can bind us. This is one of the very
important subtle things, which we don’t
understand – that we are very much conditioned.
“We the English”, “we the Indians”
or “We x,y, z”. You are human beings.
God made only one world. He didn’t make
all these things. It’s all artificial, man-made.
You are born of one Mother and you are yogis
who have no bondages of this artificial nature.
Everyone who claims to be a Guru has to realise
that he can not bound himself to any particular
mundane, outdated nonsensical ideas.
Gradually whatever the leaders will do will
be followed by the followers. So the leader
has to lead a life which is an ideal. A leader
who is very dominating, or who is very possessive
or aggressive, will create leaders who will
be of the same nature.
The another one who is very much conditioned
will create conditioned followers. And may
be, I may not find any relationship with them.
So we don’t want to have a priest class
as Gurus. Priests are different from Gurus.
We do not want people to take upon themselves
the laws of God and use them for their own
purposes.
Today is the day of the Gurus because is the
third day, the third Chakra of the Nabhi.
The same one we have the starting point of
the Mahalakshmi. Mahalakshmi energy starts
working after you have finished with the Lakshmi
tattwa. If the Gurus are still with, busy
with the Lakshmi tattwas, have no sense of
sacrifice, have no sense of detachment they
cannot be called as leaders.
The Mahalakshmi is the subtle form of our
hankering, of our desires, is the subtlest,
the epitome. Because first we search for power
through physical, mental, emotional and ultimately
we want to have spiritual powers also to impress
others.
In Sahaja Yoga you come here to dissolve all
your powers. You become so powerless that
all the powers of God Almighty start working
through you.
Supposing this instrument (pointing to the
microphone She is talking into) has some powers
I won’t be able to handle this. It would
be going here, there and there. So to worship
Mahalakshmi one has to remember that you must
dissolve all your powers. That is the surrender
that is what is ‘Islam‘ as they call it.
But these are all words for people.
Surrender is a very difficult thing to understand
for human beings. They think “I can’t
surrender.” What do you have to surrender,
is nothing but your ego and your conditioning.
All these things I am telling you but if you
learn them by heart like a parrot, you can
repeat. That will have no influence on your
followers. Unless and until you show in your
own life that beauty, that composer, that
care, that concern, that love, nobody is going
to listen to a parrot.
The meaning has to come from the practices
not from the precepts. This is what Sahaja
Yoga [is], which is very different from any
other spiritual announcements. So be careful!
You
have
been chosen by your merit as sahaja yogis,
so respect yourself.
May God bless you!