Yesterday I told you
how 'Self' is more important
than anything else
at the present state of human awareness
When you are at the human awareness
first thing that should happen to you
is to feel your 'Self'.
As Shri Krishna has said,
"Atmane atmane thushtaha."
Unless and until you reach your Atma, your Spirit,
you are not going to get the satisfaction
of achieving anything.
Because Kundalini, which you see here
seated in the triangular bone
which we call as the sacrum
that means, Greek knew about it.
Greek knew about the sacrum bone.
Otherwise they would not have called it as sacrum, means sacred.
Even when I went to Athens I was surprised
that Athena, the word 'Atha' comes from Sanskrit,
means primordial. And she had a snake like thing
in Her hand with all the chakras.
So the Greeks knew about it.
And when I talked to them
they told Me, that it is a fact.
that Indians came much before Alexander.
We had a rapport with Indians
much before Alexander
and they told us about the Primordial Mother
and Her three powers.
It is very amazing how they knew all about it.
And then it all got lost because of the extroversion,
a moving out from reality.
So this bone, sacrum bone contains
or here resides the Kundalini in three and a half coil
This is the power of our pure desire.
The pure desire is the desire, when it is manifested
should give you full satisfaction.
For example, some people seek it in power.
They indulge in power.
Some seek it in possessions.
Some seek it in other things.
But all these seekings do not give them satisfaction
If they could give satisfaction
then there would have been no problem.
Because once you buy a car then you want to buy something else
and then you buy…want to buy something else.
You start moving from one to another and as Economics says
that in particular a want is satiable
but not in general.
So we have to understand, that the wants
that we have, the desires we have,
are not pure desires, but are impure desires
and when we deal with them,
we never get that satisfaction.
For example somebody wants to do something
he does it but doesn’t get any satisfaction out of it.
The only way you can get satisfaction is
that you become one with the Divine.
And this power of desire which is a pure desire is
residing in each and everybody’s triangular bone.
But we are lost.
We are seeking our pleasures,
our joys into wrong things
We think that by doing this or by doing that,
by buying this or becoming that
we will be completely, fully satisfied,
which we ultimately discover.
In a evolutionary stage
such people when they discover
that the joy is not in all these things;
there is no happiness in this kind of thing;
we have to go beyond this.
Once they discover this then they become
a special category of people.
And these special categories of people
are the seekers.
Of course today I find so many seekers are lost.
Especially in America they are lost in various ways.
We would say in all the cults,
or in all other things like drugs, or homosexuality
or whatever you may call it, they are lost into these.
Into violence, many are indulging into violence.
Or doing all kinds of things
which are not for their ascent,
but are degrading and will take them down
not to their seeking, but to their hell.
But it is happening today.
You can see it very clearly.
It is happening
because human beings do not understand
that human awareness is a transitory phase,
you have to go beyond it.
And that beyond stage, the stage we have to reach
is the stage of your 'Self'.
To begin with
you have to become first of all 'Self Realised'.
Meaning you are to be 'Born Again'.
And to be born again
you have to allow the Kundalini to work it out.
So what do we do as people said,
I told you yesterday, it is effortless.
It is without any money.
It just happens spontaneously.
Now it happens that
an enlightened light can enlighten another light.
In the same way
I may be able to enlighten you
but you can enlighten many others.
Like in India we have someone
who has enlightened 10,000 people.
and has done so much good to people,
that it is amazing.
Even there are people like the President of India,
we can say the President of the High Court
Judge of the Hague High Court
which is the World High Court,
The president of that,
He's got his Realisation
and he's a Sahaja Yogi
So we have people of that calibre
who are Sahaja Yogis.
and who have felt the vibrations
who have become Self Realised.
But they are very humble people, extremely humble people.
Indians are basically humble and they know
who is a saint and who is not a saint.
They are so sensitive that they know
But in the West, as we have now lost our power
to feel the saintliness in a person
we do not know who is a saint, who is not a saint.
So the first thing that has to happen to you to understand who is a saint, who is not a saint,
is first to get your Realisation.
Without the spirit expressing itself
into your awareness, into your attention,
you cannot make out who is a saint, or who is not a saint.
Like they crucified Christ for no reason at all
and they worshipped Hitler.
The Jews, they refused to accept Christ,
they refused. They said, no we don’t accept Christ,
because Christ said that I am dying for your sins.
They said, no we don’t believe in that. We must suffer. So they suffered.
They had sufferings.  If you ask for suffering you’ll have sufferings.
But if they had accepted Christ
at least one thing would have happened
they would not have suffered.
They asked for suffering. They thought unless and until we suffer we cannot go to God.
This was a very wrong idea.  Because Christ himself was a Jew.
Himself He took birth among the Jews.
And it was the Jews He came to save.
But they are the ones who refused to accept Him,
because they were blinded. They didn't want to see the point.
In the same way it has happened in every century.
Anytime any incarnation came people did not want to accept.
Not in India, I would say. Indians are much more sensitive to spirituality,
because they are not so much materialistic.
They understand, because we have been for ages seeking and seeking from… traditionally
So we know what this seeking is.
What it means.  For Me it’s not difficult to talk to them about Kundalini.
There I start on a different level altogether,
because they know everything whatever I’m talking, they know already, what it is.
May be not in the cities where the people are westernised. But they know.
But for other people I have to start it from A to Z.
So this is the Kundalini. We have got it. Three and a half coils, and it has a mathematical calculation.
Now it’s only Indians and Buddhists from Indians I would say believe in the non-being.
They believe there’s a non-being; being and non-being.
What is that state of non-being?
When you become the non-being means when you go beyond your conditioning and ego then you become the non-being.
And once you become the non-being then nothing can touch you.
As I told you yesterday…who are standing in the water have fear of getting drowned in the water,
but if you go to the boat then you start seeing that the water is down below it is not going to touch you.
That state has to be achieved, is the non-being, is the fourth dimension within us.
This is called also in Sanskrit as Turya dasha.
Now you might say why in India, these people discovered all that.
See now the reason is India is a very ancient country.
And there we didn’t have these problems that you had to face when you came to America.
You had to face the nature to begin with. Our nature is very kind.
You can live under a tree, eat the fruits of the forest and can enjoy ourselves.
We don’t need much in that country to cover ourselves or to have any elaboration.
So the attention has been always inside to find out why are we here?
What are we doing here?  Are we wasting our life?
Are we doing any harm to ourselves or to others?
Is it alright to exist as human beings or is there anything beyond?
This search has been there for thousands and thousands of years.
And because of this seeking
they have been able to reach, right conclusions
that there is this Kundalini within us.
And this Kundalini is to be awakened.
And if She is awakened
then you can become 'Self' very easily.
And this was the job I had to do.
For that I had to work very hard
for days together to understand
what was the problem with human beings,
the permutations and combinations
of problems that they had.
And somehow I managed it, I think.
Now en masse Realisation is possible.
Yesterday despite some people being mischievous
you did get Realisation.
This is God's work
and God's work will go on.
Whether some people come and trouble you,
makes no difference.
They are just like mosquitoes.
They come and go away, has no meaning at all.
Because you see God’s work is much greater
than what they think of themselves.
So it doesn't matter what happens
or what people say or talk.
The God's work will go on
But you must know it is a living work.
It's not a plastic thing.
You can produce thousands of plastic flowers
very easily,
but you cannot produce one single living flower.
So when this living force has to act it takes time.
And it will take time, gradually it will grow.
And you'll be surprised that
gradually it will grow so beautifully,
that suddenly you'll find
lots of people coming up and becoming.
Because in Sahaja Yoga
what you become is important.
It’s the actualisation.
It is not some certificate or some organisation
that you belong to some organisation
or there is some certificate.
But it is what you become.
Your becoming is important
If you cannot become something
the you are no good in Sahaja Yoga.
Many people who come to us
we find they improve a lot
and they become very great also.
But some people do not.
They just waste it.
Energy is all wasted whatever you try they do not.
Sometimes they are so conditioned
that we cannot improve them.
There we feel helpless about them
because they do not want to corporate also.
And also they have many pressures on them.
But 90% people go up very well
and they manifest whatever they have achieved
Now the main thing is to understand
that this mechanism exists with us.
This energy exists within us.
Now this is like a hypothesis for you.
You need not accept it. It’s a hypothesis
as one would put to a scientist.
But scientist must have an open…open mind.
They shouldn’t have a closed mind.
if you have a barrier
you cannot put anything before them.
If they are scientist they will have an open mind
to listen to My hypothesis.
And if it could be proved, if it could be proved
then you have to accept it.
If it is...  doesn't prove,
then you can say all right that's not proved so far.
All right!
So you have to wait and have patience with it.
This is what it is in simple words
that I cannot be forced on you.
It cannot be humbled before you.
You have to ask for it.
Nobody can force you that you can become.
I cannot guarantee yesterday I said. It's a fact.
But still so many people got their realisation,
felt the cool breeze and felt the cool
breeze out of the head.
This you cannot do otherwise.
All other things you can do but this you cannot do,
is to take out cool breeze of your head
which is a factual thing and experienced.
But as I told you, that we live mentally
much more than we live with reality.
And mental projection can be anything
like a person who murders someone.
He has justification,
I murdered someone because of this and this,
but that justification
does not allow you to get out of law.
Does it? No.
You will be caught in the law. You cannot do it.
Whatever is wrong you are not supposed to do it?
But that is human law.
In the same way there is God’s laws.
And it you go against God's laws
then what happens
is that we are punished.
Now today I am going to tell you
about other awareness that one can have.
That one should know about.
I am talking about the super-consciousness
which is on top of our head.
But when the attention moves
to the left side too much
or to the right side too much
then also there could be a very, very big problem.
And the big problem can come because
we are not knowledgeable about it
We do not know. What is unknown
need not be Divine. Not at all.
Now when you start say
becoming extremely submissive,
slavish or you start following something vey blindly,
you start becoming fanatic about it.
Just without thinking
what you are doing is not right or wrong
you just follow something like that.
We call it the left side movement of the attention starts
where you start subduing yourself to something.
Subjecting yourself to something.
Accept the slavery of some ideas.
Accept the conditioning of some sort of theories.
Now once you start accepting such theories mentally
the attention starts moving towards the left side.
And also some people have a capacity to posses you like that.
They can posses you and can do like that, that you
lose your freedom and you become that kind of a person.
Then at that time what happens that you start moving
from your conscious mind to the subconscious mind
and then to the collective subconscious.
If you move to collective subconscious
then what happens to you.
If you move to the collective subconscious
then a person becomes possessed.
This possession comes to you through what we call
the protein 52 or protein 58 in medical terminology.
They say that if a person is vulnerable to cancer
it is triggered by the presence or entrance of protein 52 or protein 58.
These are the names the doctors are given which trigger the disease
and once that happens then a person cannot get out of cancer
Because then the triggering starts
and he starts getting from bad to worse.
This 52 and 58, where do you find it?
According to doctors you find 52 and 58 in the area
which is built within us since our creation.
This area is placed within us
on the left-hand side, as you can see. Somebody can come and show.
On the left hand side this area is placed.
And this area one enters very easily.
Say you go on taking somebody’s name.
Now a days it is a fashion to give you a mantra.
Now start getting mantras, going on saying mantras, mantras, mantras.
Now what happens that you are not connected with the Divine.
And you start taking the name of some ‘x','y','z.’
So you are not connected
and you are just pressing hard your mind to get connected.
But it cannot because the Kundalini has not arisen
so you move to the left side.
And there you get caught up,
and that’s why you know in the cult people are so much mesmerised.
In every cult people get mesmerised
because they move to the left
for the domination of these gurus and things.
Because they want to make money out of them.
And then they cannot think of anything else.
They just think this is the right thing.
I was amazed that some of the cults
the gurus don’t know even Sanskrit language.
Some of them have come out of the jail
and they have become gurus
And they have give mantras which are so funny.
That somebody has been given mantra of Inga.
There is no word like Inga,
except for this word in a colloquial way is called inga
when a spider or something,
you can say, a scorpion has got the sting that is called as inga.
And this scorpion, when this scorpion hits it
to a person is called as the inga;
means that biting.
Now that’s the mantra given to many people, I was shocked
and it was told not to tell anyone about it.
So if you tell to anyone, he will just start laughing
and rolling with laughter.
Another mantra I heard was 'thinga';
meaning when you show someone like this is thinga.
In colloquial word, not in Sanskrit language!
There is nothing like a gerund ‘ing’ in Sanskrit language.
It has no meaning.
And everything is meaningful in Sanskrit.
Even every syllable is meaningful.
So such people have come over
and have become great gurus.
And they give you names.
May be the names of some proteins which exists
and which enter into you and you get possessed.
So this left-side movement is a very common thing.
And once you get to this left-side movement
you cannot get out of it.
It's very difficult,
so the people who have been to such people
or to such enticement
show immediately when they come to us for realisation
and that we don’t know how to deal with them.
Because if you tell them,
"You forget your guru." They don't like it.
They go on contortions, their bodies start getting into contortions.
They feel terrible. They cannot sit quiet.
They cannot move up.
But if you tell them that this was wrong,
they don’t want to accept because they are still carrying on with that idea.
And they don’t want to believe
that whatever they were carrying on was wrong.
That they have to ascend.
Even when they ascend they take time.
This is one very big problem we face.
But as a result of the left side movement
you get most of the incurable diseases,
For example your AIDS disease that has come
is because of the combination of the left side Mooladhara Centre
and heart…is that…that’s the one.
Of course it has to have Swadisthana with it, left Swadisthan.
Is due to that.
If somebody could cure these three centres of that person,
that person can be cured.
Sclerosis comes from the same.
If somebody is suffering from multiple sclerosis, same problem
that it comes Mooladhara Chakra, Void
and also sometimes the Right Heart.
Sclerosis! Most of the muscular troubles go like that.
Then we have got cancer.
Cancer could be due to any chakra
which is on the left hand side.
Must be the combination of two chakras
on the left hand side
depending on where the trouble is.
But when the cancer trouble comes into the centre
then it starts ascending.
Then it starts moving and you get galloping cancer.
You can start going from one to another end
and it can finish off a person.
That's how you can just be finished with a galloping cancer.
Now when somebody is vulnerable like I would say
a person who is a very, very active person
who is very much under shock all the time,
is very, very active and hectic, supposing he is a…
getting up in the morning, reading newspaper
and getting up into his bath and then getting ready somehow or other
and getting into his car
and then going out in a very hectic manner
he lives under shock
because he is reading horrible news, then he is seeing a big jam on the street
and all this things are happening, he is so full of anxieties,
such a person is venerable to another thing called blood cancer.
But for that also the Left Nabhi, this centre, is attacked.
If Left Nabhi is attacked under these circumstances
such a person can get blood cancer.
Supposing your mother is like that, she's a very hectic person
and she is trying to sort of do many things at the same time
and she is of that nature then also the child can pick up trauma.
If a mother is a very extreme type of a person or has gone through shocks like that…
I have seen people who have gone through wars and have come out of problems.
Their children also are very prone to troubles of the brain.
And they also get it because of the left side movement.
But as you go upward, as the chakras come upward on the left hand side, say the Left Agnya is caught up
and Left Swadisthana is caught up, that means the person is completely possessed.
But with that if the Heart Chakra is caught up or with that if the Vishuddhi Chakra is caught up
then one can become mad and such people could be there
But they become mad, they become alright, then become mad, like that you go on and ultimately they end up as mad people.
But in Sahaja Yoga one can cure people who are mad but they have to be treated in a way.
Normally we do not take up any person who is a mad person in our yoga because it is very difficult to cure them and better them.
But if they want to work it out on themselves we say all right work it out this way.
Try if you can be alright
But there are many in between phases like schizophrenic you can call it, or some people who are imbalanced, who are nervous, all kinds of things are in between.
So absolutely mad even if you forget, but there are so many others who look sane, but inside they have problems.
All such people can be cured with Sahaja Yoga, if they act according to what we tell them and the way it is to be worked on.
Now in Sahaja Yoga the practices are extremely simple because it’s question of balance.
The left side catches…if the left side catches then you get all these problems.
But if you can balance it, if you can balance left side with the right side, the troubles can be all right.
For example, if you have got say a left side problem and you do some right side activity of ego development, you will be amazed that your cancer can be cured.
But then you go to the right side.
That means you become ego oriented. You become extremely ambitious.
You become futuristic. You start dominating others.
And this is what was practiced by Hitler.
He got this knowledge from Dalai Lama. He said it in his book that he got it from Dalai Lama
How to control the minds of the people by which you dominate them and by domination what do you make out of them?
Devils!
And that’s what he did it,
because they become so ambitious, they become racist to begin with
They become racist. They think they are the best. They are the highest. They have the right to kill anybody they feel like.
They have the right to take revenge. They have a right to ill treat people
All kinds of funny ideas come into their heads, these right sided people.
And when they come into the right side they do not know what they are up to,
because once they develop the right side. then they have other troubles.
Like they might develop blood pressure, they might develop kidney troubles, they might develop heart trouble.
Heart in the sense, not angina and all not a lethargic heart, but overactive heart,
they can get a sudden, massive, heart attack and they may die with it.
So such people are also suffering from all kinds of liver trouble
Like cirrhosis of the liver.
Liver…other liver troubles, skin troubles, skin problems,
all these come from the right side movement.
So when you start moving to the right side too much,
you can be possessed by people who are overactive.
Like a ego oriented person if he bcomes
friendly with another egoistical person
both of them combined together in such a manner
that they form a group of egoistical nature.
When they become egoistical
they try to dominate and a big group can form
a frantic, horrible, violent group which can try to kill.
In India we had one such group which was formed,
under the name of the Goddess they started it.
In India they all are called as Anand Marg.
Of course it is now banned.
The fellow is under supervision,
but still in America he has followers.
Surprisingly!
they were caught killing
some ambassadors and all that.
And the leader
had to go in the jail for days together.
Everything happened but the followers,
because they are so possessed
with the idea that they are in charge
and they have to kill everyone and that they have
to become like Hitler.
Now you cannot stop it.
It’s very difficult, but you can
if you can raise their Kundalini
then they will understand this is not reality.
We are just doing something that is not reality.
Is not for our beneficiary…
beneficiary or…neither for anybody else.
It is such a dangerous thing
we are doing to ourselves.
It is not at all benevolent to ourselves
or to anybody else.
So the benevolence only comes
when you move upward.
The third we can say is the awareness of hell
where people are really devilish by nature
You cannot change them.
They are very devil.. devil like,
very possessive type,
extremely arrogant, aggressive,
and they are really devils incarnate
in human forms.
And such people have to go to hell,
because we call them as
the awareness of the hell.
They always think of destruction,
of destroying others,
of overpowering others
or of destroying themselves.
There are many bhoots you know
who destroyed themselves.
Just like that they killed themselves.
These are all the people
who are on the other side of the ascent.
So when you start rising higher and higher
due to these chakras,
and when the Kundalini rises
through all these chakras
and goes up beyond the Sahasrara,
as you call it the Brahmarandra, here,
you become a subtler being.
Like your human attention say, we can say is like cloth here
And now the Kundalini is pushing it upward,
upward, like that
So all your attention which is outside goes inside.
And when it pierces through from here,
this piercing makes the attention subtle
because the subtle that is around which you do not feel normally starts penetrating into it.
It starts covering your attention.
And that’s how we say now your attention is enlightened.
And now it is enlightened. Not just talk but it becomes enlightened with collective consciousness.
You become collectively conscious.
Then such people when they talk, when they talk have such a personality, such a knowledge.
They become knowledge. They have no problems.
They become knowledge because they become the absolute knowledge.
But it is for you to decide. What are you seeking in life?
What do you want in life?  What is your life worth?
If you want to cheapen your life, waste it for something very cheap and ordinary and useless then you can go ahead.
But if you think your life is important as a human being, it should be,
because you have become from amoeba to this stage as human being not to waste it.
Not to throw it away, uselessly, but to become the Spirit.
That is what you have come on this Earth for
and that's what should happen to you.
Now the main problem with human beings is
that there are barriers we have got.
To accept anything we have barriers. But there is nothing to be accepted.
In Sahaja yoga you need not accept anything what so ever but you should also not deny.
If you deny I cannot raise your Kundalini. I cannot.
You should allow your mind to be open to get realised.
Because one reason is there,
why you have to do that more,
because you do not know about Kundalini
People told Me they don’t even know what Self Realisation is.
Imagine in India when My grandchild was born
we had our astrologer in My husband’s place,
about two thousand miles away
from where the child was born.
He sent a telegram saying that
this child has found her guru,
sadguru in the household.
It was such a great thing to find a sadguru
who will give realisation to the child.
To us it is the most important thing.
In a horoscope the first thing they’ll ask,
"Will, shall we get Self Realisation
in this life time or not?"
Then they will say, "All right,
this life left, time be mine.
May be next lifetime.” Then they’ll think, “Oh God,
we have to wait one life time more."
And all the action is surrounding that.
The whole behaviour
that you must try to check your attention.
Chitta nirodh, try to check your attention.
Wherever it wants to go just keep it out.
While here it is, “What’s wrong?" "So what?”
If you want you jump in the sea. "So what?"
"Who are you to tell us?"
It is not that.
There it is, you must control your attention.
Control your attention! Keep the attention pure!
If your attention is not pure at the time of Realisation
there will be a problem
It is just a different attitude towards life in India.
If somebody is angry
here people always say. "I hate you."
I mean in India if a child says like that
he will have two slaps on the face.
Its regarded bad manners to
even to think like that, that you hate anyone
To hate anyone is a sign of degraded personality.
I mean it’s very common with Indian people.
Whatever you know of Indians are the people
who are uprooted,
who have come here to make dollars.
They are different people.
They are sort of sieved out.
But the people who are in India,
now we have here
at least 20% people who have been to India.
You can ask them.
To them generosity is a quality.
Righteousness is a quality.
Purity is a quality. Quietude is a quality.
Peaceful nature is a quality.
They do not boast of their angers
and they do not boast of their hatred at all.
I mean it is never, never, never done.
Even if somebody hates he will
not say that, "I hate you."
I mean it took some time for Me
to even say this sentence to people
like it is something prohibited.
Because it's your tongue gets spoiled.
If your tongue is spoiled and is impure
then whatever you say becomes untruth.
Your tongue must be pure.
You should not say something which is not true.
In the sense, true doesn't mean that
supposing somebody is a person,
who to your mind is not a good person.
You shouldn’t say that. Need not say that
you are not a good person. You just keep quiet.
Let him discover,
because if he is bad, he will suffer himself.
This is a common attitude.
I am not talking for Indians,
but I must say for Spiritual life,
one has to learn from them.
Some of them who were thugs
must have come here to loot you. That's a different point.
I mean I am sorry for that. I am sorry.
But I also blame you for your naiveness.
I came much before that. But I said
you are not to pay to anyone any money.
Nobody listened to Me. They didn't like me
at all, when I said that.
So you had to suffer.
I know it was wrong, but it happened.
Now at least people should realise
that purity can only be achieved
through Self Realisation.
Innocence can be awakened within you
on the first chakra.
On the first chakra you develop innocence.
In the second chakra you develop creativity.
I’ve known people who never used to sing
have started singing very well.
Who never used to create anything
have started creating beautiful paintings.
They have become great painters now, very well known painters, musicians.
Those who were never doing architecture have become great architects and who  have never done any interior decoration have achieved a lot.
So, to say that we are very creative one must know that you have limited energy and for that you have to be connected to the mains.
So, all the time the energy is flowing into you.
Then on top of that is the third centre, which is the centre of your seeking.
So whatever you were seeking was not alright.
But you do get your material well being. No doubt.
You do get your material well being but up to a point where you feel absolutely satisfied about it.
You don’t need anything anymore.
You also get a great blessing of dignity and divinity.
You get a proper understanding of your being. You become like a king.
For a king what we call the emperor, he doesn’t need anything.
For example as you know I am born of a very rich family and it’s a royal family and My husband also is a very rich man.
It’s alright, we live in a very great comfort no doubt. But I can sleep anywhere. I can sleep on the street,
I can live anywhere. I am not bothered where I live,
what I do, how I move. I have no problem.
Because if you are the emperor,
you don't ask for anything. Do you?
If you get the food, alright, if you don't, alright.
If you like some food, or don’t like food
somebody says, I have said, “I don’t know what I ate in the morning.
I don’t know what I am going to eat now.
I don’t know if I had my lunch or not.
If I've had, all right.
Otherwise you can do what you like.
It’s that simple. Your body becomes your slave.
You can lie down anywhere you feel like.
You can do any amount of travelling.
You can do thousand and one things.
You become so dynamic.
That happens when your Lakshmi Tattwa is arisen.
There are four Lakshmi Tattwas within us.
The first is the Lakshmi Tattwa,
where you become a person very dignified
and endowed with material comforts.
But comfort which kill you is not there.
Comfort means you are materially no more bothered.
You get jobs. In London we have so many jobless people.
But in Sahaja yoga all those who are there,
all of them have got jobs.  All of them!
It's difficult to find one person who hasn’t got the job.
Moreover it is compulsory in Sahaja yoga that those who stay in the ashram
must have some jobs.
We have tried to allow some people to come without that
but we had very bad experiences of such people.
So all those who are living on dole or some sort of a thing,
we don’t allow them to come in the ashram.
And you will be surprised that as soon as they join Sahaja Yoga they get jobs.
They get better and better jobs
because Krishna has said, "Yoga kshema vahamyaham."
"When you get your yoga, your well being will be looked after."
He didn’t say, "Kshema yoga," he didn’t say
"I’ll look after your well being and then you go to yoga."
No! First yoga. "Yoga kshema vahamyaham."
"First you get the yoga and then the kshema will work out."
That’s what happens to you on the Nabhi Chakra,
which is very important. But Raja Lakshmi that is
you become like a king.
That you become Gruha Lakshmi or Gruhastha
means you become a house holder.
You become a good wife and a good husband.
You develop proper feelings for each other.
And you develop proper feelings for your children.
You improve your societies through that essence
if it is born in you that you understand the importance of a good family life.
And that automatically happens. You don’t have to tell anybody.
Just those people who hated each other after coming to Sahaja yoga
have started loving each other,
understanding and enjoying each other.
And married life in Sahaja Yoga is tremendous.
Ninety percent of married life is so great that people in America
where they divorce third year, every third year,
we have seen people are doing very well in the married life
even in America.
Even here the…you see this mental projection,
the wife is no good, the husband no good, all vanishes.
You become the Spirit. You start enjoying
the deeper significance of marriage.
Then comes the fourth side of the Lakshmi Tattwa
Is the fourth side is the ascending side.
The people who have got more money are fed up
and now want to have something beyond.
In the same way in Sahaja Yoga, when you start moving
then you find that nothing but spiritual life gives you real joy
So you just don’t care for anything else but the spiritual life.
And what is the spiritual life of Sahaja Yoga is
that you become the light
and you give light to others.
Selflessly, there is no selfish motive in it.
Just because you are the light,
you become the light,
You don't see the light, you become the light.
And you give light to others and just do it selflessly,
without charging any money.
Without asking for anything
you just start giving what you have got.
Spontaneously without paying for it
You just do it in a way that is a saintly way.
Saints always spend their own money,
always have spent their own money
to give joy to others.
They have never taken money from anyone.
I mean I have not heard of any saint
who has built up big palaces
and big places and big organisation, never.
That's not a sign of a saint.
A saint just emits compassion
and this compassion doesn’t speak. It is silent.
This compassion acts.
It doesn’t speak. It acts.
When it acts it works out wonders.
That's what you know when Christ
was touched by some lady
he said, "Some energy has flown through Me."
That is what it is.
That the energy starts flowing through you
and you do not do anything
just happens automatically.
Without doing anything you achieve it.
So for today
I think I have come up to the Nabhi Chakra.
tomorrow I'll tell you about other chakras
in better, elaborate way
that you will understand
what is the essence of these chakras.
That what becomes of you.
They have described to you the chakras
but why these chakras.
What do they mean?
These are the different,
evolutionary milestones within us,
which have been crossed and the last one
is this one, which you have to cross now. That's all.
See you are just ready for it.
You are made for this. God has made you for this.
Its best is that you get to it.
And that’s why I was yesterday asking questions
and people have now told Me,
“Mother please don’t ask questions because it is a waste
it’s a waste of time.”
Those people who are asking questions
are not asking any sensible questions.
They are not bothered about themselves
why, how they are spending their lives.
of course some people
asked very sensible questions also
I must say, but there’s no need to ask questions.
Let us see if it works out within in you.
If it works out it will be a good idea.
Now you want to have Realisation first?