1994-10-15 Public Program, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset we have to know that truth is what it is.
We cannot change it; we cannot transform it.
Also, unfortunately,
with this human awareness we cannot know it.
Can they hear, all of them? Ask them can they hear, all of them.
Yogini: He is saying that with the fan it is not helping,
All right, then put it off.
If you move the fan further away, it will be all right.
Better. It makes too much sound; fan was making too much sound.
So now we have to know that our awareness
is not sufficient enough to know the absolute Truth.
Actually, we don't know the absolute Truth.
That's why there is a problem.
Somebody says this is good. Somebody says that is good.
There is a quarrel, fight, arguments, and ultimately wars.
That means we have to evolve more.
Whatever I am going to tell you today,
you should not accept it blindfolded,
but accept it as a hypothesis.
And if it is proved, then you have to accept it as honest people.
Because it is for your benevolence,
for the benevolence of your family, your country,
and for the benevolence of the whole world.
At the very outset, I would like to tell you
that the truth is you are not this body, this mind,
these emotions, intellect, conditionings, or your ego.
But you are the pure Spirit.
There is another truth is, you see all these beautiful flowers
and we take them for granted.
Actually, it's a miracle.
If you ask a doctor who runs your heart,
so he will say, It is the autonomous nervous system.
But who is this auto?
Also, if you take to science you will find they cannot answer
all the questions because it has its own limitations.
For example, science cannot tell you why are you on this earth,
what is your identity.
So we take to religions.
But in the modern times, religions have become
money oriented or power oriented.
Also, it was great incarnations who came
like Christ, Mohammed Saab, Moses.
They were very great, pure incarnations
and they did not know what sort of people they were facing.
The way they were tortured and crucified.
They preached to people who cannot follow their followings,
they cannot follow their principles.
For example, Christ has said in the fifth chapter  Mathews
that if your one eye commits a sin, you take out the eye.
If your one hand does some sinful thing, you cut out the hand.
If somebody slaps you on this face, turn the other face.
I haven't seen any Christian without eye and without hands.
It's an impossible thing and very difficult.
It was easy for Christ to say that because He was so great.
Actually, you have to become a saint to follow His principles.
Ordinary people cannot follow Him.
Then I think Mohammed Saab thought that He was so strict
with the men, so He made lots of laws for the women also.
And so strict that any woman who looked at any man
with any lust, she should be buried halfway
and should be stoned.
Imagine what would have happened to American women.
So the principle of morality
was really too much for normal human beings.
Also, the Sharia which was brought in by Mohammed Saab
was given by Moses for the Jews.
In the Bible in the Old Testament, in the Jeremiah,
it is described clearly.
But Jews thought it was too much, so they didnt bother.
But Muslims think they can do it; I am sure they can't.
So, they believe they are Muslims, but they are not.
Christians believe they are Christians, but they are not.
First you have to become a saint.
You have to become an enlightened personality
so that automatically you become righteous, automatically.
In Sahaja Yoga, we dont have any punishments.
Here, we have to accept human beings as they are.
There are no confessions, and no physical or mental punishments.
At the most, we can ask them to get out of Sahaja Yoga.
As this Power lies in the sacrum bone, it's your own.
She is your Mother, your individual Mother.
She knows all about you
and She is very anxious to give you your second birth.
It is in the real sense of the word
[that] you have to have your second birth.
It is not just a make-believe that you are twice born.
It becomes like any other brand like you are a Christian
or a Hindu or a Muslim or a twice born.
But anybody can commit any sin.
Anybody can commit any sin.
So one has to become innately righteous,
innately moral.
It's only possible when you become the Spirit.
When this Kundalini rises, She passes through six centers
which are responsible for our physical, mental,
emotional, and spiritual being.
Thus, our physical being improves,
or sometimes absolutely in perfect condition.
In India there are four doctors from Delhi university
who have got their MD in Sahaja Yoga.
Many incurable diseases can be cured with Sahaja Yoga.
For diagnosis or for treatment, you don't have to go to hospitals
because you know self-knowledge.
You get self-knowledge
because you start feeling on your fingertips your own centers.
You start feeling this all-pervading Power on your fingertips.
So, this is the second truth that you have to know
that there is an all-pervading Power of divine Love.
In the Koran, Mohammed Saab has clearly said that
when you will get your resurrection,
your hands, your fingers will know about you
and they will tell you about you.
This is the time of your resurrection.
I call it a blossom time, but in the Bible it is described as the last judgement.
You have to choose; you are free to choose.
If you want to go to hell, you can go.
If you want to go to heaven, you can go.
From the day you get your realization,
you start the transformation within yourself.
In the light of the Spirit, you become your own guide,
your own master.
You give up everything that is destructive.
You give up everything that is not for your progress.
All bad habits drop out automatically.
And these bad habits just remove all the diseases,
all the destructiveness from your body.
Its like this: if I am holding a snake, and there is darkness
and I cant see, and I am obstinate,
I am not going to believe if you tell me its a snake.
And unless and until the snake bites, I won't give it up.
But if there is little light, even little light,
immediately I will throw away the snake on my own.
That is why enlightenment is the most important thing.
If you want to save the world,
it is important that we should take to our enlightenment
and give enlightenment to others.
As a result of this, your attention becomes absolutely innocent,
devoid of lust and greed.
Innocence is an eternal thing,
but we have covered it with some clouds.
It is never destroyed,
and it comes back as soon as you get your enlightenment.
So your attention becomes not only innocent
but very powerful and active.
Wherever you put attention, it acts.
Such a person emits joy and peace.
Then you know the absolute Truth.
That means everybody knows the same truth.
Supposing if you have ten children who are realized souls
and tie their eyes, and ask them what is wrong with this person,
they will all lift the same fingers.
So in our awareness, a new dimension is created
called as vibratory awareness.
Many people don't believe in God. But if you want to know,
you just put your hands and ask, Is there God?
And immediately you start getting tremendous cool breeze in your hands.
And if you, say, want to find out was Christ the son of God,
you just find out. And it is true because you get the cool breeze.
But if there is falsehood, if there is a false master,
you can immediately make it out because you get heat,
sometimes pins and needles.
Everybody knows the same.
Then the greatest thing that happens to you
[is] that you become collectively conscious.
Because you can feel the vibrations of another person,
and you can feel the chakras, the centers of another person also.
Then who is the other?
Like a microcosm becomes the macrocosm.
Microcosm becomes a macrocosm.
Like a drop becomes the ocean.
And such love, pure love and compassion flows in them.
Then you understand the value of another person also,
and also your own value.
But you become humble.
You can give realization to others. You can cure others.
That is how one enlightened light can enlighten other lights.
It's a natural process.
Just like a seed. If you put it in the Mother Earth,
it sprouts by itself.
Because in the seed it is built in to sprout
and it is in the Mother Earth the power is there to sprout.
This is how everything is built in within you.
It is spontaneous, means Sahaj.
Means it is born with you, this right to have this union, yoga,
with this divine Power.
When we think, we think about the past or the future.
We cannot be in the present which is the reality.
We think about the future and past,
and we cannot be in reality, which is the present.
Because the past is finished [and] the future doesn't exist.
But when this Kundalini rises, She elongates these thoughts
and establishes the silence in between them.
That time you become absolutely thoughtlessly aware.
You are aware but you are thoughtless.
You want to think, you can think. You don't want to think,
you need not think.
But inspirations start coming.
This state is the state of peace within yourself.
You become a witness of the whole drama,
and you become extremely peaceful within yourself.
There is no stress, there is no strain.
You become so free of all these things.
Actually, you become your own master.
Last of all, the greatest thing that happens to you
[is] that you jump into the ocean of joy.
When you are happy or unhappy, these are two sides of a coin.
When your ego is pampered, you are happy;
when it is punctured, you are unhappy.
But joy is singular.
And it's a state in which you transcend all these limitations
of your conditionings.
For example, we have huge gatherings in India
of people who have become saints
and it is surprising [that] I have never seen them quarreling,
fighting, nothing of the kind.
It's a state in which you realize your importance,
your glory and the glory of others.
Its all your own.
It's all within you.
This power, what we call Kundalini, is in the sacrum bone
that means the Greeks knew it was a sacred bone.
Now this power of yours is the power of pure desire.
All other desires are not pure.
Today we ask for a house, we get it. Then we try to get a car,
then we want to have a helicopter, then an aeroplane
I mean there is no end to it.
It is not satiable.
In general, they say, wants are not satiable.
Economics says so.
So whether you are aware or not aware,
this power of pure desire in within you.
And once you get connected with this all-pervading Power,
all your problems get solved.
Even economic
[and] political.
Because most of the world problems come from human beings.
And all the human problems come from these chakras,
from these centers.
If these centers are somehow or other corrected,
the whole world can be a beautiful place to live in.
By talking about peace or having organizations of peace,
you cannot have peace.
I have known people who have got awards in peace
and [are] absolutely very hot tempered, very.
They never even smile. They never even smile.
And if you have to approach them, it is better to go through a barge pole.
I dont know how they get peace awards.
You have to have peace within.
In this short lecture I dont think I can tell you everything about it.
But like in this beautiful hall you have so many lights.
Only you have to switch on, thats all.
But if I go on telling you about the history of this electricity,
how it came here, it is so boring.
So why not get it, enlightenment?
It is so easy.
You cant pay for it, you must understand this.
God doesn't understand money.
He doesn't understand banking that's our headache.
I don't know how people can sell God in the market.
Its all right [that] you can pay for this hall, all right.
But not for your Realization.
It will hardly take 15 minutes for you to get your Realization.
You are feeling warm, but after that you will feel very cool.
But as I said, I cannot force on you.
If you don't want, I cannot do it.
So those who do not want to have, have to go out.
It is not mental; it is beyond the mind.
So even My lecture is just an introduction,
but it is not the happening.
Happening is the actualization,
I would say the actualization of your baptism.
It's the experience, it is not just talking.
And you all can have this experience,
not at all difficult.
You dont have to think about it, just it will work automatically.
There is no problem of any kind that you will face.
I feel Brazil can do very well in Sahaja Yoga
because people are faithful and simple-hearted.
As in Russia I found they have no conditioning of any kind.
At least 65 to 70% people are very sensitive to spirituality.
The rest are stupid I must say.
They are taking to American culture of Coca-Cola and all that.
They want Marlboro cigarettes.
In Russia, in one place called Togliatti,
we have got about 21.000 Sahaja Yogis.
And also the government is very good there, I mean the universities.
They have thrown away all other false gurus from there, everyone.
Surprisingly, they awarded Me
the award of the St. Petersburg university,
which was the oldest university,
as the honorary academician which were only ten so far.
I am the tenth.
And one of them is Einstein.
One of them is Enstein.
I was quite surprised, you know. So I said,
Why do you include Me with Einstein? He was such a great scientist.
So they said that, Mother, what Einstein has done
is only on the matter. You are working on human beings.
So they have given Me such a high award.
I said, I am not doing anything. Actually, they have their own powers,
and they are getting awakened to it. What am I doing about it?
I don't know.
But they are very sensitive people. There were 2000 scientists
in that conference.
They dont have much conditionings.
I think they are people who are like clean slate.
- Like? - Like clean slate,
Clean slate, on which we write, clean slate.
And it has worked really wonders there.
So, I would request those who do not want to have
their Self Realization should leave the hall
because it is not proper to disturb in-between.
But after Realization,
one should not sort of get dissolved into that and do not grow.
Because it is in the beginning you will feel really on top of the world.
But you have to grow.
You have to grow in the collective.
You cannot grow in your houses or your homes, or in your rooms.
But you don't have to give up anything.
You don't have to go to Himalayas and stand on your heads
or go to Gobi Desert to get nirvana.
Here, on your seats, you will get your Realization.
Don't have to give up your family, don't have to give up anything.
You don't have to change your dress or anything.
In Chicago I met a gentleman, the head of the Hare Rama.
He was wearing a dhoti, what we wear in India, a dhoti.
Specially that day it was very cold in Chicago.
I said, Why do you wear a dhoti in this cold? Its terribly cold.
As a mother, I feel concerned.
He said, My guru has initiated me like this.
I said, Do you think that by wearing this dhoti
you will get your nirvana?
80% people in India wear dhotis and go on saying,
Hare Rama, hare Krishna. Are they all going to get nirvana?
I mean if they all go to heaven, where will you be?
It is the internal change that is needed, not outward.
I think you all are intelligent people, and you will understand
what I am saying.
We don't have any organization.
We don't have any priesthood. We have no hierarchies.
Nothing of the kind. Everybody is equally the same.
I have no secretary. I travel every day, practically.
Tomorrow I am going to Sao Paulo and then I am going to other places.
Everyday practically I am travelling.
But I don't think I am travelling. I don't think.
I will be 72 years of age [but] I dont feel tired.
I am the same because I feel tremendous love for all of you.
That compels Me to travel.
And that love itself is so nourishing
and so joy giving.
Same thing you all can have.
You all can have the same powers.
These are your potential things which you must get.
Now, this mother Kundalini, She knows everything about you.
Like a tape recorder, She has taped everything. She knows you.
She knows what mistakes you have committed,
She knows what are your aspirations, She knows you.
So please dont judge yourself.
She knows and She is anxious to give you your second birth.
So just understand
that you should not feel at all in any way diffident.
You must have complete respect for yourself.
That means you should not feel guilty at all.
This is the first condition that
please don't feel guilty about anything that has happened in the past.
Past is finished, we are in the present.
So this is a very important condition because if you feel guilty,
the center on the left-hand side is in jeopardy.
So you may get Spondylitis, you may get Angina,
you may get Tuberculosis
or, could be, lethargic organs.
So what is the use of feeling guilty
and troubling yourself like this?
The second condition is that you have to forgive everyone
even without thinking about them.
As this center is caught up,
the Kundalini cannot rise above this center.
Whether you forgive or you don't forgive, you don't do anything.
It is a myth.
Because if you don't forgive, then you play into wrong hands
and torture yourself.
Specially at this moment.
The center on the optic chiasma is like this, absolutely constricted.
And if you don't forgive, it won't open out.
And at this moment,
you will miss the great opportunity of Self Realization
because Kundalini won't be able to pass through that center.
Also, don't think about people whom you have to forgive
because it is a very painful, I think, sometimes.
You get a headache.
In general, you have to forgive.
The third condition is very simple. You have to take out your shoes.
In England, first time I said please take out your shoes,
so half the people walked off.
You have been already told about the subtle centers
and the channels that we have within ourselves.
So now we have two powers  left and right.
The left one is the power of desire,
the right one is the power of action.
Is a mundane desire,
everyday desire.
Now, so those who are sitting on the chair,
not those who are sitting on the ground they are all right,
have to put both their feet apart from each other.
And put the left hand on your left lap, that's all.
And we have to nourish our centers with our right hand.
Only for tonight we have to do, is not to be repeated.
Now we will show you what is to be done,
is to put the left hand like this, which symbolizes that
you desire to have your Self Realization.
All right. So please put the left hand like this.
Now the right hand you have to put it first on your heart
because in the heart resides the Spirit.
If you become the Spirit, you become your own guide,
your own master.
So, we work only on the left-hand side.
Put your right hand on the upper portion of your abdomen
on the left-hand side.
This is the center of your mastery
created by great prophets and seers.
Now you take your right hand in the lower portion of your abdomen
on the left-hand side.
This is the center, surprisingly, is of pure divine Knowledge.
Now you take your right hand to the upper portion
of your abdomen again.
Then take it on your heart.
And then in the corner of your neck and your shoulder
and turn your head to your right.
This center is not all right. Please don't feel guilty.
Now, take your right hand on top of your forehead across like this
and bend your head slowly.
Now take back your right hand on the back side of your head
and push back your head.
Without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes,
you have to ask for forgiveness from the divine Power.
Now the last center is important. Stretch your palm as far as possible.
Now put the center of your palm on top of the fontanelle bone area
which was a soft bone in your childhood.
Now push back your fingers as far as possible.
Now please put down your head.
Here you have to move your scalp slowly seven times clockwise.
Please push back your fingers otherwise there will be no pressure.
And bend your heads please.
Please move it seven times.
That's all we have to do.
Now we will start by closing our eyes.
Please don't open your eyes until and unless I tell you.
Please put your feet apart from each other
and let hand on your left lap.
And put your right hand on your heart.
You can take out your spectacles and close your eyes.
Please don't open till I tell you.
Here resides the Spirit.
So you have to ask a fundamental question
about yourself three times to Me.
You can call Me Mother or Shri Mataji, whatever you feel like.
So please say it three times in your heart, "Mother", ask the question,
Mother, am I the Spirit?
I have told you already that if you become the Spirit,
you become your own guide, your own master.
So now please take your right hand in the upper portion
of your abdomen on the left-hand side and press it with your fingers.
Here you ask Me another question in your heart,
very fundamental, about yourself.
Please ask, Mother, am I my own master?
I've already told you that I respect your freedom
and I cannot force on you your Self Realization.
In the same way, I cannot force pure divine Knowledge on you.
So please take down your right hand in the lower portion
of your abdomen on the left-hand side.
Here you have to say again I mean you have to ask six times
because the center has got six petals.
So ask six times,
Mother, please give me pure divine Knowledge.
This is the knowledge about the science of divine Laws,
which you get spontaneously, automatically on your nerves.
As soon as you ask the question for divine Knowledge,
the Kundalini starts rising upward.
So you have to nourish the upper centers
with your full self-confidence.
So now raise your right hand in the upper portion
of your abdomen on the left-hand side and press it hard.
Here you have to say ten times with full confidence,
Mother, I am my own master.
I've already told you that you are not this body, this mind,
this intellect, these emotions, these conditionings, this ego,
but you are the pure Spirit.
So now raise your right hand on top of your heart
and here you have to say again with full self-confidence.
Say it will full confidence, Mother, I am the pure Spirit.
That you are, have faith in it and say it,
Mother, I am the pure Spirit.
This all-pervading Power of divine Love
is the ocean of knowledge and bliss.
It is the ocean of energy of compassion and love.
But above all, it is the ocean of forgiveness
and whatever mistakes you might have committed
can be easily dissolved
by the power of this ocean of compassion and forgiveness.
You must have faith in yourself.
So, forgive yourself and put your hand, right hand
in the corner of your neck and your shoulder
and turn your head to your right.
Now, with full confidence you have to say sixteen times,
Mother, I am not guilty at all. Have confidence.
I have already told you that
whether you forgive or don't forgive, you don't do anything.
But if you don't forgive, then you play into wrong hands
and torture yourself.
Specially at this moment if you don't forgive,
the center of Agnya won't open and your Kundalini
will not be able to penetrate.
So now raise your hand to your forehead across
and put down your head as far as possible.
Here you have to say again with self-confidence,
but not how many times from your heart,
Mother, I forgive everyone in general.
Now without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes,
just for your satisfaction,
you have to ask forgiveness from this all-pervading divine Power.
So now please raise your right hand on the back side of your head
and push back your head as far as possible.
Here you have to say, again from your heart,
not how many times,
just for your justification,
without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes,
Oh Divine Power, if I have done any mistakes, please forgive them.
Now the last center as I said is very important.
You have to stretch your palm fully and
put the center of your palm on top of the fontanelle bone area,
which was a soft bone in your childhood.
Now stretch back your fingers as far as possible
and please put down your head as far as possible.
With a pressure you have to move
your scalp seven times clockwise slowly.
Here again I cannot force Self Realization on you.
So you have to ask for it saying seven times while moving your hand,
Mother, please give me my Self Realization.
Now please take down your hand.
Slowly open your eyes.
Put both the hands towards Me like this
and watch Me without thinking.
Now put the right hand towards Me like this
and put down your head, and with the left hand
try to see if there is a cool or hot breeze like vibrations
coming out of your fontanelle bone area.
Now, please put the left hand.
Also, bend your head, it is important.
Now again see with the right hand.
Not on top of your head, away from your fontanelle bone.
If there is a cool or a hot breeze like vibrations coming.
Sometimes they are cool, sometimes they are hot.
They could be close or away.
But if you have not forgiven yourself or others,
you get the hot breeze.
So now again please try to forgive everyone, yourself also.
Now please put again your right hand towards Me
and see with the left hand.
You have to move your hand because sometimes it is far,
sometimes it is closer.
It is coming out of your fontanelle bone area,
so please have faith in yourself.
Please bend your head, bend your head, otherwise.
Now please put both your hands towards the sky like this,
push back your head.
Now, here you can ask one of these three questions three times,
one of them.
The first one is, Mother, is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?
Ask three times.
Second one is, Mother, is this the all-pervading Power of divine Love, Ruh?
The third one is, Mother, is this the Paramachaitanya?
Ask any one of these three times.
This is the first time you are feeling the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost.
Now please bring down your hands.
All those who have felt
cool breeze on the fingertips,
or may be hot,
same on the palms
or out of their fontanelle bone area,
please raise both your hands.
What do you say to that?
I bow to you all.
Most of you have become saints now, so I bow to you.
Please put down your hands.
All those who have felt the cool breeze,
this all-pervading Power of divine Love, have to grow into it.
Some of you may not have felt.
Maybe something physically, mentally wrong with you,
maybe spiritually.
Or maybe you are thinking too much.
Or maybe you did not forgive,
you do not forgive yourself and others.
Whatever it is,
everything can be corrected.
Respect your Realization
and grow into it.
Most surprising thing is that when I come,
so many of you come here and get your Realization.
But I am a foreigner, I am an Indian
and you trust Me so much.
But we have here very beautiful Sahaja Yogis.
They will not take any money and you can grow.
They'll tell you all about it,
complete knowledge.
So when I go away, you should not just give up, you have to grow.
Otherwise, it would be like the parable of Christ that
some seeds fell on the barren land
and some on the marshy land which just sprouted and were finished.
It's a very great responsibility
that you are born in this special time.
Then you have got your Realization.
And it's only you, the enlightened ones,
who can save the world.
Make the world beautiful for your children.
So please understand your own worth and value.
Now, please know your identity that
you have entered into the kingdom of God.
Life would be full of blessings.
But please grow and give it to others.
Have faith in yourself.
My message is, now enjoy yourself and enjoy others.
May God bless you all.
Thank you very much. Thank you.