any other question please
just be little loudly can you say loudly
please
looking
why don't we
why you don't like it I said something
here is a question really is something I
can't understand
you see if I have something if this
picture is my true picture then why not
have it in this picture you will be
surprised the person who first got
realization got through this picture in
this picture there are vibrations when
you will get realized you will know that
only this picture has such vibrations it
was a real thing it is thank God the
science has given us the real thing if
there were cameras before we would have
had pictures of all those great people
because there were no photographs they
said better not have any pictures
because all the pictures were imaginary
done by people who wanted to have
someone with this picture
many people have been cured all right
it's a very good thing that has happened
that we can take pictures now because I
think I cannot meet everyone in this
world but they cannot see my picture I
do not claim i doing no question of
blaming you see I do it have done it you
can do it don't you everyone can be this
dr. Warren Delta it's not so many people
yes it is surprisingly low myself I was
surprised that you are
that's my photograph has also got
reservations and people get cured before
the glass in your country maybe when I
gave the press was very kind to the
reason was there was a lady who was sick
with coma as I said she had what love
cerebral aneurysm and once another
disciple of mine
to fight photogram put it under her head
and she started getting all right in the
sense that she started opening her eyes
so the doctor got frightened they said
if even if she gets all right she will
be damaged she won't be able to follow
but today she's perfect all right not
really bad but she is very hard work
from the photograph from the photograph
the photograph is a real image of myself
see and this fine body has got a
positions which aim it's working same
happens with the photograph that too has
the same coefficients of course it
hasn't got the other dimension but it
also emits the vibrations because of the
coefficients being the same say even if
you take prize photograph it's not real
because it's all come out of the
unconscious all right but just got a
free Majan Asian put it any photographic
tape of any person it is like that but
there are so many things I've seen which
are which have come out of the mother
earth
they emit vibrations like Stonehenge in
England has vibrations so many places
like that have aggression but not so
strong as mine because I am a living
person there was one fellow in
Rasha supposed to be very intelligent he
said that all right if we keep mother's
photograph and also the icons we can get
the same type of vibration you cannot
because icons are made by some artists
imaginary these are not representing
actually even Maria or Christ or anyone
they are all all imaginary if an Italian
ones makes Christ his Italian stuff he's
somebody French one makes is thin like
Frenchmen if you get us somebody say
from Holland he'll ever forehead like
that so you can see Christ if she's
Japanese
he'll have [ __ ] eyes
if he is Chinese she'll have no nose if
it's Indian he'll be down so all kinds
of crisis II and I feel that how can
they emit vibrations till while with my
photograph how can you come back also
cameras were to be developed at this
time you noticed that one cameras were
developed at this time not before that
this loudspeaker was not developed
before this so all these things are even
video even the way you are seeing my
image there was that available before No
so this is a very special time where
science has also supported seekers to
find it
science has so first just like a
scientist to try to accept one by
whether there's nothing has to be done I
mean don't have to pay me anything of
course that good you don't have to do
any acrobatics or anything but for
example a small thing like my photograph
you see many people say why your
photograph so use your photograph I say
if that works out you see is something
surprising that's how people you
challenge me why your photograph is if I
not use yours I will be very happy use
anybody's but doesn't work out what to
do now it's mine photograph that works
out but even if you don't like it you
have to use it what can I do
it's as simple that's bad you see but in
that I don't gain anything from you I
don't want anything from you nothing
material that you can give me but you
will enjoy you'll enjoy my laugh you
will enjoy but surge or by realization
how is it going to work it was a very
big problem for me it's not that I can
just give you a book and you just sit
and read it and say that yes I have got
it I become it's real becoming ripening
maturing living process now how am I to
do
and here is the answer is a photograph
so this is what it is that all your
media's can be used through my
photograph what a blessing and the
photograph if you think is representing
me I think you're not expressing it
fully
that was a main session my photograph
are much more powerful than any sketches
together even to these by mother earth
because photograph has got so many
elements in it for example you see it
has got light element it has got water
element it has got earth element it has
got also air element if the air is not
alright little bit
and also it has got the eternally
with all these five elements you cannot
reduce the statute
ether element it has got because if you
have a photograph here you can
constantly transmit it but you cannot
transmit the statue as it is only the
photograph of a statue thing so it has
also got ether in it so photograph is
much more powerful than any other statue
moreover it is a reproduction
no but reproduction of reality with five
enemies so I wouldn't call it just a
representative it's quite me because my
attention is there so the protocol of
these photographs also is important so
start developing that faith you should
keep one photograph with you all the
time in your pocket respective
as many as possible respective