For ascent it’s not a mental procedure,
it’s a procedure of the heart which is thanksgiving.
Look at the flowers,
they are
giving thanks to God.
The whole being is nothing but thanksgiving!
Not worried, they are being plucked, they
will die tomorrow – not worried.
As long as they live it’s giving thanks.
Look at everything, look at this candle, what
is it?
Is thanksgiving.
Everything that is created is giving thanks.
What about us human beings?
We say, because we can say it, they cannot
say.
It doesn’t have words to say.
We have language, that’s how we have become
superficial,
we have lost our depth because we have language.
There is no language for the silent expression.