is
understanding and invite otherwise you
will be wasting
[Music]
I wonder how many give me that Vista is
the center of gravity
which uses the welcome all which will
rotate by which we realize that we are
inclined left or just other night this
twelve
we have to be aware of
because otherwise
[Music]
because if you Center it healthy and are
succeeding
completely so this to me is specific
between you understanding
I'm the understanding
waste it has to be helped
it
the newborn during his nine five
children
one has
it works Edom you are testing instrument
so if you try to do something of your
own something too much
[Music]
for example if Emily says that whatever
is there a ninja but not before
[Music]
because our genes
in nature to see
wonderful what she doesn't she doesn't
she made itself up damages a lot to me
I got the wisdom it's the one
it is I carry the state of you in when
you because it
[Music]
outside the gyroscope
evidently
only the personality which is a phenom
if you're frustrated it's if you're
unhappy so count your blessings
[Music]
extreme predictions
but in one spirit
[Music]
I think positions try to stabilize mr.
logically what do we
this one in happy camper
except for you will you study
development university but example now
we are seeing it's not be not be near
life
[Music]
when you in this position so we see the
quality the best and that is whether
religion
so how wisdom is important that you even
become a star chief your wisdom you know
how it is only when you have done focal
points and just leave your Center
that's
when people tell me about someone as if
it was the another ball
then you more listen to another site
they paint another Oracle Jones
if he leaves two pictures find the one
is reflecting the other
there's no entry is determined for this
how do you end up
you live by your wisdom by understanding
itself in you may think is the mirror on
which is reflected it's just an illusion
that is appearing and we are very about
holy you gave me profound as soon as you
just see the winner
I don't worry about equations
they
there is a relative quality are all the
refrigerants arguments that's how with
this all this
a little
[Music]
wisdom lies only sea floatie what are we
here we are are they moving with our
divisor of getting ourselves to survive
with all these artificial decided
teacher that says that you are this you
are that you are not a person it's a
fertility and told many times that you
are receipts on you of you see now what
will you see is and once your itself
everything wisdom
which is so joy-giving time is nothing
popular is
I mean I will be on
meeting
Miss Piggy well mr. B coming up
unloving
[Music]
open your hearts hello Eurasian is that
bad business which occurs every month
everyone
who'd they hit remove my heart
[Music]
no question
they were on know
new ideas
looking about
and more
more usually do you understand that you
have
[Music]
and he was