family
whatever you do it should please me is
is one of the ways
it should please me
that's one of the signs so how do we do
it put me in your heart
just try to put me in your heart it's
very simple
i'm before you now i am in person
i was trying to give realization to one
of my relations yes
today and i said that you don't lose
your eyes he said no
i'm not looking at your face because
when i see you
i feel you are my aunt
but i'm just looking at your feet so
that
i shouldn't feel any more that you are
my aunt
you are very great and your face is the
one that puts me into illusions
he could see it's a mahamaya he said
only at your feet
i look and through your feet only
i can get over this barrier this feeling
in the same way when i am a mahamaya i
know i am i had to be
but you have to put my
feet into your heart
just by feet into your heart
because photo face everything
might be an illusion
might be by seeing my face you do not
get over your barriers
to say i must see mother i must do this
mother must come to my house she must
have food at my place
she must visit my home all this is so
stupid i cannot understand what's the
matter with these people
mother please come in my heart let me
clean my heart
so that you are there put your feet into
my heart
let your feet be worshipped in my heart
let me not be in delusion
take me away from illusions
keep me in reality take away the sheen
of superficiality let me
enjoy your feet in my heart
let me see your feet in my heart
only such people
even brahma vishnu mahesha have done
that
so don't you think you have to do it
so humble down yourself humble down
yourself
in your heart humble down in your
heart enjoy your humility enjoy your
virtues
the greatest virtue of sahaja yogi is
humility
now so many things you have seen
to convince you but in no way it can
mean
any kind of subjection
because what subjection you can give me
think of that
when every subjection is a blessing what
subjection you are giving
every feeling in the heart is a blessing
just just now you feel it and you feel
the joy
in your heart
then what is your subjection about what
i can understand people who are just
newly calm or good for nothing
just but you are not on the periphery
but some of them do go into periphery in
no time you give them some work
finish if i am sweet to someone finished
if i see someone finished i mean this is
too much
i can't even be nice to you
if you do any mistakes or anything then
you feel
then you get your left visually
you've done your mistake or not finish
it you love me
maybe there's something wrong in the
love or maybe something has happened
doesn't matter
now i'm going to be cautious
i'm not going to make any mistakes how
could i
do this mistake because i i was not
fully in love
if i had loved something i would have
not done such a mistake
all right so develop your love no you
will do
i feel guilty because i have done such a
thing
so you miss this and that both so your
mistake becomes a barrier again
don't feel guilty about it we have to
progress further forget the past
forget the past forget the past we have
to go further we have to be serious
people
when we talk we should talk with that
dignity of that
or
that's very important and once you
develop that all your ekadasha will
disappear
ekadasha will disappear just think of
the awe
the silence and the joy and the
the joy of the
o is deep very deep like a sea
see on superficial level is very
turbulent but inside is
silent absolutely silent feel
that depth without all you cannot go
down