I hope you all are meditating every morning
and talking Sahaja Yoga, meeting each
other,
and this is more to get together that we
should all discuss about Sahaja Yoga
and find out what is the way we can do it
better.
Morning time I was thinking that we can
allot it now to people
who would like to have a sort of a,
they call it a brain trust sort of a thing,
a conference. You could have it.
Of course, day after tomorrow we are all
very free. I’m sorry,
tomorrow is the Puja but day after tomorrow
we are free in the morning time
and also ninth we are free. So you all
could discuss and talk about things
and about what has happened in Satara
district
and all those things can be discussed among
all of you and it can be established
that we understand Sahaja Yoga properly
among ourselves.
Many people do not know much about
Sahaja Yoga, especially ladies.
I think they have to know quite a lot.
They just think they are in Sahaja Yoga;
so they are floating
with the big flow of water. That’s not
the way to know about Sahaja Yoga.
Sahaja Yoga you must know precisely, must
know what is,
what is there, what is not there. So I
would say that you could have a meeting
tomorrow sometime or, I’m sorry, day after
tomorrow, sometime
and could discuss about what is it and how
it helps you,
what are the chakras are, any problems,
anything. We have all kinds of people here.
So it should not be just entertainment
but it should be
more sort of a morning session for learning
things.
We have, now tomorrow is a very important
day for Puja.
All of you are expected to come here for
the Puja
and I’m sure that it will help you all
to achieve something in that Puja.
As it is, you know that you have to go
beyond your thoughts
to absorb the vibrations. In your thoughts
you get lost.
but once you are above the thoughts you
get absorbed.
Also most of the marriages have been fixed.
But some people unnecessarily
giving way to their conditionings or maybe
unnecessary thinking and all that
have tried to say “No” to certain people
without any rhyme and reason,
without any rhyme and reason. So it is
nonsense.
And such people, I would say, that should
not apply anymore
because we have wasted so much time. Of
course, if they had some rhyme and reason
one can understand but without rhyme and
reason if you say,
“We don’t want to marry,” that mean it’s
quite insulting to the other party.
So if you have just said “No” because you
feel it from your heart
and from your brain and from your these
things, this is not the way to behave.
And before saying “No” you should see Me
and I would request you, all of you,
to meet your fiancés and see for yourself.
Even now there is time.
But if there is no reason for saying “No”,
if there is no understanding about any
point,
it is better to decide it now than to decide
it later. Now I’ve been telling you.
Of course, you have all the freedom
to do it.
But for no rhyme and reason you have no
business to insult other people.
So I would request you that even if you
have any objections, even now,
please write it down and give it to Yogi
Mahajan.
He has really worked very hard and you know
we have no choices.
You see, it is very funny how so many
marriages have come up. I didn’t expect
even to fix ten marriages,  because the age
and the heights
and everything was so much from one
extreme to another extreme.
Moreover, those ladies who have got
children and all that, it’s rather difficult
because we find people who are not very
happy about the situation.
So they should not feel bad about it.
We hope to see people
who would love to have children. All such
people should come forward
and they should marry women who have
children and look after them.
But it’s difficult. In the same way for men
also, if they have
some children or something, there is
a problem.
But one should not feel bad about it.
One should know that we are here
for our Sahaja Yoga, for our ascent, and we
have to rise higher.
As it is, you know, one or two marriages
do fail in Sahaja Yoga
and they create lot of problems for Me. But
is this the way are you helping Me?
I am helping you in so many ways. Which
is the way are you going to help Me
is to understand that if we are married
let us try to improve ourselves.
Of course, I would say that certain
problems come only from one side,
not from both the sides, but whatever it is
we have to understand that these marriages
are not just for marriages
but for something great, to create a new
progeny of realized souls,
to emancipate human beings. There are many
saints who want to be born on this earth.
So it is important that if you are married
in that understanding
then you will try to see to the good points
of others and not the bad points,
and should not see superficial things.
If you are superficial it is better you
don’t marry.
But if you have any depth then you should
understand you are marrying for something
that is the concern of God’s work.
I hope by this you’ll be able to sort out
many of your problems.
And then some people when they get married
they just get headlong,
absolutely get lost into it. This is the
another stupid conditioning of romanticism.
You have married because you are in Sahaja
Yoga, you want to help the Sahaj Yoga,
you would like to have a companion who
will be helpful in Sahaja Yoga.
But they get so headlong into it that I’ve
seen many characters have been ruined
and people have been spoilt. But in a way
it’s good because this is Last Judgment.
If by marriage, by temptations, by wrong
doings, by conditionings,
if you have to go out, you have to go out.
I must tell you that also there’s very
little place in the kingdom of God.
Unless and until you prove to be good
Sahaja Yogis there is no place for you.
For mediocres there is no place. You have
to be serious, deep,
seeking, dedicated Sahaja Yogis. Otherwise
you have no place.
If you are playing around only with your
children, with your wife,
then all right; go ahead with it. You have
to get out of that
and you must know that my first and
foremost attention should be on Sahaja Yoga.
That is so very important today.
Formerly, that’s why people used to give
sanyasa to their disciples.
No marriage, no children, no household.
Just be sanyasis.
So complete dedication to the guru,
complete dedication to the work.
But in Sahaja Yoga it is not so. Because
also I have given you realization
so you can feel it within yourselves what
is important.
If something goes wrong with you then
the vibrations also go down.
Then also I have reports, say, from many
countries that people are very miserly.
They do not donate for daily work.
Of course, you don’t have to pay Me
but you must know that without donation
we cannot do anything,
you cannot even buy a little thing like
that, and from where it has to come?
Of course, as far as possible I’ve tried
to compensate
but also you must know my husband is now
retiring.
So I hope the whole, with his retirement,
the whole of Sahaja Yoga will not collapse.
If you are such miserly people, only
worried about your money,
you want to extract each and every pie you
spend, each and every
little money you have given, then I must say
such people are no good for Sahaja Yoga.
Such calculating people, nobody wants
to shell out.
I mean, I’ve seen people, even if they give
a little bottle of, say, Limca to someone,
they want to charge it. If you are that
miserly
there is no place for miserly people
in the kingdom of God.
You have to be generous, you have to look
after people, you have to love each other,
you have to give presents to others and you
have to be very much giving.
And in this I find that people will live in
a good house, they’ll have a good family,
they will spend on their children, for
their holidays, for their education,
for everything. But Sahaja Yoga, they
become very miserly.
So they are still so conditioned. So this
is the Last Judgment.
And you will be judged for everything
that you do for Sahaja Yoga.
Is one has to be very careful as to how
you behave,
what is your attitude is and how you should
change.
Your attention is also very important,
if your attention is not there.
I’ve seen some people still sitting
outside, talking to people, doing this.
In between the program they just get up
and walk off.
When there’s an, some, some artist is
sitting you are not to go like that.
It’s an insult to the artist. I, I just sit
for hours together.
And if I am supposed to be your Guru, you
must learn at least that much from Me,
how to respect and where to respect. So
I have seen many people just getting up,
walking, sleeping down, this, that. If you
are that kind
then you should sit on the corner and just
disappear.
Nobody should walk this way back and this
way. It’s not proper.
There should be, if you go to your church,
do you do like that?
Church which is based on falsehood?
While this is the church of truth.
And the way people take things without
any discipline looks very funny.
People start walking up and down, sitting
the way they like.
There’s no alertness about them.
This is all…
You must know when the music is on,
I am trying to spread
vibrations through that music. But some
people are dozing off.
Some people are walking about. That is not
a Sahaja Yogi.
You have to be just Spartan and smart.
Like any, if you see a saint, you see,
if you see old saints we had,
their disciples used to be sitting straight
before him for hours together.
Of course, I don’t say that you should sit
here hours together
but if I am sitting here you have no
business to behave like this dog
that runs about without knowing what
he’s doing.
We are all human beings and there’s no,
no reasoning behind it.
I don’t understand - And there’s no
explanation needed.
It’s the behavior itself is wrong.
Now anybody who has children and all that
should sit on the other side.
I would not like you to carry your children
here and there
when there is some program is going on.
We have to show at least this much
of discipline.
So yesterday’s program was a little bit
a farce, perhaps maybe because
some people really behaved in a manner
that they should not have behaved.
All such people who want to go like that
should wait
because in between the program we’ll give
you some interval when you can go out.
So let us have a society, a proper
beautifully built-up collectivity which
shows that we are very saintly people.
We have poise, we have adjustments, we have
understanding,
we are doing everything in such a manner
that it is all dignified.
Now also some people have a bad habit
of raising their Kundalini
in the program, suddenly giving bandhans,
giving bandhans to themselves, bandhans
to others. Is nonsense.
Just now I am there. You don’t have to.
Just you desire.
You just try to develop your desire power
and just desire.
You desire something; it will work out.
I mean, I work like that and you should
learn this trick, how to desire.
But desire should be pure desire. Then
Kundalini works it out.
I was in Kolhapur and I was telling him,
our Yogi Mahajan,
I want to buy those chimtas for the,
for the,
we should say all the countries, western
countries and also the leaders.
And just imagine, they said that you can’t
get them in Kolhapur.
And there they are; they have bought it
and brought it.
I mean, it’s a small incident but there are
thousand one things I can tell you.
I have to just desire. I desired that
the Eastern bloc
must be cleared out, must be freed.
So a program of Sahaja Yoga, of what you
call the Yoga seminar, was held in Russia.
And I told My husband and I told everyone,
“I’m going there
to break the Eastern bloc.” I just told.
When I went there they gave Me hardly
any time.
But I broke it because the people who got
realization,
they were from all these countries and they
just went and triggered it.
So I had told beforehand that this is
My purpose
but I am so intensely desiring anything;
in the same way if you have a pure desire
about it,
not from any, any malicious or some sort
of a selfish attitude.
Like my brother, my sister, my... this is
Indians have this greater problem…
my wife, this, that. The wife will support
the husband,
the husband will support the wife,
nonsensical things will go on.
But by this they are really taking them
down.
And you people also should not sort
of have, because somebody
is from, say, Switzerland, Swiss people
will sit together.
It’s a very wrong thing to do. I’ve told
hundred times, nobody from the same….
Now I can see it’s even that the same thing
happening here.
English must sit together. And English have
the worst habit in this,
that they must form a group. That’s their
style, is to have their group.
So this is all is our conditioning. You see,
why I am telling you
that Sahaja Yoga is not going to benefit
by you but you have to be benefited.
So all these little, little conditionings
that you have, you just judge yourself:
“Are we doing like that?”; “Are we
sitting?”; “Am I sitting next to a Swiss?”;
“Am I sitting next to an English?”.
Run away.
And then maybe that you think you can speak
in the same language
or whatever it is. No. Let us sit away.
Then Delhi people will sit together, Bombay
people will sit together
and you ask them, “Do you know this lady?”
“No, who was she?”
“I mean, she was there.” “No, I never
met her.”
Because nobody wants to meet, nobody wants
to talk, nobody wants to know.
And it is to be understood that this is
a place of pilgrimage,
there’s no fashion show on.  And one should
not go about putting
fashionable clothes and fashionable dresses
and... Be humble about it.
This is sometimes I’m really shocked
the way people are dressing up.
It’s all right, for Pujas and all that,
you can come.
But the way people are dressed up sometimes
it’s surprising.
You are coming here, for what? For your
meditation.
So be in a simpler dress, in a simpler
attitude, in a simpler mind.
Today I have to tell you because I’ve been
noticing few things
that you are missing the point. We are
here for our ascent.
We have come all the way. Pilgrimage is
there for your ascent and for nothing else.
We are here only for our ascent, for our
joy,
for opening out ourselves. And that is
what we have to remember.
I’m your Mother. I have to tell you
the truth because it is your benevolence
that I want, that you all should become
great foundations
of Sahaja Yoga which is going to emancipate
the whole world.
Moreover, anybody who is sick need not come
to Me.
You can cure that person with it. You can
yourself cure.
This person who is a realized soul can cure
himself or herself, or you can cure.
What is the need to bring everybody to Me?
This is sick, that is sick,
that is there. No need.
Among yourselves only you can have these
things done,
and I think the doctors and all these people
can also have a little conference together,
and anybody who has problems can come and
tell them what’s the problem is.
And can be done. There’s also no need also
to have doctors.
We have some people here, very simple
people, who can help you a lot.
So among yourselves you should help and you
should learn how to do it:
how to raise the Kundalini; how to tie it
up; how to clear the chakras;
what’s wrong with you. Attention should be
how I am going to achieve it.
But the attention is not so high.
So I would request you today that you
please pay full attention to the program
and enjoy and really try to develop that
sensitivity of enjoyment.
This is just you are clinging onto something
which is not going to take you
to the Ocean of Joy. All right?
May God bless you.