After the great tour of U.K. I feel very confident
that Sahaja Yoga is taking its roots, and
you can see some of the plants coming up.
It's surprising, when I declared that it may
be the last tour I'll be doing of U.K. that
things have started working out.
Everywhere we went it was very good and successful,
specially certain places it was very miraculous.
You must have heard about the lady who would
not go out of her house, was suffering from
agoraphobia, and the press challenged us that
she should be cured because she can't go out
of the house.
And only on her photograph and treatment she
got cured, and now she's walking about, and
they have given a big report saying that the
Guru fulfills Her promise.
This is one of them and there are many things
have happened of this kind, of which you should
get the report.
I must say I found all the Sahaja Yogis very
cooperative, very alert, very helpful and
extremely progressive.
And I was happy that they are trying to come
up and improve themselves, build themselves
up, and are doing much better than what I
had expected, really.
I was very, very enamored by all of them,
and I hope that by the time it is twelve years,
we'll be all absolutely top class Sahaja Yogis
of the world.
Now today is a very great day of Raksha Bandhan,
so I have to tell you something about Raksha
Bandhan.
Before that we have to talk about the maryadas
that are to be observed by Sahaja Yogis.
One of the things I discovered here in the
West, that though we have understood the importance
of Mooladhara, which is very important and
that unless and until we re-establish our
Mooladhara fully we are not going to have
a speediest ascent.
Despite all that, still there are lingering
things you see around.
Like people start choosing their life partners
in Sahaja Yoga.
That is not allowed, that is not allowed.
You are not to spoil your ashrams, your centers,
using them for a marriage-searching society.
You must respect, this point you must respect.
If you have to marry, then you can find your
life partner outside Sahaja Yoga - to begin
with.
But if you want to marry in Sahaja Yoga, then
you should not go on searching people in Sahaja
Yoga.
Is a very dangerous thing for Sahaja Yoga
itself and for you people.
That is one thing one should never try to
do with Sahaja Yogis.
For all practical purposes you are brothers
and sisters.
And that's why I always encourage marriages
between people who belong to another country
or another centers.
As we are now having a marriage - big program
- I would say that most of the marriages which
were done like that are very successful than
the marriages that were selected and were
done.
It's very wrong to do such a thing as to arrange
your marriage with a Sahaja Yogi by yourself.
It will be dangerous.
I don't want to say anything; but it won't
turn out to be good, because it is anti-God
activity, absolutely anti-God.
You are supposed to develop your brahmacharya,
you are supposed to develop your Mooladhara.
Instead of that, if you start using a Sahaja
Yogini or a Sahaja Yogi for the selection
of your married life, it's going to be very,
very troublesome.
Your Mooladhara will not settle down.
I mean that's a very bad stroke for your development.
Because of the background and the kind of
conditioning you have had, you people don't
understand that it is important to maintain
the purity of the centers, and of every place.
So any such relationship in one city is a
very wrong thing.
It spoils everyone.
To add up to the trouble, it's a habit of
people, I have heard, that they try to tease
that "You look better together, you are nice
together."
They tease and enjoy.
It's a kind of a very perverted enjoyment
of Mooladhara, to tease others "You are looking
very nice with him, and you better marry."
It's a kind of a romantic nonsense.
Of course, for all this, yogis - they have
to have a brahmacharya.
But even if you can't have brahmacharya you
must have maryadas.
Not to tease each other and enjoy that kind
of a nonsense, when the marriage is not settled.
If marriage is settled, it is all right.
And this kills completely the joy of marriage,
because there is no curiosity left.
And many a times I find that absurd relations
are established.
Some of them are really no good.
And they will really be detrimental, and some
of them never are established.
So if they are established, they are wrong;
and if they are not established, they are
heartbreaking.
So all this kind of thing you should not do.
You have got experiences of people who married
outside and brought wonderful people to Sahaja
Yoga.
If you can do it, you should do it.
But if you have to marry Sahaja Yogis, you
should not marry them at the cost of destroying
the purity and the idealism it has.
For your own sake, for your own pleasures,
you should not spoil the name of Sahaja Yoga.
That is one thing I have seen, so I would
say that today, as it is the day of purity
between relationships, let us know that you
have to treat each other as brothers and sisters.
No such play should be followed.
Don't allow your mind to drift into this.
Because if you allow, then there's no end
to it.
As it is, you know how hard it is to bring
you back to normal.
When Christ had said, "Thou shalt not have
adulterous eyes," He didn't say it because
it was not practical.
It is quite practical for Sahaja Yogis.
And there is nothing to worry about marriages
so much.
What is so important?
So many are married and what has happened
to them.
Even with Sahaja Yoga marriage, some of them
have failed because of these bad habits.
So you better get rid of these bad habits
before marriage, because after marriage also
they go on like this, and searching for boys
and girls.
Because if these habits are not curbed before
marriage, then they go on lingering on.
So one should not try to do all these things
before marriage.
And I have seen such marriages are never,
never successful so far.
And even if they are, it is a sort of make-believe
thing.
It doesn't give real joy, it's a joyless pursuit.
Maybe in one case, may be successful; that
doesn't mean that you should take any help
from such difficult things, but have normal
marriages which are enjoyable, which have
created permanent bondages between people.
All the marriages ...
Now we have to understand the maryadas, about
which I have told you before also.
The relationships between men and women are
only pure if a certain amount of boundaries
are kept.
Like, supposing you have milk in one container
and you have got something else in another
container.
To keep the purity of one container, you have
to keep it in its bounds, in the cup.
If you allow them to mix up, if they fall
together and they mix up, then there is no
purity.
It's a simple thing like that.
One should understand that we have to understand
that how to keep our relationships in proper
respect to each other's modesty and chastity.
Now for example, there is a girl who is younger
to you.
You must keep all the distance from such a
person.
If she is much older than you, then it is
all right.
You can talk, laugh, joke - she's much older
than you.
But normally with a girl who is younger to
you, even much younger, you should try to
keep away, after all if she is a young girl;
not with the children, but still.
You must learn these things: how to maintain
a distance.
Now, there is a man who is younger to you,
then you must not have any funny ideas about
such a person - is absolutely absurd.
If some gentleman is younger to you, it is
only in perversion you do such things.
See, you should not have any funny ideas about
that person.
It's only done when there are emergencies,
when there is no possibility of a marriage,
when there are so many women or so many men
- or under perverted conditions.
We don't have none of these conditions here,
so we have to behave like normal people.
And when the proper atmosphere is given to
us, why not make use of it?
Why should we create absurd things?
Then they come out to Me saying that "Mother,
now we have decided to marry.
Let us marry."
I have to say "Yes."
To many things I don't want to say "Yes" but
But creates a very bad precedent.
Maybe that in certain cases, as an exceptional
case, I might have chosen to marry somebody
like that.
But that doesn't mean you should take things
into your hands, and just start doing things
like that, so that I'll have problems later.
Because once you do like that, then anybody
starts doing it.
It's a kind of an aggressiveness, that you
arrange something, come to Me, say.
"Mother, we want to marry."
Now what am I to say?
"All right, marry."
But it creates a problem for Me, for the rest
of the people.
They will say, "All right.
If he has married a girl who is twenty years
younger, why not I marry a girl who is thirty
years younger?"
You must understand My problems.
If you ask Me for something, "Mother, should
I do it?"
You really force Me into it.
I have to say "Yes" because I cannot be very
strict with you, because I am your Mother.
But you should be sensible what to ask Me,
how far to go.
This is the biggest maryada you have to learn.
Suddenly you will come, "Mother, should I
sit here?"
What do I say?
Should I make this gentleman sit here?
What should I say?
All right.
You yourself should not ask such a question.
Because sometimes you give undue importance
to somebody, who is "my brother," who is "my
sister" -something - and make that person
sit on My head.
Sometimes you telephone to Me, "Mother, she
would like to talk to You."
Who is she?
Is she all right?
Should we take her to Mother?
Is she capable of talking to Mother?
What is her condition?
Will she trouble Mother?
Nobody thinks about it.
So you must first establish your relationship
with Me of proper understanding that you should
not try to trouble Me.
But this is something is not yet in My hands.
I think because people do not understand what
they are doing.
So first try to see that you don't try to
take advantage of Me.
And secondly, don't try to bring people to
Me who do not deserve it.
There is no need to waste My time with them.
I have so much things to be done, so many
ideas to be formulated.
I have to work so hard.
You know, I am working harder than any one
of you, those who are doing Sahaja Yoga.
And at this age, if you try to trouble Me
like that, I don't know how to tell you that
don't you trouble Me.
In the presence of the person you will come,
you will bring the person on My head, "Oh,
that person has come from Timbuktu, and I
have brought her."
Just you do it.
It is aggressiveness only.
Please don't try to do that.
This is a wrong thing to do.
So the maryadas are to be established first
with Me, that understand that you should not
try to trouble Me at all like this.
Secondly, you must try to please Me by being
good people.
I hear that somebody is trying to be very
egoistical.
He doesn't even put on My tapes, he just gives
his own lectures.
This kind of a thing is very surprising.
How can people do like that?
Try to bring down your egos, super egos.
You must learn to please Me, Prasanna bhava
He Devi, Prasanna bhava.
(Note: Sanskrit meaning "the Goddess is to
be pleased by Her devotees") If you cannot
make the Devi Prasanna ( pleased), what will
be your achievement?
As Rustom says, I am Mahamaya.
All right, but don't you know that I am that?
So try to keep to it.
And keep that understanding that if you have
to grow, we must have proper relationship
with Mother.
And we must understand what will displease
Her the most.
"Am I pleasing Her by doing this?"
But if you force Me, "If it pleases You, we'll
do."
Then what am I to say?
"All right, go ahead."
If it pleases Me I'll just spontaneously say,
"ll right, it pleases Me.
Go ahead do it."
Like that, so many things are there that people
just try to force on Me and I say "Yes."
But I am very cunning and clever in that,
because I tell in a way that you should realize
that it is not joy giving.
All right, whatever it is.
Now the second thing is that the maryadas
of relationships between you is relationship
of pure love, of purity.
Unless and until you develop pure relationships,
you are going to be ruined.
See, this finger has to have pure relationship
with this hand.
Supposing if this finger has some dirty feelings
about this hand, it may dirty it, it may spoil
it.
In the same way, we should have extremely
pure relationships with each other.
Means, we should try to give our heart to
another person without any lust or greed in
it, that we should try to do.
Try to help each other.
I find when they feel in a lusty way, or a
greedy way attached to others - this is not
for the Sahaja Yogis, but non Sahaja Yogis
- they get so much interested in that person.
It's a very baser way of attachment.
But in Sahaja Yoga, your attachment is with
your Spirit, with your Atma.
And Atma is the purest form of our being.
We have to keep it absolutely pure.
And then the enjoyment is higher than any
romance, any marriage, any worldly thing.
It's the highest and the top-most.
First achieve that.
First of all you should arise and achieve
that.
Achieve that purity.
That is very important.
Now the relationship between the men and women:
have told you that you should not try to enter
into any bedrooms where the ladies are.
It's not proper.
Nor the women should enter into men's thing.
But it is very common.
Women should not behave in the way other women
behave.
Like, I was told in a wedding in Maharashtra
that the women went and took out all their
clothes.
I mean, that is not England; they got a shock,
you know.
Some of them lost their appetite for three,
four days.
They have never seen such women in their lifetime.
They went and took out their clothes suddenly,
all of them.
I mean, they were shocked, so much shocked
that three, four days they didn't eat their
food.
So you have no business to shock them also.
Because if you go to somebody's country, you
must know in what way they live.
It's never done; nobody becomes nude like
that.
And about twenty girls, if suddenly they become
nude, what will happen?
So the sense of shame must be developed among
men and women.
It looks nice, it looks beautiful.
It gives you an additional charm if you have
the sense of shame, a little bashfulness.
See, your Princess of Wales is regarded as
something beautiful.
She is bashful.
Her bashfulness is so natural.
That bashfulness is not there, like a - I
don't know what animal does that, but somebody
who has no shame.
I mean, I just don't know which one is that.
Everybody has a sense of shame, even animals.
So why shouldn't we have that sense of shame?
How to behave towards women, how to be ... Suddenly
there is no need to just ... I have seen one
lady going from England to India, and she
just went and put a big slap on the back of
Mr. Modi, "Hello Modi, how are you?"
And Modi got such a shock.
She did not mean, she was innocent, but that's
not the way in Sahaja Yoga we are going to
behave.
Like some sort of a debonair or some sort
of a fantastic - what you call - a modern
woman, you see.
One must understand one must have a sense
of shame.
How do you talk, even with Me they will talk
with a hand like that "Mother, You see this
thing is happening."
But there's no need to do all that, you see.
Talk in a way that is gentle and beautiful.
The other day I met a very nice taxi fellow.
And I tell you, his gestures and things were
so beautiful.
Immediately I said, "He is a realized soul."
He would not say anything without putting
his hand like this, and with his eyes down
below.
He would not say something like that, nothing
of the kind.
So sweet he was, his whole gesture.
He is an Englishman.
Brought up and bred here.
Not a single vulgar word he said.
Like one of your players was so stupid.
When Princess Anne went to meet him he said
all kinds of things, you see.
It's kind of an ego, or stupidity - I don't
know.
Because, how you talk, how you speak, everything
should be saintly.
You are saints now, do you realize?
You are all saints.
So how you behave with dignity towards each
other, how you respect their dignity, how
you live, is very important.
And that you should try to maintain in a way
that looks like a saintly behavior.
You have to be a saint.
And that is not difficult for you, to take
to that, that you behave in a manner that
you are saints.
This is very important I must tell you because
I have seen that these maryadas.
It would be killing, it would be absolutely
killing Sahaja Yoga, if you do not keep your
maryadas.
That is one of the most essential things one
has to know.
I have told you again and again how you dress
up, how you bear yourself up, how you talk,
how you listen to others more than you talk
yourself, how you become non-aggressive, is
the best way to impress people and to express
Sahaja Yoga.
I tell you, as it is, people have started
saying, "They are very beautiful people, you
can see they are very beautiful.
You can see they are very different type.
It's something different.
They are something great."
People have started saying that.
But still we lack in certain things.
Like we start going on a plane which is not
suitable to our stature, to our dignity, to
our position as saints.
We are all prophets, and prophets have to
behave like prophets.
They can not behave like cheap-type people.
So, in that we have to understand the maryadas.
Now the maryada to your leaders also, you
should be respectful.
I have seen that nobody calls any body - even
the children will call somebody, say, elderly
person also - never they, say, call them uncle
or anything like that.
It's a wrong thing.
You must teach your children to call elders
by the name as brother or uncle or someone.
Give some respect to the elders.
But when the leader is also not respected,
what is the question of it?
I have seen little boys calling big, married
people with three, four children, by name.
That's not our style.
You should never do it.
I saw this - even My husband's office has
this problem.
Because when I came, you see, they always
called you by name.
"Tom"- he's such a big man, he's called as
"Tom", and all that.
So C.P. looked at it...
And we always call them - even the drivers,
we call them by the name "Mister," you see.
So we could not understand why is it like
this.
You see, it being democratic or something
like this.
You see that's how you become demonocratic.
We must respect.
We must respect each other, must call them
by higher names.
Specially when in a meeting, there are people,
you should call them - each other, even your
friends - by "Mister so and so."
It's all right for Me to call you.
It would look very funny if I call "Mr. Brown"
or "Mr. Reeves" because they are My children,
you see, I am their Mother.
But for you, because you are equal, at least
call them "Mister" and say something in a
way which is beautiful.
Like the English language has many words as
"please, thank you."
All these must be used profusely, profusely.
We are going back a little bit.
We are now becoming much more modern.
That we should give up and become less modern
and more elevating.
Now the whole idea of this maryada is such
that when you have called somebody as a sister
or a brother then it is not only lip service:
You are my sister.
It is something innate, and very deep.
You have to develop that feeling of a sister.
Because that's how your sublimity will go
up, your left Visshuddhi will improve, your
Vishnumaya will be satisfied.
If you call somebody a sister, the sisterly
and daughterly relationships, and motherly
relationships, always bring down, you see,
the so-called ego, which is hiding in the
left Visshuddhi.
So try to be kind and gentle with the person
whom you call the sister.
Stand by her, look after her.
If somebody you call your brother, you have
to pray for his protection, then you must
know that you have a right to ask him for
his protection also.
But you must also give something to him, and
you must try to look after him, welcome him
to your house, and treat him as a part and
parcel of your being, because he is very much
near to you because he is your brother, and
he's very much closer to you.
But such a brother should not try to dominate
the wife.
This is the maryada, again.
Like a brother or somebody is very friendly
with the brother, or a lady is friendly as
a sister, then she should not try to put a
wedge between the husband and wife.
That is the worst thing to do, is to put a
wedge between husband and wife.
Anybody who tries that must know that he is
a mean person.
One should never try to put a wedge between
husband and wife.
I know there are problems between husband
and wife, I will put them right.
But you don't try to put any wedge between
them.
And don't try to create a problem.
If it is problematic, it is for Me to solve,
not you people don't have to solve.
And don't interfere with their married life.
Let them be as they are.
I will find out how they are; I will try to
help them.
But it's very wrong to play with their married
life or with their marriage problems, and
suddenly jump on somebody, is a very wrong
thing, which is very common here.
A woman is in distress, you see, a man will
come to help her.
Even if she is married, he will elope with
her.
This is how he comes to help her in the distress,
to create another distress for her.
So this is how one should understand that
this kind of a cheap heart-giving business,
and taking business, is not for Sahaja Yoga.
In our heart resides the Spirit.
We are dignified people, and in that dignity
we have to rise and live with that dignity.
Not to cheaply allow the Spirit to be insulted
or dominated or subjugated to anyone.
Now the relationship with children also one
should understand.
I have seen some people have a habit of getting
a child very much closer, and pampering them,
"Oh, this child is this thing.
Oh, that child..."
Let the parents handle the child, you just
don't interfere with other's children.
Don't interfere much with them.
If you find any child is such and such, inform
Me, I will cure the child.
But if a child is being spoilt by you, it's
the worst thing to do is to harm that child,
is to spoil.
Children here are very clever and intelligent,
you must know.
They are very good at manipulating.
They will, because they are extremely precocious.
They are realized souls; they are born in
this country.
What a combination!
At that time you must be very careful as to
their training.
From the first five years all the parents
must be extremely strict with children, extremely
strict.
Don't allow them to overpower you or manipulate
you.
It's very important.
If you allow them to overpower you or to dominate
you, they'll sit on your head.
Tell them not to do like that.
And one day you will come and say, "Mother,
what to do, these are realized souls and,
you see, we were looking after them."
They are not deities.
They are not deities to be worshipped.
They are only realized souls.
So keep them at that point.
And you are My trustees of those children.
And if you spoil them, it is you who will
he held responsible.
You have no business to spoil the lives of
these children as Sahaja Yogis, and their
chances of ascent.
So if they are born-realized, they are not
deities; this you must understand.
They are not beyond corruption, they are not
beyond all kinds of things.
So this, if you understand this little point,
that dealing with your children you have to
be really strict.
They must know how to meditate, they must
know how to pray, they must know how to respect;
and all the good things you must teach your
children.
And don't allow them to sit on your head.
Many people have ruined the lives of their
children like this.
Now will you please see that such child is
brought into proper level?
If the child is trying to take liberties with
you, and cheeky and does not listen, please
give that child to some other Sahaja Yogi
to look after, whom you think can look after,
and see that the child is put right.
Nip in the bud is the best way, because we
don't want to have children who are spoilt,
who are spoiling other children, nor we want
children who are subjected to such children.
So, you can have proper children, well-behaved
children, sensible, wise children.
Because they can really be a drag on you,
on Me, on everyone, if you do not properly
bring them up.
And they are our liabilities; we have to look
after them.
So the relationship between the father and
children, mother and children, is important.
Actually the mother should look after the
child much more.
And the child must respect.
Father should never scold the mother in the
presence of the child.
That's one thing one must understand, that
if the father starts scolding the mother in
the presence of the child, the child will
have no respect for the mother.
But the respect must be maintained, because
if the wife respects the husband, then the
child will know how to respect her and the
husband too.
So the whole thing is built up like that.
Is a kind of a pattern for children to follow.
One should not try to dominate the husband,
at least in the presence of children.
That's very wrong.
Because then the children learn that trick
and they start dominating you.
So it flows from you to children.
So try to see that if you have to do anything
then you do it yourself.
And respect the husband and in a way that
is very obvious to the child that the father
is respected by mother.
And they are just like monkeys.
The way you behave, they behave.
So you allow them to behave in a particular
manner, they will behave that way.
But if you put a good pattern of behavior,
they will imbibe it.
The other day I was thinking, how Indian children
are so obedient, so sensible.
They will never ask for it.
"I want this, I want that."
They never manipulate.
What happens?
What happens, how do they do it?
The reason is, I think, the good pattern in
the house.
Everybody knows whom to respect, how to respect,
how to behave.
The relationship in Sahaja Yoga has to be
even more than this, much more subtler.
For example, if - this I have said before
also - if we are in a room, try to give another
person always, try to do for them.
If you have to pay, better pay yourself, not
that wait for another person.
Try to do it yourself.
Run forward to do it.
You see, if someone is carrying the luggage,
you run, you do it.
That is the way a Sahaja Yogi should be.
Mostly, children are like that.
They will say, "I'll get it, I'll do it, I'll
receive it."
May be ego, you might call it, but whatever
it is, but that is the sign you all have to
achieve by organizing a proper type of an
image for the whole society.
That if somebody needs something, you run.
"You want water?
All right...
You want this thing?
You take mine."
Food also - same thing.
First let others have, not that you should
first have anything.
How you eat your food is very important, everything
is very important for the children to see,
and to behave like that.
In money matters also, I have seen that people
should be very, very sensible and should have
proper maryadas.
Now with Me, whatever maryadas you want to
keep, you must understand.
It is very embarrassing to talk about it.
But so far, as you know, I had to shell out
lot of money to manage many funds, many things.
And last time also we had many people who
came to eat, doesn't matter.
At the time now, when we are talking about
maryadas, we must know that, in any case,
Mother should not be made to pay any more.
Because we are so many, we should try to manage,
if possible.
Like yesterday, I had a person from BBC, and
he said, "It is wrong of You not to take any
money from them."
I said, "Where is the money?
No question of taking, I have to pay Myself."
I said, "It is so invaluable that how can
you charge for it?
You cannot charge for it, it is very invaluable.
The Spirit is very invaluable, and you cannot
charge for it."
So he was insisting.
I mean, he took half an hour on this subject
only.
He said, "This Anglo-Saxon brain won't understand
unless and until You make it a little more
money-oriented or something."
I said, "I cannot.
Tell me how much is to be paid."
Just to shut him down, I said, "What about
Christ?
How much money did He take?
By God's grace I am quite well off and I really
don't need either.
But He needed, still He never took any money
from anyone."
Then he kept quiet.
But this is what it is, you see, that people
think that you are getting it easy, cheap
and that's why you want to take advantage,
which is wrong.
You must respect.
You must respect and understand that it is
never good to take any advantage of it.
On the contrary, whenever it is possible you
should try to do whatever is possible for
Sahaja Yoga.
It's very important.
Try to surrender.
Not that I will take any money from you, you
know that.
I don't want any money or anything.
But surrender yourself absolutely to Sahaja
Yoga.
That is the best way people have risen and
have done so well.
Now the relationship among yourselves, among
different groups, among different nations:
we should try to help people.
Supposing there is a couple now, wants to
go to India to get married.
Now if they don't have money, of course I
am there.
I said, "All right, they need not pay any
money, I'll pay for them."
But Warren has put down his foot, he says,
"Why not the people, or the center, help them
out, for the time being?"
You see because now, supposing they have helped
somebody - he had no money, he went to India,
he got married and then he got lost, you see,
he misbehaved, in the sense that he doesn't
talk to anyone, he thinks no end of himself,
then he started behaving in a funny manner.
So a kind of a feeling came into their mind
that "Why should we do it?
If you do it for somebody, then he behaves
like that.
If you try to help somebody..."
Is this a natural reaction that if you try
to do something for someone then people try
to misbehave?
That's not so.
Must be one person has done it, that doesn't
mean that everybody has done it.
That's what it is.
They say that a kind of a barrier is built
in a person who is helped by us, and his ego
is challenged, and he tries to behave in a
manner which was never known before.
And he starts behaving in such a funny manner
that he doesn't talk to anyone, he keeps out
and he becomes mad with his ego.
So his ego is hurt.
There's nothing to feel hurt.
Because if you have no money and if it is
one part and one body, if somebody's helping
you out, doesn't matter.
You can help, when you are well off, to somebody
else.
But when it comes to you, you give up.
So this is a very absurd type of a behavior
of one individual, or two or three, or maybe
five or ten.
Doesn't matter.
But still we must not forget that we have
to help.
We have to help as many as possible.
And we must try to do whatever is possible
for us, for others.
This is important.
If we cannot do for a group, like Sahaja Yogis,
whom are we going to help?
So we have to give that help.
Now in Sahaja Yoga itself, on the subtle basis
we should not try to judge anybody's vibrations.
It is very common in people, "Oh, you are
caught up on your Agnya.
Oh, you have got this wrong, let me clear
you out.
You sit down."
Morning till evening, without meditating,
they are clearing each other's chakras and
catching on themselves.
It's an absolutely wrong idea.
Everybody, individually, should sit before
the photograph, get the vibrations, every
morning, there should be a discipline.
You must know that the system of Sahaja Yoga
today has worked out this way that I have
given you Realization just to say that "Let
your light be enlightened."
Now you have to see your lamp, if it is clean
or not - only possible when the light is enlightened.
See your lamp, if it is enlightened or not.
See, if somebody is over-aggressive, then
it's all right, you make a joint attack on
that person, and tell-off that person.
Or there are leaders who will do it.
But everybody should not judge others.
You better judge yourself, cleanse yourself,
look after yourself.
And also try to see how your lamp is.
Is it clean?
Mother has given us the light to see; and
why not see?
So if you work it out on these lines, you'll
go very fast.
And you have to, now, perfect yourself.
We have so many Sahaja Yogis.
But how many are perfect?
This is the point.
Now your relationship to Sahaja Yoga is also
very important.
There's a maryada about it very much.
Sahaja Yoga should not be taken for granted.
Anybody who thinks he has got Realization
and now he is sitting on top of the world
- is not so.
You must work it out, you have to have discipline.
The same gentleman, the BBC fellow, was saying
that it was before, for years together, you
had to live in celibacy and wash the feet
and sweep steps of the temple and do all kinds
of things, work hard, do this, do that - and
then they would raise it to one chakra.
I said, "Now we do it the other way round."
First build the dome and then the foundation.
Sahaja Yoga is like that.
So that with the dome you understand, you
are protected, you are looked after.
But people take it for granted, like.
"Mother will do it.
Leave it to Mother."
No, it is not so.
You are My hands.
Supposing My hands have to lift this, I should
say that Nirmala will do it?
Now, which is Nirmala?
These hands are the Nirmala at this point.
So, many people drift like that.
So, to Sahaja Yoga also, your attitude should
be of respect.
You should not try to put yourself into bandhan
before others, you should not try to do these
things; but in a dignified way you must respect
Sahaja Yoga.
And foremost of all, to Sahaja Yoga your relationship
should be that you should know Sahaja Yoga,
what it is.
Otherwise every time if you have to talk about
Sahaja, Gavin must come, or somebody.
Why?
Gavin did not know a word about Sahaja Yoga,
he did not know a word about Indian mythology,
he did not know anything, he did not know
what Realization is.
He studied, he's even studying Sanskrit.
Like many of you have done it.
But all of you, one and all, should become
a big pandit.
But you get lost in your marriage problems.
Then your children's problems.
Then "my mother," then "my sister."
I mean, it will take too much time for you.
First of all you should see, "I am a Sahaja
Yogi.
Let me get to work."
And it creates problems for us also.
Because your wife will sue you, your children
will come round, this, that.
You should say, "I have nothing to do, I am
going to study Sahaja Yoga."
I was surprised that many people have taken
Advent just like as a bible, just as a bible.
They never read it.
I was surprised that some people do not know
what I have written in the Bible.
So it is like the Jews, you see, having a
Golden Bible tied up here.
They keep The Advent in a very good cover
near the photograph, worship it - finished.
Then the knowledge goes into them.
You must read some chapters at least of Advent,
if not anything else.
There are so many books you can read; I have
told you.
Try to make your own library.
Try to improve in it.
Everybody must try to get perfection - perfectionism.
You should never be a liability on Sahaja
Yoga, but a great asset of Sahaja Yoga.
That's what everybody should try to be.
That, your problems I will solve.
But you solve your ascent.
That is very important.
You must ascend.
Otherwise, whatever problems I solve, you
get into another problem, then you get into
another problem.
Now the relationship - say you have an ashram;
somebody has bought it.
Now, nobody should think that "This is my
house."
Now this is the best way to get out of this
idea of possession.
Because then I trouble you.
That's the place where Mahamaya plays.
If you say, "This is my house," then you will
have it.
And you will have it forever.
So such things you should never develop, the
feeling that "this (is my house)."
Now I have seen people, they go into an ashram,
and then they think this is their house.
They live there.
They manipulate all the money that they save
and this and that, and develop this, want
to make everything comfortable.
They never think, "This is not my ashram;
I am doing it because I am a Sahaja Yogi.
This is the Ashram of Mother.
I have to do it."
But that detachment is not there.
Not at all a detachment.
And it is something surprising, that if you
have to go to Himalayas and make an insurance
policy, then what's the use of coming to Sahaja
Yoga?
It is as absurd as that.
We are writing two insurance policies, that
"I have gone to Himalayas.
When I die, give my property to this one.
If I don't die, I will come back after that."
And nicely packing up in a nice plastic bag
so that ice doesn't spoil it.
It's as absurd as that.
So you should not have anything.
Now some people have a habit, "Oh, I'll get
a house for myself.
Get my wife there, children there."
Finished.
All such people should, for a change, leave
their houses, come to ashram, put some other
people in their house.
Because they are getting attached, you see.
How will you get detached?
Is there any way out?
Because that is very important in Sahaja Yoga.
Unless and until you are detached, you cannot
ascend.
Supposing you have all the tentacles down
here on the Mother Earth, and you say, "Let
this plane fly," how will it go?
So those people who have houses of their own,
or buildings of their own or anything - flats
- should give up their houses.
Not to be that comfortable.
Get out of it.
Ask some other people to shift, and you shift
to the ashram.
Go on shifting, training your mind to shift,
to live with everyone, to be able to share
and to do things.
I have changed forty houses after My marriage,
you can imagine.
And the kind of a house I have to carry on
with is a very multi-purpose house.
And I have changed, so far, forty houses,
and if I change now this house, it will be
the forty-first.
You can imagine, I have been married forty
years and forty houses I have changed.
So the relationship of purity must be understood,
in everything.
Is it pure relationship?
Am I living in this ashram in pure relationship?
Because this is the house that is giving me
comfort, that's why I am living in this house;
or am I just living here, just because it's
an abode - I am here today, and I will be
there tomorrow?
You will be amazed, you will enjoy every part
of life.
As soon as you are attached, you are doomed.
It's a headache to be attached to someone.
Then you hanker.
"My wife has not arrived.
Oh God, what to do now?
I must telephone to her, get her here."
But if you are detached about it she'll come
in time.
Not only that, but you will enjoy her company.
Otherwise you'll shout at her, "Why didn't
you come in time?
I was waiting for you."
Then why were you waiting to scold her, and
shout at her and spoil all the relationship?
Just see, the absurdity of the whole thing
is the attachment.
You should get completely detached about everything,
and you will enjoy, just enjoy.
But in that also, one has to judge.
You are really enjoying or you are just making
a drama out of it?
Try to be sincere.
Purity is brought forth by sincerity.
If you are not sincere to yourself and to
others, you can not be pure.
And purity is the main thing you have to achieve
in Sahaja Yoga, apart from the unity, which
I have given you.
But if you do not use this unity for purity
- no use.
So this light should give you complete wisdom
that you enjoy a pure, good life.
You are married.
All right, you have life of enjoyment with
your wife - that I have already described
to you.
And with your wife how to behave also, I have
described to you many a times, or with your
husband.
But when it comes to others, you should have
absolutely pure relationship of no exploitation.
Even there are flirting exploitations - as
the same as money exploitations.
Here if you exploit somebody by money it's
called a "thug".
But flirting is not called anything.
I think that is a much worse crime, according
to Christ.
So you have to be careful on this point, and
understand that relationship with each other
has to be pure.
Now there are people who have, say, horrible
wives or horrible husbands.
I don't mind, they can give them up.
If they are absolutely impossible, if they
are spoiling their purity, if they are torturing
their lives, then the best is to get rid of
them.
I don't mind.
Because if they are so bad that you cannot
use them - just like this body, if it is so
bad, it's better to give up and die.
So that let that relationship die out.
But that death should come to you as a very
forceful help; otherwise, after that, if you
become a nervous personality, what's the use?
So what you have to do after such a thing
has happened - that you have given up such
a relationship - then, if you have to go to
courts and all that, you should give up Sahaja
Yoga for the time being.
Solve your problems.
Solve your court problems, everything, then
come to Sahaja Yoga.
We do not want to get involved into this kind
of a thing at all, that we have broken any
family or anything.
If you cannot carry on with a wife, not that
Sahaja Yoga should be an excuse.
Because you can not carry on with her, you
should have this thing - go out of Sahaja
Yoga, do what you like with your wife, finish
it off once for all.
And you should tell her, "I am no more a Sahaja
Yogi."
Get it out, and then come to Sahaja Yoga.
But by coming to Sahaja Yoga you will be really
troubling Me too much.
So I have to make a humble request to you,
that if you have any a such problem, do not
allow any child who is younger than a proper
age - sixteen years - to be kept in the ashram
without taking a full permission, written
permission from the parents.
Or a wife who has made problems with the husband,
should not be allowed to come and stay in
the ashram with the children unless and until
it is resolved.
We are not responsible for all kinds of problems.
Then people who are sick or mentally deranged
should not be kept in the ashram.
That is also quite a sympathetic attitude
of so many Sahaja Yogis.
Ashram is for the best people, not for the
lunatics.
So please do not get such people who are no
good.
We do not want such people to come in the
ashram who are going to ruin the reputation
of the ashram.
So coming to the relationship of Vishnumaya,
is that Vishnumaya is the One Who is the sister,
sister of Shri Krishna.
She is the One Who announced the coming of
Shri Krishna.
She is the One Who sacrificed Her life to
save Shri Krishna's life.
Vishnumaya is the One Which surrounds Shri
Krishna; and She was born as Draupadi Who,
you know, was later on humiliated by Duryodhana,
and it was Shri Krishna Who came and helped
Her.
So it's a very sweet relationship of purity,
of help.
A very delicate relationship is to be maintained
of a brother and a sister.
And that is a special relationship today.
Those who want to tie the Rakhis to a sister
should tie today before Me, it will be a good
idea.
It is a greater relationship than any other
relationship.
Because here somebody is your own sister,
is all right.
But if she is not your own sister you should
know that you all are born of one Mother.
So the brother and sister relationship should
be all right.
In that also one should not have preferences
- because some would like to have a rich sister,
or some sort of a nonsense like that.
Or somebody would like to have the most miserable
one.
This is all the maya.
But a relationship with a person with whom
you would like to be happy, you should tie
the rakhi.
And if there is anybody left out, you should
not try to do that.
So anybody who is listening, I would say that
best thing would be to have your lucky dips.
I think for people, something like that could
be done so that they choose their sisters
and tie the things.
Which ever way you like you choose it.
But I have got some nice rakhis for you, that
should be done today.
And I will be very happy.
And then we'll do this little havana for the
Vishnumaya.
May God bless you.
TIE THE RAKHI AND HAVAN:
(Informal conversation with yogis about who
will live in which ashrams)
This house has too much right-side.
[Inaudible] It's a very right-sided house,
it's very right-sided.
I don't know; you have to, little bit, fill
with some left-sided [inaudible].
absolutely right-sided.
There is one more thing I have to tell, which
he had asked Me to talk to you.
I don't know if you are interested, but they
are showing some sort of a program at seven
o'clock on Saturday.
They are showing some program of revelation,
how people see lights, things like that.
Sahaja Yogis must know why these things happen.
Like, one gentleman suddenly felt a flash.
He went to a lady and she was a widow lady,
her husband had died in climbing, and he himself
used to climb a lot with him.
And the husband died, so he went to get the
lady, the widow.
And she was telling all the stories, and he
felt very sad about it, and suddenly - he
didn't like the way she was telling the stories,
I think - and suddenly he felt a flash on
his head, of light.
And then he felt tremendous compassion for
her.
What must have happened, can you tell?
No, I'll tell you what must have happened:
the Kundalini must have risen.
He used to climb and do all these right-sided
business, so it must have spread - one possibility
- on the right side.
It could have been that, without Kundalini
awakening also, the sympathetic might have
broken its way to the right because he's too
much right-sided and all that.
And ultimately with these things, he might
have broken himself to the right and gone
to the right most probably.
But by going too much to the right, you see,
he must have felt the pull of the left, because
right is too much pulled out, then you sink
to the left.
And that's how he must have felt the compassion
for the lady.
But could be also with Kundalini.
With some people it can happen that Kundalini,
at the time of such tension and problems,
sometimes rises and tries to... because It's
a parasympathetic thing.
Might rise and just soothes the person, at
that point.
But most probably, I think, it is the sympathetic
activity which he was doing, and suddenly
the whole thing flashed into the right, then
he went to the left.
Another lady who did some dirty act on the
stage, some filthy act, and she was not very
happy with it.
Though it was indecent, she had to do it.
And she did that on the stage, and after that
she was feeling very sad, and then suddenly
she felt a lot of fire in her stomach, tremendous
heat in her stomach.
And then in the morning, when she looked in
the mirror, she felt her eyes were all heated
up, and heat was coming out of her eyes, when
she looked at her eyes she felt very sad about
it, and all her body was frozen.
And this is the one where, I think, is Shri
Ganesha's anger, that He showed Himself as
the Mooladhara heat, and from the eyes Christ,
His heat was coming.
And because the heat was all consumed in those
chakras the rest of the body was heat.
One fellow has an experience that from his
back he gets cool breeze coming out, but not
from his head, because, I think, should be
an Agnya bhoot was blocked, so he's just emitting
from his back only, and the Kundalini is trying
to come out.
(With) some people, the Kundalini will rise,
definitely.
The reason is this: that so many now of you
have got Realization.
And I have told you that once a particular
number of people gets it people will get the
experiences.
But getting the experience is a very vague
thing.
They are just vague; they do not know what
it is.
So it may be also that hundred monkey syndrome
has started and that people are getting this
Kundalini awakening within themselves.
Because suddenly so many revelations are coming
forward.
[Shri Mataji asks for the center leaders to
come and perform the Havan]
Let this fire light go into your Left Vishuddhi
and cleanse it completely, burn off all baddha.
May God bless you
So we had this complete, this Vishnumaya where
we have never done before.
And Left Vishuddhi has been the biggest problem
of this country - feeling guilty and all that.
So now I'm sure the people will come out of
it, and will try to show everyone not with
ego but with complete balanced mind, the dignity
of Sahaja Yogis.
May God bless you
Now, we have decided not to have too many
marriages in Switzerland, because, as you
see now, we cannot go up to that point where
we can have marriages.
It's all full of snow, you cannot have fire,
you cannot have all the arrangements.
Even a garland of flowers may cost you fifty
pounds.
And it's not going to be cheaper marriage,
in the sense that everything is so expensive,
even if you find out in the market.
Now I have to make a request to you people:
those who want to get married in Switzerland
should be mostly the people who want to remarry,
or those people who can not at all afford
to go to India.
But try to help the people who do not have
enough to go to India, that they get married
in India.
It's much easier, it's much [inaudible], much
more simple.
All right?
So, if you understand that, if you can go
to India and if you have leave, then do it.
It's better to do it there.
And you need not jump...They say that [Indian
saying], means a person who is very anxious
to get married, doesn't even raise the head-dress
here, he ties upon his knee.
So one should not be that much excited.
Take a very sensible view of the whole thing,
those who want to get married.
And we have decided on the people who could
marry in Switzerland.
So those who have no money or something, apart
from this you should try to help them if possible,
every way possible.
I will also try to help.
Now another thing I have to say is that you
all have to send some money for My travel,
because I have to travel now.
We have been traveling throughout England,
again I have to travel; and if there is no
travel money, you know who has to pay the
amount.
But the people will be again replacing the
money of the travel, which will again be there
ready for other travel.
As it is, for India and all that, you don't
have to pay.
But, I think that, if you decide that I have
to travel, that you should pay for My traveling,
then it is better that you should send some
money for the traveling.
We have been all over the country and, so
far, nobody has paid anything for travel.
So please try to send the traveling money
to Gavin Brown, and all the money that you
want to contribute to him and the travel.
Now another one, we have decided now to keep
the emergency money.
Plus, if you people donate more than the travel
money, or the money you want to donate for
the programs and all that, should be in the
emergency money.
It can be used for other things like mailing,
for photography or any kind of such expenses
where you have to have a hall - all these
things.
Certain people, like Isle of Wight people
have sent five-hundred pounds for the program,
within three persons it was too much so I
decided to pay half of it to them back to
the travel money.
Then we have to buy one tape recorder which
will cost about sixteen hundred, fifty in
the market, for which we have money - not
the whole but we have lot of it - and we have
to buy that also.
So the only now money left with us is emergency
money and the travel money.
Out of it, the travel money is very limited.
If I have to travel, then either I pay and
then we reimburse, or something like happens.
It's a big problem, because how to adjust
it and how to do it?
So keep it free from all these problems.
If you people donate some money for the travel
money to Gavin Brown, it will be easier, which
will be again replaced by the people.
But just now the traveling is important, for
which you have to pay.
And the rest of it, just now, is that we don't
have to pay much for anything else.
So that all the money should transfer to the
travel money - for the time being, only for
the time being.