in one of my lectures
i have talked to you about the emotional
intelligence
that is what we should try to invite
emotional intelligence that means
the intelligence that is based on
emotions
unless and until we become emotionally
intelligent
our society cannot
emotional intelligence you care
and you enjoy caring
you do everything
for others with a great
emotional understanding not for one
child
not for one son but for everyone
you have to be emotionally intended
some children are born like this but
some are to be made like that
that they should be emotionally internal
because if the mother and father
are money oriented very selfish
they won't allow their child
to give anything to others so such a
child will grow
into a very funny type of a person
and will never do anything for anybody
not even for his own country
why should he do it everything for
selfishness
then such people indulge into corruption
indulge into all kinds of things which
are
only selfish in attitude
now we are talking of collectivity
in collectivity we do for others
we enjoy doing for others we love giving
things to others
not for our yourself because your
children will also
become the same kind and they'll only
bother about themselves
this emotional intelligence has to be
brought in our life in our pattern
that we have are we emotionally
intelligent or we are just
intelligent or emotional
both things are wrong if you are just
intelligent you can become very dry
person
you may just have few friends maybe you
may not have
and you will always try to preserve
yourself away
from the collectivity
and if you are emotional you will be
attached only to one person
attached to one child maybe attached to
one person
to someone even in the society
for no rhyme and reason why why are you
attached to one person
why are you bothered about one person
only
all such people fall into such terrible
praying
in the politics you have seen how people
try to help their own sons and our
daughters and
this and that and we indians have
suffered a lot with this
kind of a emotional attachment
so according to
ethics emotional
intelligence is the highest quality
by which you give to others
you care for others for everybody
and you become very very collected
now exclusiveness is another fashion
that's very much that it's exclusive
because you don't want to be one of the
multitudes you want to be
exclusive you should be
exclusive in emotional intelligence
not on other things that is the best
thing
you can have as i agree i am just a
woman
i'm just a mother but what i have
is really the emotional
intelligence ocean of it
and from that i know
about everyone
i understand about a book and all this
work has been done
because of that quality in my head
i am not attached to one person or to
one style whatever you say
i can understand because i am at a level
where i can understand everything that
you are doing
to achieve that you try to develop
emotional intelligence here the children
won't even
give a toy for somebody to play
even the mother is like that the father
is like that extremely selfish
and we must have our own say everything
should be our own
this has to go this has to go from
american
especially because they are the leading
nation in this kind of selfishness
what selfishness they have done i did
not count but you know that
you go and ask the people of canada
mexico
peru all this they will tell
being selfish they are not ashamed
they are exploiters they are not ashamed
nobody can even tell them because they
think they are very rich people
but all these riches will not give him
the joy
of life joy of life is only in
the emotional intelligence
if you don't have that it becomes very
dry
life becomes very hot unbearable
horrible
and even the family
gets broken up if there is no emotional
intelligence in the family
i have known so many women who have
had three marriages five marriages i
don't know how they can do it
but they have done because this lack of
emotional interest
it is something that is a sense of
giving
it is not that you are sacrificing
anything no
that's also another idea that we have to
bear these nothing of the color
look at the life of christ he gave his
life
why what was the need for him to do that
behind it was the truth
when you have truth with you the light
of the truth the force of the truth the
strength of the
truth you become emotionally
intelligent you understand
that if you really love something then
you
have to undergo every kind
of trouble you have to tolerate a lot of
nausea
i know it's too much to say but i
thought that
for the special puja i should
say something about the sound
in our ashrams or in our programs
or wherever we are we should remember
this point that are we
[Music]
having that emotional intelligence when
we are trying to talk about sahaja yoga
why do i need to be every place to tell
them
what is the need you can tell them
if you have that emotional intelligence
everybody will listen to you why not not
necessarily i should go everywhere
and talk to them how many countries can
i do
and the reaction to it's so beautiful
and so
nice it's very surprising like in a
country like benin country almost lives
there
all black people they all have become
sahaja yogis
nine thousand
how could i capture that just think of
that
nine thousand people summative then
also other countries have seen just
this is the power of emotional
intelligence
that captures the heart of the people
you may have any amount of property
money everything people will abhor
all right so you may say what's wrong
what's wrong with this
that you are harming the greatest
thing is the human being
and the politicians they are horrible as
they say
why because they have no emotional
intelligence
also as administrators
they are very much difficult
because they have no emotional
intelligence
all these people are devoid of that
great quality of emotional intelligence
if your country is very progressive i
must say
you must progress in emotional
intelligence
that way they are philosophized i know
americans are known to be
philanthropists but behind that
is they want to have power
they want to rule people with that money
it's not emotional uh intelligence is
they just want to rule
if they start some sort of a charity
that is just to have a big name on the
television
or to have a very big
advertisement about oh yeah and then he
moves like a tycoon all over
we part of it they will donate be part
of their property
work it out and make such a fuss about
it
because they want to cash it everything
cash has been given so cash flow
you are sahaja yogi
you have to send waves of emotional
intelligence
you have to send love to all over the
world
you have to show how you can eat love
whenever
it is also possible if you are not so
attached
if you are attacked say to your country
only
now this is a bigger issue then you will
try
to exploit other countries take
advantage of them
try to run them down but if you are
emotionally attached to your country
then you will bring good name to your
country by doing
real good work i don't know why
people do not know how to discriminate
why are they so selfish trying to build
them up
trying to do all the
good things for themselves
there is a very great chance for all of
you
to get this within you your reach
because you are
all sahaja yogis you have become like
lotuses
and the lotus has the fragrance which
spreads all over
and days together it stays in the water
in that dirty water
and it spreads the fragrance with that
fragrance also you can do
lots of things that the bees come there
they sleep in that
beautiful house of a lotus
and in the night it closes down very
carefully
all kinds of things that come
for the flower to take the
little of the
beauty of that flower we can say because
you can extract also the essence of that
which has
fragrance you can
also get some honey out of that whatever
is possible
everybody comes to that flower
that doesn't mean that flower in any way
is weak
but that's his quality that's his
strength that's his understanding
that's what you are you are all made
into lotuses
you are not made into some sort of
creeps
or some sort of stupid
donkeys no you
are the people who are to give fragrance
of your love
fragrance of your compassion to others
and you should feel happy about it that
doesn't mean
that you give up this give up that
nothing of the god
but it means that whatever you have
whatever is your possibility capability
you must try to do for others
give it