[Music]
chastity
-
just to
[Music]
today we have gathered here
and very auspicious day to worship Shri
Ganesha Shri Ganesha is the first deity
that was created so that the whole
universe is filled with auspiciousness
with peace bliss and spirituality
he is the source he's the source of
spirituality as a result of that all
other things follow like when he trains
and his windy you feel the coolness in
that misfile
in the same way when Shri Ganesha emits
his power we feel all these three things
within and without I think I've told you
a lot about Havel and his nature but
still in so many of us have not yet
realized what are his powers and what he
wants
first and foremost thing is that to
respect Shri Ganesha is to understand
the importance of chastity chastity is
not only for the women it is more for
the men to observe if you have
self-respect in the real sense of the
word you will take to translate ly
without any difficulties because
chastity is a very joy giving any joy it
is not a thing that you have to tell
somebody or to force somebody or to
restrict somebody but it is to enjoy to
enjoy yourself and enjoy the chastity of
another person is such a great blessing
of Shri Ganesha such a great blessing
that you enjoy your chastity you are not
bothered about the another person he is
chased or not if he's doing bad things
if he's a ruined person doesn't matter
you don't get spoiled with that you have
your own chastity your own life of very
chaste moments it is nowadays such a
modern style of thinking as a flowing
towards unchaste life and all kinds of
wrong ideas about chastity if somebody
now talks of chastity people think this
must be mad how can that be
now to understand the significance of
chastity within us we have to know that
chastity is the foundation of all
Dharma's unless and until you have sense
of chastity you cannot have that Dharma
is not possible because that's the
foundation it will be a house of cards
if you do not have the foundation of
chastity
it will just collapse in no time so is a
very important thing is chastity which
has been challenged in the West
throughout and that's why I'm saying
it's difficult to sow the seed of
chastity in this country but that is a
very important thing our whole morality
depends on our idea of chastity we
should be very chaste so many religions
have come and they have talked about
chastity but religions have become so
useless now have become without any
basis without any any proper execution
of what is written for them they do all
kinds of things and they call themselves
Hindu Muslims Christians all kinds of
religions actually the religions have
failed completely
people are sick now all over the Western
life one feels they're sick sick because
they have never recognized Shri Ganesha
if one Freud came that doesn't mean that
you should accept him but you did as if
it was such an important thing to be
done so today we are faced with our
power of ascent and the power of
conditionings we have had when Freud
talked of conditioning he didn't know he
was putting another type of horrid
conditionings on terrible
six is not important for human beings at
all
is not at all important and this
civility one has to that it's so much
surprising it comes from a very low
Grady within us it comes from the low
graded human beings that one becomes sir
why to it you should be the master of
that and today when I see around myself
in the West which is also part and
parcel of the same creation so much of
sickness that has come I am really
aghast how to turn your attention now to
the maturity of sex when the sex matures
you become a father a mother and the
pure personality that doesn't mean I'm
saying austerity at young age that
doesn't mean that another absurdity is
that but of course you must mature you
need it the pasilla for that
six
the perversion has to be diverted
towards your family your wife and you
have to respect your chastity now the
whole thing becomes nothing but just
lead a chaste life not to be like a dog
but like to be like a human
all that attention has to become
chastity which is your power which is
your protection which is your connection
with the divine not force Chestatee but
a chastity of balance and understand
with your family with your wife
you're very chaste way we can live and
the women are chase men also Avengers
and this chastity is your main power
this is just T is the one is the power
of Shri Ganesha and when you get HT the
nature's power
you know how powerful you become the
innocence that is submitted
without the chastity that women cannot
achieve anything one has to give up all
the pasta all the pasta and also the way
there is compartment from the newspapers
from the media from everything
recently I read a beautiful so because
that has come up that media forces
haven't in that they have said and how
this media has put ideas into the heads
of women
married divorced married and divorce now
what I gather that Western society is
built up against marriages against
families to be married according to them
it's a sin and once you are married to
get out of the scene you must do
something like that because they live
together for days together and once they
marry immediately they think of divorce
because marriage is now so much
connected with property money is that
nonsense but the whole thing has become
so gross and after marriage there is no
question of love because how much money
goes how much part of the house goes how
many things are mine in harmony the
whole thing have become so materialistic
such marriages can never be successful
but in sahaja yoga we marry for our
ascent and we have to respect our
marriages and to respect our chests it
is with our brothers and sisters those
people who try to somehow other way in
the purity of connectivity I assure you
will be in very very trouble hence both
so please do your soul-searching find
out if there are any impure feelings try
to throw the moment and know that you
are not possessed by such funny ideas
if you start developing a deeper
understanding then we will not be
attracted by superficial things and you
won't be distracted from your path after
getting realization you should be
absolutely chaste people you shouldn't
have your eyes roving around everywhere
and sort of what you can call a very bad
method of communicating with young women
and young men and spoiling your chastity
even your eyes should be clean even your
thoughts should be green for that you
should introspect and see for yourself
what mistakes were made
committing and what kind of an unchaste
behavior you have and the negative
within us disappears the light of Shri
Ganesha you can see it so clearly in
another person if you don't have
chastity you can never see who is
unchaste or just you cannot
everybody is just the same very good
very good very nice person when I
suppose I were a real possessed people
are certified as very good people in
sahaja yoga also sometimes and I start
wondering what's happening what is it
how is it these people are certified as
that can't you feel it there's no light
even if you get your realization even if
your spirit is working out your
collective consciousness even if you are
giving self-realization to others you
are nowhere if you have no chastity
that's like a broken glass which is
trying to reflect something it can never
give the right picture it's so important
and I have to tell you this now the time
has come for me to tell you this is the
snag in our life first thing people will
ask whom am I going to marry what is a
Johari of course marriage I call it an
auspicious thing marriage should be
there there should be a collective
sanction everything but for what to
adorn the chastity within us now
supposing you are worshiping today Shri
Ganesha so why are you worshipping Shri
Ganesha
you're worshipping because your Ganesha
must be awakened that you should have
the qualities of Shri Ganesha that you
should feel that innocence in your eyes
otherwise you are a hypocrite if you are
sitting here in worshipping Shri Ganesha
and you are not trying to put your
attention to your ascent as the Ganesh
then it is useless the magnet within you
is Shri Ganesha many people know that I
have a great sense of direction that
comes through this magnet which is
perfect this magnet is the one which
keeps you sticking or existed or all the
time
pointed toward spirit if you don't have
the sense of chastity you will dangle
this way that way suddenly you become a
very good sahaja yogi tomorrow you
become a devil because there's nothing
that keeps you binding to the great idea
of the spirit let us face it up now the
time has come for all of us all the
sahaja Yogi's that the greatest thing
within us is not sex but his chest
once you understand the importance that
sahaja yoga you can only achieve your
ascent through purity there's no other
way anything which is hanging on to you
will keep you down
and whatever you go start dropping it
out whether it is ego super-ego anything
but the highest of all is the purity of
your mind as far as the sex is concerned
I will give it the highest birth that's
what we call as innocence that's the
only thing that will think you are head
and so we all should try to search our
suppose you have got of course
realization you have got great qualities
you are not even aware as to what you
want through easy but the knowledge also
so easily didn't have to go to any
college or anything and you are capable
of so many things but remember that the
power that is within you is cleverer
than you and anything you try to do
which is not correct which is not
righteous which is not holy it will try
to bear it
so try to be a different person try to
understand what is behind this person
what is the spiritual quality of this
person and then only you will know that
pure relationships are so fragrant and
so beautiful I really enjoy you people
because you have such pure relationships
of know yourself I have such understand
somewhat
[Music]