What a beautiful place to come to! As such
/ Which[Sounds like as such…] I have been
here before also. You have such nice places
on the outskirts. On the outskirts you have
really very nice places in Sydney and this
picnicking has helped you to make your collectivity
better. That’s how they started having picnics
and in the picnics they develop the collectivity,
which is very beautiful to be one with the
nature, see the bounty of the nature and the
variety that they have.
Is a innate feeling inside always that you
should be one with the nature, that you should
enjoy the nature. I mean it’s maybe because
they say we have evolved from animals so we
like nature. But it’s so much …xxxx………
[Cannot hear the word…] so much your temperament,
everything when you see the nature and start
seeing it, how it obeys the laws which govern
it. Now see, if you see every leaf, any leaf,
is not comparable with another leaf, if you
put it under microscope they’ ll be all
different leaves.
The variety’s so much in the nature, but
still how they abide together and the greatest
thing they have is that always the desire
to get the sunlight and every leaf, every
branch tries to give chance to another leaf
and another branch, that they all get the
sunlight. If you have to see collectivity,
really you see in a jungle or in a place like
this. How they live together and with such
happiness, with such unity. They are all under
the complete control of the divine laws, no
doubt, and they are so much enjoying.
It’s only the human beings who have got
this freedom, the will, “free will” as
they call it. If you want to go to heaven,
you can go to heaven. If you want, you can
go to hell. And that is what we are facing
now in modern times, that if we do not take
course to sensible things we may be all wiped
out of the surface of the Earth. I’ve been
telling since long that it affects our genes.
Supposing a father is an alcoholic, the son
also gets it in his genes. So many things,
most of the vulnerability that you have or
what you can call the susceptibly
is coming from these genes. And the susceptibility
to do something wrong, always to take to something
bad, whatever is destructive, comes from the
gene and it was said that the Asians have
two genes which protects them, bars them for
doing something wrong. Might be a culture
research, I don’t know. And the Aboriginals
and the people who have lived in the nature
have only one gene that protects. But for
white skin, there’s no gene to protect.
Can you imagine? They’re left to winds.
Whichever way the wind blows, they start blowing.
So, it’s such a big problem with the white
skin — also they think they are the higher
race, but they’re not according to the biological
process, you can say. You can see the Germans,
what they did. I mean, killing children in
the gas. How could they do it? I mean, I just
— unimaginable. The way they have killed
people in all the African countries also,
specially in America, the Spanish. Unimaginable.
The way they have treated other people everywhere.
Cruelty comes to them first. Very easily they
can become cruel. They take to bad things
very easily. There are some Sahaja Yogis who
came to Sahaja Yoga, stayed in Sahaja Yoga
for so much and again they have taken to their
bad life.
So now it is very much to be understood that
you have to be very careful and cautious.
The bhoots will first catch you. That’s
why so much schizophrenia everywhere. If you
— schizophrenia is so much true in America.
So much. All kinds of horrible diseases they
have. I can’t understand how they got it.
So one has to be very careful that after coming
to Sahaja Yoga you must stick on to your sublime
Self, to your glorious Self, otherwise it
is dangerous. When one thing about Sahaja
Yoga I was amazed that how it cleanses the
gene. Actually, gene in a Persian language
is called like a “bhoot,” you know Jin,
but this whole theory is now showing that
white- skinned people are more vulnerable
to all kinds of things and I think they are
the ones who have suffered a lot because there
must have been a big fight within, that ‘What
is this nonsense we are doing? Why should
we do it?’ And that’s why so many of them
started seeking, so many of them. The seeking
is so much suggested in Indian culture, everything,
but no body did that the way that you people
were seeking is creditable; because you realized,
perhaps, that this is a terrible life you
are into. ‘Why are we here, so unprotected?’
and that’s why so much of — we have so
many Sahaja Yogis all over the world who have
taken to Sahaja Yoga and are steady themselves
and are progressing beautifully. That means
the genes which we are not protecting have
become protective, one thing, and those genes
which make you vulnerable to things also become
clean and you cannot get to those things.
They said the people who get AIDS are the
ones who have genes like that. They’re vulnerable
to AIDS.
So, this new dimension that science has exposed
before us tells us two things, that by living
like a white country, people saw the hell
itself and that’s why they have taken now,
with such a big jump, to Sahaja Yoga and your
duty is to see that you get more out of all
that hell. Around you, if you see — I mean,
when you read the newspaper you’re shocked.
It’s not the accident by which people die,
but all kinds of diseases, murders, this,
that going on. God knows, such violence. Specially
in America, you’ll be surprised that I can’t
even wear my wedding ring there. My husband
doesn’t allow Me to wear My wedding ring,
even mangal sutra. And what goes wrong with
them, I don’t know, that they take to violence
without any difficulties.
We had one gentleman who came from America.
He had already murdered his brother and murdered
his mother also — mother and brother, both.
I said , “How could you do that?” And
so many you will find in England who have
killed their children and the children, when
you see them, nothing but — you develop
a kind of a special sweet feeling, isn’t
it — very sweet. It’s a in Sanskrit called
as “Vatsalya.” In our all Indian languages
we use that word, Vatsalaya, when the feeling
that you get when you see a little child.
They have described Shri Krishna as a little
child. They have described Shri Rama as a
little child. Also Christ as a little child
has been described in the Indian churches.
Beautiful, very beautifully He has been described.
One song, one poem was there, written very
beautifully that Christ as a child, who can
turn the whole universe with His own finger,
was putting His own finger in the mouth as
a child. Such beautiful poetry is written
about children, how they behave, but not so
much in the English language, Spanish language.
They go more for this love affairs and things
like that. But what about children? They never
describe children, how beautiful they are.
I think I have read hardly about ten or twelve
poems. One of them I remember is “The Toys.”
There’s such [Low and muffled], Poet says
that he got very angry with his child and
he beat him and the child was crying and then
the child went off to sleep with the little
doll maybe or something and when he saw him
sleeping like that he says to God that maybe
I might do lots of mistakes and you might
punish me, but when I’m dying, then you
must forgive me as I have forgiven my son.
That is a very beautiful song was written
by him. But still, the description of a child,
how when he runs when he runs, when he jumps,
when he walks it’s a beautiful songs about
Shri Rama. Thumko atta hai who – Thumakat
chalat Ram Chandra, atta hai kya? [Mother
says in Hindi “Do you know the song Thumakat
chalat Ram Chandra...”]
Now these words are such that we cannot explain
in English, but when they walk, you know,
with — started walking, so their body, you
know, moves in a way that’s called “Thumakna”
in Hindi language. So described by Tulsidasa,
as Shri Rama is walking in that way. Thumakat
chalat Ram Chandra. And His anklets are singing
and then He’s looking round and every pebble
on which He’s walking is reflecting Him,
like the souls in which He’s reflected.
Even Shri Krishna’s childhood is described
very well, His mischiefs, everything. All
these things have been described and this
is called as one of the moods. As we have,
you see, nine moods described, one of the
moods is vatsalya, vatsalya rus. Or “rus”
means kya kahengey usko[Mother speaks in Hindi
and It Means what we will call that?] rus
means the essence of a poetry where that gives
you a feeling, is rus. This is not there in
the western idea, you see. They just think
of romance only, nothing else. So they don’t
have rusa in their mind. We have nine rus,
out of which this vatsalya rus is the best.
We have bhakti rus when you have bhakti for
someone. Also we have shringar, but shringar
is only between husband and wife and also
just before marriage, once marriage is settled
or you know you are going to marry such and
such. That’s a shringar rus.
Like that, we have also vibatsya means…xxxx
[word is UNCLEAR] — see something very ugly,
described the death or something you describe
the vultures eating, eating the corpses. All
this is also described as Vibhatsya.
So we have nine ragas, Mother corrects nine
rusas and these rusas are - you must have
seen in some dances they must have shown.
One is also of anger and when a person gets
anger, you see how his anger is expressed
and — in words, but then later on this thing,
this anger is also depicted and all these
rusas are depicted in the form of dancing
— dancing also which is a very, very fast,
we can say, fast movement. And these fast
movements are also shown very — these all
nine rusas can be shown in one dance. See
how one changes from one to another and then
to another.
So it is a very deep understanding of human
beings, but as far as the children are concerned,
I think Indians love them the most. They love
them, but, on the, though because of their
love, they discipline. If you love your children,
you must discipline them.
Today I just wanted to tell you that the children
are to be brought up in a proper way. That
means you shouldn’t spoil them, firstly.
Now, we have problems of children who came
to see Me and they’re telling that these
children cannot fit into the pattern of our
Sahaja Yoga school in Dharamsala.
So one child is a very adamant child, extremely
adamant and you tell him something he goes
on more doing the same thing and if you say,
‘I’ll punish you.’ ‘All right, don’t
give me food. Don’t do this.’ He is so
adamant and he’s developed this kind of
a funny situation.
Now definitely such a child, we should say,
is possessed. He’s not a normal child, the
possessed child and one has to deal with that
child in that manner. Another child could
be who is a back-number in the class, can
be. Now the back-number child is the child
which, which is also possessed, maybe in some
depressive mood he must have felt something,
he lost his brother or something. So he’s
become depressive. He’s depressed and when
he’s depressed then what he’s doing that
he is always sulking and he cannot pay attention
to his work and he’s not so good.
Thirdly, there are children who are not disciplined
at all. Maybe the father is not disciplined,
the mother is not disciplined. They’re not
at all disciplined and you cannot discipline
them. It’s very troublesome and they make
such problems. They go on answering.
The fourth category of children that they
have reported are really very violent type,
extremely violent. They want to bash this,
break that and every sort of thing. It is
impossible to understand why they do it, but
My own theory is this: that if the children
are told all the time that this very important,
carpet is important, ‘Don’t spoil this,’
all material nonsense we talk to them, then
these children sort of develop an kind of
an antagonistic, you can say, or a kind of
a opposition to that kind of a suppression
and then they want to destroy everything that
they see as a possession.
So how should we manage these things is a
big problem. The last and the least is the
most horrifying thing is that they start taking
to sex life very early, very early. They’ll
enter into the teacher’s bed or into some
friend’s beds and that’s horrible. And
for this, I don’t know whom to blame, but
maybe that, again we can say gene. But the
newspapers, the media, all those things are
teaching children all these things. Horrible
films we have. I mean, they’re, they come
to hell, born into hell. So they learn these
things sometimes, I don’t know how and it’s
very difficult to get these things out of
their mind. There’s no innocence at all.
At a very, very young age they do it. Some
people say that because children are sometimes
molested or something, so they develop this
in their childhood and they go on developing
it more and more and more. But still, I just
don’t know what is child molestation is
suppose to be. Why such stupid feelings come
into people’s mind? They also ruin their
own children.
So if you see the whole thing is, there’s
one point is missing, and that is, we don’t
love our children as we should. We should
punish them in case we find they’re not
all right. It is our duty to teach them discipline,
not only for their good, for the good of the
whole society. There’s a story in India
that there was one thief and then he murdered
people. He did this and he did that. So he
was to be hanged. They asked him, ‘Have
you any desire before being hanged?’ He
said, ‘Only one. Please call my mother.’
So they called the mother and he went and
bit her hard on her hand. Say, ‘Why are
you doing this?’ He said, ‘Because when
I did the first crime, you didn’t say anything
to me. You tried to hide it and you didn’t
do anything to me. That’s why now I am being
hanged. So it was your duty to correct me
at that time, whichever way it was possible,
but you did not do it.’
So, the love of a person should not be such
that it should spoil people. Say now, if I’m
your Mother, I love you very much, you know
that very well and you also love Me, but if
I have to correct you, I must have courage
to correct you and tell you what I want you
to do. You need not get into temper or anger.
I seldom, I am think very seldom, I really
get angry with people. But you have to tell
them.
So you start now as you are Sahaja Yogis,
your children are born realized and Sahaja
Yogis the other way round. ‘That you are
all Sahaja Yogi,’ you tell your children,
‘You can’t behave like that.’ Put the
dignity into their mind. Tell them that this
is the way you have to behave, otherwise you
are not Sahaja Yogis. Give them the credentials,
I would say of Sahaja Yoga, that you are Sahaja
Yogis, you are born realized, you cannot behave
like that. But I have seen some people try
to fight with others for their own children,
which is absolutely wrong and immature behavior.
If somebody says something to your child,
it’s all right, and you should try to accept
it very well. See that at least somebody has
told you about your child and you must correct,
is a real loving father or mother who are
concern about it, not only to protect him
and protect all the vices he is developing.
Now as it is, in the Western life there’s
such an attack on innocence, I can see this,
such a lot, because why should they kill their
children? Well, I’ve never heard of such
a thing in India, that anybody’s killing
their children. I had a washerwoman. She was
staying in our house, in our [low and Muffled]
We had quarters for them and she had eleven
children and I had gone away to Lucknow. I
was building a house and in the meanwhile,
you see, these people they cook — what do
you call that? — starch in the house. And
in a big pot they cook it. And this, by mistake
you see, then she had so many children that
this child crawled up to it and died. I mean,
he got into it and he died. This lady had
ten children left. She was like a madwoman
— crying, weeping, not eating. When I went
back she had not had her food for twenty days.
She had not even taken water or anything,
so much she was crying. I told her, “There
are ten children you have got. Now one child
God has taken away, so why are you crying
for that child?” She couldn’t get over
it. She it - took her months to get over it,
that she has lost one child out of the eleven.
But when I hear of people who kill their two
children who are there and — now the children
are killing the parents. Can you imagine?
There was recently a case in England, two
boys, I think eight and ten, got hold of one
little child in the supermarket and killed
him and put him under the railway track. Imagine.
This sweet age of eight and twelve, what nice
things children can do. What nice things they
can do too, instead they went and killed one
child. Why? We should introspect. We should
find out.
I wouldn’t blame anybody here, but I would
say that we should understand why children
do like that. Firstly, they must get affection.
They must know somebody loves them very much
and dearly and, secondly, the respect. They
should know that they are very much respected
and they have to be repectable. Thirdly, they
should know also that they belong to a very
prestigious family of Sahaja Yogis. They can’t
do all this. Their attention also is to be
such that they understand what they are doing.
In the West children don’t have that attention,
I tell you. Normally, what attention we have
in the East, we don’t find it, that children,
even if they’re realized souls, they have
the same attention. It has to be brought in.
I remember My Mother always use to — “Where
is your attention?” all the time. She said,
“Where is Your attention?” I was quite
a philosopher, you know, so I use to go into
meditation. So she use to say, “Where is
Your attention?” I said, “Inside. It’s
all right.” But I never minded. Nobody minded
it, when she said, “Where is Your attention?”
Attention is very important thing, where it
goes, what it says. So when, say children
are describing something, tell you something,
they’re very sweet. You should ask them
questions. You must see that you ask them
questions and they answer you very sweet sweet
things, they answer. But in that, you should
see where is their attention, what they are
describing and what they are saying to you
because they’re realized children and the
realized children always talk in the third
person also. Like you tell them, ‘Now, you
better go home.’ So they’ll say, ‘This
boy will not go.’ I tell you, he doesn’t
want to go home. ‘This boy will not go,’
meaning this boy is different from the one
which is speaking. So they speak like that
and the way they speak and the way things
they say, it’s beautiful things they say
and one lady tried to write down certain things
the children had to say about politics, about
politician and then she wrote a book and the
book was sold within one week’s time. It’s
so sweet.
I mean, innately, all of us have the same
type of sweetness for our children, except
for some, I don’t know, what sort of people
are they who have a different reaction, but
for Sahaja Yogis, you see in collectivity,
you must try to bring your child in a manner
that he doesn’t feel that he belongs to
you only. There should be no competition.
You should also praise other children you
should, and never try to praise your child.
It’s not good manners, I tell you. It’s
not good manners to praise your child, ‘My
child is like this. My, my.’ Nothing. But
you praise others’ children first and the
child will see that also and he’ll also
praise others’ parents, not his own. If
he learns that, then the collectivity improves
that you start seeing good things in everything
and now, as I was telling you, it’s a very
dangerous situation when you read about the
genes and the no protective genes because
I remember once, one student who had gone
to Cambridge. He came back and he said, ‘What
surprises me, he - they take to drugs like
a venture. They take to anything bad like
a venture, while for us, we are frightened,
you know, we think this is wrong. All throughout,
we know it is wrong and we are doing wrong,
knowingly.’ So he said, I don’t, he told
Me, ‘I don’t know how they get over this
protectiveness.’ They just go headlong into
it, anything, you know, a love affair with
any unknown girl, they’ll sleep with anyone.
How can they do it? They don’t even think
whether it is right or wrong. That’s what
is true, that to introspect and see for yourself
whether it is good or bad, is very important.
Now also we have some national problems. Different
nationality has different problems, but in
Sahaja Yoga I think we are washed of all these
things. I’ve known some people who were
drug addicts. The first seven who came to
Me, out of them four were drug addicts and
they told Me they couldn’t see Me. They
were just lights coming out of Me, that’s
all. Some sort of a miraculous photographs
they had become, I think, and they couldn’t
see Me in one person. And one came and just
was there like a coma, she was sitting like
this. So difficult and one of them was a professor
of physics from Australia. I don’t know
where he has disappeared. This fellow, he
was a professor of physics from Cambridge
and so much in the drug that I asked him,
I said, “What’s your name?” So he went
on, ‘Ah, ah.’ I said, “I asked you what’s
your name.” ‘Ah, you asked me my name?’
I said, “I did ask you.” ‘My name, You
said what is my name?’ I said, “Yes, I
did say what is your name.” Went on for
five minutes. He could not come to terms with
his name even. I said, “What sort of this
drug addiction is there? [There is some word
but not clear] It’s too much. But then he
got all right. He improved a lot and he was
just dying with liver, but he got all right.
I took him home, treated him. He was all right.
So, you see, with such dull brains, you think
this drug definitely harms — really definitely
harms the brain cells because the way I have
seen, after coming to Sahaja Yoga, they got
Realization, very intelligent people. Some
were PhDs. I call them PHD-MADs, you see.
And all of them, these PhDs and MADs, were
so much harmed, so much harmed. I asked them,
“You’re such intelligent, educated people,
why did you take to drugs — for experience
of what?” ‘Experience of spirituality.’
I said, “Who told you?” Some guru told
them or somebody told them, but I said, “In
India nobody would think that these drugs
can give you spirituality.” He said, ‘No.
Such and such guru came from there and he
told us that you take to — drugs and you’ll
be spiritual.’
I mean people like Rajneesh who try — means
all these gurus knew that if you tell them
something that are the weaknesses of human
beings they’ll take to it, easily. Not in
India. If Freud had come to India — I tell
you, I don’t know. He would have been cut
into pieces perhaps. Nobody would have tolerated
a nonsense like that, the way he was talking
about the mother’s love.
So all such people have been accepted blindly,
all over. See you, not only in America, but
also in this thing, U.K., there was one boy
who came to Me who was the disciple of this
fourteen year old gentleman, Guru Maharaji,
and he was actually on potato diets. So I
said, “Why are you on potato diet?” ‘Because
my guruji has said that if you give me a Rolls
Royce, then only I come to England.’ He
already had, I think, fifty-three or something.
‘ So we have to give him a Rolls Royce,
so we are on a potato diet. We are saving
money.’ I said, “Why are you doing that
— saving money for potatoes? Out of potatoes,
how much are you saving?” He said, ‘We
are saving quite a lot and we are sure at
the end of this year we’ll have lots of
money to buy a Rolls Royce.’ “Wah, Wah.”
But I said, “Why are you doing it? You see,
why do you want to give him money? Why do
you want to give a Rolls Royce?” He said,
‘Because, you see, this Rolls Royce is just
metal, but he’s going to give us the spirit.’
“Which spirit?”
I really — this fellow was ultimately died,
you see. This one died because I don’t know
what harm they do to people, but Rajneesh
was using all kinds of dirty tricks and people
took to it and that is why I want to tell
you that you should all be very careful. Also
among Sahaja Yogis we had some problem in
Melbourne. Somebody came from Portugal and
he learned certain things from Nepal and he
did some tricks there. So, among us also,
maybe somebody who thinks that he should show
that he is a great Sahaja Yogi, take to some
so-called spiritual life and try to create
problems.
So we should not have groups. We should have
no groups. Nothing should be a secret. Everybody
should know what everybody is doing. That
is how collectively will be all right. Because
supposing somebody comes and tells you, ‘All
right, I’ll make you something special and
for that this is to be done.’ It has happened
before with your leaders also, that they use
to tell them in their ears that, ‘Mother
has told me to do this. Mother has told me
to do.’ Never listen to such people. You’ve
got leaders whom you can ask what is good
and what is bad. If not, you can even write
to Me, but don’t listen to such people who
are telling you things just to destroy — destroy
Sahaja Yoga, destroy the only hope for the
whole world. You have to be very, very careful
about it and if you are careful, I am sure,
you have now the insight, you have now the
powers, you have now the authority. Everything
is there, no doubt, but vulnerability is the
problem I sometimes feel. For that you have
to be very, very careful because now, as you
see in Sydney, it started in a very bad way
and now we are so many sensible people sitting
here who are my children of whom I’m very
proud, very proud, but, at the same time,
please try to understand that you are surrounded
by vultures actually and the whole atmosphere
is full of such things because I see your
newspapers, I see your media and I am really
shocked. Much worse than you could see in
India, though in India also these things have
come now. The Western life is coming there
and many people are taking to it, no doubt,
but only in big cities and very few people
who’re suppose to be very rich or elite,
they try to do all this. This will all go
away, I’m sure, one day.
Then another point is, apart from your family,
your children, where normally people are glued
into, you are Sahaja Yogis. You are not only
for your family, for your country, but for
the whole world. Then attention should be
on all such things. For example, I read about
what is happening in Johannesburg or in Natal
and how the people are massacred there and
what they are doing there. I was very disturbed,
couldn’t sleep — very disturbed — and
I decided this year I must go to South Africa.
Also Yugoslav is another problem where these
stupid Muslims are killing themselves. All
their funny ideas are working out in such
a disastrous way that they must die now in
the name of God, so after the Qiyamah comes
in, the Resurrection time comes in, they’ll
come out of their graves and they’ll get
Resurrection. Such stupid ideas are also for
Christians, for Muslims and also for Jews.
Now, imagine those who die five hundred years
back, what will come out of their graves?
But the sensible idea is from Nav Damyan Vyakhayan
that all the souls will be born again and
there will be population problem, but they’ll
be born again. Souls will take forms and they
will seek their Realization and many will
get Realization, which is a very sensible
thing to say that the souls, not the body,
from the graves and that’s why they were
occupying such a lot of land all over, that
in Spain, what they do is to put the dead
bodies in rocks like this. They cut a piece
and push it there, one after another. They
go on pushing all these coffins inside a rock
like that, all over. I was wondering what
is this made like this, like a drawers, you
know. In these drawers they put it and they
push it in. They’re all dead there and they’re
all going to come out when there will be Resurrection
time and all of them are going to get their
Realization. That’s why these people, Muslims
in sari jagaha [Mother speaks in Hindi means
“everywhere”], you can call it the Yugoslav,
Yugoslavia, they are killing themselves, stupidly.
Also they have no wisdom to see that this
is wrong. How can it be that our dead bodies
will come out?
(Mother speak aside ).
So now our attention should be global. If
Sahaja Yogis put their attentions, you see,
global, you don’t know your powers, how
important it is. Just put your attention now,
say, to South Africa in the Natal where they
are having all these problems of suppression.
It will help — very much help, you don’t
know. Things will subside because through
you this all-pervading power, Paramchaitanya,
will focus itself there. You are the one who
can focus. You should have your global attention
there and you should see for yourself very
serious problem. I’m doing on My Own whatever
is possible. For that you must read newspapers,
but not all the nonsense of the newspaper,
but see where is the problem is, what is happening.
Because you’re in Sydney, but you’re responsible
for the whole world. Wherever you are, you
are responsible for the whole world.
Now there’s a very good thing that has happened
in Russia. I don’t know if you have that
paper with you? Russian paper? No. You have
that?
And see the Russian University of St. Petersburg
which is the oldest in Asia, perhaps oldest
in the whole world, has got now only ten people
as member of their Academy and one of them
is Me, I’m surprised. So — so when they
applied — you see, they applied for My membership,
they wrote — I can’t read it — it’s
too much for Me. They wrote, you see, this
application and why, I mean, saying that I
should be appointed as one of the members.
Einstein is one of the members, can you imagine.
I was surprised that they have put Me with
Einstein. And I was quite ashamed, though
it was done. So they said, ‘What? What is
Einstein? What has he done? He is just working
with the matter, but You have worked with
human beings, You see.’ So, can you read
it out?
A gentleman reads the letter:
‘This is addressed to the Presidium of the
Peter’s Academy of Arts and Sciences. It’s
the official presentation of Shri Mataji Nirmala
Devi for election as an Honored Member of
the Academy. Mrs. Nirmala Srivastava, Doctor
of Philosophy and Medicine, a Distinguished
Authority on the fields of Religion, Philosophy
and Science, by Her noble activity does very
much to promote happiness and friendship of
Indian and Russian peoples and all the nations
of the world. She was always regarding our
land as a center of the world’s spirituality
and morality, center of rapprochement, people
of Western Orient, the centre of the revival
of sublime ideals which have been put forth
by Russians and many other nations of Russia.
Being the founder of the elevating teaching
of Sahaja Yoga, Mrs. Nirmala Devi Srivastava
absolutely, reliably connects physical and
psychic health of a man with the mode of his
life and morality. Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi
was born in 1923 on the 23 rd ( Error in the
birthdate …to check was it in the original
letter ) of March in Chindwara, central part
of India in the noble Christian family. Having
revealed Her extraordinary abilities already
in childhood, later She got the high medical
education and took an active part in the struggle
for the National Independence of India. In
1947 She married Mr. Srivastava and now They
have two daughters. Sir C.P. Srivastava for
sixteen years occupied the post of General
Secretary of the International Naval Organization
of the United Nations, having been unanimously
elected for this post three times in succession,
now he is the honored General Secretary of
this agency. During the elections to the Prime
Minister of India, Sir Srivastava held office
of General Secretary. He was rewarded by thirty-four
awards of different countries. The Queen of
England marked his retirement, granting him
honorary title of Knight-Commander of the
Order of Saint Michael and Saint George. Mrs.
Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi and Mr. C.P. Srivastava,
considering the Russian people to be spiritual
and pure, see in our Motherland the center
of spiritual revival of the world. Being absolutely
sincere from the bottom of my heart, I recommend
to the Presidium of Peter’s Academy of Arts
and Sciences to elect Shri Mataji Nirmala
Devi to be an Honored Member of our Academy.’
“And this was spoken by the Vice-President
of Peter’s Academy of Arts and Sciences,
Mr. Varanov.”]
Talk restarts from here:
Very nice man. He even came to My Puja. Can
you imagine? He did the Puja and gave Me some
very nice present also and I told him that
I have never graduated in science or philosophy
or anything, so he said, ‘ That’s why
You are so great.’ I said, “Why?” ‘Because
none of the discoverers have ever been to
colleges, or university.’ Very nice person,
very nice and he’s willing to come to India
any time you want.
Then I met another personality who is called
as Ayatollah, means the person in charge of
Religion. His name was Rohani Ayatollah and
Rohani Ayatollah is a gentleman — Ruhani.
“Ruha” means this all-pervading power
or spiritual. So he was in charge of Religion
when the - there was this rule of the King
and afterwards he had to run away from there
and he came to Paris and settled down there.
Now, his younger brother is also an Irani,
is voted for becoming the new President of
Iran. So this old one, the one who is a very
strict and, you can say, a very fundamentalist
type, he arrested those six families which
supported him and took a affidavit from them
saying that ‘No, they are not going to support
him.’ But, if you all put your attention
to it, he might be, he might be elected and
if he’s elected that’s the saving of the
Muslims there because they’re Shia people
and this Rohani gentleman is so wonderful.
He touched My Feet and he danced when he got
his Realization.
I mean, some things are happening which are
so much of a joy. Even in My country I find
— India — that there’s a big recognition
of Sahaja Yoga and which is so obvious that
people are recognizing the purity of Sahaj
Yoga.
Let us see how far we can go. But in Brazil
also they have — the President of the Senate
called Me, got his Realization, he was very
happy. He called his secretary, everybody,
asked them to get their Realization and then
they sent — you see, they said that Brasilia
is what they have selected, is the one is
depicted by some philosophers as this center
of spirituality. And when they came, he called
all other people also and their Vice-President
was there. The President was already impeached.
So this Vice-President, I never liked him.
I said, “Funny person he is.” And then
he was arrested.
So, so many things — like Italy also — lots
of things are happening. Maybe all this might
just change the atmosphere. You know about
Marcus who was in Vienna, who troubled us
so much, did so much against us in the newspaper
and all that? This Marcus fellow, I don’t
know what has gone wrong with him or he’s
come round. Now, he’s saying that you can
live in this Ashram for two years without
paying any rent. I’ll also give you money
that you can purchase a land. Afterwards,
you can leave the house and he says, ‘The
maya was too much for me and I got lost. I
hope I’ll be back again in Ganapatipule.’
Can you imagine.
So all such things are happening and it’s
tremendous because you can’t expect a person
like Marcus coming around like that, you see.
So Sahaja Yoga is showing its own success
and you all can add to it. You have seen among,
among yourselves only, there are so many beautiful
people who come out of lot of troubles. All
troubles can be overcome. There’s no problem
about it. Only thing, one has to be sincere
and attached to Sahaja Yoga. You may be a
family man, you might be a father, mother,
anything, but first and foremost thing, you
are a Sahaja Yogi.
I tell you about Myself also. You know I have
a family. I have My husband and all that and
whenever, you see, it was needed, I always
said, “Sahaja Yoga first.” Even money-wise,
I would say that, if you have to spend any
money, then spend on Sahaj Yoga. So the first
thing was Sahaja Yoga. All these are secondary,
all your art, all your business, all your
music or whatever line of life you take, is
a second. The first and foremost thing is
Sahaja Yoga and you get in that everything,
but should do it very sincerely, respectfully.
If you think you are not in it, then you better
understand that if you’re not in it, you
cannot be there. You have to be fully into
it, you see. So either you are in the sea
or you are outside. It’s like that. And
this will give you the greatest pleasure,
the greatest fulfillment of life. I can see
that’s happening now and I’m very happy
and, as I said, I’m very proud of you. It
should happen everywhere and with all My love
I bless you that you all should really become
great Sahaja Yogis, very, very great Sahaja
Yogis and you’ll be all known all over the
world.
May God bless. So thank you very much.