Yesterday’s experience was that
the whole day I had to spend it
with police people explaining to them.
And now I feel that in Maharashtra,
there is a rule of Mafia.
And that it is for us to face it
and we have to prove it.
I am sorry some people were hurt
so badly
and I'll think after Puja they’ll take
you to the hospital.
Here there is a very nice hospital where
we have very good doctors.
And then I would request you
to know that,
the evil and the good, always has
to struggle and fight.
Formerly in this great country of
Maharashtra all the saints were tortured,
to such an extent that it is amazing
how despite all that
they kept the banner of spirituality
so high.
They are still existing, the same people,
who have tortured the saints and I think
they are the same people
who have behaved in such a bad manner
towards you all.
This kind of ego-trip builds up
in everyone
– even in among sahaja yogis, it does
build up.
And they are all the time
on a different scene.
This is like Hitler's style of behavior
that you pick up some sort of an issue.
An issue could be anything, like they
are saying that
“we are trying to remove all the blind
faiths”. I mean,
I've done this for eighteen years,
what can they do more than that?
And I have removed all your blind faiths
in all kinds of stupid things
that the religion, so-called, was teaching
you.
In every religion, there is no question
of only Hindu religion.
But here they dare not say anything
about the Muslims
because the Hindus are very mild people.
They (the muslims) want that
all the temples must be removed,
all the deities must be thrown away.
This is all I think Rajneesh is their guru
because he made a...
he made an exhibition where he tried
to show
that Ganapati was something very funny
and all that.
Now medically you know in Sahaja Yoga,
that without Ganesha we cannot cure
many diseases. Is a fact.
So a stupid fellow talking like that,
has become now the guru of these people
who are discarded all over the world
and who have been insulted.
So these few newspapers have made
him as a guru, perhaps that
they are following his methods of saying
that we should be,
we should be rid of all these ideas
and this and that.
But they have gone to the extent that
all the spirituality is an illusion.
It's such a joke. And that we should
give up
all the, all readings and all understanding
about spirituality.
But they do not know that their heritage
is spirituality.
And the whole world depends on that.
The whole world, because when the people
took to industrial development,
you know how far they have gone
and how much they are lost.
And how far you were in that mess.
And how you came back
because of Sahaja Yoga’s spirituality.
Now if this nourishment from the roots
of spirituality
does not reach the West, the real
knowledge, as it is in Sahaja Yoga,
the West will be finished. West will be
finished, you know that very well.
There is no joy, there is no love,
there is no poetry,
there is no music, there is no culture.
But as you have understood that now
these people have now started
talking about “no religion”
“no religion”,
like many of your western countries
have also done,
specially Russia has done that way,
that there is nothing like God,
there is nothing like this and that.
And now after all that now they
are coming to God.
So now we’ll have to go through
another circle.
But they are only hardly twenty people.
So even one fellow who is like Hitler,
can destroy the whole thing.
This is a very important thing - to destroy
something you need only one person.
But to sustain and to construct
you need many people.
To drown a ship, you need only
one hole in it.
But to build the ship, you take months
together.
So the work that is done for these
last eighteen years
of Sahaja Yoga, is really tremendous.
And the truth about it, you know
for definite,
that it has helped so many people. Though
we have been going from ups and downs
and all that, we've been doing wrong
things, no doubt about it,
but still, now we are quite established
and we know what Sahaja Yoga is.
The experience of Sahaja Yoga you all
have had. We have seen so many,
(towards someone…) “What is she doing?
Please be seated”.
Miraculous photographs you have seen,
so many miracles in your life day to day.
Every day there are miracles. Now to say
there is no God
is impossible for you because you have
felt the miracles
of this All-pervading Power,
the Paramchaitanya.
And also all the religions are explained
and the complete integration of them
has been brought in.
But for that we have to know, as I told
you in Brahmapuri,
that the sahaja yogis have to know that
they have to become dynamic.
Whatever energies you have got, whatever
you have achieved within yourselves,
is not sufficient enough. You have
to manifest.
And in that dynamism, I think people
get lost.
I have seen that some leaders become
horrid.
I mean, sometimes their Vishuddhis could
be horrible, then their heart goes out.
So you should not allow anybody (to be)
a leader for more than one month.
It goes off. I have seen it. Because your
balloon has been already bloated
and again it gets re-bloated in no time.
(speaking in Marathi…).
They have religiously kept all the Indians
outside, I think. (speaking in Marathi…).
I mean, he is the organizer here.
(speaking Marathi)
So the heritage of our country is
spirituality.
And this is the nourishment.
Only the one-sided growth in the West, due
to machinery or whatever you may call it,
has ruined it completely.
And one-sided growth in this country,
and all such countries,
where religion has become a blind faith,
has also ruined it.
But in the center lies Sahaja Yoga.
Now your wisdom, your sense,
is so apparent.
I mean, people have been to all kinds
of gurus here and have been to everyone,
but they don’t know anything about
anything. Except for remembering by heart
- some these Hare Ramas, talk about,
“Rama” “Rama” – like that.
While you know everything about Kundalini.
You know how to raise it.
You know how to give Realization. You know
what are the diseases are caused,
how to cure it and everything and
everything and everything.
I mean, it has come to such a stage
that nobody asks Me any questions.
Otherwise, in the beginning in London,
My lecture was for five minutes
and the questions were for the rest
of the time.
So now you know so much.
And you accept which cannot be explained
also, because you know that.
For example, somebody will ask Me,
“Mother, how do you get these photographs?”
Why are we talking about it?
I know how it happens, who is doing
this trick. But I don’t want to tell you.
Moreover, if you demand something,
I’ll never tell you.
That’s one of the characters I have.
Ah, if you come with humble thing
and honest desire to know,
then I can tell you about everything,
that you want to know.
But if you just want to force Me and say
that, “I challenge you”,
I said, “I also challenge you.
Get out of here”.
Like that. You see, it doesn’t react,
that way.
So it is just the temperament
of the Divine
that if you are convex, the Divine
becomes convex also,
and fights and says, “No, get out”.
If you become concave,
then it emits and gives knowledge,
or receives knowledge.
So one has to be humble. That’s very
important part of it. One has to be humble.
So the awareness, again I talk about
awareness,
within you should be that, how much
we have come to know about ourselves.
How much we have to come to know
about others?
How much we know about our own being?
How much we know about chakras?
In such a short time, how did we come
to know about it?
Like we should know, if you are dealing
with a computer,
and you know how computer works, how
it acts, how it is programmed, everything
without programming it, without working
it out, without building it up.
I mean, if you build it up, you know
how it works. But without doing that
just to know a computer how it works,
and all the machinery about it,
is a tremendous knowledge.
And this is what has to be there
for all of us
to know what we are there as human beings,
and what we have to do
to emancipate the other human beings.
Of course, I shouldn’t say that every
sahaja yogi is of that level, no.
Or comes up, but everybody is trying.
Nobody has denied Sahaja Yoga.
Nobody has said it’s not true. Everybody
is trying to get
higher and higher in his state
of spirituality which doesn’t speak.
It acts. It doesn’t manipulate. It acts.
And we've seen it acts in so many
miraculous ways.
So first to know about all these things,
after feeling that Paramchaitanya,
is different from just to talk about it.
Many have talked about it, but you have
never felt it.
Now you have felt it, you have verified it,
you have experimented it.
And you have found it that, this is
something absolutely real.
In science, as Dr. Khan was telling Me,
that in science,
the one theory which is established today
might be refuted tomorrow.
Another theory that is established,
may be refuted.
It goes on. So that no theory is
an absolute theory.
But in Sahaja Yoga for the last eighteen
years, whatever I have been saying
is the truth. And is absolute. It cannot
be challenged again.
Nobody can say, “No, Mother,
it is not so”.
A simple thing is, somebody comes to you
and you say, the other day it happened,
one doctor was there in Aurangabad,
and he said that,
“I have never had any guru”. But his left
Swadhistana…
and he was looking very disturbed. He was
a sahaja yogi in a way,
not looking normal. “I have pain
in the stomach,” and this and that.
I asked him, “You had no guru?”,
he said, “No”. (speaking Marathi).
So now as science has progressed
we can see clearly
that it has not got the theory
which is absolute.
But in Sahaja Yoga, as I told you,
there was a gentleman, a doctor,
who was denying, he said, “I had no guru”.
I asked him, “Do you read books?”,
“Yes – he said - I read Vivekananda”.
I said, “That’s it”.
He said he was reading the book
of a particular guru.
We gave a bandhan to that guru
and this fellow felt alright.
There are so many things one has to know
about.
Little, little things are there, which must
be understood in Sahaja Yoga.
And one should do it according to them,
because it is for your benevolence.
Now supposing I say, “Just do these
things”. If you don’t accept Me,
why am I telling you? I am not telling you
because I have to gain anything.
But is for your good. Now if you don’t
want to accept me or if you react,
is not going to help you. Sahaja Yoga
is not for Me, is for you.
Now if you are, truthfully, honestly,
if you are seekers,
then you must know that "My aim
is to rise spiritually".
Now in science you have risen quite a lot,
you are fed up with it.
Now you’re back into spirituality
and for spirituality you have to be
a subtler person.
And for these subtleties you have
to give up all your conditionings.
All funny conditionings are to be given
and the worst that you have,
is the ego part. It just jumps up. I have
seen that appointing people leaders
has been the greatest harmful thing
I have done to them.
So many of them just got lost, because
they became leaders.
I mean, a kind of a Hitler, enters
into them.
So this is one of the worst conditionings
we have.
We have to be very careful that we don’t
try to assert our ego on others.
When we become leaders or a some position
is given to us,
or ask something is to be achieved
through your authority.
Only we have the authority of God.
Unless and until we become humble
like that, nothing is going to flow.
You can see that, that the sea lies
the lowest in height.
And all the rivers and everything flows
to the sea.
And from the sea only rises the rain.
Supposing sea was somewhere on top
of Himalayas,
we would have been all living
in the Sahara desert.
Is a very simple thing, is to be humble
- that’s first sign - is to be humble,
is to be non-violent, because we depend
on the All-pervading Power.
It is a power which is completely
integrated within us.
Only we are not the ones, we want
to be aware of it.
So this ignorance, this blindness,
if it disappears from us,
that Divine Power will manifest.
But our styles are so complicated.
Sometimes I just don’t understand,
why we have complicated ourselves
so much.
I mean, look at the flowers, look at
the leaves; they are on a tree, supposing.
Automatically they will open out
to the sun. Automatically.
You don’t have to take a leaf towards
the sun, not at all.
Automatically it opens out. You have
seen it every day.
Automatically. Because it requires sun.
Now you want to have spirit in yourself.
You want to get to spirit.
So automatically you should, really
automatically, if that is your desire,
you should, with your own desire only,
should get to the light of the spirit.
And should grow in that spirit to know
that this is what you have to achieve.
But small things disturb you,
like somebody doesn’t get married. Next
day you see the face of that person,
as if somebody has died in the family
he is sitting there.
Really, I have seen it. Immediately I make
out who has not been yet engaged.
Then after marriage I find again
the same sort of nonsense.
Because they are analyzing, “I want
this kind, I want that kind. I want”.
I mean, whatever is available here
is available.
Like on the ship, you don’t have any
problems, because you have no solutions.
If you are moving on a ship and you
just ask for something,
“Oh no, not available here,” finished.
But then you lose all the fun of Sahaja
Yoga for a small little nonsensical thing.
If not this, next year. What is
so important?
I mean, certain there are limitations
of age, height, this, that.
Then even if you arrange their marriages,
is very interesting,
then they come and tell you, “No, no,
I would not like to marry this girl”.
Why? “Because I want such and such”.
All right, then we find.
“No, no, no, she is no good. She has
these things,” so move that.
I mean this is not the way. You are not
here to choose a girl for yourself.
Then there is another one who can say,
“All right, I came down, I saw one girl
and fell in love”. So you fall in love
and get out. This nonsense going on.
See, you must have certain amount
of dignity. You are all sahaja yogis.
And when I see all this kind
of stupid attitude,
I say these people can never gain
in Sahaja Yoga.
In India you will be surprised. I mean,
even I was married to a man who was
from another, another place.
Absolutely different country, different
religion, different everything.
And a different person.
So one can say that it was a very
unconventional marriage, one can say.
But I would never touch this man
or he would never touch me.
And if he would talk to me,
in the presence of others only.
And despite that, our marriage is very
strong and we are very happy couple.
With all these nonsense you go on doing,
bringing it to the level
of physical appearances, physical
understanding, your ego,
“I want this, I want that”, you find that
just after the marriage you get off.
You start analyzing. That’s why
I am telling you today.
I may not able to talk to you about
marriages later on. That be careful.
And that’s how you have brought
problems to Me.
You see, once you accept that in Sahaja
Yoga you are going to marry,
then you must accept that Sahaja Yoga
has its own norms and styles
by which it will marry you and will look
after your marriage and will bless you.
But if you start analyzing
and misbehaving,
it’s not going to work out, and you
will have lots of problems.
Either you believe in the All-pervading
Power and surrender your ego to it,
or else you have your ego.
Sahaja Yoga is decided by Me,
by Paramchaitanya.
Now sometimes in Sahaja Yoga it may
happen that, maybe, it may not work out.
But invariably I have seen, invariably,
is none of My faults. None of My faults.
Mostly the leaders have given wrong
information,
mostly the leaders didn’t talk about
the, about the background.
Or maybe that there has been some sort
of an ego-trip with the people,
and they are the ones who are creating
problems for us.
But things work out. Slowly, gradually
we can improve. We must have patience.
If only on first day you start demanding
something doing that,
it’s not going to work out.
We must learn to give, in marriage
it’s an adjustment of giving.
It is no adjustment of demand.
We have to give. We have to sacrifice.
What is there with you to sacrifice is
all these rubbish things.
Your spirit you cannot sacrifice,
so you keep to your spirit.
And live with it. What is you going
to sacrifice?
I mean, what do you have to give?
And then only you will enjoy.
Then only you will enjoy the spirit.
I am getting cool breeze from you.
So I want you to be very great sahaja
yogis, very great.
And you should really manifest
your powers of wisdom.
Now men have ego part and women
have another side,
is that they are very dull sometimes.
Extremely dull.
They don’t think they have to play a very
dynamic role, while they are the shaktis.
Like they will not even clap hands,
they will not even have their torches
to see what’s happening. Nothing. They just
think they are just a, sort of parasites.
Just coming here as wives or sisters,
or whatever it is, wearing saris.
No, you have to be extremely dynamic.
You must know all about Sahaja Yoga.
You must know all about chakras.
You should know everything. In India,
when in the ancient times,
they used to teach them about God,
religion and all that.
So many great ladies we had, Gargi
and Maitreyi and all those,
who were very learned women.
So in no way you should be just women who
do not know anything of Sahaja Yoga.
Sahaja Yoga is not only meant for men;
it’s meant for you, much more for you.
Because you are shakti and I am your
Mother. So I find the women lack that.
They are more worried about the saris,
the this and that, and I mean,
now from the hair-dressing they have
come to saris. That’s what I feel.
Well, it’s just the same.
Of course sari is a very good dress.
It’s nice to wear.
By that we give lot of encouragement
to our weavers in India.
It’s very artistic, and good that
represents also
a very lady-like feminine thing. But that
doesn’t mean you should become so feminine
that you don’t understand Sahaja Yoga.
I have seen women don’t know where
the centers are of the feet.
Indian women know. Men do know….
Indian women know,
but the Western women don’t know,
so many of them.
They don’t know about chakras. They don’t
know how to raise the Kundalini.
They don’t know what’s the problem is.
So once you have left that life, where
you are wearing a sari,
doesn’t mean now that you have become
a woman in the gosha.
Gosha is the one where they have to wear
chadar; chadar, they call it.
No, sari means you can also be
very dynamic.
The same sari that you are wearing,
even the saris of the nine yards,
we have had queens who fought
the English.
You have must heard about Jhansi Ki Rani.
She was hardly of any age.
She jumped from eighty feet height with
her child behind her. She was a widow.
And she fought the English. Left and right.
And when she was killed,
the person who was here, the Englishman,
he said, the governor,
he said, “We have won the war but
the glory goes to Jhansi ki Rani.”
Then we had another one, Chand-bibi,
another lady, in a ...
Ahmednagar; she fought. We had
so many women like that.
Tremendous type of women we had,
though they lived like women.
We had Padmini, we had Noorjahan,
we had Ahilyabai, so many women.
They were not manly at all.
Very woman-like.
There was the last one was Shivaji’s,
Shivaji’s daughter-in-law.
She was only seventeen years of age,
seventeen years.
And she fought this Aurangzeb and she
is the one who defeated him.
Nobody could manage this Aurangzeb
horrible fellow, she defeated him.
So though, you see, the Indian women look
so docile and simple,
but when it comes to their personality,
they are capable of tremendous things.
So this character when you are wearing
the saris you must also know how to tie up
the backside and to fight.
Otherwise you have not got the Sahaj
culture in you.
Either you are very dominating or you are
so docile like cabbages.
You must understand that we have
to be alert, very alert.
And Mother depends on us. On our own
personalities,
that the way we are going to develop
ourselves, our children, our husbands,
our society of Sahaja Yoga, the whole
of Vishwa Nirmal Dharma.
Is the woman who makes the society.
The whole universe is in the hands
of a woman who creates children.
So the stupid ideas of romanticism
and all this nonsense,
has to be finished. The possession
of husband –
“What time you came,” “When did you go,”
“Where did you go,”
and here the women when Shivaji
started his fight
they used to cut their finger, thumb,
and used to put the tika
on the forehead of the husbands who
were going in the war
and they said, “Don’t come showing
your back”.
Such great women we have had
in this Maharashtra,
where you find them to be so mild.
If it comes to their country, if it comes
to their own personality,
to their own chastity or anything, they are
tremendous. Just like lionesses.
So with this sari lots of things go
hand in hand.
Is not only the sari you are wearing,
but you are representing
something very dynamic within
yourself.
Now when we talk about our further
programs
people are insisting that we should have
a program in any case in Kolhapur.
But I told them I’ll not allow sahaja yogis
to go there
because they were hurt so badly. But some
of you can come, not all of you.
I would be rather worried. I don’t think
anybody will hurt you
and they are saying they will make
arrangements.
So if you want to come, if you are
not afraid...
But on one promise. That nobody is going
to beat anyone.
I am saying, “Don’t beat. Don’t beat”
and somebody heard, “Beat”.
I mean, I mean, I have never heard such
sort of thing, when I am saying
on the thing that, “Don’t beat.
Don’t beat,”
then somebody hears that, “Beat them.
Beat them”.
I just don’t understand how can
(that be).
So you don’t have to, really, you don’t
have to beat anyone.
There is no need. You know that
there is Paramchaitanya working.
All this is also the work
of Paramchaitanya. In the afternoon,
Yogi Mahajan was discussing with Me
very seriously like a lawyer,
saying that, “Mother we cannot form
a criminal case on them,
because there is no evidence”. Afternoon.
And in the evening we have evidence now.
And then they are writing in the other way
round, that they were beaten up
and that you threw stones at them.
And none of them were injured.
They must have been vibrated stones,
I think.
How can you? They had no injuries. They
wrote it down they've no injuries.
So there is no need for you to bother
about it.
With all that there were at least more
than four hundred stones that came
and only eighteen people got hurt. And
really seriously, I think, one or two.
So there is nothing and I can cure
all of you, [you] know that very well.
On the whole, you see this country,
especially Maharashtra,
is so full of devotion to God.
Like these things are not going to work
out. But they are very dangerous people
like Hitler, you see, they start moving
about and giving some ideas and all that.
So it is better to finish them at the time
when they are just prospering,
as they call themselves Nirmulan,
is to remove the roots.
So we have to do the Nirmulan
of Nirmulan.
All right. So now today we'll have
the puja.
Then after that if you want you can go
to Kolhapur for your purchase.
But it starts, the shops starts quite late
and will keep quite late till eight
and tomorrow the whole day is available
for you. So you can take your buses.
You can go down there, and you can have
your purchase and all that,
then come back here. Tomorrow also
you can do the same.
Day after tomorrow, our Mr. Govind has
very kindly invited you all to his place,
as it is he is an extremely generous man.
So,
and when I told him that, “You must
take money from Me”,
he was just fighting with Me, “Mother,
give me this first chance.
This is my great honor that…(speaking
Marathi and Hindi to someone)
So… Let them come, if they want to come.”
So then the program is that day
after tomorrow,
after this thing he says it will be over
by 12:30 or one′o clock.
So you will have tonight and tomorrow
full day for your shopping.
But I think then you should not bother
more about shopping.
Whatever you have to do, better finish
tomorrow.
And then you have to come
to the program also.
Day after if you linger on then it will
be very difficult.
So all of you should go there, have your
food, and then go to Ganapatipule.
This is the program. So you reach
Ganapatipule in the evening.
I hope it’s all clear to you.
And whatever you want to buy, you have
to buy here. But I would say
that some of you are really, really
do not know what is real silk is.
And I've seen some people buying
something horrid.
And very thin silk you should not buy
because it will last only for eight days.
And then it will be finished. So don’t go
for cheap things.
One sari which is good sari, silk sari,
is better than ten bad saris.
Luckily now we have some saris that you
wanted for, the printed saris
which I can give you in Ganapatipule.
Nice printed saris,
of the tassar and also silk. We’ll have
them there. You can all buy, there.
Anything else?
Because I don’t think I’ll meet you any
more perhaps till we go to Ganapatipule.
Now also if you could get those
bhajan things, please buy.
I have given you presents twice. But you
never bring them on your tour
and this time again, I don’t want to get
this kind of a thing. (Hindi).
Just show them. Anything of this kind,
please get it. Is very important.
I have given you twice as presents
but it’s very difficult every time
to go to the shop and get it for you.
If you can get them please buy.
Some of you should at least have them.
(speaking marathi to someone)
He will organize, you better purchase.
Now all the marriages practically have
been decided. One or two are left,
which he has also adjusted. Now those who
were over age or something like that,
we could not arrange their marriages.
Doesn’t matter.
It may work out, it may not work out.
After all, you are in Sahaja Yoga. I mean,
you are really married to Sahaja Yoga,
that’s all. This is something sideways,
you see.
So don’t make very, your life
miserable,
so all the way you have come, to know
that you are not ...
we have not been able to arrange
your marriage. It’s not proper.
Just enjoy. Don’t miss the point.
May God bless you.