Warren: They are just asking questions, Mother.
Shri Mataji: What kind? Warren: Just practical.
Shri Mataji: Practical? That’s good,
practical questions are very good.
Warren: Would you like to talk to them for a while?
Shri Mataji: First I talk to them and then
ask the questions.
I am overjoyed to see you all here.
Actually the whole night I was working
on Melbourne seekers,
that they should come today and
should establish their realisation very well.
Now we have to understand
a few things about Sahaja Yoga very clearly
and there is no compromise on these few things
that we have to accept.
Because, as I told you,
Truth cannot compromise for you,
you have to compromise for Truth.
So the first is that
Sahaja Yoga is not just a precept,
is not just a precept:
it is practice.
It is not just a mental idea.
Now you got realisation, all right,
but it is not sufficient.
Even if you think that you got realisation so, now,
you are all right, you become the Spirit,
all right; but still, it is more a mental conception
than a real identification.
So it is not that
if you get your realisation, and you start the
awakening of your Kundalini, starts very well.
Still, it is
to be understood that it is the practice of Sahaja Yoga
which is more important than the precept of it.
There are many people in India
who can’t read or write,
who don’t have all these mental activities as you have
and are not so complicated as you are;
some of them are aboriginal people,
just living in the villages, very simple people.
They get realisation,
they feel the joy much faster than the complicated ones will
and they just start working on it. You have to work it out.
This is not the compassion that speaks, talks,
elaborates and advertises, but it works.
Sahaja Yoga is a thing that works, the religion that works.
And this is what we must understand first of all,
that it is not the talking, it is not the
precept that you are a great soul:
you have to become.
Not that you are not, you are. But you have to be aware of it.
More light has to flow into you.
Definitely, you must be something special to get it, no doubt.
But you must allow
your lamp to be cleared out,
cleansed, so that more light is given.
And it works wonders for people
who honestly want to ascend
in spirituality.
As I told you before also that it is a concept
many people have that Sahaja Yoga cures people.
It is not true.
It is just as a by-product it may cure you;
just as a by-product.
So one must understand the blessing has come to you
only because
you are a seeker,
you have done a lot of good in your past life and this life also
and that God has chosen you to be in His Kingdom.
But it cannot be demanding, you cannot demand,
you cannot demand anything from God,
He has to give you because He knows what you deserve.
And He gives you much, much, much more than what you deserve.
I mean, I have seen people who have been in
Sahaja Yoga that after one year they start asking,
“Mother, what did we do to deserve all this?”.
They just can’t believe it. I said, “Must be something,
you must know there must be something
that the blessings have come to you”.
This is one thing that one has to understand
that you cannot make Sahaja Yoga compromise for you,
you have to understand all the techniques and things
about Sahaja Yoga.
Now the thing could be that you may start doubting,
you see, so that’s what we have people who
are doubting about it and doing all kinds of things; you see,
in the beginning, they are rather slow movers.
So we have to sort them out, to begin with, because the second
stage of awareness is doubtless awareness:
you are doubtless about yourself,
doubtless about the working of Sahaja Yoga,
doubtless about God’s existence,
doubtless about His Laws.
You become absolutely doubtless, not mentally, it’s a state,
it’s a state of your being
by which you achieve lots of
results and you really become powerful:
you can see your compassion so powerful,
so discrete, so understanding,
so forbearing. And you are amazed of yourself,
you really become a saint
in the real sense of the word, that you become humble,
flowering,
beautifully, not taking anything
aggressive upon yourself; and you are really
in the Kingdom of God that you
feel that you are looked after, protected,
guided, blessed, every moment you walk along.
And that’s the state everybody should aspire
to reach this doubtless awareness;
and unless and until you reach that state,
we don’t call you Sahaja Yogi,
you may start calling yourself,
but that’s left to yourself.
There are not sort of… we do not have sort of certification,
or things going on; or we do not give any written
certificates to people, nothing of the kind.
It is you who have to certify yourself.
So gradually people grow up
into beautiful beings.
They start
having their self esteem fully established,
understanding themselves.
But practice of Sahaja Yoga must be done
without thinking too much about it.
First, you just try it, more trying
– because if you start doubting, I tell you,
your progress will be much less.
So first, just like a scientist, to try to
accept one by… there is nothing that has to be done,
you do not have to pay Me anything, of course,
you do not have to do any acrobatics or anything.
But for example a small thing like my photograph, you see,
many people say, “Why Your photograph?”
So “Use your photograph,” I say, if that works out, you see.
It is something surprising: that’s how people challenging Me
“Why Your photograph?”. “Why not use yours?
I will be very happy, use anybody’s”
but doesn’t work out, what to do now?
It’s My photograph that works out, but
even if you do not like it, you have to use it – what can I do?
Is as simple like that, you see,
but in that, I do not gain anything from you,
I do not want anything from you, nothing material
that you can give Me.
But you will enjoy, you will enjoy My love, you will enjoy.
It is all for your own enjoyment, everything is done.
And this is a special time we are born in,
we have a special responsibility.
Today we had a lady who came,
her husband came, and they were saying that
“We had a son who was very well equipped
and he went to one of the gurus and he got completely ruined.”
And this particular guru
we need to be rather careful about, it’s this Rajaneesh fellow.
His disciples are rather difficult.
They come to Sahaja Yoga, all right, but they are a very
extreme type of people.
They come with a great force to Sahaja Yoga, again go back;
so all those who have been to Rajaneesh and have taken his initiation,
have to be extremely careful. All of you who have been to gurus
must know that they will be again and again attacked.
So you need to be rather
patient with yourselves as we are with you,
and must know that you must assert your will power a little bit,
to come up, and shed off all that
was screwed into your head…
and you paid for it, you see. Forget it.
Some time people say that “We have paid for it, so better have it”.
That’s not the way. You’d better through it away.
It is horrible, you have bought a snake on your head, on your neck.
So just through away all these things that they have put
you on.
You all forget it and become your Self, first of all,
and become your own guru. Ask your vibrations,
develop your vibratory awareness and grow with it.
Some people will find also that
their vibrations are not showing
very good results, some of you will find that kind of thing.
And when you find
that your vibrations are not
working out in your hands and
things, you should not get worried about it.
Maybe your Vishuddhi chakra is not all right.
There are ways and methods to
improve your Vishuddhi chakra, by which
you know the exact
mantras to be said
and how to improve it; and we also
vibrated oil and all that, you can apply here.
And also there are other methods
by which you can improve your sinus.
And if you have any problem with the
Vishuddhi because of over-smoking or anything,
there are so many ways
which you can call the
Grandmother’s medicine, simple, simple things
which will work it out, should try to clear out.
So whatever centre is not working out,
you should get after that and
don’t worry about the centres that are
good because those who are good are good.
So we have to look after the centres which are in trouble
and try to improve our centres and
complete being has to be brought into balance.
Some people have some centres
so badly off that,
despite the fact they have all the centres all right,
because of one centre, you see,
they are in imbalance. So, the first thing in Sahaja Yoga
is to establish a balance.
Now certain things about morality and all that,
I do not want to talk to you; gradually your self will realise
what is good for you and bad for you.
But in Sahaja Yoga, you will be given a proper guidance
as to what is to be done, how to lead a life and
how to have a normal, good
married life, how to have children,
how to look after them, how to get to your parents.
So the social side also
you can learn very well by which you really feel happy.
But the main society that you have is that of Sahaja yogis.
Of course, you do not have to cut off from
anyone, you do not have to give up anyone.
But you grow among your
Sahaja yogis, these are called sajñānas, you see.
“Sa-jñāna”, the people
who are the followers of Truth.
So once you come together, it is a collective happening
and it works out more collectively and it helps you much more.
But if you say “Individually,
Mother, I can do it”, it doesn't work out.
In Sahaja Yoga, I have seen, you do not go too far.
You all have to work it together, you have to meet.
Luckily, you have a very good ashram here.
You all can come and meditate and
take a proper help from these people.
God has already blessed this place so much.
And when I came to Melbourne,
I stayed in a very small little house, with, I think,
two bedrooms and some sort of a thing like that.
And this time I find a big, huge thing given to you,
and they may start here also a nice school for
small children here.
Your small children can go to that school
where they can be looked after well,
they won’t have any complications.
And everything can be done at a
much better level
than what you find in mundane life.
Everything has a meaning, spiritual meaning,
everything in life has a meaning!
So you should try to find out whatever is good for your ascent
and for your nourishing
of your spiritual being!
I hope next time when I come,
all of you will be great Sahaja Yogis
and will be great people!
Individually everyone will be working out
on many people, and we have to
change the face of Melbourne completely!
May God Bless you all.
So if you have any questions, you ask Me. Now…
Warren: Mother, there was one gentleman – he asked me a question.
He has got a son at home who's;
he is mentally disturbed. He was asking
how he can deal with that. Because he won’t come.
I suggested that first he and his wife should get it.
This gentleman here, in the suit.
Shri Mataji: What’s the problem exactly? What is it called?
Seeker: Well, schizophrenia.
He was very, very religious once upon a time.
Shri Mataji: Where did he go? To what place?
Warren: What religious cult? What religious group?
Seeker: Well, he belongs to the Catholic religion as I am.
Shri Mataji: What is that?
Warren: Catholic, Mother.
He himself is a Catholic and he is a great believer in Christ.
But his son became …
Seeker: He had a love affair which did not go right.
Shri Mataji: With a? Warren: I am just, I am not interrupting, I am just passing on.
She does not hear you too clearly.
He had a love affair and it did not go right.
Shri Mataji: What is his age?
Seeker: Pardon? Shri Mataji: What is his age?
Warren: Age. Seeker: Twenty-four now.
Shri Mataji: Now I don’t want to criticise Catholicism,
I say because as you are a believer of Christ, it is all right.
But there are certain practices they have taken to,
which are quite injurious to human beings.
Seeker: The thing is he is schizophrenic.
That can happen to any Catholic.
Why? See, the reason I will tell you. Please be seated.
If you listen to Me patiently there,
two things which they do very wrong.
One is to build churches
and then put all the dead bodies in it.
It is absolutely absurd you see,
to have a graveyard in the church. Absolutely.
That is so dangerous. Now I have had many Catholic
people coming to Me.
And they had very big problems with two centres.
One is this back centre and another is left this one.
Of course, left Swadishthana is there because it is unauthorised.
They are not realised souls and they cannot preach about God.
They have no authority to preach about God. Or to baptise anyone.
No human being has got the authority to touch this
precious place without being baptised.
They themselves should be really baptised.
Actualisation of baptism is needed.
You think about it, logically.
Anybody can become a priest you see, and you cannot elect them.
It has to come from God, isn’t it?
So that is one thing that is wrong there.
And another thing they are always caught up
is the left Vishuddhi, is here.
When they do this confession business,
you see – who are these priests to confess to?
Actually, I have seen the priests also go mad.
So many priests have come to Me.
Because the people have confessed
to them. And in that confession, poor
– the priests have gone off their heads.
Because they couldn’t bear it anymore you see.
The kind of confessions people did, that –
“I have murdered someone, I have done this and that”.
And they couldn’t keep it you see;
their conscience couldn’t keep it in themselves.
So one has to face it clearly;
anybody can get mad like that.
I have known people who really got very mad.
So one has to understand that
you must get your realisation first of all.
Seeker: Yeah but Mother, I have noticed when I pray,
it has an influence and
he really calms down.
Shri Mataji: He will. Of course, I agree.
Seeker: He hasn't been cured, but it changes him.
Shri Mataji: Must be. Because if you pray to Christ,
He will definitely help. But not through your church.
What I am saying, must be…
Seeker: I am a believer in Christ. Shri Mataji: That’s all right.
Then it’s all right. But what I am saying, that,
to get a complete connection with God
or with Christ, you have to be born again, isn’t it?
So you must get your realisation. Seeker: Yes.
Shri Mataji: And if you can get your
realisation, you can help your son immensely.
Seeker: That is what I want.
Shri Mataji: So you all must get realisation. All parents
who are interested in their children;
all children who are interested in their parents,
must get their realisation. Seeker: I want to tell you Mother,
that since he became sick four years ago,
I have turned to Christ more than ever.
And I have found very great comfort.
And I have found all the answers.
That is why I want to help You.
Shri Mataji: Yes, but one thing must
be - Seeker: I know that this life is a lie.
The life we are leading is a lie. I know that.
Shri Mataji: So you must get
your realisation and understand Christ
and in a better way, in a fuller way,
in a real way, how He helps you.
Otherwise, you cannot understand Him.
Superficially how far can you go? He’s been kind to you,
but now you have to be
more realistic about it. All right?
Seeker: That is why I wanted to help of you.
Shri Mataji: No, don’t bring your son.
We can work it out. Have you got a photograph of his?
Seeker: I haven’t got it, but I can bring a photograph.
Shri Mataji: You send Me the photograph. All right? I can work…
Seeker: I send you the photograph.
Shri Mataji: Yes, that’s better.
You send Me the photograph, all right.
To our Sydney address. When I'm there…
Seeker: You'll be going. I will give it to one of your - Shri Mataji: No, no. You can give it to one of them.
They will bring it along. All right?
That’s all. Now what else, My child?
Warren: He is asking whether there are
different degrees of Kundalini awakening
because he has heard or read that -
that can be very dangerous.
Shri Mataji: No, no, it’s not. It
is all people who are absolutely;
you see, they – people as I told you the other day that
a person comes from the village and puts his fingers into the
holes of a plug and says it is the electricity
gives you the shock and something like that.
But I, I can assure you that Kundalini is
never, never dangerous. She is your mother.
But, there is another centre down below
which might sometimes give you a little heat
or some sparking in the finger.
Or maybe a little electrical discharge.
For a while. Just for a while. If there is a problem.
On that centre. A little bit, not much.
But you can gradually feel that
cool breeze after the tingling is over.
In the beginning, you might feel a little tingling.
So far I have given realisation, I think,
to so many people. The Sahaja Yoga has worked out so well.
Nobody has suffered. Everybody has gained.
But if you have been to some guru. For example, take,
say, people who have been to say,
Mahesh Yogi. Now, about thirty people came to Me
and only I could save eight of them.
Because of the rest of them; they used to come,
go back, come, go back. Like that,
to that state. I could save only eight of them
because they were so badly damaged you see.
But even, they went back to the lunatic asylum,
this, that – but still they were remembering Me.
I don’t know, they are still coming out,
going in, like that. So they take time.
But it is not, never dangerous. It tries to improve you.
Even when I go you will find
it will rise and gradually tickle you here and there.
It doesn't trouble you at all. It is a very
kind, compassionate mother of yours
who has been with you all your lives.
And now she is anxious to establish your realisation.
She is one who gives your second birth.
So she cannot be unkind.
See, she is your pure mother.
She has no interest in you but to give you your second birth.
And she is your individual mother.
Of course, some of you have
harmed her very much. I have seen her
very much upset.
But doesn’t matter.
She looks after you. She is the one who does all this job.
She is the one who cures you, she is one
who gives you realisation, she is the one who gives you peace,
she is the one who takes you to the Spirit.
All right? So nothing; don’t have any fears.
May God Bless You.
This is all funny people. You see,
everybody has written about Kundalini.
I am Myself, I am amazed.
They had no fear of God, no fear of anything
– all lies, they have written and
those who really suffered must be unauthorised, horrible people
who must have tried. You have to have a proper, holy life, isn’t it?
You have to be a holy person. Because Kundalini
is a kanya,
means a virgin. Now imagine,
they call the sleeping serpent on this
Ayers Rock you see –
for the “kuniya”.
That is what it is – Kundalini is a virgin.
Can you imagine how it is so much so here?
And if you see the photographs, it is all Ganesha’s things.
Absolutely the same colour, everything – just imagine.
I told them a long time back when he met Me first,
that your country is the country of Mooladhara.
And then he sent Me this photograph from there.
And I saw and I was amazed – even
the trunk is there. Can you imagine?
And the whole colour, everything is the same.
You have such a blessing of God; why should you worry?
Your land is very holy.
Is a holy land. Is written about this land.
In the ancient books of India, where a
saint was, had done something wrong.
So God cursed him.
And said, “You will go”, is called
Trishanku – your Southern Cross.
That you will go to a land and create a heaven there for yourself.
See, first, he was cursed to go
in the Southern Hemisphere.
And then it was told that you will create your own heaven.
That is what it is.
Warren: They may have not heard of the word Southern Cross, Mother.
Shri Mataji: Southern Cross.
You know the Southern Cross. It is called as Trishanku.
It was hanging down, made hanging upside down.
And the curse was, a little bit what you call
concession given we can say.
As a concession to him that,
“No because you are a saint, you will create your own heaven”.
That’s what it is, Australia.
“Aus” itself is,
“Terra” means the land and “aus” means
“antariksha” – antariskha means what?
Warren: There is a lady, blind
lady up there who is asking questions.
Shri Mataji: What is she saying?
Warren: No.
Warren: A Christian scientist, practitioner told her once
there is no such thing as birth. Is that correct?
Shri Mataji: Do you believe him?
What good has he done to the world?
They can say anything. You must ask,
“What good have they done?”. All right.
What is the criteria, see, of a saint? You must find.
Everybody can talk about God. Who is going to check them?
Even Hitler talked on God, even Napoleon talked, I don’t know.
See, you must understand if they have
any right to talk? Are they saintly people?
All these Christian scientists, do you think they are saintly people?
Have they done any saintly work?
Warren: He does healing work.
Shri Mataji: You see, you can also heal with spirits. With dead spirits.
That’s one thing you can do. Horrible. Keep away from them.
She doesn’t know what she is talking about.
Warren: Any other question?
Shri Mataji: You see, anybody can say anything. I am not here answerable to them.
There can be a lot of mad people,
funny people, people who are anti-God, any sort but
what I am talking is talking for myself. All right?
What is she saying?
Warren: She brought some sugar
and she would like Your vibrations in it.
Shri Mataji: All right. I will give you but what about your eyes?
Warren: She’s got very poor vision.
Shri Mataji: All right. Now for that,
we have to work out for you, all right?
We will tell you what is to be done. Have you got somebody to be with you?
Have you got someone with you, who lives with you? Warren: Okay we could show them.
Shri Mataji: All right. We can tell you what is to be done. That can be cured. All right?
That thing can be done. So you have to come back again.
And they will tell you precisely what is to be done.
So work it out. You can get back your vision.
All of you who have got poor vision
also must know what is to be done about it. What is it?
Seeker: Can we hear something about hearing?
Shri Mataji: Healing? Yes, yes, hearing can also be done.
Seeker: Migraine? Warren: Migraine, headaches.
Shri Mataji: Of course, migraine,
can be worked out very easily, no doubt.
Yes, of course, migraine is very simple.
Seeker: High blood pressure.
Shri Mataji: Of course. He is another;
he had high blood pressure.
Warren: She was born partially
deaf; that may be a little more difficult.
Seeker: Yes, she's three years.
Shri Mataji: It is all right – still we
will work it out. You see it is, what I am saying,
you don’t have to pay for it,
you don’t have to do anything – if it works out, well and good.
You should try.
You should try everything, all right, but…
Warren: She brought her with her.
Shri Mataji: Good. Where is she?
Seeker: In the car. I will go and get her? Shri Mataji: All right.
We will see. Little later, little later, all right. Let’s finish the whole thing.
What else?
Seeker: Falling of the hair.
Shri Mataji: What’s she…. Warren: Falling hair. Shri Mataji: You have?
Warren: Alopecia.
Shri Mataji: You have the kind where you lose part, part of…
Warren: Yes, clumps of hair goes.
Shri Mataji: That we have got cured now of somebody.
He's much better.
Shri Mataji: Who is it? Warren: What’s the question?
Seeker: Supposing you get realisation
and wake up the Kundalini -
Warren: How would you get it?
Shri Mataji: We will work it out.
You come for the first time.
All right we will work it out.
Warren: How will we get Kundalini awakening, he is saying.
Shri Mataji: We will work it out.
His Agyna is too much. What, are you Christian or…?
Your,
centre of Christ is catching so badly.
Just imagine. We will work it out. All right?
Doesn’t matter.
What Christ has said, “Humble down yourself in your heart”.
First of all, humble down yourself in your heart.
Then it works out. Humble down.
All right?
Agyna. This centre is very important.
It works out better, you see.
Don’t take up responsibility upon yourself.
God is doing everything for you. Don’t worry.
Seeker: Earlier on, we heard that,
there is good and there is bad.
But if God is in all people. Shri Mataji: What is he saying?
Seeker: But then if you say
something is bad, you say God is bad?
Warren: Earlier on, he heard that
there a Good and bad people.
But if God is Good
how is it that we can reach such a conclusion?
Shri Mataji: You see, you should not
decide mentally who is good and who is bad, all right.
And you should not give up anyone as such;
as an absolutely wretched person.
But on vibrations you realise
that you can help
quite a lot of people. Some of them you have to give up.
But you just can’t help it, you just can’t help it. You can try.
Like people are getting drowned, all right?.
They are overloaded with things.
You can bring, in the West about,
I would say about forty per cent people.
easily up
and twenty more with little
effort or quite a great effort.
And ten more with really
very great struggle with them.
But such an ego-oriented society; it is difficult to reach them.
Because the ego covers them completely.
But never discard anyone; just try.
But don’t try very difficult words just now, you know.
Try simple words. When we want to first learn a new language,
we try simple words, you see.
In the same way, first, try simple people.
But don’t discard anyone,
but postpone.
Till you become a master.
Then you can try the most difficult ones also.
But just now don’t think of the
most difficult. Normally what happens,
people stick on to someone very difficult, like an ego challenge.
“I must transform” – and then you go wrong.
You don’t have to transform anyone, God has to do it.
But as you are a beginner, try with simple people.
All right?
Warren: You spoke about Ayers
Rock. What was it you were saying?
Shri Mataji: Ayers Rock is the
first centre.
Which shows. The deity of the first centre.
It’s very vibrated.
You get tremendous vibrations from it.
And the whole story about it they will let you later on.
Because, actually I told him that
the centre is, the first centre is –
and then they sent Me the photograph
of the Ayers Rock. It is true. It has vibrations.
Such a great thing that has come out of the Mother Earth.
Seeker: What vibrations? Will it vibrate?
Shri Mataji: Yes, Holy vibrations.
Seeker: Evil? Shri Mataji: Good.
Seeker: Holy vibrations? Shri Mataji: Holy vibrations.
Seeker: Ayers Rock?
Warren: From primordial times. From way back.
Shri Mataji: It has come from Mother Earth.
Which is told in the Bible.
That you shall now worship anything that is created by Mother Earth.
Now, what is created by Mother Earth?
We should not reproduce and worship.
But whatever is created by Mother Earth. And this is one of them.
You have got such a great thing here.
It is tremendous. When you become aware of it,
you will be amazed. It just emits vibrations all over.
But people who are evil, who are following black magic,
wrong practices – may call it an evil one.
Because for them, you see, it is evil, isn’t it?
Because that destroys all black magic and all that.
Seeker: Something’s gone wrong with my Kundalini.
It has been burning at the bottom of my spine for years.
Shri Mataji: When was this?
How many years back?
Seeker: Must have been four years.
Warren: Did you go to anybody? Shri Mataji: Did you go to anyone?
Seeker: Yeah, Maharishi. Warren: Maharishi.
Shri Mataji: That’s a difficult fellow. But I will work it out.
Sit down on Mother Earth.
Maharishi is one person; is horrid.
Warren: Take your shoes off. Shri Mataji: Take it out.
Warren: This is a good example.
Shri Mataji: But despite all this you see, nobody has made
a very joint effort.
Why don’t you write to our government or someone?
You see, it can be done.
Actually, when I talk to the government people because
I am quite highly connected. My brother himself is a minister.
I know the President and everyone there.
What they said is that is it You only who says these things.
I openly say. But nobody says anything you see;
nobody has anything written against it.
So if you people write from here,
join together that they have taken so much money from us,
they have ruined us, they have done this and that, isn’t it?
Then it will be better.
Because they think that you are all very much satisfied with them.
And it so happens that in the beginning,
some people come, they get ruined; the others come.
It’s like a moving train, you see, that takes passengers ahead.
And the passengers who have suffered are
left behind without any combined effort.
But in Paris, they have started a thing like that now.
Which is a very good thing.
Which is trying to oppose this.
But unless and until you write something,
I don’t know how to take up with the government.
What’s it?
This one is talking too much.
Warren: Look, you have asked quite a few questions.
I'll give this one to Mother and we will make it the last.
Warren: Doctor McDonald Baynes who was
a writer who lived in the Himalayas,
about the spiritual development said there is a celestial city
over the Dandenong ranges which is
nearby to Melbourne here.
What are your views?
Shri Mataji: I haven’t seen them as yet.
But must be, must be celestial here, no doubt.
Is it towards the sea, the Southern side?
Warren: To the…what is it, the east? To the east.
Shri Mataji: I don’t know this Baynes fellow,
how much to depend on him also.
Warren: He’s not realised.
He has good vibrations, but not realised.
Shri Mataji: It’s all right. Makes no difference, you see.
You have to have vibrations.
What is the use of having these ranges around?
You better have them.
Now done, everyone?
How many of you did feel the cool breeze the other day?
Let's raise your hands.
Warren: Put your both hands up so Mother can see.
A lot of them haven’t been before.
Shri Mataji: All right. If you all put your
hands, let us see how many of you feel again.
Just sit down, comfortably, put your hands towards Me.
You can’t sit like that. Can you get some chair for the lady?
Just, there are some chairs. You get a chair.
You are not supposed to sit with your feet towards Me, you see.
It is not regarded as good, all right? Better take chairs.
I am sorry. I know why you feel…
you can put the chair here on the sides. Come along.
Then you, that’s what it is. Then you can’t…
hello, how are you?
Put yourself like that
or you can sit on the chair.
Come along, it is all right. Just come here.
This doesn’t matter, If you have to sit on the chair, doesn't matter
it is all right.
Shri Mataji: Anyway, anyway, but not towards Me, you see.
You just can’t put your feet like that.
That’s what it is supposed to be.
Doesn’t matter, after all, you are children.
And I am the Mother. Doesn’t matter what you do.
Some of them are great people over here.
Now, put your hands towards Me like this.
I think, better close your eyes.
Can you take out this a little? I will put My feet on the ground.
Mother Earth.
Warren: Would you like me to pull the
chair forward? Shri Mataji: It’s all right.
What’s the matter with the lady?
Are you shaking too much?
You been to some clairvoyant person?
That’s the reason. All right. You come sit on the Mother grass,
all right, would be better. Yes.
Shri Mataji: Anyone shaking there?
Anyone shaking in the body?
Keep your eyes open and sit on the Mother
Earth. She takes away the problem, you see.
If you have been to a clairvoyant or someone, you may.
Shri Mataji: If you are not shaking it’s all right.
Everyone doesn’t get affected but some do, you see,
it’s those horrible things they do.
Sit on the Mother Earth, it’s better.
What’s she saying? Warren: A bit giddy.
Shri Mataji: Better sit on the Mother Earth.
You have been to some clairvoyant person?
No?
Been to a guru?
Must be having a liver.
All right, come along here, let me see.
She has a liver. Very bad liver you have.
Did you feel giddy also before?
Seeker: I just had a serious operation.
Shri Mataji: What operation? Seeker: Brain surgery.
Warren: Brain surgery.
Shri Mataji: It's all right. Keep your eyes open all right.
Don’t close them. Keep your eyes open.
You had an accident?
Doesn’t matter.
Nabhi is too much.
Keep your eyes open, please.
How are you feeling now?
Still giddy?
Better? Would you like to lie down?
We can get you a pillow. All right.
Better lie down. You can let her
lie down here. You can lie down here.
Warren: Come over here. Shri Mataji: Put the pillow there.
Put the pillow on that side and the feet at the back, yes.
Let her lie down.
Warren: Put your head down here.
Shri Mataji: Don’t cry. Don’t cry. You are going to be alright.
You just don’t worry. Put your head here.
Towards Me. Yes, just…
You have to work it out. Don’t cry. You wanted to see Me, is it?
Or lie this way.
Parallel to, will be better.
It shows, you see there's any problem, it shows, it shows.
Just lie down. Be comfortable.
Will work out. Don’t you worry.
You are going to be all right.
It’s good, fine. May God Bless You.
All right?
Now those who are feeling the cool breeze,
already,
can get up and see others,
who are not feeling it.
And you can stand behind one person each.
I will teach you how to give them realisation also.
Can be done now.
All right. Those who are really feeling the cool breeze, can get up.
It’s a good idea to help others. Yes. Let’s have it.
Warren: Can the Sahaja Yogis do the same thing.
Shri Mataji: Also the Sahaja Yogis. Those
who are feeling the cool breeze. Come along.
Now, all of you should put your
left hand towards Me and right hand on top of the head of the person.
Left hand towards me, yes.
On top, not touching, not touching.
Higher. Like this, yes.
See. It works better.
You act as a sort of  a
wire, thing.
It passes. See, now, ha, better?
All right.
What about you? You feeling it?
Now get up. You can get up. Those who are feeling can get up.
Now, are you better now?
Not yet.
You put your right hand out like that, yourself.
The Indian gentleman put your right hand.
Like this, at the back, yes. And put left towards Me.
All right? Good.
You getting it?
Are you? No, not yet.
All right. It will work out. Just don’t you worry.
Maybe some of you can put your left hand and see
with the right hand like this. It will work out.
Left towards Me and right hand out.
No, no, left towards Me like this, left like this
and the right like that.
Just try, some of you.
If it works out better. Or the other way round.
She’s got it. You feeling it?
Good. She’s got it. Now work on ….you feeling now?
Good, good.
It’s good. Put it like that
and this one like that.
You can put it towards Me. The right hand if you want.
Right towards Me. One hand has to be towards Me.
Put one hand towards Me, like that. That’s it.
Now, tell her also.
Put the other hand,
the way she is doing. No. Yes, good.
Good.
Are you feeling? No.
Sit on the Mother Earth. Move on the Mother Earth more.
Now try another lady.
Yes, yes, you go on trying. She’s very good.
She doing very well, yeah. Just put one hand
towards Me, that's all. Simple. Is it?
Seeker: Hot vibration. Shri Mataji: But not cool.
Not cool as yet. Seeker: Not much though.
Shri Mataji: It will, it will work out. What about you?
Not yet? Try on her. Maybe.
Seeker: Very hot, Mother.
Shri Mataji: You are feeling hot?
On her?
What’s the problem?
You think too much, do you?
Seeker: I don't know what I supposed to be feeling?
Shri Mataji: You feel the cool breeze on the hand do you?
No, no. No, no. That’s a different thing. You feel a
sensation in your hand. No?
All right?
She’s good.
It’s rising, it’s rising.
She’s got it.
You got it, no. Not feeling it?
Can you take out that necklace a little bit?
These things a little bit, sometimes that also affects.
Are you better, My child?
Better now? Good. Good.
Put your left hand up that way.
All right? It will work out.
Is she better?
Little bit. She's improving. Put your hand like this.
Have patience with yourself. You
must have some patience with yourself.
That’s the main point is.
Better now? It's Better?
Yes, it is. Working out?
Better.
Keep your eyes open.
Tell her to keep her eyes open.
All right? Better?
No?
Her Vishuddhi is not all…yes?
Very hot?
All right. She has been to some guru?
No one.
To no clairvoyant or anyone?
Not at all?
Put your left hand on the right-hand side of your stomach.
Is it all right?
Put your left hand
on the Mother Earth.
Like that, yes. And right hand towards Me.
Like this.
Did you feel the cool breeze? Good.
Why not work on these two gentlemen?
This gentleman and this lady?
Did you feel? No? All right, you get up and work on them.
Not on your relations or friends all right? Other people.
That’s important. In the beginning.
It’s better now?
No? No?
He is a very difficult, horrible person I tell you.
One of the worst you can think of this Mahesh Yogi.
And how much money has amassed do you know?
We have someone there from him. The whole family is ruined.
It's Terrible.
Is it?
Comes and goes. All right. Don’t think.
Just watch Me without thinking.
If it comes. Are you better?
She has an Agyna, I think. This lady.
What about you?
Did you feel? Good.
He has to put his left hand on his stomach. Liver, you see.
Liver and Vishuddhi both the Center.
He is difficult. He is very difficult.
You sit on Mother Earth. Let him sit.
He is difficult. He’s from that horrible
Satya Sai Baba. He’s the worst.
Till you get a heart attack he won’t leave you.
Put your right hand on Mother Earth and left hand towards Me.
Is she better?
Little hot is she?
She has a liver too.
Hello? You put your left hand
on your stomach on the right side.
Right side.
Right side, yes.
Who is the gentleman with migraine?
You have got migraine?
Seeker: No, my wife has.
My wife has it, I have nothing!
Shri Mataji: All right. You watch at Me. Watch this side.
You see, don’t watch other people.
She?
She’s all right, she's coming. She a liver, it's true.
So many have livers, livers – I don’t know why.
What about this lady? Did she feel any?
Good, good. But keep your hands, have more.
You see, I am here for a short time. I'll go away.
Now don’t put your shoes towards Me, all right.
If you can take out, thank you.
Is she crying? Put her right to the left.
You are all right. She’s got it.
I can see from your eyes. Good.
You are doing a good job.
Seeker: Mother, can I ask you,
I know I shouldn't be asking you questions
but I've been ill for twelve years with
kidneys and...
Shri Mataji: Now no more. It’s finished.
It is done, it's done.
Got some water for Me?
Seeker: You saw me at a lecture.
Shri Mataji: Did you bring water?
Seeker: No, I have been drinking the water you gave me.
Shri Mataji: Good. You are all right.
No kidneys, nothing. Finished.
Did you go on the machine anytime with the kidney?
Seeker: What machine?
Shri Mataji: That they do circulation of the -
Seeker: No.
Shri Mataji: Thank God. Then its all right, no problem.
What about this gentleman here? Did you feel?
Hot? Hot?
You put your left hand on your stomach, on the right-hand side.
Can you?
What is it?
Can you try this gentleman here?
He will be all right.
Keep your eyes open.
This lady.
Ask her also to open her eyes.
Very pale.
What about you?
Left hand?
Not right hand?
You also put your left hand on
the stomach, on the right-hand side.
Good. It will work out.
It will slowly work out in everyone.
Good.
You still have? All right. Come along here.
Can you sit facing that side?
I have to put My foot if you don’t mind.
Seeker: On the back? Lovely.
Shri Mataji: Just sit comfortability.
No, I think it’s here.
There are certain exercises you have to do for this.
But in any case, I will cure you now.
This will dissolve out.
How are these people? Are you all right? Good.
I am happy you are working it.
From Mauritius, yes, good.
Good, good, I'm happy.
They are not getting it?
They will, they will. All of them have to get it.
They will get it, don’t you worry.
It's better now?
Some ossification has taken place.
What were you doing?
Seeker: Hatha yoga. Shri Mataji: Hatha yoga!
That’s it, without your...
I was wondering how it’s gone into that.
Seeker: Yeah, it is difficult.
Shri Mataji: It is horrible. Stop all Hatha yoga.
No, no, no, no. I will tell you what exercises are to be done.
For everyone, not the same exercise
– for everyone there is a different exercise, all right.
Good. Enjoy.
Is he all right?
He’s been to some guru or someone?
No, not you. Him. Have you been?
Seeker: Don't believe in gurus.
No? Thank God.
Shri Mataji: But...
Seeker: I practice meditation.
Shri Mataji: Your own?
Seeker: No not my own, it's
Buddhist meditation.
Shri Mataji: That’s it. That’s just the same.
Just the same, all right?
Ask him to put his right hand
towards Me and left hand on his stomach.
And say, “Mother, make me my own guru”.
Better now, madam? All right?
Seeker: There is blue light in the Agyna centre.
Shri Mataji: No, that should not be so. It should go away.
All must go away. It’s a horrible thing.
You ought to be.
You are to become the light.
The light does not see the light, does it?
You have to become. Not see something.
If you see the sky, you don’t become the sky, do you?
But when you are the sky, you don’t see the sky.
All right? Now better?
What about you? Didn’t feel it?
Don’t be upset about it. Nothing to be
– you have a liver problem, do you know that.
That’s all. It’s very simple. Now do one thing.
You put your right hand towards Me
and left hand on the Mother Earth.
Just on the backside.
No, that side. Behind your hand.
Yes. It will work out. Now don’t get upset.
Nobody should be upset. Now those who are not feeling anything,
please raise your hand. Let’s see.
Keep your hands raised, all right?
You put both your hands and say, “Mother, is this the
power of God? Is this the power of Brahma?.
Is this the Brahmashakti?”.
Are you feeling, some of you?
Don’t doubt it, you see.
It’s a kind of feeling you get in your fingers.
Raise them higher. Let’s see.
You are all right.
Higher, on your heads.
It’s there.
Now, are you feeling it now?
It’s there. Good.
Are you feeling? Seeker: Tingling. Tingling.
Shri Mataji: Tingling? Tingling has to go away a little bit.
You can put both your hands on the
Mother Earth. Now let’s see. On the Mother Earth.
For a while. There’s tingling.
Now just see. Tingling has gone? Raise your hands and see.
Tingling is gone.
Better?
It’s better now.
All right, now bring it down, see.
Let her sit on the Mother Earth. Is she sitting on the Mother Earth?
Let her put her left hand... left hand on the Mother Earth.
Is she been to some guru?
Warren: It’s a man.
He’s getting hotter and hotter.
Have you been to a guru?
Shri Mataji: Rajneesh?
Warren: Has he been to a guru?
An Indian fellow or…?
Muktananda.
Shri Mataji: Put your left hand towards
Me and right hand on the Mother Earth.
You have to work hard I must tell you, this Muktananda.
Warren: He had only one visit to the centre, it wasn't by
-Was it by him, himself or by the people?
Was it the guru himself?
Shri Mataji: He also is left
Swadishthana is so catching, how can that be?
Warren: Yes, they were affected by him.
Shri Mataji: Very bad left Swadishthana.
Better now? Are they cooler?
Good, good, it’s working out, all right.
Warren: Even if you go to meetings where
you don’t get initiated but
mixing with these people, do you get affected?
Shri Mataji: Of course. You see, to get dirty is easy, isn’t it?
But to get holy is difficult.
Seeker: I've been hot and my hands radiant heat
and my body has gotten very, very hot.
Shri Mataji: Why don’t you sit on the Mother Earth?
She will clear out.
Shri Mataji: Which meetings you have been to?
Warren: She visits any.
Shri Mataji: Let the Mother Earth help you.
All right, come along on the Mother Earth. Please.
All right? She will help you. That’s a very good thing.
Mother Earth, those who are sitting are better helped, here.
It’s all for that.
Warren: Anyone who’s not feeling should move on the earth.
Shri Mataji: She helps. Definitely helps, definitely helps.
If you are even sitting on this
impervious material, whatever it is.
something artificial in those,
things stuck inside those.
Warren: And slip your shoes off too.
Shri Mataji: It’s very pleasant today, isn’t it?
How is he? Keep his eyes open. All this thing just see this.
He’s got all this, Hamsa. Keep your eyes open.
Warren: He’s been to Muktananda and
he’s got it. But he can’t feel it, unfortunately.
Shri Mataji: Hamsa, you see. Hamsa
is there. Hamsa and Vishuddhi both.
You get it, sinus?
So only Hamsa.
All people who have been to gurus put your left
hand towards Me and right hand on Mother Earth.
That’s the simple thing as that.
Let him sit on the Mother Earth. Let him work it out.
Warren: If you have been to a guru and see if it works out.
Shri Mataji: It will improve your,
always improve your sensitivity. See, better.
He is a Hamsa fellow, problem with his...
What are you wearing in your hand? Take it out also.
Right Vishuddhi. You can take it out for a while.
You sit on the Mother Earth. All right? It is better.
It’s good.
Warren: Anyone having problems, come up to the front here.
Shri Mataji: On the Mother Earth.
Mother Earth helps you, the sun helps you,
the light helps you. Everything helps you.
All right let’s see. What the problem is now.
Can you take out the cross for a while, for a while, just for a while?
If you could. Ha!
Been to a Muktanand?
He’s horrible – gives such a bad Vishuddhi and
all this, Ekadasha?
Keep your eyes open, My child.
Keep your eyes open. Watch Me, please.
I will let you know, I'm talking to him.
Right, it’s all right. Don’t you worry. We have clear it out.
Are you all right?
Sahaja Yogi: She doesn't feel it, Mother.
She doesn't what?
Warren: She has Vishuddhi catching.
Shri Mataji: She’s been to some guru?
She will be all right.
Whom do you worship?
Whom do you worship? Seeker: Ram, Shri Ram.
Shri Mataji: All right. Ask her to say the mantra.
Just let her put her left hand on the heart.
Right heart. Right heart.
Just ask her, all right.
It is good. It will work out in no time.
Just see on her head.
Good.
The time has come for you to recognise
and get the reward for all your bhakti, isn’t it?
The time has to come. May God Bless You.
Indians are very easy to handle. Ask her.
Is she an Indian lady?
Krishna. All right.
Good. Better, this will work out.
Close your eyes now. Enjoy.
Good.
All right?
We have to get over all these evil forces, isn’t it?
You have to. Are you all right, My child?
All right?
You can come here, on the Mother Earth.
Anyone who needs help, come along. Come here.
Warren: She is feeling it too, the
other lady. She’s from Ceylon. She’s asked,
“Are you Krishna?”.
Shri Mataji: All right. Now keep both the hands.
And you enjoy yourself. Is she, what’s your name please?
She’s from Ceylon?
Seeker: Prabha. Shri Mataji: Prabha?
And the surname? Seeker: Rao.
Shri Mataji: Prabha Rao. All right.
It will work out in no time.
You put your bag on the ground
below and put both your hands towards Me.
It will work out Mrs Rao, yes it's working out.
Sit down. Yes. Be comfortable. Be comfortable.
Better? Are you? No, same?
Seeker: I seem so very tired.
Shri Mataji: It’s horrible, I tell you.
We have to work it and work it out. It will work out, all right?
Don’t give up. Patience. It will work out.
Touch your, Mother Earth. Little.
You have lost your fingers? Seeker: Yes. Shri Mataji: How?
Seeker: From a saw.
Shri Mataji: Are you?
Put your, all right, no, no.
Put your left hand on the Mother Earth. Left hand.
Now, what about you My child?
You feel it and
goes away, is it?
Put your right hand towards Me. Right hand like that.
Put it on your, on your lap.
All right? Comfortably on the Mother Earth.
Be relaxed, yes,
at the back you can put it.
Just be relaxed, be relaxed. Just, it will work out.
Gradually it will works out.
It’s like the power flowing, all right.
Shri Mataji: Hamsa.
What is it?
I couldn’t hear. What is the word he is using?
In Sanskrit, you are saying something?
I didn’t follow your word. Just ask him.
What word is he using in Sanskrit language?
Warren: Varashamsa.
Shri Mataji: Varsamsha is not a
Sanskrit word, My child. Who’s told you?
It’s not a Sanskrit word.
Shri Mataji: No, no, just don’t do any mantras. Don’t chant.
Don’t chant just now. You have to learn the whole
science about it, all right? Don’t chant.
Don’t do any chanting of mantras.
You have to know the whole science of it.
Don't do it with your closed eyes and closed brains.
Have to understand why you are doing that.
Put your hand like this, My child.
In the blue.
It works out better this way.
Better?
Shri Mataji: He has already.
And then?
He had it, before?
What cancer?
You got pain there?
Just watch him. On the Vishuddhi.
Can you, Warren, look after the gentleman there? It’s all right.
You see, all these are chakras which are showing.
He has a right Swadishthana.
What sort of a cancer?
He’s been to some guru?
Sahaja Yogi: You been to any guru at all or nothing?
Shri Mataji: Is it on the right-hand side you have a liver?
Cirrhosis or something?
Where do you have?
In the liver?
Muscle?
Put your left up like that.
Left hand like that, yes, left hand. Right towards Me.
Can you bring some vibrated water?
Put it on his feet. So the Mother Earth can take away.
Or ordinary water. Just put it on his feet.
Are you better now?
Shri Mataji: There’s no breeze passing.
Seeker: Only the physical one. Shri Mataji: No, no, not physical.
It will be all right. You just stay, we will
tell you, if you have got it or not, all right.
Ask this lady to put her hand towards Me like that. This way.
Towards Me, you have put like this as if
you are asking for something. This one.
You are all right. You got it.
Now still those haven’t felt
any cool breeze, raise your hand, please.
Warren: This fella has a cancer of the muscle
on the right space of the right side.
Shri Mataji: Is he, has he been running too much?
Now stop all that jogging business! All right.
Everything you do to such an extreme.
Jogging, sun tanning,
I mean it’s madness. I just don’t understand.
Going too far with your body.
Then you develop cancer, you develop this problem, that problem.
What is the need to tan yourself to that extent?
Now give up that jogger of yours, all right.
Some possessions to do this kind of madness.
Even old people of eighty years are
jogging – For what? I just don't know.
They look quite funny, don’t they?
To Me, I don’t know, if you feel that.
You must accept your age and live with it.
And be decent about it.
The more grown-up you are, the more mature you are.
We can’t be horses, can we?
All kinds of fads we accept; we shouldn’t.
It’s not sensible.
No common sense in that.
Better. Are you better sir?
Muktananda is it?
Did…Muktananda?
You know how much money he’s got now?
He’s got
sixty thousand – he’s dead now, thank God.
Sixty thousand
crores. I don’t know if you understand crores.
Warren: Six billion. Six thousand million.
Shri Mataji: Six thousand million worth of
diamonds he’s got. And both the disciples are fighting now.
Must have also contributed to that.
Are you all right? Better, Mrs Rao?
Mrs Rao: I haven't so much tingling now.
Shri Mataji: No, it’s better. It is passing.
It will work out. You see, gradually it will works out.
Have patience in yourself. You's better, aren’t you?
Put on your hand, head.
Left, Left hand. Just see
if there’s a cool breeze.
Warren: Don’t look. Just put your attention there.
Shri Mataji: All right?
It will work out. How are you? Are you better? Good.
Be peaceful. First thing you feel is peaceful.
You feel your peace within yourself.
Now if the people who haven’t got it;
if you raise your hands.
Can you attend to them, some of the Sahaja Yogis?
Where are the Sahaja Yogis now?
Can you attend to the people who haven’t got it there? One or two.
Please keep your hands raised, all right.
This lady hasn’t got it yet? What’s the problem with this one?
What’s the problem? Are you keeping
all right, your health is all right, My child?
What’s the problem?
Come here.
You fell down? Seeker: No, motor car accident.
Warren: Motor car accident. Shri Mataji: Ah, that’s why.
Seeker: Also I am on medication of lithium. Shri Mataji: Medication?
Seeker: Of lithium. Warren: Lithium.
She’s an alcoholic. Are you an alcoholic?
Seeker: No. Oh yeah.
Warren: A bit of everything drugs, alcohol. The whole thing.
She’s addicted, Mother.
Shri Mataji: All right. Sit down. Turn around.
All right? Now put your,
take your feet
that side and sit on the ground. Can you?
Or can you give her a seat or something to sit down?
It’s all right? Can you?
It’s terrible.
It’s all right, but it’s working out.
Warren: The right side.
Shri Mataji: I know, it is the right side.
Yes, my child?
Seeker: My hands are warm on the inside, cold on the outside.
Shri Mataji: All right. Now put it up like that.
Just take it out like that, you see.
No, no, no… Warren: Up, up and down.
Up and down.
Shri Mataji: Some people haven’t got
as yet attended? Ask somebody else?
Some of the girls can come out.
Have they made the rice alright? Warren: I don’t know Mother.
Shri Mataji: Did they prepared the rice.
Have you got some plates and things?
This lady hasn’t been attended to, just see. Warren: Which one?
Shri Mataji: This one, there.
Shri Mataji: Veins?
I will work it out. All right. Don't you worry.
Seeker: It doesn’t really worry me.
Shri Mataji: It worries Me.
Better now My child?
Still the pain?
Shri Mataji: Still taking a lot of these drugs are you?
Sahaja Yogi: The lady is coming in forty minutes at the most.
Forty minutes?
Shri Mataji: To put the rice? Sahaja Yogi: Rice is on, yeah.
Shri Mataji: And what I have given should be put in a…,
should be put in a little... It is all right if the rice is very hot.
Rice is ready? Sahaja Yogi: Nearly ready.
Shri Mataji: But see that it is cooked well, otherwise…
Ask Bill to look at it.
Ask him to cook it well. See that’s very important.
It’s here.
Now give up all that. Give up all the drugs. You can.
Have you reduced it now?
Since you met Me?
All right. You can give up overnight. Just put a little bit power.
Right side is your willpower.
Which is out of gear.
How is this lady? Ask her to open her eyes.
It’s on the Vishuddhi, what the problem is.
Ask her to take out the cross for a while. Rosary.
Just for a while.
All you all right, My child?
Better? Did you feel? No?
Now we should see. You should feel it, why not?
What’s that? Are you better?
No.
I will see. All right? Are you better?
Yeah. Yes.
Are you all right?
All right, I will see.
This is the place. All right?
It’s your willpower. It’s finished.
Now you must have a willpower
because you have to live more
and you have to enjoy your spirit
and you have to give it to others, the enjoyment, all right?
You have a purpose now.
Right to the left. Right to the left.
No, you are all right. I will work that out.
Are you feeling the cool breeze?
It’s all right, put your hand on the sciatica on the back.
Ah, that’s all. You can put your
hand towards Me. You can do it yourself.
You can cure yourself.
Yes, of course, you can.
That’s the minimum.
Are you all right?
Just don’t go into thinking just,
be alert.
Be alert.
Seeker: Mother, I think I am starting to feel the cool breeze.
Old drugs when I was in my teens, you see taking drugs.
Shri Mataji: It’s all right. Everything will be cleared.
It’s like a flood.
Don’t worry. Don’t worry about your past.
Just don’t worry.
That doesn’t exist for Me.
You just go on thinking about
what wrong you have done. Forget it.
I told you a hundred times to forget it. Let Me look after you.
Actually, I don’t want to know about it. All right?
But some were still very worried, so I said write to Me.
They wrote and I never read them.
Burnt them off.
What to do? How to convince them that…
Seeker: What can I do for my high blood pressure?
Shri Mataji: No, no that will be automatically
taken over. Don’t you worry. You will be all right.
Blood pressure takes no time.
Are you better My child now?
All right?
What’s it?
Warren: She's been to Muktananda. Why don't you just say,
“Please forgive me Mother, for going
to him and give me my Self-realisation”.
and straight away she felt it.
Shri Mataji: Really? Let's, better try.
Say that. Come along, let’s see.
Mother, forgive me, all right. Tell them. These two.
Better?
Seeker: Don’t know.
Shri Mataji: Touch your hand yourself.
No, see the pain.
Still there? Where?
Wherever is the pain you put your hand.
Just you put your hand.
Better now?
You have got every kind of a drug in your body, is it?
Left, right both sides.
They are so particular in customs; we saw.
Went round every
bit of it, even pencils and the
even the fountain pens they opened out to see the drugs.
I don’t know how they penetrate.
Yes, despite all that effort.
You must help the police to find them out. Really.
These are all anti-God things.
Yes, I came out because
I have a diplomatic passport.
They didn’t bother Me at all. But these people were held up for
about an hour. They went thoroughly into everything.
Every bit of it, you see. Even a pencil, even a
sharpener every bit of it was opened out completely by them.
Such a thorough examination.
Better now?
Ask for forgiveness.
You too ask for forgiveness.
For going to this horrible fellow.
Take a chair. I think you will be better off.
Are you all right now, My child?
You're all right, I think you are better now?
May God Bless You. Let’s see.
May God Bless You. Now see if you feel the cool breeze.
It is looking better.
Now, who else? Sciatica. Come along.
Turn around.
Left side?
More on the left hand? Seeker: It's on the left, yes.
Shri Mataji: All right, just sit down with your stretched legs here.
Stretch your legs fully.
Let’s see. It's here.
I have done medicine for the same reason.
All right?
To know the names, what you call them.
How, how are you, My child? Felt it?
Good.
Are you all right?
Nothing much. What is you feel the
You feel the pull in the muscle?
I see.
You are better.
Isn’t it? It is flowing down there.
Good. But don’t do too strenuous exercise, all right.
Try to avoid for the time being. You can walk at the most.
Be careful When you have your bath especially.
Just wipe out yourself well.
All right, that is the thing – you leave yourself open
and you catch this as a cold thing.
It is melting. It is all right.
What’s the matter?
Is she all right?
Sahaja Yogi: Liver. Shri Mataji: Got a liver?
Come on the Mother Earth. The best to cure your liver all right?
Just sit on Her, put your left hand
on the right side of your stomach.
Lower, little lower, little lower. Just a little higher.
Little high. Under the ribs.
All right. Now push it hard and put your hand
on the Mother Earth. Right hand.
You've cleared out.
All right? Cleared out. May God Bless You.
So sweet of you. Thank you very
much. Thank you. Are you going now?
Seeker: This is my friend. Can you do something for her at home?
Shri Mataji: Whom? She’s all right now. She’s all right.
Yeah, she’s all right. May God Bless You. Thank you very much.
Seeker: I'm in a lot of pain with my back at moment?
Shri Mataji: So what do you want?
All right. Come along.
What do you do?
Seeker: I'm in the bank. And I have traction once a week.
I've had that... twisted spine.
Shri Mataji: All right. Now put your hand towards Me. Right one.
Put this one on the stomach.
Lower. Little bit.
You just say, “Mother, are you the source of all the banks?”.
Shri Mataji: Again.
Again.
All right? It’s working out.
And the pain? All right. Come along, turn round.
Sit down.
You see, in the bank, we are just cashiers aren’t we?
We don’t do anything.
We don’t own it, do we? Seeker: Exactly.
Shri Mataji: Did you fix his right Vishuddhi?
Warren: Which one, Mother? Shri Mataji: This gentleman.
Warren: He’s got a total spine problem.
From top to bottom. And I…
he’s a major problem from early,
what is it, curvature?
Shri Mataji: Can you go forward a little bit?
It’s left Swadishthana. Have you been to anyone like that?
Seeker: Nah, nah nothing like that, no.
Warren: Who have you been to? Any spiritual seeking?
Warren:  No. But who, what sort of seeking?
Seeker: I am a Catholic.
Warren: You're Catholic. He is Catholic.
Shri Mataji: All right, let him ask
the question of the Holy Ghost then.
Warren: Turn around and face Mother.
Shri Mataji: Put your left hand towards Me.
And right hand on the Mother Earth.
On Mother Earth. Now ask a question.
Warren: Ask the question – “Mother, are you
incarnation of the Holy Ghost?”.
Seeker: Are you incarnation of the Holy Ghost?
Seems like cool, cool breeze.
Shri Mataji: Ask the question,
“Is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?”.
Shri Mataji: All right. It’s more physical. Just turn around.
Warren: Did you feel that cool? Shri Mataji: Yes he did.
Just move further. All Nabhi, see catching.
He’s got it on the Nabhi. It's a very bad Nabhi.
Now, what have you got?
To begin with, this?
Warren: Left swadhisthan the Nabhi is there.
This little boy’s got,
Shri Mataji: What’s it? Warren: - Diabetes.
Shri Mataji: What this, Diabetes? Come along.
Come here.
Take out their shoes. Please take out their shoes. Both?
Shri Mataji: Take out your shoes, please.
Very bad Nabhi he has got.
Warren: Sit down, just sit down. That’s it.
Shri Mataji: Let me see.
No, towards Me.
Warren: Turn your tummy towards…
A bit closer still, bit closer.
Shri Mataji: Did you feel the cool breeze,
these two ladies?
Good.
Did you feel the cool breeze yourself?
Good now. Are you feeling peaceful now?
Better.
Put your right hand on the spleen yourself.
Shri Mataji: She’s more on the spleen, he’s more on the
pancreas.
Warren: She’s on the spleen, he is on the pancreas.
Shri Mataji: Better sir? Are you?
Warren: Is it easing?
Shri Mataji: First of all, to ease out this centre is very bad you see,
than that one.
Now push back, My foot.
That’s good.
Well feeling hot there? Seeker: Yes.
Shri Mataji: Little hot? Seeker: Yes.
Shri Mataji: How are you feeling now, this lady?
Are you feeling better now? Good, good.
Better. And in the hands?
Seeker: I am still very hot.
Shri Mataji: Now what you do is put left hand like that.
Is she better? She’s all right.
She’s all right. She’s very good I should say.
Warren: Clearing nicely.
Shri Mataji: You must get her some
olive oil or something to put in the head.
Warren: But she’s having acupuncture
at the moment, Mother. She should stop it.
Shri Mataji: No need.
Acupuncture.
You did too?
Seeker: Four times.
Shri Mataji: Oh God! Are you all right now?
Seeker: I've just finished now I suppose.
Shri Mataji: Better now my child? Seeker: It is easing now.
Shri Mataji: Easing now, it is out.
It has to melt away. How are you?
Terrible.
Warren: Is it always on the left side?
Warren: Left Swadishthan.
Shri Mataji: Is there any Sahaja Yogi here? Available?
Warren: Who would you like Mother?
Shri Mataji: Anyone. Get some ice for Me.
He’s better now.
Warren: It's good to clear him.
Shri Mataji: Right heart. What about your father?
Warren: Where is he, is he alive or? But he's incapacitated?
He was in an accident nine years ago but is he well otherwise?
How is your relationship with him?
Shri Mataji: Where is that? Have you kept the masala?
Sahaja Yogini: Masala? I don’t know.
Sahaja Yogini: Garam masala?
Sahaja Yogini: Cut that fast and into smaller pieces.
Shri Mataji: Where is it?
This is My profession. I live by that.
That’s how I earn My living.
This will bring about the whole thing.
Hold it with the whole hand.
Cumin seeds must be jeera.
This can be done in the blender?
Can you make smaller pieces in the blender?
They are very nice some of these plates aren't they.
They are old, aren’t they? You can’t get these nowadays.
Cardamom powder?
I am sorry we are using quite a lot of this.
Shri Mataji: Are you sure this is saffron?
Yogini: It's saffron, Mother but
I don’t think, I think it’s imitation.
Shri Mataji: Salt?
It's the colour?
We can use it just to make the colour.
They have written it is artificial.
Yoginis: Yes, yes.
Shri Mataji: But the thing is, if it would have been real
it would have been better because
this gives the colour you see. Saffron.