Shri Krishna Puja
Cabella Ligure, Italy
August 16, 1992
Today we have decided to have the puja of
Shri Krishna.
We have many a times done this puja and have
understood the essence of Shri Krishna’s
advent, which was six thousand years back.
And now, what His manifestation was, what
He wanted to be accomplished has to be done
in this Kali Yuga.
As it is, this Kali Yuga is going into a new
realm of Satya Yuga, but in between there
is Krita Yuga where this Brahmachaitanya,
or we can say the all-pervading Power of God’s
love, is going to act.
At this time, what is going to happen with
Shri Krishna’s powers – this is what we
have to see.
Shri Krishna, as I told you, was the incarnation
also of diplomacy.
So He plays around quite a lot, and ultimately
He brings forth the untruth and the falsehood;
but in doing that He judges people.
So it’s very important that Shri Krishna’s
powers of His diplomacy were to be manifesting
at this time, when it is the Last Judgment.
So now whatever we have done wrong before,
whatever karmas which have been done in ignorance
maybe, or maybe deliberately, all of them
will be paid back.
Those punyas which you have done in previous
lives, this life, will be also rewarded.
This is all done through Shri Krishna’s
principles of collectivity, where He collectively
sees the situation.
For example, as I told you last time also
that Columbus luckily went to America; luckily,
so we were saved, otherwise we would not have
been here.
And then these Spanish people, bullfighters,
they went and started fighting the poor, unarmed
people who were just very simple owners of
that land.
But they went and occupied those lands, and
killed every one of them.
So in America you can’t find anyone, no
doubt, but even in South America you have
to go to Colombia or to Bolivia, to great
heights, to see some aboriginals there; otherwise
most of them are finished.
So now in Krita Yuga all these diseases have
started cropping up.
But the best part is the drug addiction.
These drugs are made, for your information,
in Bolivia and in Colombia.
You drove them down there, so now you have
the drugs and very nicely you are very welcoming
them.
People went in Nicaragua to help them and
brought back all these horrible drugs to Washington;
and in every elite society they are just discussing
which is the best drug, where is the sale
on and where should they buy the drugs.
So the all of America is now worried how much
drug they can import, and kill themselves
and destroy themselves.
So this destruction has started from inside.
Then in addition to that, when I went there
first I told them not to indulge into these
Freudian practices but keep to morality, otherwise
you’ll have problems.
So they had first AIDS, secondly now yuppie’s
disease, and all kinds of secret diseases
they have.
Among ten people there would be at least one
person who is suffering from that, and among
twenty people there’ll be at least one person
who must be suffering from schizophrenia.
Because they made every person, every other
country nervous, so now they are getting schizophrenia.
Like this we can see even in England.
Now in England they came to India as traders,
ordinary traders, and plundered us completely,
no doubt, ruled us for three hundred years
– as I say, it’s gracious hospitality
they had – and then they left us in three
pieces.
And now in their own country there are problems,
all kinds.
First of all nobody wants to call themselves
as English; they all call themselves Welsh
or Scots, or specially the Irish.
And there is always a bomb scare in London,
every time, and for our first program also
there was a bomb scare.
So you can imagine these English who tried
to divide us are automatically divided among
themselves, and now fighting each other.
But there are other problems also like AIDS
and immoral life, everything like that.
Same with the French.
French tried to sell their wine all over,
and bring their horrible bathroom culture
everywhere.
Now they are suffering from it.
For example, most of the time they’re drunk
and they have lost all moorings, I mean, they
have no sense left in their heads.
Like a housewife could be a prostitute – allowed
by law.
All such things are happening.
Now they are paying, and the worst that they
are paying, all these countries who think
no end of themselves, are recession.
This is also Shri Krishna’s power, because
He’s Kubera.
He’s the one who is the power of wealth.
He gave lot of wealth to all these countries,
and now they don’t know what to do with
themselves.
We can see in these fifty years how many things
have happened, but specially these twenty
years have been really remarkable.
All over the world you can find out there
has been some sort of a complete change, or
an exposure.
Even in Italy you see every day this Vatican
is here exposed, or some mafia connections
are there, or this what you call, people from
the government are exposed.
I am doing nothing, I’m just sitting here,
but it is working out that way.
Since I have been here I don’t know how
many people have gone to jail, God knows.
(I don’t know if she’s not brought My
throat pastilles.
I had a bath early in the morning, so a little
bit … This is, Shri Krishna is trying to
fill Me up!)
We Indians are also suffering,because our
past deeds – like we had a caste system.
So now the caste system has become the greatest
headache for us in India, that’s the greatest
cancer for us.
Like that, everywhere these twenty years or
twenty-one years have been … ( … I don’t
know, because morning.
Also reaction on Me … ) So like that in
every country, you’ll see gradually, every
country will have to face for what it has
done.
Also Shri Krishna’s own style was that He
can never believed in caste system.
He Himself was born in a caste which is a,
what you call is a milkman’s caste, and
then He became a king, of course; but to begin
with, and He lived like an ordinary person.
He used to take the cows outside, look after
them and bring them home.
Now if you see His life you’ll find He is
absolutely very human, the way He used to
tease His mother, tease other ladies.
All this is extremely human and childlike,
and extremely sweet.
But behind that also there was a great significance.
For example, Shri Radha – as you know, She
was Mahalakshmi – and as Mahalakshmi She
used to put Her feet, take bath in the river
Yamuna, and the ladies would take water from
the same river, carry on their head the pitchers.
Now Shri Krishna wanted to raise their kundalini,
so He used to hit them from the back so that
the water falls on their back, and that vibrated
water would raise their kundalini.
This was His childish trick, but it had a
meaning.
Another one, when we see Him in ras – “ra”
means energy.
Radha: “ra” is “energy,” “dha”
means “the one who sustains it” – so
it is Radhaji who had the energy.
“Sa” means “with,” so when they played
ras, was nothing but to play with the energy.
And that’s how He wanted to have a collective
awakening of people, of gopa and gopis, and
He did it.
But then He had to leave and fight this Kamsa.
In His own lifetime, as a child or grown-up,
He punished all kinds of devils and women
devils who were like Putna, and all that.
He did it, and in this Kali Yuga also He’s
active.
We have seen how gradually He has finished
so many false gurus, one by one; somebody
who called himself Shri Krishna, somebody
who called himself as God, something else,
something else.
He finished them all, exposed them nicely,
and now we have very few people in the arena
left for us to fight.
They themselves are trembling and they are
quite frightened of us, because we are standing
on truth.
So now, when we have to think about Shri Krishna
who is residing in our Vishuddhi Chakra.
Many people have this problem of left Vishuddhi.
That is because we are more sort of very social
people.
Now in the Western society, the social system
is so rigid that anybody can collapse with
that, or used to be; now better because of
the, maybe the revolt, anti-culture.
But otherwise if you could put one spoon from
here to there, then you are finished.
If you start your food with, say, not with
the fish knife but with an ordinary knife,
then you’re finished, you are no good.
And these French have made even much worse
by using a big science out of alcohol.
For this alcohol this is the glass, for that
alcohol that is the glass, and all that.
So the whole collective was made so rigid.
It’s much more rigid than in India.
I used to think Indian collective is quite
rigid because of certain conditionings we
have, but after coming to the West I was surprised
that it is such a conditioning in the heads
of the people, that some of the conditionings
you cannot remove – say from Catholic Church,
you might say, or from wherever it is.
But when it comes from somebody like Freud
who was absolutely a devil, they just give
up all these conditionings and take to that.
I cannot understand any country where there
is Catholic Church so predominant, they are
following Freud.
So this collective rigidity, which was then
because maybe Shri Rama was a very formal
person, because of Him maybe the collective
rigidity might have been in India.
But in the West it is all mental, it’s absolutely
mental.
If you make this kind of hair then you are
all right, if you put oil then you are absolutely
lunatic: all kinds of funny ideas were given,
and people started doing like this.
If you don’t put oil at all you’ll become
bald.
If you become bald, then they will have a
business of their wigs.
So the whole thing was money-oriented, and
everything was made so fixed that you had
to do it so that they could sell their things.
England was, as you know, is tailcoat: you
have to wear a tailcoat if you have to see
the Queen.
I don’t know why you have to wear a tailcoat
to see the Queen, but it’s compulsory, and
if you don’t wear then you are not allowed.
So they have to borrow these tailcoats and
all that from one shop, which can be tight,
which can be loose, and everybody looks like
Charlie Chaplin to Me!
They can’t walk straight.
So this kind of stupid rigidity that came
into the West has really made them very nervous.
People are so nervous here.
If you tell some lady that “I am going to
come and have food with you,” she will collapse.
God knows what she thinks, I mean, it is caring
for the public opinion, or her own conditioning.
But in an Indian, a housewife, if you tell
her you are going to come, she’ll be the
happiest person.
She’ll be very happy that you are coming
to her house for dinner.
But here even if you say, “I would like
to come and see you in the evening,” they’ll
say, “All right, come in the pub.”
Because they’re so nervous, they’re not
sure of themself; and this has come, I think,
perhaps from these norms that there have been
created in the West.
In India also we had lots of these ritualism
that came up very serious.
Like we had people, Jainis who’d pick up
their hair with their hands.
They are not supposed to use any knives or
any scissors or any barbers, so they were
supposed to pick up their hair on their own.
So from their beard, from their this thing,
they would pick up all the time.
That went to such a horrible conditioning
that they would say that if you, even if you
breathe then you can, you might consume some
animals.
So they would put some sort of a cloth before
their mouth, and all kinds of nonsense they
did.
At that time Shri Krishna came in.
His own cousin was a tirthankara, you’ll
be surprised, Neminath.
He became a tirthankara, and that made Shri
Krishna think about it, that this kind of
stupid ritualism that we have.
Like in the morning women will get up, in
their sleep they will go, put some water for
tulsi, do this thing, that thing, throw water
here and there.
And also the untouchables and touchables;
and you can’t take water from this, you
can’t eat this, you can’t move like that
– all kinds of restrictions, timing, everything.
This time is not good, that time is not good,
this you should not do, that you should not
do, to such an extent that the whole movement
of our country was round these rituals.
I had nephews who used to come to Bombay for
their work.
Every time they went to Lucknow, they would
come with shaven heads.
I said, “What’s the matter?”
He said, “There are many people in our family
who are old, and when they die we have to
shave our heads.”
So every time they went there somebody died,
so they came with shaven heads.
Like that such horrible rituals existed, and
even now in the South India there is a lot
of rituals are there, terrible rituals, and
they cannot get out of it, they’re frightened.
If they get out of it then they might be sinners,
or they will go to hell.
So the Indian conditioning was, as far as
these rigidities were concerned for religion,
to be on the right side in such a way that
we should not be caught up without doing this.
So early in the morning they’ll get up and
do the rituals, just without even thinking
about what they’re doing.
But in the West the lifestyle is nothing but
rigidity, the whole lifestyle is; there’s
no freedom anywhere.
And all that then was rewarded by these hippies
and other people, and all of them, and they
fought it, and that thing went to another
extremes.
So from one extreme to another extreme they
went.
Now, how Shri Krishna’s advent changed it.
When Shri Krishna came on this Earth, He said
this is all a leela, it is just a play.
Because you are involved into it, you cannot
see the play.
But if you ascend – if you are in the water
you are afraid of the water, but if you get
into the boat you can see the water, and if
you know how to swim you can even save the
people who are in the water.
So He says that if you develop a witness state,
sakshi swarupata, if you develop that state
then you see the whole thing as a drama.
Nothing affects you.
Nothing matters, you don’t worry about anything,
you see the problem above; you are, and you
see the problem, and because you are out of
it, you can solve the problem.
This was His great advent, I would say, that
has taught the first step towards the ascent,
is that you have to become a sakshi.
You have to become the witness.
Now let’s see in Sahaja Yoga.
In Sahaja Yoga there are different types of
people come from different areas, from different
cultures, because the door is open to everyone.
Now if an Indian comes in, he will be all
the time watchful about others, and will say
that “Mother, this man is not doing this,
this man is not doing that.
He should have done footsoaking.”
He’ll find faults with others, all the time
saying that this man is not doing like this,
and you know.
But in the West they start finding faults
with themselves.
And I receive letters, ten to twelve pages
sometimes, confessing what wrong they have
done.
Who is interested to know, what wrongs you
have done?
I mean, if a lotus is born, nobody wants to
know how many filthy things are inside the
pond.
You are now a lotus.
But it’s so common that they think we must
confess, we must tell Mother what wrong we
have done.
Every moment you are changing, so what is
there to confess?
And the life is so formal, as I told you,
that people suffer from guilt for anything.
Apart from the influence of this Catholic
Church has conditioned you so much that even
if you are not a Catholic, you’re a Protestant,
still you have guilt, and as a guilt you develop
this left Vishuddhi.
So then this left Vishuddhi is Vishnumaya
– means what?
Once you have this left Vishuddhi you develop
all the problems of the Vishnumaya, and one
of them is the heart.
Because Vishnumaya is an active thing, She
is like electricity; and if you have Vishnumaya
problem, then you become lethargic.
“Oh, I’m so guilty.”
You become depressed.
That Vishnumaya Principle disappears from
you.
She’s the one who’s quick, fast, and She
gives the light, and announces to the whole
world what Shri Krishna is.
While what happens with such people, Sahaja
yogis who come in, who feel guilty, they say,
“Mother, You know, we thought that if we
do this then our ego will come up.
If we do any work outside and work in some
fields or in some villages, then our ego will
come up.
So we don’t want to do it.”
This is absurd.
It’s like you give light to some light,
and the light says that “I don’t want
to give the light, because maybe this light
might develop an ego.”
It is absurd.
But such absurd things Sahaja yogis tell Me.
For them one has to understand, to get out
of this left Vishuddhi is to become absolutely
dynamic in Sahaja Yoga, go all out into Sahaja
Yoga.
Otherwise they can’t get rid of their left
Vishuddhis.
Left Vishuddhi is a thing that’s a very
depressive action on the whole being, and
a person who has left Vishuddhi is always
a very slow person to do anything for Sahaja
Yoga.
You have not been given light to hide it.
Christ has said that you don’t put light
under the table.
So you have been given light to work it out,
to be dynamic, to think what to do, how to
arrange, how to organize.
But if you are guilty, then you will all the
time say, “Oh Mother, it’s very difficult,
You know, this . . .” Always you’ll find
the other side of the whole joke, just to
avoid.
Now for a Sahaja yogi is to witness himself,
first of all.
That is the introspection.
He should see for himself, “Where was I,
and I have come here.”
Don’t indulge too much in the past, but
see the distance you have crossed in such
a short time.
Now you have come into the Kingdom of God,
you have all the powers.
I don’t tell lies – it’s a fact.
I’ll give you an example, if Wolfgang allows
Me to say that.
Wolfgang was with Me when we were traveling
from Prague to Vienna and the plane, you see,
he told Me that the plane is at ten-thirty,
but it was at nine-thirty; it was a mistake.
It’s all right, there can be mistake, of
course, that also is Shri Krishna’s style.
You can always do mistakes, doesn’t matter.
So we reached – I mean, why all these things
happen, see, to create an event, a ghatna.
So he was very upset about it that he told
Me a wrong time, and I reached there about
fifteen minutes late.
And there was a ground hostess, horrible,
she started shouting at Me, saying all kinds,
“It’s not fair, You don’t know,” this,
that and everything.
I just didn’t bother about it because I
knew that it was out of mistake we’ve done
it.
And they could have taken away their plane
instead of shouting, but they kept the plane
and shouted at Me, because she wanted to shout,
you see.
Then the plane was filled in with people and
it would not leave, so I asked the engineers.
They said, “It has been like this for the
half-an-hour.
We are trying to correct it.
It’s like this.”
So it’s all right.
He said that “We’ll have to wait till
we put it right.”
But because she shouted at Me, Wolfgang was
full of tears, you see; just look at this
German having so many tears in his eyes!
Then Alga was telling him that “It’s all
right, doesn’t matter.
It’s not your mistake.”
He was feeling so sad that Mother has been
insulted like this by this lady, because of
my mistake – I mean, it’s love.
Now the power of his love was so great.
At the same moment there were so many, to
about fifty people, Sahaja yogis standing
on the balcony watching us.
We also felt and they also felt, but they
felt a tremendous cool breeze like a big blow
came to them and blew upon them vibrations,
and they just got enamored.
And suddenly when they opened their eyes what
they find, the whole sky was filled with clouds.
There was not a single cloud.
In one second, in one second from where the
clouds came, God knows.
It was all completely filled with them.
Then they asked us to get out because they
could not do anything.
So when we came back it started raining.
When we came in, he got after that lady.
He said, “Now, whom are we to shout?
We can’t catch our planes now.”
And then they announced that all the flights
are cancelled.
So see the power of his love for his Mother
that the whole sky couldn’t bear it, you
see, the, his eyes became the sky.
And in a second they said, “Mother, we have
never seen such a miracle, that there is not
one single thing and the whole thing was filled
with this.”
So you must know your powers.
That is what is – first of all witness yourself,
is the introspection.
See for yourself how many powers you have
got.
Now with your left Vishuddhi you will always
conclude, “Oh, how can I have any powers?
After all, I have done this, I have done that.”
Even if you give somebody hundred pounds and
you tell him that now you go to the market,
buy something, he’ll say, “Oh, what’s
the use of this hundred pounds?” this, that.
Use it!
As simple as that.
But then Sahaja yogis start saying that “No,
no, no, no.
Mother says, but how can I have?
How can I have these powers, after all?
It’s not possible.
I’m no good.”
Because that left Vishuddhi’s all the time
telling that you are good for nothing.
It’s like a leaking hole in your brain that
takes away all the sense, and you accept it.
So first thing is to introspect yourself,
and see for yourself how many powers you have
got.
Like in the beginning no Sahaja yogi would
give realization, in India.
Nobody would even touch anyone.
It so happened that My car failed and I was
late two hours, luckily, and there was a big
meeting and they didn’t know what to do,
so they started giving realization to people.
And then they realized they can give realization;
otherwise they would not touch anyone.
Now you know that what you can do.
You also know that whatever you say happens.
Whatever you want you can get it.
Try, try, try!
But if you don’t do it, then you’ll be
all the time half-baked.
Take the experience of your powers, see how
dynamic you are.
Don’t have formalities about it, just use
it fully, and you will be amazed that you
have so many powers.
Somebody told Me that “Mother, You have
given a siddhi to Guido.”
I have given siddhi to all of you.
I never discriminate; but it’s only he is
very brave, he’s used it left and right.
He uses left and right.
If you do not use your siddhis, what can I
do?
I’ve given you all the siddhis, no doubt
about it, so try.
Like in the beginning Baba Mama told Me that
“How can I write a poem?
I feel like writing but I am rather frightened,
because I could not even write an essay.”
I used to write essay for all My brothers,
you see, when they were studying.
I was very good at languages.
But that’s what he said, and now look at
him!
I told him, “You go ahead and write whatever
you write.”
He said, “I may write something wrong.”
“It doesn’t matter.
Write it.”
In the same way, somebody wants to paint something,
one should not think how they will criticize
or anything – just paint.
If you want to sing, just sing.
If you want to do anything, any manifestation,
just do it boldly.
Go in a big way.
You’ll be amazed at yourself how you have
achieved it and how you are doing it.
It has worked with so many artists, you know
that.
That day Debu told you about himself, and
in so many they can tell you that this has
happened to them.
So now the first thing is to know that you
have powers.
Now believe in them.
Have faith in yourself.
If you have left Vishuddhi, this Vishnumaya
won’t work out.
But be like Vishnumaya.
Just give up this guilt.
“No, I am a Sahaja yogi.
I’m not an ordinary person.”
People sometimes talk to Me and I say, “Do
you know what you are?”
“What, Mother?”
“You are a Sahaja yogi.”
“Oh, I forgot.”
“Now go and do it.”
And the another style of this left Vishuddhi
is this, which one must understand, that it
tries to give an explanation.
As I told you many a time, you tell somebody
that telephone to someone.
First they will say, “He may not be there,
Mother.”
“Baba, you telephone!
First find out if he may be there or may not
be there.”
But they would not.
They would just avoid, and that is another
thing.
Vishnumaya never avoids, you have seen that.
Once She has to shine She shines, wherever
She is, whatever She is.
So in the same way we have to be like that.
We have to know that we are special people,
we are chosen, we are angelic and that we
have entered into the Kingdom of God, and
it will all work out.
Sahaja Yoga is not meant for useless people.
As I told you, in Marathi, Tukaram has said,
“Yeddya gabalyache kam nave.”
It’s not meant for lunatics and lousy people.
It’s meant for somebody who has tyala pahijet
jatiche.
You need people of character.
I know that there cannot be many like that,
but there is no place in God’s realm for
many people, for all these useless people.
It’s only for something special.
These seats are reserved and you have got
your realization now, somehow.
So now try to understand that this Vishnumaya
Principle has to be expressed and has to be
shown, and you introspect yourself: have I
done that or not?
Don’t be afraid that they say that “But
our ego will come up.”
Doesn’t matter.
You will also see your ego.
This is the second part of Shri Krishna’s
play, that in this Krita Yuga you see your
ego.
There was a lady who was rather not very kind
to some Maharashtrian ladies.
So I told her, “You have got right side.”
She wouldn’t believe.
She came to see Me in Rome, and she fell down
on right side, completely.
Then she realized that her right side was
not all right.
So to know that, whether you have a right
or a left, there’s a very good method, is
of meditation.
Now the third situation is that you must accept
whatever is wrong with you.
If you do not accept, then you have not been
kind to yourself.
That is the central part of it, that you must
accept, “Yes, this is something wrong with
me.
I have gone in this part I’m wrong, of my
Vishuddhi, or that part I’m wrong.
So now I have to improve.”
Now, right Vishuddhi people will always try
to correct Me.
I’ve seen it.
It’s very simple for them.
If I say anything, “No.”
First words.
Different types “no’s” there are.
Sometimes, “No!”
Sometimes it is “No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no!”
They will contradict Me or try to put their
own idea, and then they discover that it was
wrong; they should not have said it.
Say for example, if I say, “I saw these
things lying here.”
They said, “No.”
I said, “I saw with My own eyes and once
I see something, you know, it’s registers,
it’s there.”
“No.”
I say, “All right, just try to find out.”
“It’s there.
How is it we didn’t see?”
I said, “Because your ‘no’ was written
on your eyes, I think, you couldn’t see
anything.”
And then they’ll pull their ears – that’s
the best.
But if you see that “This is a habit I have
of saying no to things.”
So first of all, I also test you.
Supposing I say it is just now nine o’clock
in the night, you just say yes; let’s see
what happens.
Try to see.
You see, I test you many a times like this
and then I see that some people – if I say
so, all right, if it’s so, if Mother has
said, it is so.
And then it starts building up their faith
very well.
I can see they’re, clearly how they are
coming into the realm of real faith, and there
when I say something absurd they’ll just
smile.
They know it is Mother is just testing us,
you see, so they just smile.
They wouldn’t do anything, but they’ll
just smile.
And then if it is so and if they don’t know,
they’ll say, “Yes, it must be.
Mother must have done this or said so.”
So your testing time is there.
You have to test yourself.
As Mohammed Sahib has said, that your hands
will speak and they’ll give witness against
you – so on your hands you will know.
Now these hands are the blessings of Shri
Krishna.
They come out from the same Vishuddhi, and
as you know the pelvic nerves serves it on
all that.
And there are two chakras of one Lalita, another
Shri Chakras, all on these both sides; they
also play into the hands of Shri Krishna.
With these hands we can feel the vibrations.
Now if your right Vishuddhi’s too strong
you may not feel, if your left Vishuddhi’s
too strong you may not feel, but that doesn’t
mean that you haven’t got realization.
You have got.
You just work out your hands.
Now for working your hands, you have to see
that you don’t use them for useless things.
That’s very important, because you have
special hands.
These hands are the ones with which you spread
the collectivity.
Now for example, Italy example this: here
the people when they talk, they’ll go on
… They don’t know anything what they are
saying, they only know their own, all their
gestures, and they only can depict.
For a person who doesn’t know them, on they’ll
go on like this, like this, all the time.
So this should be reduced.
There’s no need to use your hands so much
all the time, like this, like that.
Little bit, but while using the hands also
it should be decent, it should be regulated,
it should be
very indicative and useful.
Just showing off your hands is not good.
It is some sort of a theory came out, I was
told, that you must put your gestures into
your hands and speak.
Is all right for people like Hitler, but not
for us.
For us we should be decent.
We should, whenever we have to say – now
for example, you want to point out something
to someone, shouldn’t say “do this.”
This is Shri Krishna’s finger, you can’t
use it like that.
Let them do, means supporting everything.
This looks better.
These hands are to be used for collectivity.
See, we say “namaste” when we meet others.
To thousands of people we can say “namaste.”
But I don’t like the shaking hands business
because it’s no good.
Shaking hands doesn’t create any collectivity.
On the contrary, you might get all kinds of
pins and needles and all kinds of problems
from others.
But when you talk to people also, with these
hands only you can feel them; with these hands
only you can care for your children; with
these hands only you can suggest your softness,
your sweetness, and also with the mouth – which
is of course is a part of the Vishuddhi, that’s
different – but specially hands.
Your gestures and everything should show very
heartfelt emotions, and then only these gestures
have some meaning.
Now in Sahaja Yoga as you know, you hold each
other’s hands and the vibration starts flowing
among yourselves.
And you can also hear the tabla on your throbbings,
so that shows that they are the communication.
So these hands, which are really the beginning
of the collectivity – most important, I
would say the most important things are the
hands, which act for your collectivity.
As far as you are concerned there are many
other angels and other ganas who are standing
behind you.
They also, they extend their help to you whenever
you want to communicate something, they also
do your jobs very well.
So whatever is expressed in your hand or through
your hand, they immediately pick up.
As you know that Vishuddhi has sixteen petals,
and all ear, nose, throat, eyes, all are guided
by this.
Also the sub-plexus of this Vishuddhi is this
one, is the Hamsa Chakra.
So we have these eyes to see, eyes to communicate.
The pure eyes communicate pure love, purity.
With the pure eyes you can cleanse people,
with the pure eyes you can help others, you
can bring peace.
The purification of the eyes takes place through
your Vishuddhi and Agnya.
Here both things have to work out.
The nose is very important.
Nose has to be pure, in the sense that you
should be able to discard whatever is smelling
badly, and you should be able to accept whatever
is fragrant.
It’s very important, because nose is the
speciality of Shri Krishna, I would say, in
the sense that He’s the Kubera, and the
Kubera has given the nose to the Goddess.
Some people have a bad habit of moving their
nose just to show disapproval or something
like this, they go on doing like that.
This is very wrong, because then you are insulting
yourself, you’re insulting your Kubera power.
So you have to keep your nose in a dignified
manner.
It should be a dignified nose.
It should not be used for doing something
which is undignified, or which expresses contempt.
Then your teeth are very important.
You have thirty-two teeth, see: sixteen of
Krishna’s powers divided into, you can say,
thirty-two.
These are your teeth on both the sides.
The right side is on top and the left down
below.
That is one thing we neglect very much in
the West, I must say.
In India it is not.
It is very much we neglect, and that’s what
we have to look after.
The reason for neglect is that, I would say,
is laziness, must be the laziness, but at
least twice or thrice you must brush your
teeth.
Is important, that I need not say, but more
important is to change the brush.
Also you have to use butter, or salt and oil
to rub your gums.
If you rub your gums properly, you will never
have problems with your teeth and your gums.
Moreover, every time in the evening you must
again brush your teeth.
I’ve seen many people who come to Me in
the evening in the program, such a horrible
smell from their mouth comes out.
It is not that it’s a disease but it is,
only thing is that they have not cleansed
their teeth.
Also there are people who will not even brush
their teeth, and start eating breakfast.
I don’t know, it was another theory started,
I think, that you can eat your food without
brushing.
Teeth are very important, and one must look
after them.
On the teeth it depends all the qualities
of your Vishuddhi.
So one has to look after the teeth in a proper
way, and should never clench and never show
temper with the teeth.
It’s a very bad habit.
Also here is a gesture I have seen that if
they don’t like something, they just go
on like this.
It’s a very wrong thing.
One should avoid that kind of a gesture, and
it’s very dangerous for your teeth.
So today’s lecture is more sort of medical,
I must say.
A person who is spiritually endowed has an
expression which can never be aggressive.
He may not be good-looking, may not be very,
a sort of a attractive personality, but the
expression on the face is absolutely saintly.
That is also the blessings of Shri Krishna.
I have seen people after one year of realization,
and I was surprised how their faces were changed,
that I could not recognize them who they were.
The whole thing becomes absolutely mild, soft,
peaceful and very joyous.
All the qualities of Shri Krishna can be expressed
on your face.
You can be sometimes mischievous to look at.
So many expressions there are which come on
the face, and give you a very sweet feeling.
But some people have a habit of looking in
the mirror all the time, which is very wrong,
because it gives you a kind of a funny ego.
Is better to look at Shri Krishna’s photograph
than to look at your own faces, so that your
face will become like that of Shri Krishna;
instead of you start looking in the mirror
all the time.
What will become of you, God knows, because
maybe if you go to your past, God knows what
you’ll become.
So also I’m thankful to psychiatrists that
they don’t like narcissism.
But it’s very dangerous to all the time
watch your face in the mirror, very dangerous.
It creates a very funny personality, that
you start telling yourself, “Oh, I’m Napoleon.”
So you become Napoleon, and start behaving
like Napoleon.
Next day you find one Napoleon walks out of
the bathroom!
So one has to be careful not to pay so much
attention and importance to your own self,
but to your Self which is within, which is
your spirit.
And if you look after that side, then all
these things will happen in such a beautiful
manner.
Also the hair are looked after by Shri Krishna.
Now you see, you know that He’s very fond
of anything that is like butter, so you have
to put either butter or oil or something in
your hair.
If you don’t put it you’ll become bald.
What can – I mean it is after all a karma
phala.
If you don’t put oil, you’ll become bald.
So you have to put oil, and oil was put always
before in the West.
I see all these old films and all that, they’re
all oiled people.
But now of course, if you don’t want to
put oil in the daytime you can wash it off,
but at least once a week you must oil your
head.
Shri Krishna’s star is Saturn, Shani.
They say that if He gets after somebody, then
nobody can be saved.
If Shri Krishna gets after someone, then nobody
can be saved.
In the same way, if Saturn gets after someone
then that person is finished, so we say it’s
for sometimes, it is seven years He’s after
you, or sometimes two-and-a-half years after
you.
So this Saturn of Shri Krishna is a, it’s
a quality within us that, supposing if somebody
troubles us or does something, we don’t
have to do anything.
Now this Shri Krishna policy, this, we can
say, the Shri Krishna’s nature will work
it out.
It will inform this all-pervading Power, and
through that this man or this woman, or this
party or this organization which is trying
to trouble us will be hounded, while we’ll
be just sitting doing nothing.
They’ll be just hounded till they jump in
the sea.
Automatically it will happen.
But you have to know that you have the powers
of Shri Krishna by which, if He gets after
someone, then nobody can save them.
He’s the last one who plays around, but
He doesn’t forgive.
He doesn’t believe in forgiveness.
He says, “Now, you had enough of it.”
He gives a big, big long rope to hang yourself,
but He never forgives.
One thing for definite, He never forgives.
As you must have seen in Mahabharata His own
judgment of things, you see, He doesn’t
forgive.
He says, “You have to pay.
You have to pay for it.”
Except when, when you transcend.
If you become a Sahaja yogi, if you have transcended
Vishuddhi, then He cannot do anything like
that to you.
But if you have not, if there’s no ascent
you cannot be saved, you cannot be saved from
Him.
They say once Mohammed Gajani came to loot
our country – I mean, it’s a story about
the village folk.
And there he’s looted Somnath, a big temple
of ours, which had lots of gold, jewelry,
everything in it.
So these brahmins were, you see, taking money
from all these people and looting them, and
putting them in the temple and using them,
and the rest of the people were very poor.
So it was sort of a reaction in them, and
the story they tell like this: so this Mohammed
Gajani looted Somnath, is the temple of Mahadeva.
Now Mahadeva never needs any ornaments or
anything, but they had put this there.
So Hanumana saw that Mahadeva got out of the
temple and was running, so Hanumana ran after
Him.
Then at one point Mahadeva sat down, and Hanumana
came.
He said, “You are the God of Gods.
Why are You running?
What are You afraid of?”
He said, “You don’t know this Mohammed
Gajani?”
He said, “No I don’t know.”
“All right, hide behind a tree.”
They hid behind a tree.
So this Mohammed Gajani came and sat down
– this is the folklore I’m telling, folk
people tell – sat down under that tree.
And turning to Shri Krishna, he said, “This
horrible thing, if He gets after someone,
who can be saved?
Under my nose these brahmins were making money
and all that, putting it in Somnath temple,
which was not to be done.
I couldn’t do anything, so He came, and
with this fellow after me I cannot be saved
either, so I am running away from the temple.”
So this is the story given by the villagers,
but which shows that if Shri Krishna is after
somebody, then nobody can save that person,
he has to run away; because He has so many
tricks and so many styles that you can’t
get out of it.
He’ll use His brains in so many manners,
and that He’ll put that person right who
is trying to trouble you.
So you must have complete faith in the powers
of Shri Krishna which is within yourself,
which is being aware now.
And also if you have ascended fully out of
this, then He will not trouble; but if you
have left Vishuddhi He will trouble you, definitely.
If you have left Vishuddhi Shri Krishna will
definitely trouble you, and be careful.
So get rid of your left Vishuddhis now.
That’s very important.
Because then Shri Krishna will take your test
and will make you so miserable that you will
not know why.
“Mother, You see, I did this, I did this
puja, I did this till, let’s see now, this
is the situation in my family.
This is what happened.”
“All right, are you a Catholic?”
“Yes.”
“Feel guilty?”
“So have it.”
What can I do?
Shri Krishna cannot be controlled by anyone.
He does whatever He thinks proper and He is
meant to really punish much more than the
Mother, I can tell you.
They say that She’s Adi Rudra, Adi Saumya:
She’s the one who’s very hard and also
very, very soft, but up to a point.
He is not.
Nothing can convince Him.
Once you get into His control, that He’ll
see to it that you are put right, left, right,
any way He’ll make you all right.
So one thing is there, that you should be
sure that you should have your Vishuddhis
all right, first of all, and also get Shri
Krishna manifesting on others.
You don’t have to do anything.
He’ll look after you, everything, and work
it out.
But left Vishuddhi is a disease of the West.
I also feel so much from you all that I sometimes
feel like running away to India, because in
India nobody feels guilty.
They don’t believe in feeling guilty.
“What is there?
We have not murdered anyone.
Why should we feel guilty?”
Here it is a disease with everyone, “I feel
guilty.”
I don’t know who has introduced this idea,
maybe this Catholic Church, but carried too
far.
So then we come to the Virata's point, is
here.
Before that we have to cross the Hamsa; without
that you cannot reach the Virat point.
So Hamsa is as you know very well, is the
discretion, divine discretion, which must
be within you.
Once you develop that, then you don’t commit
mistakes.
You never commit mistakes – mistakes in
the sense you don’t do things which are
again pushed back on you, or for which you
have to pay.
It’s just a very straightforward life.
“It’s so?
It’s so.”
With this discretion, absolutely you have
a complete understanding as to what has to
be done and what not to be done.
And if that is established, a discretion is
established.
In many Sahaja yogis, I must say, discretion
has come even with their left Vishuddhi.
Even if they have left Vishuddhi they have
this discretion, they know what is right and
what is wrong.
With that divine discretion, the first thing
that happens is that people get impressed
by you.
It’s real collectivity, it impresses the
collectivity.
A person who has divine discretion, people
immediately see the wisdom of that person
and think, “See now, this man, how could
he be?
He’s so young, how could he be?
He’s such a child, how could he be?”
So this divine discretion which is the, here,
Hamsa Chakra’s speciality, when it starts
manifesting then automatically you impress,
automatically you impress the collectivity.
This is a very important point one has to
know.
While introspecting yourself, you just see
if you have developed this quality of divine
discretion or not.
For example, there are many I have seen when
they come to the program, they come and tell
Me, “Mother, some Sahaja yogi told me that
‘You have a bhoot.’
Have I got a bhoot in me?”
I said, “Not at all.
How can there be any bhoot in you?”
He may be having, but the divine discretion
is not to tell him just now, but to remove
it.
So divine discretion gives you a complete
understanding what is the way to handle another
personality, what is the way to handle a collective,
how to talk to others, how to impress on them
the right things.
It’s a very, very expansive manifestation
in so many directions.
If you have no divine discretion, you’ll
start speaking what you should not speak,
you’ll start saying at a time when you should
not say.
I mean, you’ll have no sense at all of any
direction.
So to have divine discretion is very important,
for which as you know, Hamsa Chakra physically
as well mentally and also spiritually must
be kept all right.
In My Hamsas – we had one puja where I talked
about it.
The last is the Virat: that is the state you
have to reach.
Is the Virat is here in front, as you know.
And I was surprised when I went to Nepal,
which is a temple of Shiva there: despite
they were worshipping Shiva they were putting
all the kumkum here.
So I thought that they don’t know why they
are putting, because even if you worship Shiva
you must also worship here, the Virata.
They don’t put it here – here; because
they’re absolutely hundred percent only
Shiva worshippers, so why should they put
it here?
Because somebody who knows, who was gnostic,
has told them that this is the place of Virat.
Once you get into Virata, then all your ideas
of separating or differentiating goes away.
You do not have any more ideas of races left,
of nationality, of your city, of your village
or anything.
At that stage you don’t belong to any place.
You belong to every place, and you don’t
belong to every place.
Such a situation comes in when you don’t
hanker after any particular food, you don’t
like any particular type of people, you can
adjust yourself into any circumstances, into
any families, into any kind of people.
You can live with drunkards.
I mean I have lived with drunkards – “lived”
means I have shaken hands at least with so
many of them.
You can be with any kind of person.
Nothing bothers you because you are in the
Virata state; because everything is absorbed
by the Virat, and you do not feel anything.
Whatever sort of person may be, you do not
feel it.
The Virat has to suffer, not you, and that
is what is the best state where I want all
of you to reach, and to become absolutely
free.
Nothing can impress you, nothing can influence
you, nothing can dissuade you, but you stand
on your self-esteem and understanding about
yourself, that you’re a Sahaja yogi and
that you are connected with this power, and
you are a citizen of Kingdom of God.
At the Virata state there's no doubt left
about it, no doubt, because you become part
and parcel of the whole, absolutely, and you
can affect anywhere.
If this finger is hurt, then this finger can
feel it.
In the same way such a person is felt everywhere,
and not only that, but that person can be
effective everywhere.
For that state of reaching to Virat, one should
try to slowly, gradually, “Ya neti neti
vachanaih nirgama avochu” say.
You have to go on saying, “This is not my
sister.
This is not my brother.
They are all my brothers.
They’re all my sisters.
I love them the same as my sisters and my
brothers.
This is not my family.
The whole Sahaja Yoga is my family.”
The whole attention should move like that.
“This is not only mine, it is everybody’s.
It belongs to everyone.
Everybody has a right.”
That sort of a thing, when it starts growing
from individual, what we call is the “vestiti
tu sumestiti” in Sanskrit, they say “vestiti
tu sumestiti,” from individual to collective.
And such a personality then is the most effective
one for any kind of collective work.
I think for today it’s quite sufficient
for you to know about Vishuddhi Chakra.
I mean, I have talked about it thousands and
thousands of times, and now this is one of
the sides which I wanted to say, because I
find that still there are people who do not
understand that they have to rise above Vishuddhi.
Otherwise, if they do not ascend over Vishuddhi
they can never be proper Sahaja yogis, they’ll
be always half-baked.
So we must try to rise above the Vishuddhi,
the discretion part.
Then at that point we can never doubt Sahaja
Yoga, can never doubt, and that’s how the
doubtless awareness can come to us.
May God bless you.
All right.
Shri Krishna Puja is very small that way,
not such a long thing.
at Agnya
above Agnya