[Music]
[Applause]
why all the religions have failed
because they did not get their
self-realization they did not become the
spirit so there's a tremendous
difference between you on earth and all
others who profess somebody it looks as
if they're hypocrites they
intellectualize it as you know they
explain it very well but you can see
very clearly that they haven't absorbed
spirituality that absorption was
impossible without self like this
everybody felt good I went to this limit
and Mahavira both to say that forget
about God forget about God Almighty you
just get yourself yourself relation so
they are called as atheist any rickshaw
body they don't believe in Israel but
they felt that the way people are just
talking about God Almighty and what the
books are said these books also speak of
righteousness except in some books there
has been some sort of interference but
most of them speak of spirituality and
what you have to achieve what is the
purpose of religion
everybody claims that they are the
chosen ones but they are just the same
there's a tremendous achievement of
sahaja Yogi's that they have achieved a
state of spirit so now you can absorb
Dharma without any difficulties without
any you will stick on to the truth first
of all which is the most important thing
that you have a rapport with God
Almighty that you are in a way in awe
about God all your attention will be
towards the expansion of your awareness
in the light of the Spirit this is the
vision of your mother because she was
just a witness so that Shiva is just
witnessing all this plane he doesn't
have any visions about but now you must
have lots of hopes after seeing the kind
of people that are created out of
certain very unique very beautiful
wonderful angel like people have been
created now only problem is that you
have to keep to your angelic foundations
but I find that sometimes it happens
doesn't matter that you fall and falter
again you rise into your awareness and
try to locate
the new dimensions that are available to
you that you can find out
so this speciality that you have got is
the region of all the saints of all the
prophets of all this years of all the
incarnations is you the heart has become
so large because she was shining there
is purity shining it has become such a
large heart that it encompasses the
whole universe I think the way people
looking look at it that's why you all
have become Universal people but that
universe something you have got thanks
to your spirit that was there quite
intact and which has started shining
sahaja Yoga is such a subtle subject
because you know everybody has failed to
make people understand anything about
impossible situation but this was the
trick your spirit once your spirit is
enlightened it goes into your head
without any difficulties absolutely such
you don't know how difficult is the
subject of such it is such a fulfillment
but the desire of the divine that your
divinity is now expressive once you have
got the spirit you get that power that
you can surpass all the sin temptations
not only temptations also the
differentiations that you always make
this is that this is that but you
integrate integrate among yourselves you
integrate among different states
integrate among different countries the
whole cosmos seems to be integrated
woman and governed by the divine laws
this integration gives you a complete
understanding of sahaja yoga mentally
emotionally
as spiritually
it's not by some sort of brainwashing or
body but just through the light of
spirit you have seen the truth and you
have understood it also you have so many
powers you do not want to exert that's a
different point or thing but just on one
word of Prayer from you it's very
powerful than hundreds of prayers of
these people one asking is much more
powerful then thousands of these asking
you have never tried that try that so
very powerful in collective and also
individually I don't desire it but you
have to decide you have to pray you have
to ask and the wider you become your
prayers will be wider for a wider world
wider region not limited to your
children and not imitate your family not
limited to one place but unlimited areas
because if we have the power and if we
can operate the divine power then why
not we work it out ourselves we can so
your attention can go to any place it
can go to Nicaragua it can go to Israel
it can go to Saddam Hussein to any place
that you want to work it out it moves
its mobile it's Universal just start
expanding your heart your mind and your
attention
I bless you all from my heart really
sights the Shiva the Sadashiva and
Sadashiva bliss is he the one who is
watching watching all of you with such
admiration his joy knows no bounds it's
tremendous as if he is Dancing with joy
I hope all of you respect the principle
of Shiva within you that's the most
important and look after your vibrations
which are Sates in your being because
the spirit has awakened in your
attention in your central nervous system
that's the most important thing you have
to do the rest of it is such the stuff
it is absolutely such may God bless
[Music]
Oh