There has been no never such confusion in the
minds of human beings as it is today,
as to the right or wrong.
Never so much:
whatever\hwas said, "This was not good",  they would do,
knowingly that they are doing wrong.
If they\hwere good people they would say, "All right, this is good, we'll do the good".
But everybody knew\hthat this was wrong or right.
They may do it.
But today, no one knows what\his wrong and what is right.
Apart from wrong and right, it's much beyond that,
you have to know yourself.
Because this awareness is within us that we do not know ourselves.
We do\hnot know the absolute we live in a relative world.
Of this, everybody seems to be conscious.
Maybe\hin the subconscious or maybe in the unconscious.
But definitely, there's a feeling in every one\hof us,
that we do not know.
And it's a very honest feeling.
It's a very sublime feeling that we have
to know something more.
Now when we say the word 'no' we think as if I would say, "I don't know"
about Derbyshire, I've never been there.
Now this means what? "I don’t know about Derbyshire".
What don’t I know about Derbyshire?
I can read it in the books, I can find out. I can know all the history of Derbyshire.
I can find out who were the people who, who were making beautiful porcelain here,
I can find out all about their history, everything I can read about it.
Still, why should I say I don’t know anything about Derbyshire?
Because I have not been to Derbyshire before.
I have not been to Derby.
I have not been\hto this area I have not seen this place.
I have not visited it I have had no experience of this place
so I don't know about it.
This is exactly what is the situation.
The situation is that we do not know
about the Divine.
We have read about it we have heard about it.
So many people have written about
it once they know there's an inquiry about it they come out with books.
Books after books thousands of
books they have written.
How many of them are true and how many of them are untrue?
It is impossible\hto find out.
Because we do not actually know.
Supposing somebody says that Duke of Bedford was born in Derbyshire.
All right. How will I know?
I would not know till I meet somebody who is
really belonging to that place, who knows about it.
In the same way, the knowledge that we have also
about Divine
is very confusing but this is not knowledge.
This is never the knowledge.
The idea\hof knowledge comes to us
as if it is a kind of an answer
to our inquiries which\his rational,
which we can understand\hintelligently through our intelligence.
But now this area is beyond intelligence,
beyond rationality.
Beyond all that\his limited, is the unlimited area
All such unlimited areas can be only known by
experience
of your awareness.
Now this one should\h\hunderstand is a very delicate thing
how to know\hsomething
and experience of our awareness.
Not an experience they suddenly see a light. So it's an
experience.
I mean you can always see a light.
So great the people feel about it that they have seen
some light suddenly sparking before them.
Nothing so great! There could be some area, from there as sparking can come
and maybe it is of no use to you,
but just you might feel that you have experienced.
So, one must know that seeing is not experiencing.
For example, a dog sees this instrument [mike].
But what does he know about it? He sees it.
Awareness, the human awareness has so many great
things about itself
compared to the animal\hawareness.
For example, we can say the awareness of
beauty, animals don't have.
Awareness of cleanliness, animals don't have.
Human beings have these built within themselves.
They can feel it, they\hcan feel it
on their central nervous system
So, whatever is your awareness is to
be felt on your central nervous system.
It's not just an imaginary thing or a intellectual
discussion,
"Ah I see, yes, I know". Not that.
The knowledge should come\hto you through your feelings;
like I can feel this is hot or cold.
But a stone\hwill not feel anything.
In the same way, the feeling has to come through your central nervous system.
That means your awareness itself is to be going, has to be charged.
It has to get a new dimension.
Your awareness itself has to get a new dimension.
All other experiences has no meaning
whatsoever in evolution, if you see.
In evolutionary process, it is the awareness that
improves,
receives better and better dimensions.
And these dimensions have reached its maximum at
the time when you become a human being,
where your\hawareness is just ready to receive
the awareness\hof the universal Being, of the collective Being,
so that you become the collective Being.
Now\hI would like to tell you about this within\hourselves,
how we are placed.
For every practical\hpurposes,
you should not take me for granted,
but you should not also deny what I tell you.
It's like entering into a new University:
we listen to the professor and we try to
follow him.
Supposing he propounded, he propounds a hypothesis before you,
then you just\hstart judging
it, work it out.
If it is true,
then you call it a law.
In the same way,
we should enter into this new understanding,
by first seeing it, not denying it.
Then if it is true, then we have to believe it.
There should be no blind faith about Sahaja Yoga.
Blind faith does not help at all.
Neither there should be a denial.
And with that cheerful attitude, if you just listen to Me as a hypothesis, whatever I'm telling you,
you need not accept it as truth just now.
But then the time has come for me
to prove the truth to you.
And the truth can be proved to you.
Time has come to prove the existence of God;
to prove, not prove that
I give you a big lecture or take you to course
or some sort of a thing like that.
But how\ham I going to prove it? On your awareness!
It is going to be absolute experience of your awareness
that\hyou are going to feel God almighty.
Time has come to prove the scriptures,
all the scriptures.
The time has come to prove your own connection with God,
your own relationship with him,
your own relationship with that Primordial Being,
whether you call it God or anything
I it makes no difference to God himself.
Whether you call him by any name there
is God.
And that God is not the way you conceive God.
It's not the way you understand\hGod or you know God.
But it's the God as he is.