What a beautiful place you have!
Hello! Om Twameva Sakshat
Shri Mahalakshmi Mahasaraswati
Mahakali Trigunatmika
Kundalini Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namoh namah!
Om Twameva Sakshat
Shri Kalki Sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namoh namah!
Om Twameva Sakshat
Shri Kalki Sakshat
Shri Sahasrara Swamini Moksha Pradayini Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namoh namah!
Jagan-mata Shri Nirmala Devi ki Jai!
Beautiful place.
What a beautiful place, ha? Beautiful place,
under the sky.
You all have a ride, is it?
Nice shady place also.
Hello, yes, You are playing? Did you go on the river?
How can you all be sitting there, it's so muddy!
Come down Michael
Aah!
Is that a nest?
No, that's a dead branch, Mother. Just a dead branch hanging down.
Looks a little bit like mistletoe.
Yogi: There is quite a lot of mistletoe on the trees all around here.
This is the eucalyptus, you see.
Hmmm!
These are Gum nuts? Yes, there are the flowers and then they become nuts.
The one we saw... these are the same?
Yogi: The same flowers that you saw in, where was it Adelaide.
The ones which are like Ganesha's flowers?
Yogi Yes, yes, yes, Mother.
With the four petals? Yogi: Yes, but it had a much bigger base.
Let Me see. Yogi: Much fatter base.
Yogi: They're all different shapes and sizes but the one we saw had-
definitely had four sections on it.
No, these are those different thing which has eyes sort of thing.
Is that the one?
Yogi: That was a banksia nut, actually, Mother, I think
He? Y:That was a banksia nut the one that you got little naps made.
That was in Perth.
Which may be had got four little slices in
Yes, yes, that was another one.
That was just like Ganesha.
Yogi: Western Australia is famous for that flower.
Great!
Yogi: In fact in the spring time after the rains
Yogi: Western Australia is just a blaze of wild flowers.
It's famous all over the world for that.
These are six, you see..ha... six.
Yes, these are six.
So, these are more Swadisthana I should say.
The fragrance is different from what we get in our eucalyptus.
Yogi: It's a whole, it's a whole range of fragrances.
Many, there is lemon scented and peppermint and
I think the one which is that, is Indian.
Can you get a leaf out of that? Let's see have a look.
Yogi: I think they are bringing You a selection of leaves, Mother.
Many eucalyptus here.
Children are very happy
They're so full of joy, children, just look.
Yogi: They've all been down in the mud, in the river.
Come along. He?
Look at them, look at the children.
How they feel one good nature immediately.
Thank you. This too has six.
They are so rich, I tell you.
Yogi: They make a lot of eucalyptus oil from these.
Yeah. But I feel our eucalyptus is very strong, Indian way.
It's smelling not so strong.
It's more the chlorophyll than eucalyptus oil in it.
Yogi: Some of these varieties are not so strong.
Yogi: It's the same I think that one, Mother, it is not a strong one.
Yogi: There are no lemon scented ones around at all?
This this one yeah, this is..
This is a willow. This is a weeping willow I think.
Yogini: No, it's not weeping type of gum but has no scent at all.
Yogini: The lemon scented one looks similar to that but
has beautiful smell of lemon about, (...)
Oh, this doesn't have.
But it has, not that it does not - but very faint.
I think on the whole India has got great quality of...
Yogi: Perfume, trees, flowers.
...flower, everything, you see even chandan is grown there
and once I talked to a lady
a Japanese lady, I said I enjoy Japanese garden.
She said, "But it doesn't have the perfume that You have in India."
Yes that's true.  Hm. We have trees with these Parijatakas and all.
Why don't you bring next time when you come that Parijataka?
Is a good idea
Very small flower, you must have seen, with a red stem.
Parijataka. This time I'll show you, if it is there.
We have so many scented flowers in our country.
One of them is this of course.
But we have another one which we call as Mogra -
It comes during summer. You can bring all these.
Yogi: From India?
Yogi: Yes, they should grow here too.
Yes, there's another one called Bakula. Bakula is a -
it looks like more like a wood like thing,
a little, little flower is there.
but it's a huge big tree and the whole place gets filled up with them
We have so many like that.
If they allow you to bring - do they?
Yogi: Well they don't but we could,
if we use it discriminately, I think, it would be alright.
We just hide it away in our bags.
I mean they are not, there's no danger with them. It's just that
some people bring some dangerous seeds in and
they become pests or become a source of infection.
Yogi: This is the type of trees, Mother, that are used for timber.
Yogi: Very, very straight.
But this is a very light, light wood, very light wood.
Yogi: No, no it’s a hardwood actually. Is it?
(...) Yogi: Heavy, heavy, wet hard wood.
Alright, in India you don't get that hard one.
Yogi: In fact it's so hard that it won't take a nail easily.
Hmm, that's great!
This is another variety. What we get is just a waste, you see.
Yogi: Mother would you like a coke or something?
I'll have little chana first,
then I'll drink a little water. Yogi: Coke?
Yesterday was a good day.
Yogi: You missed the great program. Hmm. Amazing.
Did you hear about it? What happened?
Yogi:Yes Mother, we've been questioning people all morning about it,
the events of the last few days.
Tremendous! Yogi: Tremendous Mother!
We have got rid of the evil effect of Mr. Terence
and he's out for ever and ever.
And I have to tell all of you who are leaders -
I was telling yesterday - now we have to take very mild ways.
Specially the leaders have to be extremely mild.
They should not be strict, they should not get angry,
they should not shout.
But a very patronizing way should be,
because that's the way they can appeal to people.
All the time getting angry or disciplining is not a good thing
and judging others as what he did and then he started on jumping.
First he started judging others, correcting others then
on firmer grounds and firmer grounds
and also I think he did not allow
it to spread to other places because he wanted to control.
See this is the main thing for that.
Yogi: Yes, he wanted it in one place.
Yogini: It's apple juice for you personally.
Yogi: Even that was partly the reason why
the ashram at Morunga failed, Mother because
he basically didn't want it to be.
Yes he has had a very influence on everyone, very bad influence.
He had an influence, but of a very bad nature
and egoistical people
were charmed by this thing some time
and they don't try to get it off.
But one must learn a lesson now,
that all kinds of egos must be dropped.
Now he's dropped out of Sahaja Yoga, he and his wife permanent,
they have nothing to do, nothing to do.
The amount of damage he's done to Sahaja yoga, you can't imagine.
So many people came in the party,
I mean in the hall up to the, up to the dais and told Me
that because of Warren they left Sahaja Yoga.
Yogi: Because of Terence.
I mean because of Terence. I still combine you with him.
You see he was so much identified and
he just used My name and his name (...)
Yogi: Yes, he did, Mother.
A very nasty fellow.
Very rotten person, rotten to the core in the way he behaved.
Did they tell you?
Very shameful to behave like that.
And I too telephoned to his father-in-law
and the father-in-law told Me they are very ashamed of themselves
and this that. I said this is a permanent feature now.
You do what you like and then just to say sorry. Nothing doing,
now we are not going to have any more of that.
And she's a liar. She's told him lots of stories, she made a big
thing out of him as if he was something special.
She was a - not at all.
In India she's not regarded as even a sahaja yogini.
So many people don't think her to be a sahaja yogini.
She was out of Sahaja yoga for five years for misbehaving!
And she thinks no end of herself.
This dream and all those business you should all
forget these nonsensical things that she told you.
That this is a dream we are having and dream they came and told Me..
Cary I'm rather worried because you have been
with that horrible fellow - better beat him with shoes every day.
Can you go and do it now, nicely?
Horrible fellow!
Actually I never thought him anything good much,
but Mr. Warren was rather anxious that he should be pulled in within
and then I said that Warren is your leader.
He said you should also take the name of Terence.
I never thought him to be something good.
But it was a nice thing that he came down
and everybody could see him he was exposed
and that's how he got into his problem.
Yogi: That's just the idea Mother, that's why Hmm.
I wanted him to go away. So everybody
could see it, not just Sydney ashram or Melbourne or something.
Very ego-oriented.
Has done nothing for Sahaja yoga, nothing so far.
So many marriages he's broken,
so many people he's talked to so rudely, isn't it?
And some of them are not willing to come back
because of this.
He said horrible things you know.
Maybe your wife also, maybe one of them, I don't know.
Just find out.
Christine told Me that it is he who created a problem for her.
Phil and Christine took to that ego behavior.
Yogi: Christine mainly.
He? Yogi: Christine mainly huh?
Not only Christine.
Yesterday Michelle's mother - Michelle's mother is here?
She said that
her husband is not willing to come to Sahaja Yoga anymore
- she is there.
She told Me the same thing. So many of them.
He is very dangerous. He's got married by that.
(...) he's got a good father-in-law whom he can lynch very well.
Come along.
But then I had to declare.
But one lady who was there, who was a reporter,
she reacted very strongly and we have to now deal with that
on Monday or Tuesday perhaps, Tuesday morning.
She's coming to see Me.
It's terrible!
Better now - much better.
Hmm! That's it, that is him.
Give him bandhan - useless fellow.
I think best is to give yourself a bandhan
so that he doesn't attack you -
Some sort of a cancer I think.
Yogi: Like the false gurus Mother,
it won't be easy to get them out of the brain.
You should beat them with shoes.
You have to put Me in your brain, first of all,
just put Me in your brain.
Just say: "Mother, You are in my brain", that's all.
That's the mantra.
Mother,  Seven times.
Just say that seven times.
Yogis: Mother, You are in my brain.
Hmm! Nirvichara.
You've better eyes.
Ha! It is working  Yogi: Yes everything has gone peaceful
Good?
So now Warren is coming with Me and who else is coming?
Yogi: Mathew's going and.
Yogi: Mathew and Albert.
Albert is going.
So,
and we are going to fix up for our next trip to India.
I may not be able to come next year, I don't know
whatever is the situation because
I'm going to be rather busy building up ashrams for you
to have in India.
So I don't know what will be the situation next year.
But in any case you all are coming
and we are thinking of making it one month and one month.
So, some people who want to come in this month
can come in first month and others in second month.
And
that will reduce pressure because we'll be having more people now.
And these trips also may come to an end, after some time.
Because it's, you know it's very difficult
to manage the whole stuff with so many people going
and I think you are very much uncomfortable also.
Now, huh?
Yogi: What... touring with You, Mother?
We've talked about it a number of times and said that most of us
have felt that the most enjoyable part of the tour
apart from, of course, the beautiful climax in Delhi,
was round Maharashtra and, You know,
we all seem to recall affectionately that
the buses and the dust and the moving
but we did miss that, Mother, when we got to Delhi.
There was a great joy in meeting those people
and sharing the programs.
I can take you to a dense forest this time if you want but
the thing is in one month we'll have to do Maharashtra.
Three weeks it will be Maharashtra and one week will be lapping,
overlapping each other- like that you know - about what - oh no,
four weeks will be in Maharashtra, one week in Delhi overlapping
for about 2-3 days, if you want to get married or all sort of things.
So, we can have about 3 days overlapping.
Yogi: So, it will be 4 weeks tour and 1 week overlapping.
Now 1 week overlap,
we can't have so many people in Delhi, you see, double group.
Yogi: No, seems impossible.
Impossible. So what we can do: you can have a group of people
will go from here for one week in Delhi
and the others will be coming for another week in Delhi.
But in between you can have 3 days,
3 days which could be overlap.
Only 3 days could be easier.
Yogi: Maybe 1 group could stay in the temple or something like that.
One group can stay in the temple for 2 nights, it's alright.
Yogi: Also those that had to go home early
could always leave from Bombay again and go back.
If they could only stay for 1 month. Yes, yes.
Yogi: So they don't have to come to Delhi for the extra week.
Yes, those who want to come to Delhi can come otherwise they need not
because Delhi will be mostly you will be staying with other people
and not with there with sahaja yogis also
Isn't it? That's a good idea
because you enjoyed it very much
Yogi: That was the best part of Delhi, Mother.
After Your program that was the...
That was a thing you all enjoyed.
So we'll have 100 people for the first week
and 100 people, first month and hundred for the next.
Because this time it was 140 together was too much.
So we'll have two.
Yogi: Sahaja yoga's leaders of the world will start battling,
Mother, I imagine any time now for their quota.
Yogi: The only problem with all this, Mother, is
You're going to have to be in two places at once.
Yeah! that I'll have to.
Two months I can give for all this -
always been two months there, so we can manage with two months.
But then we'll not have many programs in Bombay.
And the 15 days or 15 and 3, 17 days, 18 days, I'll be in Delhi.
So we can have 18 days program in Delhi.
In Bombay, we can have about 3 days here and a 3 days here.
That we have to adjust.
Any other suggestions you have?
Yogi: People could start working on the assumption that
they'll be going about what time - about Christmas time? Yes.
Yogi: Before christmas Mother? Before christmas.
Yogi: Just before christmas?
Easy to arrange like that.
So that it will be January and February
and we are again back in March.
Is she crying? Which one?
Yogi: That's the other one.
Yogi: Has anyone got any suggestions or anything that... Yah,
Mother is just asking any ideas that they want to
put up about the trip in India?
Don't be shy.
Y: Could we make a visit to a silk mill to see how sarees are woven?
Y: Can we have a visit to a silk mill to see how sarees are woven?
For that you have to go to  Banares
to see the sarees woven.
That's done in Banares, most of these silk sarees.
You don't find them in Delhi or anything but ..
Yogi: One in Dhulia, we saw some in Dhulia we saw sarees being woven
Yogi: but they were cheaper ones. Yes, cheaper sarees
but for these special intricate ones, you see, which are whole silk,
mostly you can find cotton ones being made here but not silk.
But this fellow who gave you dhotis
you can go to his place and see.
Yogi: If we can bring the trunk? Can you bring it over, Mother can give those things out now?[UNCLEAR]
Yogi: Get a couple of people to help you.
What about the presents that Tumal has sent for you?
Yogi: They haven't arrived, 25th they'll arrive.
Very sad!
Yogi: Did You see them all, Mother? Mother: Huh You saw them?
Oh, nice things!
We brought it with such love for you, just what a shame!
Really.
So what about your ordering for the
juice we were saying? Juice machine or something?
Yogi: Ah, somebody is looking into it more carefully.
Mr. Pai was the only one who did it in Bombay.
I want somebody else who knows a little bit more about it.
They cost about from about 1500 up to about 3000.
3000 for a bigger one, which has capacity to roll about
four or five stalks at once. That's a better one.
But I want to wait now until we get Queensland open because
the cane does not begin until the North coast of New South Wales.
So only when we get Brisbane open should we start that project.
That's a very good idea. Yogi: There's no cane down in this area.
That will be, maybe a next year project now.
Mother, should we start up Brisbane ourselves in the next few months
Yes, yes you should start. Is alright.
Yogi: I was wondering [UNCLEAR] Albert, is he here, he might like to....?
Oh, you get lot of people from other cults coming.
That would be the problem and maybe you might feel it rather
embarrassing. But take it slowly and tell them that
"see now, you have to give up your gurus. We have no quarrel nothing
but we can't work out with your gurus, so please give up."
Yogi: We could say, start gently up there and do it too
Yeah! Yogi: ...slowly..
Yogi: Have the dhoties been torn up in the two pieces?
Yogi: No they haven't Yogi: We could do that.
Yes. So how are we going to distribute it?
Yogi: I think they will just have to be very common sensical about it
because there are not enough for everybody.
If you had told Me I would have
asked him to put some more. But how many did not get the dhoties?
Yogi: All the men that didn't get dhoties put your hands up.
The ones that did not get the dhoties.
Just put your hand up. Oh! it's not many, very few.
Must be some of them who are cooking - just find out from them.
Yogi: The three men who are cooking, they were in India, they would have had theirs
They must have had, alright.
So now how many did not get? Please raise your hands.
Ah, one, two, three, four, five, six, seven. eight.
So we have to have four dhoties.
So for two persons, these are for two persons.
Yogi: Come on and get them, quickly.
I think they are even better, so let's give these first.
They are better quality, these are better quality.
For two persons, this is for two persons.
Yogi: We tear it in half. Yes, exactly.
Yogi: Is that two, is that two or one? Yes, two, these are two.
These are all two, these are two either.
These are two definitely, now so you two can share
and you two can share.
So you need four - we have four. Now this one two can share there
and two can share here. Alright, let us give these first of all.
Now two more - again you come back, I think, let's have it.
Now one each. You two have, too, alright?
You haven't got it too? Alright.
Give it back, give Me that, give it back. Other one, the other one.
See. Alright!
Now you have these two
because, you see just you had. You have got two?
Alright, you have two now, let's see.
We'll find out one for him. So now how many?
One - now take out one.
Yogi: Has anyone who got one, lost it or [UNCLEAR]
Alright, now what I'm saying we have to give two each
in any case so you take this one.
Alright, now you do one thing with - take out these - one
How many they are? These are also two each - two, three, four,
five.
So it's, alright, now I don't know,
let Me see what's written in there, if they are two or one.
What's written here?
I think it is - it is for two. Yes.
So now, two of you should again come.
Now he's got two so you, you come along and this set -
you should have one of that and one of that, alright?
May God bless you!
Now you come along again - you have one of that, it's two again.
Now who else? Come along, you people come along also.
One each, one of this and one of that. One more group here.
Mother, would it be a good idea
if we all wore dhoties to the puja tomorrow?
Good idea, very very good idea, you wash them.
Have we, have I given to all of you two each now? He hasn't got.
Yes you have got. Now so
Yogi: You need another one? See, he didn't follow.
Just tell him what it is. See these are to be divided into four
and one each you have to take.
Yogi: Everyone should have a different one, so you take two,
one of each.
You never got one... Alright, give it to them
Yogi: A real paddle steamer!
Y: I don't see him. Oh look Mother, coming up the river!
Y: It's a paddle steamer Mother, it's...
We saw this yesterday in the picture.
Same thing.
Yogi: Wonderful! Get the film on it
(...)  Now how many is that? One
Now how many did not get these?
Yogi: How many did not get these shawls? Quite a few
How many? No, not the ladies - gents.
Not the ladies - gents. Yogi: How many men did not get the shawl?
Yogi: One - keep your hands up so we can count.
Yogi: 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11.
Yogi: Eleven. Alright, Mother: now take out the sarees.
five
six
How many ladies did not get the sarees?
One, two Yogi: One, two
Yogi: Keep your hands up, please, it would be impossible. 1, 2, 3
Yogi: four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven, twelve,
Yogi: thirteen, fourteen, fifteen.
Alright, exact.
Alright, let's have. One by one, come along.
From the little girls - first of all the younger girls come along.
The blue one. It's alright, it's alright.
One. Which one you - this is for bigger girls.
Yogi: Let the little girls come first. [UNCLEAR] this first of all.
Little Girls we can do.
One...
Now, for the big girls.
One of - one by one you should come here. Come along.
May God bless you! Now first
First Yogi: There's another little girl Mother
Ah! little girl. Now see you're small, it's pink we'll give that.
This is good for you.
Now who else? Come along.
Y: Let the people that have never had sarees before let come first.
All of them will have the first you see. Y:Mother it’s my first saree
Y:Thank you Mother, it's my first saree.
Is it?
Alright, come along. I think you come along, come along.
We have. Now how many more?
It's good idea.
One for you, come.
Sally you have a saree? She has, alright.
Now how many ladies are left out? Raise your hands.
One, two three, four
five - stand up, stand up together I would like to see.
Alright, so we'll give these - not these - not that.
Come along. For the ladies.
Is good, you can wrap your children also - both of them are married.
Hmm! Two
Three,
four,
five. Come along.
Exact, see.
[UNCLEAR] what do you say to that?
Come along. seven
Yeah! now we'll give her this [UNCLEAR]
This is just a blouse - you have a saree?
Now, I think, you better give her because she has a saree
- you can give her.
Yogi: Joyan has a saree Mother - she's got lots of sarees.
First [UNCLEAR]
Joyan can have this. Yogi: She's got lots.
Joyan you can have a blouse piece.
You can have blouse piece, alright.
Now, this is for a little girl.
Is there any little girl here? Come along.
It's good, so she can make her a
petticoat of this color - good idea.
Ah!
Now what is that?
That's [UNCLEAR]
That's a puja cloth. Yogi: Yeah, that was used for puja.
Yogi: This was bought for puja but not used
This to be kept.
Yogi: It was not used.
What is it?
Y: I think Mother that's- I was just trying to work out which ...
Yes, there are small children. How many there are?
They're quite a lot.
Yogis: Lots everywhere. 20 Mother. Annh?
20.................
Yogi: Loaves and fishes, Mother. Hmm.
This one is - now one is left out.
So, who's the gentleman who hasn't got it?
Yogi: Michael, did you get one?
Yogi: Where is he?
Yogi: Did Michael get one?
Where is he? Does he want one? Yogi: He'll be back. I'll give it to him later Mother.
This one I think you should keep for puja.
This one for Michael.
Oh! you must wash it, it's not clean. You have to wash them.
Tonight you have to go and wash them for tomorrow
or you can wear the inside one may be clean
- just see the inside ones, may be clean.
These are all clean ones, these are very clean - these you can use.
You see, you better use these first - these are all clean ones.
These are very clean.
Yogi: I said they should wear the dhoties tomorrow, Mother.
I should have said puja on monday
They'll all be turning up to the public program in their dhoties.
It'll be very interesting.
Ian has got his dhoti? Yogi: I think so.
You got Ian? Your dhoti have you got?
Yogi: Yes Mother, I have got [UNCLEAR]
What's the problem?
Yogi: Ian says it's getting him into it that's the problem. Why?
Yogi: Make it a clear instruction, Mother then it's done
It's a - you don't know how to wear it - should I show you?
Now any man, come along. Tear off a dhoti - half.
Yogi: Is there, has anybody got a pair of scissors or a sharp knife?
You see, you have to wear something short inside
- you see you can't just wear
the dhoti or you can wear a short pant will do.
First let Me show how the dhoti is
Let Me do - it's, it's straightforward you can just tear it off, Yogi: stand up
Come along, let him come, I'll show you.
Now, come here.
Now,
hold it in double
here - make it a double around. Complete. Double it that side
Yogis: [UNCLEAR] tuck it in ........
[UNCLEAR] now
Yogi: You just
Just stand, yes do it like that, alright.
Now, now can you see that clearly.
Now stand facing that side.
Now here at this point you've to pull out two things like that
like this, alright, for a knot.
Now you have to keep a big knot like this alright
and to make it a strong knot you have to change over
and now give it a knot -
so that the knot never opens out easily.
This kind of a knot is called as (.....). Imagine.
[UNCLEAR]
Now it will not open, Alright.
So, then what you have to do
you should take one side just like that.
Now, if you want to wear like Shri Krishna
or if you want to wear like - depends on -
put it the whole thing out like that, come along
like this. Now turn around.
Now, you have to push this one here. Just push one side here.
One is done like this, alright
and the another side, this side is picked up
as this - this is Shri Krishna's style.
Alright. And now take it in your hand like that
and you have to push the whole thing in there.
So the whole thing is tucked in and you have a nice dress.
Pull here and the sides like that
See this is [UNCLEAR] Now you push this [UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR]
Now, take it out
now on this side you should
the whole thing I've pushed it in, alright
and just push it a little bit on the sides so you don't show your legs.
Yogi: That side?
You follow that?
Alright, that's too much.
Did I do it very fast?
[UNCLEAR] now stand up
[UNCLEAR]
Some people take it too much inside with some too little. Whatever style you like
Okay tie it up.
Alright, beautiful now, you have to take
careful to let it wait so when you sit down
you'll be comfortable - now sit down and see if it is comfortable.
Yes, you must have something to wear
[UNCLEAR]
You sit down.
Annh?
Yes, you can cross, everything. It's very comfortable.
Yogi: Fix it, Mother. Just tuck one in, ah.
It's the left hand-side has to be balanced.
Now, can you make a small again
Now take the other one in a different way.
Now the flair is made here,
the whole thing is made Yogi: The front first Yes.
Starts from here.
This has to go inside, you see, that's the main point.
Yogi: This this loose end goes inside like that
it goes inside like that and now
you need to come [UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR]
pull it out there.
Yes, that it is
and this is to be tucked in here, you see Yogi: Yes.
Just an end of it, you see, this end.
This end - yes, tuck it in here.
and you can pull it a little bit
if you want through or very thin you can pull it [UNCLEAR]
Yogi: Tuck it in otherwise it would be there
Haan, see. Yogi: Thank You!
It's good. Yogi: I'll leave it on till Monday then.
This is a very, ah, mobile state.
You see, you can use it for bathing,
you can use it for a towel rail, you can use it for a curtain.
You got [UNCLEAR]
Annh?
Yogi: Is the Sea puja also for rain?
Yes, of course, that's for rain only.
We did for rain the Sea puja one.
Now what about you people?
Yogini: Lunch is ready now.
It's perfect.
Yogi: Are You [UNCLEAR]? Hmm.
It's perfect. Try it.
Yogi: Mother [UNCLEAR]
Put it in the[UNCLEAR]
They must have given you
I told them to give you that porridge in Delhi.
What are they called as - cuckoo? ["Cucalla"]
So many birds!
Yogi: Can Stephen please come up.
You remember the[UNCLEAR] [FRUIT OR FOOD?]
who said that first time I've seen a ..... bird.
Yogi: They found that most of the ornamental work for gardens,
Yogi: if not all of it, is done in concrete. In cement. Yeah!
Yogi: and they are not so very keen on working in cement
they prefer to work in plaster.
No, plaster won't stay outside.
in the garden, you have to use cement.
Is a very difficult work to do it with cement.
Now you must come in Sydney which there are
so many places done with cement - such beautiful pieces
- if you can just make the replicas of those.
First you have to buy some of these - just make a replica.
Yogi: Mother...These are garden ornaments.. Are they? Mother: Yes, yes.
Yogi: Mother, you were mentioning that
we could have some replica of your face
Somebody was going to do that then what happened?
Yogi: Robin is the expert
Yogi: I got everything here, Mother.
Then why not do it, tonight?
Try. It is a good idea.
Tonight you can try.
Yogi: Can I just ask one more question, Mother, concerning the John and the plastering
Yogi: job and the plastering that is
Yogi: they're all wondering whether
perhaps it might be better to go into
Y:plastering for inside things like cornices and inside moldings and
Yogi: model work for interior. Yeah.
Yogi: Perhaps, from what You were saying Mother they
Yogi: could do both?
Interior is easier
interior work is easier.
Here I saw in Sydney beautiful
I showed him beautiful roses and things. Yogi: at the centre
There are two types of things they do -
one which is a plain cornice
so what they do
is a plain cornice, you see
so they will do one thing like
they'll make a thing cut like that.
in wood or sharpen it and then put it along the
they put the whole thing and just
take it out so the whole thing comes out of a (.....)
And they sometimes mix it with cement
so it takes time to set
or if you can mix it with salt also it takes time to set
because here you see, it sets very fast, yes.
Doesn't take much time to set.
So what they do they put a triangular thing first on the walls
and just take another sharp one which chops.
He knows, hmm!
And for the roses and all I've seen beautiful things here
but as he had done is to make a Georgian style.
We have used Georgian style in Our house
because it's a Georgian house.
So, if you want I can send you the book.
You can get it also here, I'm sure, on Georgian style of these plasterwork
Yogi: you can get it here.
You had given Me the book
on Georgian style of house - you remember?
Yeah, yeah! Ah! you must see the
house - part of it has come how I have done it.
Come along, you'll be interested. Oh!
Only the ground floor, the ground floor has come up.
My bedroom and the entrance can see it here
This is the entrance I think
and you enter here
[UNCLEAR]
These are the pictures - entrance you see. This is a big hall.
But we have done it more now.
Yogi: Can everybody have a look at these, Mother? Yes, by all means.
Now,
that's only one reception - the ground floor.
Then we have one down below, we have one upstairs
and now this is leading to My bedroom - this one is.
Have you seen the staircase? Show him the staircase.
Yogi: That looks bit of the staircase there Mother.
Yes, part of it but there is something showing very clearly
also staircase.
Yogi: Where is this? This is from India.
Yogi: Yes, gilded.
Yogi: That's very beautiful! Mother: All right?
Yogi: That was done in India, was it, Mother? That, that part.
This I would tell you
that this is the door through which We enter in, alright?
and this is a sort of a partition I've built in
which gives it an inside you see is a sort of a passage that side
and this is the thing for sitting down here which extends to that
at the same one, it's the extension of the same. Yogi: Yes.
Yogi: That [UNCLEAR] is here
Yogi: This is a (....)
One they have taken in the daytime one in the night -
- so you see there are two types. (....)
But still this is the informal one. The formal one is even better
at upstairs, yeah.
Yeah, is it, does it, now see this one is the
entrance to your Mother's bedroom -
in the daytime.
This is a, this is actually
eh, what you call this black wood is ebony
this I've got it from India also.
Then this is the one which is going down also.
You see the passage going down to the kitchen?
And there's a dining room that side.
Now, this is the again in the night - I think daytime.
Now this is part of My bedroom, just a corner of My bedroom.
Yogi: Yes. This is the corner of My bedroom Yogi: It's very beautiful
it's just a corner. I mean it's a very large bedroom -
it has a sitting place and all that and a batheing room.
but just partly they have done it.
Yogi: Is C.P. happy now, Mother with everything. Huun? Very.
We're, you see, what you sent was all lost
because they couldn't make anything out of it.
so again we had to re-do it and there were so many laws and regulations
but there's so many laws you can't imagine.
That house is a Georgian house, listed house, 250 year old house
you can't do anything about it you can't
but despite that it has come out well.
Actually he's amazed despite all the laws
I've been able to do something to that house.
Y:Imagine what a lot of bother at not being able to do anything outside
No, inside also, inside also.
We had to use only Georgian style things
they are very particularly they are - this is a 250 year old house.
That's all, we did not know the laws.
Yogi: The heavy blue one
Heavy blue one is beautiful. Yogi: and was it a blue one?
Yeah. Yogi: And a colourful one for children
has lots of flowers on it.
Yogi: pink, pink flowers on it.
They saw that very beautiful!
And you know how much it is? The flower one is forty-seven
rupees a meter can you imagine? Yogi: And the other one was sixty.
All hand done.
Yogi: I mean that's a quarter of price Mother: fifty-seven,
the other is fifty-seven.
Yogi: Peter 's just saying you pay 300 rupees here, a meter.
Still you can't get it.
That work I don't know - can you get that work?
Yogi: It's imported from India here.
That this one is the best among all of them.
You see there are types and types
they were even 20 rupees available but We bought the best.
And they did not charge you any customs or anything
when you brought these things with you?
Have you all seen it?
It's in the night that's why it is looking goldenish, you see.
But if you see in the daytime it, I don't know why it looks bluish.
Yogi: Depends what light is on.
They should have had a standard lighting system
Standard lighting he must have done, he's very good way.
But I think, you know, maybe, My influence.
Yogi: What's that Mother? Must be My influence I think
in the house - vibrations wise
See this is pink, you see the same color as that.
Yogi: Yet it's come out different but you see I've touched all these.
What we should do is to have all the corners done and
put them together like that, alright. Yogi:That will make a panorama
This has come out alright - the colour,
this is also good colour the same colour. Yogi: Yes.
Yogi: Yes see the colour of the chairs is correct.
Actually that This is darker that's not so dark it's lighter
Yogi: but more reddish, you see more reddish also
but you like this. Yogi: Yes.
Yogi: That was actually fabricated. Mother: It's a, We worked it out, yes.
I've put a little gold on top here, you see
but this honeycomb is very good pattern also we must say -
pattern is very good, rare
but these look so nice on that - annh little, little things.
Haan.
Annh? Yogi: There isn't actually a hall there, is there,
it just gives the effect of a hall.
Hall. See it's a partial...
actually we should not make a hall completely separated.
There is no need. We do it and by that we kill the effect
because hall looks so small and congested.
This hall used to look very congested before.
Now just because I've put a partition instead of the hall.
And now we've done one more thing I must tell you here
is we have lifted this up a little from inside, from that side
and made a platform brought it Yogi: [UNCLEAR] Yes.
brought it at the level of this. Yogi: I see
This is it is in one level.
Y: Yes. And that side is lifted so that there is a platform on which
Yogi: A plinth, like a plinth base Yes,
quite a big one.
It is in one line you see now. Yogi: Yes, yes, yes.
is in one line. It was like this, it is in one line.
Yogi: Yes it would give it a better line. Then
Yogi: Did Laurent ever finish Your kitchen Mother Ha, ha, yes.
You see, you see these are these are 250 year old tiles here
there it works and all the story of Christ and Bible.
This is the story of Bible and the another one is the
story of Christ, the one here.
It doesn't show here but this (one is here?)
another one is here this
it doesn't show.
Yogi: Mother, was the staircase satisfactory
- the one that came from India did that
Oh! that's the one here. Yogi: Hmm, nice
Yogi: You are pleased with it?
You, you have not seen all this?
You have seen it.
It has Yogi: I've seen
Yogi: prior to being gilded and after it's been gilded.
Is he what? C.P. was like
lot of [UNCLEAR] found [UNCLEAR] try to convince him.
These carpets are built-in carpets I must say - these are not real.
Yogi: Not Indian?
The top one has got Indian.
Yogi: These chandeliers look lovely there, Mother.
Do they?
Showing the color though - it's pink color
the pink it was.  (....)
Where is the baby of Christine?
Yogi: Diane's baby.
No the other baby Yogi: No Christine No, not
Ehh!
Diane's baby with the other one whose got a (....)
Yogi: Oh, right, Sally's. Sally's
Sally's baby.
You sit here.
Yogi: He's sitting over there with his father. Bring him over forth
Are they getting better?
Suddenly it goes off. In two months’ time they will suffer.
Annh? Suddenly it goes Yogi: When he's tired, Mother.
Yogi: When the muscles are fatigued.
Come here, how are you?
Hmm! Iske bachche ki kaisi kaisi
isse se dil kitta kya ho jayega, dil ghabra gaya.
Iske jo munh mein aata woh bolti thi, ki Mataji ka [UNCLEAR]
main bahut buri huun Sahajyogini huun mujhe bahut Mataji [UNCLEAR]
aur main jo keh rahin huun [UNCLEAR] (long 4 minute break in tape then restarts)
Nothing is happening, there is nothing to cry.
Yes, no, there's nothing to cry it's all fun yes, yes. (....)
Which like soups and things.
Yogini: One month old Yes, you should start.
Little bit soup is alright. Yogi: strained, Mother: Nothing wrong in doing it.
Strained, absolutely strained - just water.
But little soup and things like will be good for them.
Yogi: In barley water soup, barley soup and In
barley, little bit, barley water is very good.
Barley water or you can start with juices if you like
and then go to soups and then to
- I mean the system must get used to that, you see.
Gradually you must bring 'round children to food
not suddenly the heavy food.
Y: Adrian six months he hasn't had anything [UNCLEAR]
Y: because we got the message You said that it was six months
that they should have food for the first time.
Food is different I mean this is Yogi: This is a clear liquid
Yogini: You know that's that's the way we
Food means solid food
solid food you see what you can give them rice
and dal cooked together make it very
because if you train up the system properly. Yogini: Yes.
First you start with juices then come to soups
and then come to solid food in the sense that it is semi-solid.
You can cook rice and dal together make a khichdi - she knows that
to make it. Thin it out and give it to the child
that you can do but not this dal - moong dal
moong dal and rice you can cook together and start with that
after six months. Food means when there are solid parts.
But juices and soups you must start.
Yogini: Yes. Important. Yogi: and water.
And water you should start immediately.
After a month you should start water, boiled water you must start.
But I saw your child getting a
isn't it your child was having water alright.
Yes. Yes, what is her age? Yogini: she's ten months
Yogi: Ten, ten months. Yogini: He's ten months.
Ten months I saw - but when you started? Yogi: At what age?
You had they had water.
That's good. So they had water.
Now what else you wanted to know?
Yogini: The baby's waking at night, Mother
Y: what do we do to get them out of doing waking up at night time?
You see there are because they're wet in the night that's why
they get up, isn't it, or for no rhyme and reason?
Yogini: Yes, no rhyme and reason.
Alright, so what you have to do is to massage their body with oil
and massage their head with oil
put lot of oil in their heads, you see
and then put some powder and clean it up, you see.
Give them a massage in the night, they'll sleep very well.
They won't get up.
In the night you should give them a massage in case
they are restless in the night or something like that
before sleeping.
You give them their last meal, say about what time you
give them last. 8 o'clock or 6 o'clock?
Yogini: It depends on their age
Yogini: Gabriel and Luke have their dinner at about 6 o'clock
Yogini: Adrian has... he goes to bed at
Yogini: his last meal at about 7.30 - 8.
Alright, so what you do 6 o' clock
you give him one feed, alright and
eh 9 o'clock another one - you can give like that.
One one more in the 9 o'  so they won't be hungry
but in between you can do the massage for the body.
Say about 7 o'clock you can do the massage.
Alright. Yogini: Yes, Mother.
So, 7.30 then he goes to bed.
9 o'clock in his sleep he must have
in his sleep and then in the morning he'll get up at about 5
that's all.
It's very simple 5 or 6.
But I think you people don't massage the body so much of them - dry.
We have to massage it twice in the beginning.
Twice - one in the night, one in the daytime.
Alright, now what else?
Yogi: When do they stop breast-feeding, Mother?
Ten months. Gradually they should take to bottle.
Ten months they can stop ten, twelve, you see.
In India they used to stop after three years nobody bothered.
But it's better to stop it by ten, eleven or eleven months or so.
Yogi: If they don't get the mother's milk
Yogi: say they have to cut it short
Of course, of course you should take to bottle
no harm in giving bottle milk.
Do it properly but you see if you do not give the nipple
in the mouth of the child of the bottle
from the very beginning or say about one or two months
or three months at the most they won't take to it easily.
So best is to give one, one feed after three months.
Start giving them one feed.
When the child is sleeping you give one feed.
then the child is used to the nipple, you see. You have to
understand the child has to get used to everything.
Yogini: Yes. Then they easily move but otherwise you suddenly
Yogini: Yes, yes Mother, they were started at six months
Yogini: but then they just don't want to eat the food that's given
Yogini: them some of the other babies that have been eating
solid food for a while. Because the food is not tasty
Yogini: It's not tasty. Annh!
You must make it tastier you see, you must put proper salt
Salt must be properly put and little tasty it must be made
you see, a little bit of butter, little bit.
You see, you must make it tasty otherwise the food is not tasty
they don't like it. The tongue, just like us.
Yogi: You tell her Mother in Sydney they must have salt
Yogi: in their food and they must...
Annh, this is a very funny idea not to have salt.
You all, do you all suffer from high blood pressure?
Yogi:[UNCLEAR] You see, without salt
you cannot do your respiration - ask any doctor.
If there is no sodium, sodium chloride in your blood
see your respiration will go down.
These things are essential for life but not too much of everything.
Salt is needed with food.
I mean these are all funny ideas that are coming up
but the worse thing is that you are so naïve just like children.
I mean if anybody tells that don't take salt we'll just be
saying oh! you, you must be coming from lunatic asylum.
But if you are suffering from high blood pressure,
if there's a problem of that or something then you skip.
Salt is very important for teeth for everything.
To feel relaxed is the best way to reduce the blood pressure.
What else is? Yogi: There's also a belief that if you give children
Yogi: sweet food as a small baby and child that it will grow up and
Yogi: have blood sugar problems.
Yogi: So they give very sour, sweet, sour lemon, sour food
I told that, you see how blood sugar comes in
because of diabetes isn't it, not because of sugar.
It comes only because of diabetes
and diabetes comes because of thinking too much.
If you make your child agitated all the time
you want him to think and do this very well in the school at the age
of five years if you want him to do 'O' level
then what would happen?
You see she want to
01:25:24:10 01:25:27:21make the child, do competition, what is left over by you then.
Take it easy. Let the child study as well as grow normally.
Yogi: Is it wise to for the baby to sleep in the
same bed as the parents and up to what age, Mother?
To very small six age. Not every time it's not proper.
I don't think it's good all the time but little bit while
and then the child must sleep in all [UNCLEAR] in his bed.
Always sleeping in his bed is the best
but in the same room not in some other room.
But then you should take the baby to with you
when you are nursing or anything for a while
that's all but mostly the child should be in the bed.
It's not with the parents if he's sleeping
between the two parents to be crushed
Yogi: And then until what age should young
children be kept in the same bedroom?
I think even now My children sleep with Me, so what can I do?
I think We are different type of people.
We don't undress ourselves when we sleep.
That's the problem with you.
I hope Sahaja yogis are not sleeping like that.
Please don't sleep without clothes - bhoots will enter into you.
Must wear your clothes and then sleep.
I'm telling you don't sleep without clothes.
Bhoots, that's the best way the bhoots enter you.
What is the need I don't understand.
Yogini: Mother this umm
Y: some of the babies have been experiencing a lot of pain while
Y: they're cutting their teeth for their teeth are coming through
Yes, a very old medicine called Steveman's powder
Steveman's powder, write it down.
Get some ivory rings, are very good for children.
Ivory rings. Y: Teething rings. Ivory rings you get them in India.
You get here plastic ones we get ivory ones.
You get some of these rings - are very good for children.
Yogi: Albert you gonna get those?
Yogi: Ivory rings, rings, teething rings.
Yogini: Mother, another question.
Yogini: What do you think about dummies for the babies?
Dummies? Yogini: Yes, you know dummies are
Yogini: the litle rubber thing shape like a nipple to an extent and
You see, they might develop that teeth are
coming out if you give too much of that.
Yogini: Yes, if you give too much but a little bit of
maybe to settle the baby down to sleep
It's alright, little bit is alright, but try to keep it away.
You see, best is to give vishudhdhi treatment
and not have it otherwise the teeth will be running parallel
Y: Yes Mother. and you'll have lot of problem setting them back.
Yogi: Yes. Haan! But it's true - little bit you can give that.
They are called as dummies, are they? Y: Dummies they call, yes.
Yogini: dummy nipples Mother: Han, alright, there's no harm.
Yogi: They want to know about toilet training, Mother.
What is that? Yogi: How to stop the baby from
Yogi: wetting the nappies and using the pot, basically?
For that at the age of only two months or three months
you must start touching the bottom of the baby to your pot
you see, keep a little pot like that and try to say, make some sound
like that and all that the child starts seeing it and
he gets used to the touch, you see, of the thing
Then he he knows that's an impulse, you see, in him
that acts as a message and you can do it.
It's very simple. Y: Very early then. Very early you must start it
very early Yogini: We don't do that.
That's it because you have these dry drips, that's why.
Yogi: Mr. Freud said we shouldn't do it, Mother. Why?
Yogi: It'll give you a complex. Mother: What?
What is the complex?
Yogi: No, that's right. Complex?
We all Indians do it. We don't have any complexes I think [UNCLEAR]
The one who has given you real complex is Mr. Freud himself.
What complex can be, kya hoga? I can't understand.
Beyond My imagination. Yogi: Whole this nonsense about
Yogi: how you were toilet trained and if you,
Yogi: It explains why you behave in a certain way when you're
Yogi: grown up and according to how you sat on the potty and
Yogi: It's true, Mother.
We don't even know about these things
How could [UNCLEAR] nonsense, ha, ha ha.
Yogini: Another question, Mother. Mother: That's why you people
are very addicted to bathrooms also, we are not.
You see, we are there hardly for 5-10 minutes,
have a bath get out of it, you see.
The addiction comes from that kind of a thing.
You're very bathroom cultured, that's why.
Yogi: All this graffiti business is Graffiti?
Yogi: Graffiti - writing on the walls
Yogi:  all that stuff it's all coming from that.
Writing on the walls?
The best thing if you are constipated take a newspaper -
simple thing and horrid news
that's how I've seen some people have treated them.
They say, "We get constipated".
I said read a newspaper in the morning.
That's the place you should read newspaper actually, nowhere else.
That it is worth, nothing else you know.
I would do that.
Mean I don't get any chance or anything I would say that better
read it in, newspaper in the bathroom - that's the place it's
because such filth in there.
No, no, no he's, I tell you he must be a sweeper in his last life.
Must be something wrong with this Freud, I think
must have been a sweeper.
Yogi: 12 years ago in England, Mother, there was a man
Yogi: called Dr. Alex Comfort who's basically a
Yogi: descendant of Freudian psychology who's said that
Yogi: you should have contraceptives available in the market place
for children to buy as from the age of twelve.
Yogi: So that's now far we've gone. For what?
Yogi: Contraception..... Oh, Oh, I see, what fun we have!
Oh, Oh! This is another joke.
I thought must be for constipation some
Yogi: Maybe that
Yogi: that's instead of the new
But where we are boys don't even understand these things.
Yogi: They do here, Mother, in the West.
In the West maybe, here they are overgrown.
You don't allow them to be natural
putting all these ideas into the head.
Twelve year boy - Yogi: Hmm.
always their nonsense
Yogini: Mother, some more questions. Hmmm.
Yogini: What should mothers do about constipation in the babies?
You see, they should not have constipation themselves.
Yogini: Well they do, when they're on the formula mixtures.
Yes so we, we have so many ways of removing in India
like we take that ajwain ka churan and all that all the time when
the little black grapes, dried ones, raisins - black raisins,
yes, fruits with a, with orange juice - orange juice is very good
and also milk, boiled milk in the night. Hmmm, very good.
Yogini: That's another thing Mother when
Yogini: when they weaned from the mother's breast
Yogini: are they weaned onto cow's milk
To what? Yogini: Cow's milk do we
Yogi: From breast to cow's milk or from breast to formula mixture?
I mean, we give cow's milk.
Because this formula nowadays I don't know what they do that.
Yogi: It makes black stools it's
If you get cow's milk better is to remove the cream
put the water in it and boil it.
Remove the cream and that's the best for the children.
But boil it together not separately.
Always boil the milk and the water together, never separately.
Yogi: So all these mothers on formula should transfer to cow's milk.
Yogi: All these mothers who are feeding their babies on formula
Yogi: on this mixture, on this powdered stuff
Yogi: should change to cow's milk?
Yes, I mean if the children can digest cow's milk nothing like that
if they can digest. But you must know
what is the amount of water you should put
Yogi: Proportion because that's more natural to take to cow's milk.
Yogi: Well you're supposed to be feeding them off the breast, if you cannot feed them off the breast
No, but what we do then, you see, for some time you
can take formula because might be it is better
according to the age group
but say after ten months you can take to cow's milk alright.
But little bit one feed you should start
by the time they are about three months
before they are conscious, must start one feed.
Is she giving one feed at least to the baby or not?
No, not yet. No, no, not her. I'm saying
hmmm Barbara
Barbara, is she giving one feed to the baby?
Yogini: No, Mother, only breast milk, Mother: only breast milk?
You should start now all right, otherwise again he'll be very angry
with the bottle. Y: he is, Mother
I tried with the bottle before he doesn't like it. See?
So, must, better start earlier always
- one feed you must start earlier.
Say one month you can start because children
here are very adamant type you see.
What other things?
Yogini: Medication for children. Yogini: Mother,
Yogini: a lot of Panadol given to the babies
Panadol? For what? Yogini: Yes Mother
Yogini: For temperatures or irritability. Teething
Yogini: when the baby is crying or upset.
I don't think Panadol is a very good thing
- horrible. Yogi: No, it contains
It's not a very good thing, you see, just Yogi: It contains Aspirin
- Paracetamol
It can make the child very bad later on
see, after the effect. Y: Liver - it could cause liver problems.
Oh, really? it's not good you see
say a child is irritable or anything, you see,
you should find out what is exactly the trouble is,
is it due to the stomach trouble or anything?
Then according to that you should give but there are natural
things that you should give to the baby and not unnatural.
Say a child has got a diarrhoea, alright,
a simple method is to boil this fennel
Yogi: Fennel, fennel fennel.  - fennel, fennel seeds
and mint together, boil it. Keep it ready
and give that with little sugar or candy sugar
and give that to the child twice, thrice.
Simple things like that I can give you so many medicines.
Yogini: Yes, Mother.
Very simple. You should see why the child is sick.
Panadol is something like a sleeping pill only.
Yogini: Yes, it is.
That's very bad at that age.
Yogini: Another question, Mother.
Yogi: What about gripe water, Mother - do we use that?
For the baby is alright but what about the mother?
Mother has to take it out now, what else.
Wind - what you can get here.
You must be having some medicines for wind,
Yogi: Just the usual ones, Mother. Antacids or something (unclear)
Yogi: It's fairly innocuous, isn't it?
Yogi: It - do they boil the alcohol off it?
What is that?
Y: It originally has some small volume of alcohol. 4%, 4%.
What is it? Yogis: 4% alcohol In what?
Yogis: In gripe water. Gripe
No we don't give gripe water to the children at all.
We give this ajwain water and to the mother.
There's another way is to
ajwain is the only thing I know very well because -
I'll find out for you there's something else that you can have.
Y: Should the mothers have a diet avoiding wind producing foods.
Ha of course, they should not eat rice at all.
They should not eat rice, they should
not eat anything that is grown under the earth.
Potato also they should not - anything like that.
Rice, potatoes all these things must be avoided. Yogini: Yes Mother
You don't know these?
Y: No, we've never [UNCLEAR]
Rice, rice is never given to a woman who's got a baby
Till about ten months she must avoid taking rice.
Yogi: So, any wind producing food should be avoided by the mother.
Haan! Everything that comes from the Mother Earth
in the sense from the down below Mother Earth gives and also milk -
milk gives wind very much.
Milk gives - but milk boiled in an iron pot
you see, made out of steel
but not this stainless one, the other one, doesn't give.
Yogini: No Milk boiled in an ordinary steel, cast iron pan doesn't give wind
Yogi: a steel pot, cast iron doesn't give wind. We have a cast iron
So you should boil that milk
with water whatever it is together in an iron pot.
So, milk should not be taken like that by mothers directly at all.
If she has to take milk then take it with
some sort of a porridge or some at the most.
She has to take milk, no doubt, so she should take it with the
porridge or these crispies or something like.
Yogini: Yes, Mother.
Yogi: What about nappies, Mother?
Some of the nappies make their legs go out
Yogi: at 45 degrees. Oh! that's horrible thing that
you make the children wear, I'm really against it.
It's very handy but it's very bad.
Poor, this girl has suffered so much
even now she has problems you see.
A plastic stuff - but we don't use plastic stuff, you see.
We use cotton ones - nice cotton ones
and we put little, what you call absorbent cotton.
Yogi: I think we call them flannelette napkins here Mother.
Hmmm. And then we remove the cotton if the
napkin is also wet, we remove the napkin - it can be washed.
You see, we can have about 12 or say 24
kept like that - it's very simple how to make it, I'll show you
[alright?] This is the say is the nappy
so you get a soft cloth - some sort of a malmal or something
- in India you get such a lot of them - readymade
Now what you do is to make it like that, alright.
Yogini: Yes. Now it's done.
not a thing like this for a little baby
but you can have a soft towel you can get
Yogini: We get, we get soft towelling
Yogini: many of us do it that way
Alright, and then you must wash them.
Hardly it takes any time for you to wash - say in
a day you take about - in the beginning they are
small and you need more numbers
later on you don't need them but you don't have all
these problems of the plastic for the baby
and the child is allowed to breathe, his body grows well
otherwise they have the back side is so pushed in funny figures and
they also have what you call the legs going like that.
Yogi: Hip, hip joints go
It's very bad, it's very strong and should be avoided.
Yogini: You mean the disposables or do you mean
The disposable are not good thing
only if you are going out somewhere, you see
this kind of a cloth is the best.
This is a soft one but this is very good, still
for a little, newly born is thick for us.
You see, we don't do all this, we don't seam it.
Not to seam it at all. It hard, you see
just take, open it out just like that - just we don't seam it.
and now put it out like that - it's too big
for a big child is alright. Now, that's all.
You can even if you want you can put like this for a big boy
here a little fold but normally for a little baby it's alright.