[Music]
now first before meditate in your heart
you should see in your heart
and then try to put your guru in the
core of it after establishing in the
heart we must bow to that
with full devotion and dedication now
whatever you do with your mind after
realization is not imagination because
now your mind your imagination is itself
enlightened so project yourself in such
a way that you humble down at the feet
of your guru
[Music]
and now a squirrel
the necessary temperament needed for
meditation or atmosphere needed for
meditation meditation is when you are
one with the divine now if there are
thoughts coming in first you have to say
the first month of course and then watch
inside also you must say mantra of
Ganesha will help some people and then
you should watch inside
and see for yourself which is the
biggest hurdle for the part
now for the thought you have to say the
mantra of nearly Chara that Thomas
akshar need which are sakshat shri
mataji nirmala devi namo namah should
say thrice
[Music]
now we come to the hurdle of your ego
because see your thought has stopped now
no doubt but there's still the pressure
on the head so if it is ego you have to
say so many visage are MOT ahankara
Mahatma is a great economy the ego Sasha
she Mataji váradi
in a Mon Ami she's right
[Music]
now even now if you find that ego is
still there then you have to raise your
left side to push it back to the right
hand side with your hand one hand
towards the photograph push the left
side higher and right side lower so the
ego and super-ego get the balance
do it seven times try to feel how you
are feeling inside is it
now you raise your Kundalini up on the
head and tighter again raise your
Kundalini up on the head and start again
they joyfully and tighter now at the
sahasrara you should say the mantra of
sastra
[Music]
now you can open again yourself driving
like this let's take it down okay and
see that you are stationed there once
this has been done then you go into
meditation this is like cleansing as you
call it Natha
[Music]
now if you find any other obstruction
you can also say like if you have got a
Mahakali problem you can say that mantra
clearly clear it and then you sit down
for meditation
any individual thing you can take it out
like if you have the euro problem if you
think then you should start with maja
Tonga
it is what you have to find out what is
your problem where is the Kundalini stop
being you can feel it within yourself
some of you may not feel if you do not
feel it feel it on your finger if you
are not feeling it in yourself then you
feel it on your fingers you can feel it
how is it now better where is the
problem
gentle heart all right hold your breath
not with great force just ordinary all
right
all right move it
better now once again all right
hold your breath
huh
okay
keep your eyes open okay holy [ __ ] I'm
sorry I just extracted
No
well that put your left hand right hand
yes titles me right hand
hmm
like this the left leg
you were
what thinking gives you liberals better
No
hmm
better now
what is it
did you feel you did
you