So lever should be treated.
And next time when you come to India we are
going to get you all the medicines of liver.
If they are very fat then they are left sided.
Try to bring them to the center with the three
candle treatment.
But first of all test it what is the situation.
Sometime they developed the puffy fat that
is alright.
They will become alright.
That is how you should look after their health.
Then also look after their behavior.
Tell them how to behave.
So I have seen in west the children are not
properly brought up because parents neglect
them.
I want blame the children.
Parents neglect them it should be loving,
kind and at the same time you should must
tell them what is discipline is.
It is very important.
Then Keep a watch on them.
How they are?
What they are doing?
Of course we have school but it has limited
seats there.
Whatever it is, they are going to adjust as
a many as possible.
Even then supposing you have any problem,
do not go arbitrarily in to it.
You many ask your leader or you may write
to me and inform me.
Among you somebody might become very ego oriented,
may start his own organization, I will do
this.
Let him say you get out and he will suffer.
You do not have to worry.
Alright you get out.
Anybody who is arbitrary will not work out.
Suppose one finger start working more than
other means it is cancer that is malignancy.
We can not have malignancy.
All of you should work together with understanding,
before others as well among yourselves.
It is very important to understand.
Now, Sahajayoga has worked out in so many
countries.
In such a big way in some and in such a small
way in some.
But wherever, Sahajayogi have to be something
special.
Even the Children have to be something special.
You have any other problems which do not want
to discuss, you say with your leader and then
you can write to me directly, no harm.
Either If I answer well and good and if I
do not answer also well and good, it will
work out.
But attention should not be all the time about
yourself.
Me, my family, my children, my house, my job,
No.
As soon as your attention on another people
it works fast.
It helps, very much.
But on your self, I am sick; I have this problem
that problem, nothing.
You are now at the stage when you can absolutely
solve all the problem but first and foremost
thing is if your attention on yourself it
want work out.
Attention should be on others.
And if it has to be on yourself, attention
then just find what is wrong with me.
But some people in that also go too far.
Mother my Agyna is caching, Mother my this
is caching, it is nonsense.
May be you are caching from other people,
possible.
There are some nice books, now already in
Sahajayoga translated in Chinese luckily and
also my tapes could be translated also.
But you have to keep my voice as I told you
because that is mantra, isn't it?
And you can have subtitle would be better
if you could do it.
That is a very good idea that you can have
subtitles, really.
Specially, for Russian if they could do in
Russia.
Now if you have any question you can ask me.
So it should be always like, if you are Chinese,
then you should not only deal with Chinese.
They should all come to the collective.
Supposing you are Indians, you should not
only deal with the Indians, but they should
come to the collective.
Because unless and until they come to the
collective they will not know what the problem
is?
It is not that you can organize separately
a group, another group separately.
It has to be one group.
Of course you could have two ashrams or three
ashrams, makes no difference.
Any other question?
Sahajayogi: is the Camphor treatment is for
left side?
Shri Mataji: What?
Sahajayogi: camphor treatment?
The Camphor treatment?
Shri Mataji: What?
Sahajayogi: he is asking if the camphor treatment
is good for left side.
Shri Mataji: what?
Shri Mataji: No no no no.
No need.
Camphor, only once in a while.
Do not do camphor.
But you have done all mixed up thing, you
see.
Just do left side treatment and you will be
alright, just mixed up.
And you can not earn money on the name of
GOD or divine work that is one thing.
You can not organize like that.
No Never.
Because once you start getting like this left
sided Bhoot will come into it.
That is the part of Sahajayog.
We can not.
Also if you have any guru's photograph and
all that it is better to put them in the sea.
Because this keeping any photograph, any book
about them creates problems.
So religiously search out and put them in
the sea.
[Shri Mataji looked at something]
"No no no no no no no"."
No no no" Don't do all that.
They will work on the photograph.
If you want to help somebody, you see some
other people who have come, who want to raise,
do not touch them.
Take a bandhan yourself and give them a bandhan.
Put them before the photograph and you just
raise the Kundalini.
But be careful.
Because you are still, you see, not that sort
of thing that you cannot catch.
You Might catch.
So Among yourselves also you should not do
that.
Do not touch.
If somebody says I have this problem alright.
Put him on the photograph.
Take a bandhan yourself.
Ask them to take a bandhan.
You also give a bandhan and then raise the
Kundalini.
Be careful.
Even if there is somebody who has came now,
who is sick man.
So you can give them a photograph, it is alright
if they are willing to do it.
But somebody in his family is willing to take
Sahajayoga, who is a healthy person he should
bring.
Otherwise don't get after sick person.
You will have many sick, in thousand, to begin
with.
Do not worry about sick.
If they are sick tell them to take the photograph
and work it out if they are left sided or
right sided.
Then the faith grows it improves.
But you do not touch the sick.
No no.
Not at all.
You are not here to cure sick.
But we are here to give realisation.
May God bless you.
Sahajayogi: For technique, if you have a problem
on one side, you have balance in left side
is weak [Not clear], Do you raise Kundalini
on this side and give bandhan to the other
side.
Shri Mataji: Supposing you are right sided
then you have to put down the right side,
remember that way it is much much better.
Then you raise your left side and put on right
side if you have right side problem.
If you have left side problem so you have
to put down the left side.
It is easier to remember this way.
So there is no confusion.
But tying of Kundalini you should be done
after you have moved out left to right or
right to left, which ever way and then raise
your Kundalini and tie up and take a bandhan,
it is the best way.
I would request you all of you to take photograph
of yours and make an album, write it down
below that what is your name, date of birth
and of self realisation.
Send it over to me because I go on seeing
that sometimes.
So, I know you better and also I will allow
my attention on you, of children and as well
as of bigger people.
So I will talk to you and talk to him because
you have little individual problem, both of
you.
So what about you?
Are you reconcile?
Ha?
..I am going to get her.
[Not clear] He came here to do Sahajayoga
and not to disturb a family.
He is been very wrong.
I am going to be very angry with him.
He is an old Sahajayogi, he should have behaved
himself.
[Not clear] You have such sweet beautiful
children.
I will never support you in nonsense, i must
tell you.
And your husband is very good man and if you
behave alright he will come round to Sahajayoga.
I am sure.
You can not be a Sahajayogi if you have no
dharma [Not clear].
"Shield".
As Buddha has called.
As we called As the Your character, your morality
is the most important in Sahajayoga.
If you are not moral it has no meaning at
all.
What you need is morality.
This is happening everywhere, nonsense.
We have to imbibe it in ourselves and we have
to generate it for others also.
Whole world is full of immoral people.
Very very few who are standing for morality?
It was the greatest ornament we have, Alright?
Don't go after.
This will never help you?
It was very wrong of you and also for your
children.
Now go back and behave yourself properly otherwise
you cannot be in Sahajayoga.
Ha, If there is something wrong then it is
alright.
We have divorce in Sahajayoga.
We allow divorce in Sahajayoga.
But there should be substantial reason for
that.
"Or to sub thik hai".
What we do?
May God Bless you all.
I am sorry you had to come so late in
the night.