[Music]
now then we have another Center on top
which we called as the heart center it
is in the center now in the sternum bone
behind the sternum bone this Center is
there and time time us produces the
antibodies in your sternum bone these
antibodies later on fight your diseases
when you are about 12 years of age did
they go into the whole body and waiting
there for a signal from your sternum
bone that means supposing you see
something you get frightened this bone
starts pulsating when it pulsates the
antibodies know there's some emergency
and they get prepared for it now this is
such a normal thing to happen to people
but insecurities car can be of the worst
time and when these insecurities they
were developed people can develop all
kinds of diseases of the lungs
especially the women develop what you
call as the breast cancer mostly these
women are insecure maybe their husbands
are not good or they feel that the
husband may leave them alone or
something like that
there are certainly insecurities that
are built in they might be quite
frightening personalities I've seen most
of the air hostesses have this central
heart catch it because they are afraid
they may miss the play you know I don't
know they have to be on the job and run
and do mostly this time-bound jobs cause
you a trouble here of the center heart
and this Center heart is very important
because for women specially they have to
be secured if their motherhood is
challenged then they are even worse and
this is how one has to understand a
woman should be very much respected if
she is your wife is your child or
anything she has to be respected and
given all the security is the woman who
makes the society is the movement who
creates the children the woman who looks
after this so the men have to give all
the security and the protection
- the women hood and understand that is
a very important factor which we
phenolate we can have lots of problems
with our society and the women will
start competing with men and then the
society will be all dislocated
[Music]
if there's any problem with your father
in the right side caches and it gives
you ask them first of all you are we can
save vulnerable to ask them are you too
bad liver plus if you have problems with
your father or eat with your father
supposing you are unhappy father or
maybe that you are not looking after
your children then you get the center
got a very bad thing it can happen to
any one of us if a man is unkind to
assume it's a father principle if the
son is unkind to the father so the
father is hurt it's the father principle
if it is disturbed by any chance or a
suddenly father dies and you feel the
pinch of that all your life all that can
work out here and you get this right
heart catch with that you get a stoma it
is said that in homeopathic they believe
that with more tension you get because
when if you have more tense you see you
remember your father if he was yet he
would have met you in the subconscious
some time signals and that's how it adds
to the it is so simple to work out that
could be amazed that if you have to just
raise the principle of father in a
person like that who might be dejected
father who might be a cruel father who
might be a son who has lost the father
can be anything that you have to just
put your hand on that part
[Music]
left-hand side of this is the essence of
Mother Nature
if in your childhood your mother had
played a role which has given you fear
or kind of a frightening experience then
this Center goes out we say the left
heart attack but damn if you are a bad
mother all through youth like that the
center is very important on the left
hand side is the mother's side and the
mother itself
the mother is a lunatic you get a
problem there you might get it we find a
heart there are two hearts one is the
heart of the spirit and one is the heart
chakra if a mother is affinity is she's
a woman who is very fanatic about her
food things like that when the children
get it it's a dangerous thing to play
with children like that to have complete
discipline on the children and just give
them must walk straight like a horse for
two things children should be allowed to
have their freedom actually when we
suppress them too much they become
Milligan's that way Indians are better
they know how to bring up their children
with this cruelty towards children I
don't know what women are up to we're
not going to take their figures and
their duties and everything in front of
God such cruelty exists such
self-centeredness then with all this the
children develop this trouble and they
have palpitations
they have very weak hearts or when the
children are not nice to the mother they
also get it
so mother and father are very important
factors in sahaja yoga and you have to
understand that if your parents have
been unkind to you you must forgive them
just forget about them because they have
given you birth
should be thankful and just forget about
them that's the best way to get over the
problem of left and right heart
so I've explained to you all these
things now this is the heart in the
heart resides the spirit the spirit is
watching the game of this creation
it is watching what is happening to this
person this person to this person to
this person
everybody has got in their heart the
spirit which is watching is called as
the shaker you mean the one the knower
of the field you know what where you go
what we states to create you watch he
doesn't interfere if you only the
interference comes from here from that
which tries to give you conscience which
tries to improve you from here sometimes
to become part it tries to tell you be
in the center by punishing you by
showing it is wrong but he is that
watching the game let's see how far it
goes he is the knower of your teeth
he is the universal green video he the
reflection of that God Almighty is a
spectator within and his power is this
all-pervading power which has created
all so to fill this all-pervading power
you have to become the spirit all this
creation has no meaning if you do not
become listed in the Vegas of first the
very first anger says that by reading
Vedas if you do not be
we believe with waiting what comes on
whether we the means to know if you do
not become the knowledge that it has
don't that's the question you are
talking about the spirit being in the
heart chakra there over on the left side
I'd like to know why it's on the left
instead of in the middle because if the
spirit is has to do with realization why
isn't it in the middle and central
Kundalini instead of on inside like that
and why is it
whining that much yeah I guess the main
thing they not that's the last one's
heart stops we don't exist
she exists that's the most important of
my god
once the spirit is angry in any way
strange anyway despaired then we don't
there's nothing left heart is very
important that's fine
[Music]