of course I've told you about the brown
now you have become the chicken
making so many eggs everyday
you study something like our birthday we
said when we became a bird out of the
cheese Michelle
so Easter is our birthday we are selling
out of our realization and every day we
must grow with our birthday why in a
human form you decrease your age as your
birthday comes in
but with this we increase your range and
you're proud that you are growing and
the human level you feel unhappy that
you are going here you feel proud that
you are going just the opposite of what
you are doing if you try to do it it
will be nice I mean that doesn't mean
bugging indiscreet you know I am quite
worried on that point discretion is the
first thing that you should have before