We had a very good session, I should say,
and a very successful trip in Portugal and
even better in Spain.
Portugal is a place where gurus have touched
very nicely because people are too simple,
and because they are too simple they are affected
too hard. And I was really confronted with
so many sick people there who have been to
gurus, who have been only for two, three years
with them are badly affected and surprisingly
how the whole thing is exposed, that we may
be able to do much better in Portugal.
Now, the Portuguese people get lot of wine.
They drink a lot; they really drink. I mean,
they have all kinds of wines in their country.
It's a very big problem of that place, is
it that has many wines and I think the drunkenness
make them extremely lethargic and that lethargy
brought down that empire. We can see it's
a very huge place. I mean the buildings, if
you see, are very beautifully done, lots of
buildings with lots of architecture, and all
that is like a desolate place. The reason
is: the people who were at the time quite
affluent were doing well. Gradually unemployment
started settling down, lots of strikes - just
the same thing as I feel is happening in this
country - and unemployment and amounting to
starvation. First they used to get doles and
all that, as we get here; gradually it stopped.
Now it's so bad that all of them have to depend
on their parents. There's no way. They have
no source of income, very few industries.
It's one of the poorest country in the whole
of Europe.
That made Me think about England, that we
have to know that this country also may face
a phase, if we do not get up now. You see
it's all right to divert your attention to
Falklands and all that, but it cannot feed
you. So, we have to understand, all the Sahaj
Yogis must understand, that they all must
have some sort of a degree or something on
the paper; that's a very important. And though
you are all realized souls and you are spiritually
so endowed, everything is there, but you have
to think of the whole. If the country completely
goes down in its production and its capacity
to activate itself, you will go down, too.
So, your attention should be now, of course,
you should not be materialistic, but towards
putting more activity into you, even in Sahaja
Yoga, in meditating, in working it out in
yourself.
So, lethargy is not going to pay. And this
is one thing, is such an inertia, such an
inertia that exists, that unless and until
you really put in complete willpower, this
inertia may not be combated, may be very difficult,
even in Sahaja Yoga. You see, it is very easy
to escape and explain, you see, yourself,
"Oh, I got up and, you know, this happened,
that happened." But, I think the symptoms
are of a very dangerous type and as Sahaja
Yogis you have to be very patriotic about
it and you have to think about it. After all,
you are symbols of the English people. Whatever
works out in you will start working out in
the rest. So, how you behave towards yourself
and towards the general atmosphere is very,
very important.
Now, towards Sahaja Yoga also the attitude
has to be understood very clearly. You see,
like a Maharaja in India who lives in quite
great comfort first of all, lives like a lord
and he orders about, you see, and then everything
is lost. But, still he talks like a lord,
behaves like a lord. His whole thing is the
same way, though, it's not that the kingdom
is there, that he's the ruler, but he'll talk
like that to everyone, because the habits
are formed. I think the mind also has formed
a habit. The whole atmosphere is charged with
such ego since long and that's why towards
Sahaja Yoga also, the attitude has to be humbler,
much humbler, because without humility you
cannot do. That's one thing you must understand.
It's no question of you rationally saying
something about it or explaining about it.
But, you see, basically one has to be extremely
humble.
First of all, it's a very big privilege to
get realization. You know that. It's a greater
privilege to do it, and it's the greatest
to be a Sahaja Yogi. Is a very great privilege
that you have, which very few people have
and you are the ones who are chosen specially.
But, the humility part of it is still missing
about Sahaja Yoga, about Sahaja Yoga. Like,
we should ask, "Make me a better Sahaja Yogi,
a humbler Sahaja Yogi, a compassionate Sahaja
Yogi, a sweeter Sahaja Yogi. Dissolve my ego."
This is very important, we must understand,
because whatever works out in you, will work
out in this country.
Arrogance is something that with ego you can
never understand you have been arrogant. The
way you talk to others, the way you behave
towards others, you will never understand,
because there is ego. If you are standing
in the darkness, the light is there but it
is covered with something. How will you understand
where is the light? So, humility must be there,
because you people have very developed brains,
very developed, over-developed brains and
that brain can, you see, always tell you,
"Oh, you are better than others," you see,
always. "The another one is no good and the
third one is useless. You see, you are the
best." That's typical of the brain teaches,
you see. And when it starts working out, it's
very difficult, you see, to see that the one
who is saying this is nowhere, because from
the point where you see, you cannot see what
you are saying. What you see is the whole
thing as if you have to command it; you have
to ask for it.
Of course, the quality is very much changing
now, everybody is becoming very, very, very
sweet and sober and nobody now demands anything
from Me like, "You must give me this, Mother.
You have to do it. You have to look after
me. After all, I have been to Your Caxton
Hall once, You see, and how dare You do not
look after my mother when she met an accident?"
Something like that. That's over now. That's
over.
The quality is improving now and one has started
learning now how to laugh at your own ego
and this and that. But I personally think
that one has to realize that if you represent
this country to your Mother, then it has to
improve still. "Still I have to improve. I
have to go ahead. I have to go further with
it and have I to develop that beauty of humility."
Like in Portugal they told Me Lord Byron,
whom I think to be a useless fellow, absolutely
good for nothing and I regretted every minute
why he was created on this earth, he went
and said that ... he went and said, "Cintra
is a very beautiful place. Cintra is too good
to be wasted on Portuguese." It should have
been from Mr. Lord Byron, whosoever he may
be. You see, typical! And it pinches everyone,
you know. Everybody feels. But think if you
are the person about whom he said.
So, one has to develop a kind of a humility
that "I have to still receive; I have to still
get it; it has to work out." Now, when it
comes to that kind of an attitude, then you
turn round. Turn round upon yourself. What
have you done for Sahaja Yoga? One question,
simple question: what have you done for Sahaja
Yoga? How many people have you given realization?
How many people have you been able to cure?
How much peace have you got within yourself?
How much blissful are you? How much compassion
have you got? How much forgiveness and patience
you have for others? How much of sharing you
can do? These are the signs of sahaja yogis,
that you break your shell. You become collective.
How much do you understand others? And how
much do you understand giving [to] others?
What have you given to others, even on material
level? Let's see. These questions should be
put to yourself. On a very material level
these questions are to be asked, on a very
material level, because the light comes down
to material level. How many people you can
forgive?
You are realized souls. You are prophets,
no doubt. You can make others prophets, but
you have to be the quality, also. The quality
of a prophet is his nobility. He is so noble.
Nobleness. In comparison with other people,
who are not realized souls, he is nobler;
he is more dignified; he is much more forgiving.
So the whole way of dealing with others will
change. He is obedient. We have to obey in
Sahaja Yoga. We have to obey our good will.
Otherwise, you are difficult people. It's
impossible. Nobody can do anything to you.
If you are like a thorn, how can anybody help
you?
So the quality of a sahaja yogi is measured
by another kind of a measure. Is not the way
human beings measure the quality of other
human beings. Like, somebody has a good taste,
for example, so-called. Then people say, "Oh,
he's great, with a good taste." Or if he has
a big car, "Oh, he's a big man." Or he talks
like that, or he walks like that, or says
this, that and all those things. Or a question
like this, "Why did you say like that?" All
these words, you know. They sound very hard
to Me. "Why do you do like that?" This kind
of a language itself was not there in this
English language.
Nowadays the language is so changed and very
rude, very arrogant and very harmful. So,
first ask yourself, because Sahaja Yoga will
spread - of course, slowly and steadily, I
hope - only through your images. You are the
reflectors. You put My thousands of posters.
I am so unique, you know. They'll say, "All
right, this unique personality is taken out,
no good. What about the disciples?" So, actually
whatever is in the lower level animals is
important, like in lower level animals the
king is the one. Say, the tiger has to kill
an animal, big animal. It is he who only can
kill. Till human stage also perhaps it is
so. The one who can really dominate others,
survival of the fittest, is the rule.
Is the other way round, now. It's changed,
completely. How much free you are in your
ideas, while you are still identified with
old ideas. But free doesn't mean abandonment,
by any chance. Freedom means you respect the
freedom of others. First and foremost thing
of freedom is that you must respect the freedom
of others. Even God respects your freedom.
He cannot give you realization if you don't
want it. He cannot force it. So, respect the
freedom of others. But, that does not mean
by respecting the freedom of others there
should be abandonment. If somebody is abandoned
in Sahaja Yoga, he goes out of the circulation
of Sahaja Yoga. It's not coming in is so important,
I've told you hundred times. It's the throwing
out part of it, you see. Sometimes I feel
I should use some glues to stick on. Maybe,
the wheel can turn very fast and some of half-baked
may be thrown out back again into the oven.
So, I feel, in these countries where I went,
Spain, they call it. Spain, still half-developing;
Portugal, developing. I don't know what you
think about Italy, whatever it is called.
Very humble people, very humble from the very
first day. Anyone who comes from the very
first day, they are very humble and because
they are humble, they are sensitive to Me;
because you have to be really very humble
to be sensitive to Me, that's a fact, because
I'm too simple, naïve, as if I do not understand
anything. I look like that, I mean, as if
I have no knowledge of anything - very simple
woman, talks in a very simple way, is very
friendly, all right. So to understand Me you
have to be extremely humble and if you cannot
go to that level of humility you cannot see
Me and you cannot understand Me. And the more
you start understanding, the more humble you
become, naturally, because you know what it
is.
So, I have told you many a times about humility
part of it, but My experience of these countries
was where I went there. I mean, they are very
humble people, very humble about Sahaja Yoga,
extremely humble they were. Even the new people
were very humble. Spanish people same thing,
extremely humble. You see, Dawn had told Me
that they have a ego of a bull fighter, but
the one who came this time were so humble
I was amazed. Even if I could touch them,
that was sufficient for them. Nobody pulled
My hand, nothing.
So, this is what it is: one has to understand
that we have certain tags of our past which
has to go down. The language should be extremely
humble language. Try to read ... I don't know
whose language is so humble. Maybe Mine, I
don't know. But, try to read books where people
speak humble language, humble way of talking.
You'll enjoy it, really enjoy it. Humility
is the glory of sahaja yogis, is the only
way they will grow. It's like putting your
roots down and down and down.
The people who went from here were themselves
amazed at the humility of the people who were
there, very much amazed, the way things are
working out there, the way they helped us
and did everything for us. And I am sure now
in Spain we'll have a very nice, very, very
nice center. Of course, the Ambassador is
a very, very humble man - you know him, too
humble - and he might be coming here, and
one day I want to call him here to the ashram
also. He and his wife will be here. So, the
Ambassador was very sweet and he called Me
to his house, invited, and he had a nice tea
party.
He called Indians and everything and Indians
said, you know they asked Me for one thing.
You'll be shocked. They said, "What about
something to depend upon?" you see. "Can we
have Your photographs, something? It must
be having some vibrations. Should we use Your
photographs for our worship?" Can you imagine?
And, at first I said that "It's all right.
It will work out," because I didn't want to
say, "You have to take My photograph." So
she was so disappointed, the lady. She said,
"No, there must be a photograph or something
which we can use. After all, how can that
be?" Just imagine! And here, first thing comes
up, like a big snake, "Why Mother's photograph?
She should give us realization, She should
solve all our problems, all our sickness,
everything, but why Her photograph? This is
too much!" In this you can see the ego of
the people.
Now, regarding ashram, I had asked Nick, I
had asked him to make certain rules and regulations.
And I must say that, of course, Nick should
say things, as you, somebody told Me that
he should have been a little softer with it
and all that. But, supposing somebody is not
soft at all, so you must know that this is
said by Mother and you must do it. You see,
actually, when you say no to him, you are
saying no to Me also, isn't it? Because I
sent him. I told him and I told him that "You
must carry out these things." If you do not
allow him to carry out, he has to be perhaps
strict. By softer means, supposing something
fails, then what to do? I really don't know.
After realization even if do not do things,
what should we do? Can you suggest? I mean,
you should respect everyone. But say, even
if you respect, people get up at eight o'clock
in the morning; then what should you do? What
should be done, you just tell us? John, tell
Me. I mean, it is really surprising. You are
now prophets. Do you understand your quality,
what are you, what have I given you? Then
what should we do about it? You see, these
are so simple things, like children also.
If you are in a hostel, you are made to get
up in the morning, take your bath, get ready,
walk out. I mean, if you do not listen, anyone,
I mean, it's simple. Then, what should one
do with prophets? You just tell Me.
This is not the problem in Australia even.
But English one going to Australia, create
problems. I have seen. Sally, what a problem.
Ba pre. You could see in contrast, her ego.
Absolutely, in contrast I could see it clearly,
very egoistical. Though she said that she
was in - what place she was in? Jersey, and
there bhoots got her. But all the bhoots were
egoistical. That's the point. Such a contrast,
you know. If we have to grow as one body and
you are enlightened, part and parcel, part
and particle of the same body, supposing this
finger says, "No, no, I will not do it." Now,
somebody is, say, putting a big attack or
something and this hand says, "No, I will
not work out," then what to do? Actually,
it's a very big dilemma for Me because a hand
which is forced to do it will never do it
properly. If you don't force it, then what
happens to that hand? I mean, just see, the
diligence is very important. We should not
take things for granted. You see, we take
ourselves for granted, everything for granted.
Is not proper. We have to work hard. We have
to work it out ourselves. You see, even if
you have ten thousand sahaja yogis, here,
what is going to happen? The quality is so
poor, isn't it?
You have to get up in the morning, do it,
meditation. You have to grow. You have to
grow still much more. And you know you are
so very few, I have to use you only. Of course,
nobody can force you. And even if you force,
a forced labor is not going to help in Sahaja
Yoga, that is. You take it from Me. It cannot.
So, these people who go nowhere, where do
they stand? Now, anyone you tell the job.
Say, Warren also, in Australia. There were
jealousies about that, terrible jealousies.
"Why should he tell me?" Because there is
nobody to tell you within yourself. That's
the problem is it. So, that which is sleeping,
I put it into one man. All right, this man
is going to tell, but, then that person tells
you, then people feel jealous. I mean, these
are not the signs of a prophet. A prophet
is never jealous, because he knows he has
achieved his powers now. He's in his own power
and his power is of surrendering. He's not
of overpowering.
See, you cannot see the other side of it.
You think power means you sit on somebody's
head, then, "I am very powerful." Like a woman,
if she can make her husband dance to her tune,
then she thinks, "Oh, I am the most powerful
woman ever living." It's the other way round,
that the woman is so loving that husband can't
do without her, that sort of a power. She's
so sweet that the husband cannot manage without
her. That sort of a power is, should be the
power of a prophet
and these things are very much deeply put
into us. So face it up and take it out. The
whole value system is upside down. I tell
you the whole value system is upside down.
See My life, own life. As a wife of such and
such and such I am expected to go into diamond
shops, buy diamonds, wear, become a big lady
with heels like that and walk with a neck
like that and do all sorts. I mean, this is
the normal thing. It's expected. And shout
at the chauffeur, and shout at the servants
and shout at everyone and behave in that manner.
I mean, that's what it is, the power is. You
see, that's how the woman express their husbands'
positions.
But, the other way round, is the situation
of a prophet. The prophet asserts his powers
through love. "How much can you hate me? I
love you double. Always, whatever you will
hate me, I'll love you double of that." Then
what will happen? But to love, one has to
sacrifice, one has to give, one has to bear.
Love doesn't hang in the air. That's one thing
people don't understand. Love is not only
talking love or if you are a little gentle
to somebody is not the point. But even that
bearing is a joy, because ultimately you are
doing it for love. If love is the joy-giving
thing, then that bearing is not much. You
are doing it for love's sake. See, because
love, unless and until it is shared you cannot
enjoy. So, first we have to be strict with
ourselves, I think would be a good idea, and
loving to others. That may be the way we might
work it out.
By God's grace we have a very nice place as
an ashram. We might get even better place.
You are the God's own blessed people. No one
can believe that we could have such a nice
place. But, what are we willing to do for
it? That's the point, we should say. Don't
take things for granted. I must warn you.
I know England is the heart, but in God's
realms one can create many hearts, not so
difficult. So more harmony should be brought
in. Even, you'll be surprised, in France,
it's so harmonious and so beautiful. Find
faults with yourself all the time.
Now, under certain circumstances I have to
appoint somebody, like I would say very personally,
I would say, Nick. Because Nick is doing no
job nowadays, he is quite a systematic person,
is all right, this thing. He has some problems,
I know. You, too, have problems, all right?
But he's the one available today and he's
the one who is going to do it. Take one case.
Now you must understand why Mother has appointed
somebody, all right? Accept it. Because...
(speaking about the children) It's a big dance,
all that... They're trying to entertain...
see, look at this dancing. They are feeling
the tenseness of the situation and trying
to entertain... That's it; that is love. See,
they want to relax you, they want to relax
you, they want you to feel nice, to be joyous.
Look at them, in the same way, we should be.
I am sure. I am sure now, henceforth. I think
best thing is to make some poems. That may
be a solution, all right? Let's see. And let
everybody start writing poems. Would be a
good idea. And then that should work out.
And sing the song of praises. It's very little
way, just a very little way, just there in
your heart, resides the source of all the
beauty. It's just, turn your face towards
that. That will work out. I'm sure it will
work out. It's not very far away.
(aside) Let her also stand there, she'll enjoy.
Now, another point was that you are going
to go to that peace mission or something.
What peace? What is that supposed to be? In
Brighton, you are? Peace festival, all right.
And I'm told Kay has written an article about
it, peace. You know that peace is nothing
without. It is within yourself and if you
can feel your peace, then only you can start
feeling peace for others. Sahaja Yoga is the
only way; there's no other way out.
You see, at the level of, say, take the position
of Falkland. Now, let's see, Falkland Island
is a very immediate problem. Now at that level
there's no solution. There's no solution.
They are quite justified in attacking back
Falkland, because these people were illegally
there, because that's not a democratic country.
They have destroyed so many people of their
own. So, English were justified. Of course
My all support was for them, because they
were correct on the justice point. That's
true. But, justice is a little half-baked,
because for whom to fight? These unrealized
souls, their right, for what? Even if you
have democracy, if it is demonocracy, what
is the use of having democracy? I mean, if
through democracy, you are creating only demons,
this demonic reign, then what's the use of
having democracy, also?
What about this so-called communism? All stupid
people. To My eye, everybody is stupid and
they cannot achieve anything at that level.
You can say little bit, "Yes, that's correct.
After all, you see, that was their people
were there under democracy." These people
should have gone because they have killed
so many people. Already Argentina, they have
no business and, of course, despotic law is
against, absolutely against Sahaja Yoga. So
democracy is the best suited, no doubt. We
have to support democracy. But, even democracy
for what? Why to have democracy? To have the
higher freedom. If you cannot have higher
freedom, and it just means abandonment, you
see, democracy means that an old man can marry
a young girl and all sorts of nonsensical
things. Then better not to have.
So democracy is only suitable to people who
are dharmic, who have established their dharma.
Otherwise, you really need a communistic country
which will settle down your dharma most, to
evolve out of it. But people think that democracy
is for ruining your dharma, you have freedom
to ruin your dharma as you like. You see,
"What's wrong?" It's a very, you see, you
cannot say. It's a dilemma again. I don't
know which way to go. It's another dilemma.
So, to end up the dilemma you have to talk
to people, that though it might be justified
at this time, say Falkland thing, aggression,
it's for peace, because next time they won't
do such a thing again. It's really for peace,
because next time such a thing they may not
try, these despots, and there are all these
Germans have gone and settled there. So, is
a good thing. But, still it's not peace, it
has killed a lot of people. This thing has
happened. Why? Because people are not realized
souls.
Come in, come in! Come inside, there's a lot
of space here, move on. All those people who
come first should come this side. Can you
move on this side, don't standing up.
So, all these political institutions are a
big joke, without realization. They're not
yet fully human beings. They're not fully
developed, because they have not found their
spirit. You must find your spirit. Unless
and until you found your spirit, no problem
is going to be solved. Once your problem is
solved, that is, to find your spirit, all
other problems are solved. How now? What will
happen? Let's see. What will happen if we
establish a kingdom of the realized souls?
Let's hear... the scholar. What should happen?
Of course, everybody will get up early in
the morning, no doubt about it. Apart from
that - that's the most difficult thing. Tell
Me. Whatever you say it will happen, so that's
what I'm asking.
Yogi: Nobody will attack such a state.
Shri Mataji: There won't be any states. You
see, God has not made any states. It's a madness.
I tell you, when I was born, I was surprised.
Oh God, what has happened? You see, God has
not made any one of these states. It's a very
different thing than what, you see, I expected.
You see, God has made a beautiful land, all
right, like this one, one sari like that.
Now, you have to have some design, pattern,
so He made some beautiful mountains and some
nice, you can say, areas. And some are desert,
some are rich. You see, it's to create ... the
whole system, if you see, has worked out in
such a way that you have equator, and you
have the sun there, so the winds start moving.
You see, it's all created so beautifully,
so you have different types of countries and
different types of places. Now, after creating
that, the human beings, stupid as they are,
they divided themselves up. I mean, it is
stupid. I tell you really there is no need
to divide like that. So they created states.
There was no need to create a state. But you
see it happened like this: that in the beginning
they created state, because they wanted to
have a, you can say, a hut to protect themselves,
then a village, then a city, now a state.
Now, after state what is the next situation?
The whole world! Collective? This is the breaking
through. Is one world. It is. I believe it
is. To Me it's nonsense to see it in so many
...
I can't understand walking in the, you see,
this Customs and all that, carrying your passport,
that criminal number so and so, and apart
from that you carry your photograph and then
tell so many things. Oh, by the way, My passport
is completely filled now. Have to get another
one. It's like that. You see, everywhere you
go, you look like a criminal. They look at
your face and then they stamp you. All right,
you are stamped. Go ahead. It's terrible.
It's indignified, absolutely there. That means
the human beings have no dignity left in them.
I mean, this land doesn't belong to you at
all. This is a land of God. You are of God
and the land is. Nothing belongs to you, actually,
to be very frank. I'm sorry to say, it's true.
So, what is a state? This is stateless. But
stateless also means there is state in it.
I say this is one world. This is, has been,
is and will be.
I mean you may in your myth, you see, hallucination,
think it is different and fight. I sometimes
feel you are just fighting your shadows. This
is the, you have created shadows and the shadows
are fighting and just to make the shadows
fight, you fight. Otherwise, shadows won't
fight. It's all a shadow. There's no truth
in it. To Me it looks like that. It's all
madness. What is there to fight? This is one
world. Everybody is blessed by God. They all
should enjoy His blessings to enter into the
kingdom of God. He is the King. He is the
one who is the ruler. In His kingdom there
is nothing like a state. So that's a very
different world you are entering into.
There are no alternatives there. There is
only one absolute state of mind where you
become the spirit, that's all. There's not
going to be any aggression. It's stupid to
be aggressive. There's not going to be any
suppression. It's stupid to do that. Nobody's
going to be suppressed and nobody's going
to take any suppression. Everybody ... Why?
Do you find that in the nature? Nobody does
that. It's a harmonious living in the nature,
even in the animal kingdom. You see, they
know that a tiger has to live on an animal.
It's all right. That cattle has its own life,
finished. Even they can understand the need,
but, human beings don't. Their need is of
spirit, and spirit hates, actually hates aggression.
It cannot. It cannot. Even if it wants to,
it cannot. It's indignified to aggress anyone,
for a spirit, indignified. Absolutely, it
is wretched. So, that is what it is, that
we'll all enjoy love, love of God, His blessings,
and all our limitations will drop off. So-called
bhoots, as you call them, they'll all run
away.
It's a very different atmosphere of reality.
This is all unreal, is absolutely unreal,
is an illusion, I tell you, because you know
that Brahma, His divine vibrations are doing
everything. They are working out everything,
even material things. Everything they can
achieve. Apart from that, they give you that
source of joy which takes you onto that atmosphere
where you exist and enjoy. All the illusions
created by human beings will drop out. This
is all illusion. Believe Me, it's all illusion.
There is no truth in it at all. But through
illusion, you can work out.
It's a very interesting thing that only through
illusion you can work out, because when I'm
talking to you I have to keep an illusion
of being here. Otherwise, you won't pay any
attention. You wouldn't see Me; you wouldn't
know Me; you wouldn't talk to Me. So, you
have to have an illusion. But, I know this
is illusion. That's all. Living in this world,
in this illusion, if you know it's an illusion,
that's done. You are going to be tomorrow's
citizens, no doubt, of a very high level quality.
The day will come when they will have to jolly
well consult us. Already you have seen how
I am playing tricks on the U.S. Did you hear
the way the lady made mistakes, you see, the
stupid things? Did you find that? I saw her
photograph and I said, "Oh, this stupid woman."
She just raised her hand like that.
Now they are realizing, you know, they don't
know what happens and then suddenly how they
go amok. They'll all go amok and then they
will have to find out how they should be controlled,
what has happened, how did it happen. All
these tricks one has to play, with all of
them.
Now, after the last war perhaps people may
not come out with very aggressive words, perhaps,
maybe, because it will be unpopular. But they'll
do such stupid things, you see, to prove that
they are good for nothing. All this can be
done. But, you must know it is an illusion,
all of you, because you are different things.
You are seeing through different eyes. You
know is what Brahma is. So, you must know
and raise your quality. Raise your quality.
In normal life, supposing, you see, like I'll
say that somebody is a peon, then he dresses
up in a particular way. Then he suddenly becomes
an officer. Then he becomes a different style,
you see, walks in a different way; his gait
changes; style changes.
So, now you have become prophets, whole thing
has to change. Either you don't accept this
position, but if you are accepted this position
and you are paid for it, then better be that.
I mean, you can't dress up like a peon if
you are an officer, can you? It's all illusion,
complete illusion. The whole thing is an illusion.
All these kings of yours and queens are like
dolls there before you. Especially Mr. Pope,
you see, who came here. My grandson says,
"Mr. Poke came here."
I said, "Poke?"
He said, "I'm sorry, Pork. He was talking
all rubbish."
I said, "How do you know?"
"Because all his chakras were catching."
And he is supposed to be the Pope in charge.
Now, Bishop of Canterbury, see, is another
funny man. I've seen him on the thing. He
was agnostic about everything. I don't know
about Christ also, maybe. He said, "I'm agnostic."
Any question you ask him, "I'm agnostic."
Is a very good escape he has got, you see.
He's agnostic of about everything, because
he says, "It's a mystery to me." So, what
are you doing there? I mean, if it's a mystery
to you, you're agnostic. I mean, I just don't
understand how is he there.
So, some people have taken up upon themselves
this crusade, I believe, and to talk to him.
I mean, how can you talk to your shadow? Can
you? So, the people live in the shadow state
and you should not symbolize yourself as shadows.
You should symbolize yourself as reality and
look at them as shadows, you see. In a way,
in a very dignified way, "This is a shadow,
you know." Just pick it up, but, not in an
aggressive way, but have compassion about
them. Say, "No, no, sir, this is not so. You
are sadly mistaken. This is a shadow of life."
The whole Christianity is doomed because they
started running after shadow. This Mr. Saint
Paul, I don't know how he came into Bible.
Now, you are a theologist. You tell Me, John.
How did he enter? I mean, anybody who says
he saw Christ, is he supposed to enter into
the Bible? How did he? I mean, his saying
and his words and his letters are regarded
as the letters from the Bible, after Christ.
Before Christ is all right, but after Christ.
What is the validity? I don't understand.
What is the credibility of this person entering
into that as an authority? How? When nobody
challenged him. He was a man who was killing
so many people before. Then, suddenly he becomes
something and he starts saying, "I'm doing
Christ's work," and this and that and writes
letter to Corinthians and all these people
and all that. And why these letters that he
writes becomes a Bible? Can you imagine? What
did he do in his own lifetime? Half of it
he spent in killing and half of it is he was
an imposter. I am happy that it has come to
your notice. But one can ask, "Why? Why is
he there?"
Now, he started this charismatic thing; he
is doing all this. I first saw it in India.
There's a Saint Paul's Church. They're all
possessed people, you know, and one of My
uncles was the priest of that. He was a very
possessed man, very hot-tempered, horrible.
And when I saw that, I wanted to see the Saint
Paul's Bible what he has written about. I
was amazed. But I said, "Let you people read
and see for yourself." And this horrible charismatic
movement is anti-God activity, absolutely
anti-God activity.
So, if you have to talk to the gentleman,
you have to tell him about it, that it is
possession. The Seventh Day Adventist and
what other is this Pentecost, is nothing but
that. Jamaicans are doing, all of them are
great spiritually-developed people - spiritually
in the pub. I mean, there should be certain
norms, isn't it, about a person who is supposed
to be a prophet or something, something to
do with God, you see. The world is coming
to a position where they are understanding;
but you see, once they start disregarding,
the danger is this: once they start disregarding
these things, because they are myths and falsehood,
they will disregard also God and all the truth
about God. They can become communists. That's
the easiest way. Then there is no return.
It's a dangerous situation. When you talk
to him you have to tell him, warn him. Already
your churches are selling here. Nobody goes
to church.
Now, about the environment. They are having
a meeting on environment. That, too, is only
solved through spirit. All environment problems
can be solved only spiritual, if you have
spiritual ascent. Otherwise, you cannot. You
try anything; it's like patching up the sky.
See now, it's a very deep-rooted thing that
we don't understand that spirit is the most
practical thing. You see, we think spirit,
we think it's like a drunkard, you know. Spiritual
man, he's a cult, he's a drunkard, he's most
abnormal. He's funny. Either he hits people
or runs away from them. This is the idea we
have got about a spiritual personality.
But just see you are spiritual. You will find
it impossible to use plastics after some time,
because you will know that the plastics give
you horrid vibrations. After some time you
will really find it repulsive. It's all right
to sit in a train for a while on a plastic
coach, all right, but, to sit in your house
on a plastic all the time would be horrible
and to wear a plastic coat all the time, our
body will refuse. So when people will be spiritually
awakened, they'll give up all these nonsensical
things.
So, they may say then, "What will happen to
the machines?" Now, machines are for us; we
are not for the machines. This is another
concept is: whatever is created is for us
and we are not for that. All right, doesn't
matter. Nothing will go wrong with the machines.
Machines should be used for anything that
is a public work. Like for your motor cars,
for your trains, trams, all public work which
is outside. For houses at the most you can
use machines. But, for personal things, you
must use handmade things, handmade things.
For spiritual people, you like to wear something
that is handmade or real. I can't wear a nylon
sari. Not that I am very fussy about things,
but I just can't wear. After some time, if
I do not take out My socks, which are only
nylon, what to do? My vibrations get jammed,
completely. So, you won't be able to wear
next to your skin, near your skin, near your
body, eating your food, everything in plastics,
cooking in plastics. I mean it's too much.
Thank God, cooking I don't think is possible,
isn't it? But aluminium is another thing.
It's very bad. Aluminium - you won't be able
to use. You'll either try copper or brass,
I think so. Now, handmade things we may have,
because they are made by hand, so they have
vibrations. People would like to have handmade.
It is a part, so by that we remove the disparity
of the world. Developing countries can do
handmade things. You cannot beat them with
computers. Can you? You go ahead, mad with
your computers. You'll have to come back.
You must understand the whole. If you don't
understand the whole, this is what is happening:
like mad, you know computers are going ahead,
ahead. Where? Into the ditch, into a big mountain.
Now they have created a big mountains of plastic
and they don't know what to do with it. So,
and now with computer, what will they do?
They'll create a greater mountains out of
plastics. Maybe a Himalaya might be created,
with the computer. So the developing countries
should not try to follow these mad people
on one side. They should develop their hand
things and all that, because they'll have
to come back. Now, the handmade things in
this country are so important and so expensive.
You don't care whether it is pressed or not.
But in India you have to take nylons, because
they say nylons is a symbol of development,
not of over-development, perhaps, but of development.
So they must take to nylons and plastics and
to stainless steel and aluminium, if possible.
That's what we are doing.
When you have less things consumed like that,
you use less things from your motherland,
because handmade you cannot go on mad like
a machine goes, like a rakshasa eating away
everything and producing more. She has to
live like that. It's not economical. So when
you have handmade things you have more value
for your things, you look after them better,
you feel better, you are comfortable and you
need not be that smart, you see, machine-made.
That idea of smartness is going down.
So, the developing countries should also learn
a lesson. They are going after you. They are
running fast. They try to run faster; they
cannot. Thank God, they cannot. But they should
stick on to that side. You see, one part of
the country has to do something; another part
has to do something else.
But, you people have to look after the side
of machines, all right? I mean, handmade things,
what can you make? Some ceramics, I think
- apologies, some apologies for that. You
better do what you know better and let them
do what they can do better and share it. If
this balance is established, there's no aggression.
Unemployment can be solved. All the problems
can be solved, if you take to handmade things.
You should take to handmade things as far
as possible. Sahaja yogis should use handmade
things. I mean, not the cars, but for their
personal use. Even I would say, soaps that
you use are horrid. The soaps that you get
in England are not meant for your skins at
all, for sahaja yogis' skin. I can't bear
them. What you have to use is natural soaps
that you get from any country you feel like,
but natural soaps, which come from natural
oils.
Foods also, natural food you must eat, more
natural food, than artificial. All that will
give you a better living and that is called
as alternative, all right. That's alternative
is important, but that doesn't mean you go
on a bullock cart. You can export your trains
to India, or your cars to India and get khadi
from there. All right? Mutual understanding,
because we are part and parcel of one whole
and we just cannot exist by our only growth
because then we become malignant, you see.
One cells eats another. You have to. If you
have a machinery, you have to eat other, because
you produce so much. You must find markets
for them, you must supply them, you must send
over and then you must have other countries
to exploit them.
People have tremendous respect for Mahatma
Gandhi, but I don't know if people understand
what he said about machinery. That doesn't
mean the people who are doing machine work
should give up, by any chance, but, some of
them they can close down. For example, plastic
toys for children is horrifying. You can't
even get wood toys now - nothing, just plastic.
They are touching plastic. I mean, imagine,
you cannot feel any plastic.
So, this is what a sane sahaja yogi has to
understand. That's how you can solve the problem
of environment, also. Thank God, somehow with
your affluence and too much of machinery,
all the western people - I am happy to know,
even in Portugal - realize the value of handmade
things. But in India if you offer somebody
in an handmade thing they'll say, "Oh God,
they have no money." But stainless steel,
"Great." In a stainless steel, glass they'll
give you tea, you see - it's very big. If
you give it in a ceramic, "Oh, what this,
village craft?"
They are to be told. But, if you create a
demand, they'll be all right; they'll look
after their handmade. And here you can't do
much. I've seen, you see, that neatness, that
deftness is not there; that's lacking; now
they've lost it. Very few people have that
left in them. Even if they have to cut one
coat with their hands, they cannot do it.
They have to use a machine, which cuts twenty-five
coats at a time, you see.
Then this problem of, you have to have a figure
exactly because these only can fit certain
figures. You can't have your own independent
figure. This is all machine-like stuff, you
see. You all must have that figure, otherwise
doesn't fit it. So, that is an ideal figure.
So, everybody works out for that. See, there's
a new machinery comes up, you see, for that
kind of a thing, then new styles come up.
It's such an artificial thing, all man-made,
artificial.
From your democracy, your politics to your
economics, to all your so-called ideas of
creativity, everything becomes so artificial.
Now people can't paint. What they paint, if
you see, you are just aghast. You don't know
what is this supposed to be. And it is supposed
to be so that it looks, "There's a hand, isn't
it? Can't you see that?" "Yes, I can. It's
a little bit showing." They can't do anything.
We can't have Shakespeare, we can't have Gauguin,
we can't have anyone of that type. We can't
have, say, Abraham Lincoln. You can have only
machines, you see, bolts and nuts, fitted
nicely. You're fixed, you're fixed, you're
fixed, you're fixed. Everybody fixed nicely.
Where do, I mean, this brain go? Where will
this heart go? What will it do then? It cannot
collapse. I mean, as long as you are existing,
the heart has to beat. 01:09:53 So all this
artificiality has to be overcome by sahaja
yogis. The responsibility is so great. Such
a big building you have to bear on your shoulders,
and the foundation stones have to get up in
the morning to be chiseled out properly. So,
I end up My lecture today. May God bless you!
Now I am getting self-conscious. Will you
please put it off? All right. Now, today I
have come specially to discuss about ...