Today, we are going to worship the Maha Lakshmi
which I think is very much worshipped in this
country where they worship Her as Maria and
also there’s a swayambu of Maria, you must
have seen. And also there was an apparition
of Her. First I never believed that it could
be, but then after feeling the vibrations,
now I know it was true, that She did appear
here in an apparition. She appeared before
Me, also, you must have seen, in a photograph.
This is the principle by which you have risen
to this state. The central path of your ascent
is created by Maha Lakshmi power for the Kundalini
to rise.
In the temple of Maha Lakshmi in Kholapur
they always sing the song of “Ude, Ude,
Ambe.” So I asked the people there, “Why
do you sing Ambe’s song in Maha Lakshmi’s
temple?” So they said that, “We don’t
know why we do it, but is it wrong?” I said,
“No, because only in the Maha Lakshmi channel
Kundalini can rise and Kundalini is the Umba.”
That’s how, you see, they understood and
they were really amazed that I explained it
very well ’cause from ancient times this
song has been sung there and they never knew
why this song is sung.
Coming to the point of Maha Lakshmi, we have
to understand what does it do, what it’s
help is that this Maha Lakshmi channel or
the Maha Lakshmi’s powers have created within
us a proper balance, a proper route for Kundalini
to rise.
Left and right has been balanced and She is
the one who creates and makes a wider path
for Kundalini to rise. This is the path of
compassion and love.
Through that compassion and love She creates
this path because She knows that if the path
is not wide enough the Kundalini cannot rise.
Ultimately, one reaches a state where you
start seeking and when you start seeking,
your Maha Lakshmi principle has been awakened.
That is awakened and sometimes it is very
strong. Then you start seeking in a mad way.
I am sorry to say that many are already lost
in seeking, but there are so many who have
now come to the right path and to the right
ascent.
Another thing this Maha Lakshmi principle
does is to allow the Kundalini’s power to
go to different chakras also. To make a way
to different chakras and corrects all the
chakras. She is a very flexible force, I should
say, which guides the Kundalini into different
chakras and She understands which chakra needs
the help of the Kundalini. So you must have
seen that when the Kundalini rises how She
pulsates, where She goes, where She shows
the need is of your awakening.
All this works out because She is full of
compassion and love that you should get your
absolute truth.
We have many problems as it is, you know,
in Sahaja Yoga because when people are ascending
they carry on with them some of their past
stones and they cannot climb. They try then
they fall, they try then they fall, then they
go up again, they fall. But today I’m going
to tell you about what is the state one has
to achieve. As Shri Krishna has said it in
the “Gita,” describes Sitha Pragya, the
second chapter, but it’s very difficult
to understand Him, He is not so clear cut
as your Mother is.
So people don’t understand what He is saying.
And they ask the question, “How, how do
you reach that state of Sitha Pragya? How
do you get to that stage?” But Ganeshwara,
when he wrote his “Ganeshwari,” he called
it as the Sahaja Stithi, means the state of
Sahaj. He didn’t call Sitha Pragya. He called
it as Sahaja Stithi, meaning the state of
Sahaj. So he describes the Sahaj in a very
beautiful manner and very subtle. Of course,
Ganeshwara also, very few people understand,
I think.
A person who reaches that state is like a
mirror and so many faces pass over that mirror,
so many look into that mirror, so many decorate
in front of the mirror, but mirror is the
same as it is. So the person who is a Sitha
Pragya or the person who is Sahaja is not
bothered about what is facing him, who is
facing whom, where he is. He stays within
himself. He contains within himself. Like
the sun. If the sun plays with his different
rays, he is not lost. All the rays again return
to him. In the same way, all the senses that
we have, all the senses that are there do
play around, but for a person who is in a
Sahaja state it doesn’t matter, it makes
no difference. He’s not involved. He just
plays around. Again, all of them come back
to him. This is a state you all have to achieve.
Then you are really Sahaja Yogis. But I still
find people lost, getting money out of Sahaja
Yoga, some people lost getting out of leaderships,
some are lost in getting jealousies and envies
and all that.
So that means a lot of work has to be done,
still, within. There is no need to work as
such if you leave everything. That’s why
I always say meditate, because when you meditate,
what happens, that all these things that are
pulling you down are finished.
Gradually they disappear because you become
yourself. You get contained by yourself and
you are never bored. I am never bored. I don’t
know what boring word means, you see. When
it is with you or alone, I never get bored.
What is there to get bored? If you are not
involved into anything you never get bored.
Another thing is you rise above all these
things, like greed. Now people who are greedy
are still involved making money here, making
money there, all that thing. Those people
who are still full of lust are still making,
organizing, some things like that. But in
a Sahaj Stithi you just watch. You are just
a witness. You are not lost into anything
that is pulling you down.
This state is not difficult to achieve for
you, at all, because you have crossed over
your mind. Now all these things come to you
through your mind. I’ve already said that
mind is a myth, which you must accept. Myth
is that this mind gives you ideas. Some people
think, “Yes Mother, but – yes Mother,
but – .” This “but” is coming from
your brain, from your mind. The brain is reality,
but not the mind. The mind says “but”
and then you start feeling very depressed
sometimes, unhappy, because some people feel
even bad because they are very good people,
that there are so few Sahaja Yogis.
Doesn’t matter. Just watch and this watching
state, this witness state is the Sahaja Stithi.
In that you become so subtle, you become yourself,
meaning so subtle that nothing can disturb
you, nothing can change you.
Now see the nature as it is. You know there
are ninety-two elements and ninety-two elements,
none of them can be, say for example, you
cannot make silver into gold. Gold into silver.
The atoms are so arranged that they have certain
valencies and apart from atom, even molecules
are so arranged that they have their own structure.
You cannot change. If you try to change then
you will create bombs, atomic bomb, this bomb.
It’s absolutely destructive. It’s only
human beings who can change, who can transform.
Now look at the blessings that you are a human
being and you can be transformed and you can
be made into a new element that is the Self.
This is the specialty of human beings. But
if somebody there is a false guru or somebody,
he tries to do something, you’ll explode.
I have seen people who have been to false
gurus, they still faint, they still have problems,
they still get troubled more than people who
have been without them. They are also all
right now, most of them are improved but this
is one thing one should understand, that in
one way when you are analyzing and when you
are breaking an atom or you are breaking a
molecule and trying to transform, it explodes.
It doesn’t work out.
The other way round is that when you try to
synthesize, then you can form anything in
the nature. Like, this has now been brought
out by synthesizing, this plastic is created
by synthesizing.
Matter can be synthesized and can be brought
together and human beings have to get synthesized
also. They can be synthesized better than
matter because they change, they transform.
Now say example, there is gold. You make gold
into ornaments, make into anything. It remains
all the time, all the time gold. Gold is gold.
It is there. It is not that by changing them
into ornaments it changes. Its element is
there. Gold is there. But for human beings
they get transformed. When they are synthesized.
This is a very big difference between the
matter and the nature and human beings. Matter,
nature, are different absolutely from human
beings. Human beings, once they are transformed,
it’s like a living process. They become
like flowers but still it is not that you
see in the nature. It’s not the same as
you see in the nature because nature doesn’t
have a mind. It doesn’t have a mind. It
just is under the control of the Divine or
nature that it’s working out that way. But
here you are under your own control. Here
you can control yourself. In this synthesis
which is growing inside you what you find,
that you are completely in control of yourself.
You know what is happening to you.
Now you start seeing yourself separating from
all these things. Some people come and tell
Me, “Mother, see, my ego is very bad, you
just take it out.” He sees his ego, he sees
what is the problem is. Somebody says, “Mother,
my nabhi is very bad, I’m still busy with
the money.” He sees it. First starts the
knowledge about yourself, we call as self-knowledge.
But one has to even go beyond self-knowledge.
By that knowledge, what do you do, we have
to see?
When you have the knowledge, first we say
there’s no knowledge, people have no knowledge,
they are ignorant, there’s darkness, all
that. Now the light has come, you can see.
You can know what’s wrong within you. Now
you start separating yourself from all those
things that you see as wrong with you. You
see them getting out.
So many nonsensical things there are. Like,
we have jealousies, envy, greed and lust.
I mean, it’s horrible things to say on a
Diwali function, see. So the Diwali is that
one by one so many lights are enlightened
and you start seeing it first. First you start
seeing what is wrong with you and then, as
you see it, you don’t want it. Then you
work out to get rid of it, to become clean.
Now this also knowledge disappears. You don’t
have to have any knowledge. You are there.
You are there. There is no need to know about
your chakras, you are just there. At that
stage nothing matters. You become just like
a stone, I can say. Stone with a brain intact
and a heart intact and a liver intact.
You just don’t mind anything, don’t get
upset with anything. You just enjoy the love
and compassion that’s flowing. And the ripples
that come back to you, even that is lost after
some time and you are just nothing but Sahaj.
That is the state people achieved. In those
days they achieved this state.
But with that, what lacking happened, that
they’d get lost. They all got lost. They
couldn’t do anything to others. One person
getting it, becoming great, finished. Or two
persons at the most.
So now Sahaja Yoga stands first of all at
the knowledge state, where you have the knowledge.
First, you should first of all have full knowledge
about yourself. The self-knowledge should
be complete. Then in the third stage we should
say that when the knowledge is full you should
get rid of all those things that you know
about yourself, which are useless, which are
hampering your progress, which you know is
wrong.
Like, I see some dirt falling on my sari,
I’ll just clean it out like that. Then you
start separating yourself into that Sahaja
state. But still in Sahaja Yoga you develop
another dimension which is collective consciousness.
That is the modern Sahaja Yoga. In the olden
days they didn’t have this, so they just
all got lost. Now you have collective consciousness
and in that collective consciousness you start
feeling others, feeling for others, compassion
for others and you start working out for others.
In that also, sometimes, you know, when you
are working around, you think how much money
I can make, what I can achieve as a leader
or some sort of thing is still there.
But this collective consciousness starts growing.
When it starts growing then you become as
I said, drop in the ocean, means complete
ocean. You become complete ocean.
So the ocean has its own mariadas. It doesn’t
bother. It has to live with its mariadas,
it lives with its mariadas. It doesn’t want
to cross any boundaries, all right. Accept
it. It will not cross its boundaries.
In the same way it happens that you are very
self-contained. You are not selfish, but you
become very self-contained. You are contained
within yourself. I know many Sahaja Yogis
are angry that I have not punished many horrible
people who have been troubling Sahaja Yoga.
I don’t have to bother. There’s Paramchaitanya
which is doing a lot of work. Let it look
after it. Why should I bother about anyone?
You see, after all, things are working out
so why to interfere? My job is just to watch,
just to see. That’s sufficient. There’s
no need for Me to kill anybody in this lifetime
or to destroy. They are destroyed by themselves.
I have told you that I need not expose people,
but whichever country I go, I find people
get exposed.
I run away from there, really, sometimes,
thinking, God knows what more is going to
come. Even little attention on any country,
it just works out. Even without My knowledge,
“Oh My God,” I said, “When did I do
that?”
So one has to become – of course, he becomes
the power of Divine love, no doubt. He becomes
the power of Divine love, but he doesn’t
handle it. Left to this Divine power which
is working, which is also separated from Me,
you’ll be surprised. I am alone. Absolutely
alone. Even this power is separated from Me,
but this power knows what is good for human
beings, what is good for Sahaja Yoga. It works
on it’s own. I don’t interfere. It’s
a reflex action, believe Me, it’s a reflex
action. Maybe you might say, “Mother, you
have made it.” All right, whatever it is,
but I don’t interfere with it. I don’t
have to tell anything to it. It just works
and it’s working so well.
I’ll give you an example. Once in England
long time back, they said, “Mother, we want
to have a very long summer.” I said, “Why
do you want to ask such things?” “No,
no, Mother, we must have a long summer, a
very long summer, very – ” Three or four
times they said it and it was a very long,
horrible summer in London. And it’s not
like India where we have air conditioning,
fans, something we have, at least hand fans.
There was nothing there. So we didn’t know.
We had a little gallery, we used to sleep
in that. So we went to the shop in England
and we asked in London City, for a fan. So
they said, “All right, after three months.
You order us.” After three months when it
will be very cold they will give us the fan.
We said, “We don’t want any fans.” So
My daughter sent two fans by plane. And that’s
how we managed. You see, Indians, we feel
very hot because we have had a lot of sun
in our country, we feel much hotter than any
one of you. The way you sit in the sun, you
know, we can’t understand. You know, in
India they used to say an Englishman and a
mad dog can only go in the sun. So our situation
is like that, that we cannot go in the sun
because we have had too much.
And this summer, you see, was so tremendous,
so tremendous that after that one thing good
happened. That ochre color appeared on the
leaves and then gradually the red and all
that of the autumn season was best at that
time and then one Sahaja Yogi dreamt that,
“Mother asked me to drive in Her back yard.”
So he told everybody that, “Mother has been
asking me to drive in the back yard.” So
I telephoned to him, I didn’t know he had
dreamt like that, that, “Can you come along
for a while, I want to go and see this autumn
all over England.” So he came and we were
driving, miles together and then they told
Me, “Mother, it was so, he told us that
that was My back yard.” Can you imagine
that he was driving for miles together, beautiful,
just like Canada, the whole England was filled
with the beauty of autumn.
So even if there’s something like that happens,
it is compensated. It is compensated and so
beautiful it was, all the people were out
in the autumn to see the beautiful colors
of the nature, of different greenery, yellow,
ochre, all kinds of colors were there. Surprisingly,
in that country you never see all that. And
because of the sun shining so bright, it was
compensated. It was compensated by this Paramchaitanya.
So the Paramchaitanya is looking after this.
All these things are managed by Paramchaitanya.
I am doing nothing. I am Nishkriya. I’m
just sitting down and watching. To Me nothing
matters. You see, it’s working out slowly
and steadily. Ha, if you tell Me something
supposing, they said, “Mother, we prayed
to You and it happened.” All right, maybe,
these people must have heard, around Me, Not
me, you see, and they must have done the job
and for that I’m not responsible, in no
way.
Like one lady in Mexico had a son, was very
sick and was about to die. She wrote a letter
to Me, three letters she wrote that, “My
son is going to die, he’s a young fellow,
studying in Harvard.” I didn’t do anything.
I never wrote to her. Fourth letter came that
he’s completely cured. Now I didn’t do
that because I was just sitting in one place
and how is it, it has worked out.
So everything, you see, you think I do is
not done by Me. Is done by this Paramchaitanya.
Because I’m also separated from you, completely,
absolutely separated. So they say, “You
pray, now.” You can pray. If you pray, you
pray to these deities that are around, you
pray to all these ganas and all that, not
to Me. Because I have nothing to do with it.
You see, they don’t tell Me that I have
to do this or I have to do that, so why should
I tell them do this or do that? It is like
that.
And in that state only we can say you are
in a Sahaja state, where you don’t desire
anything, you don’t want anything. I do
everything. All kinds of things, I am doing.
Like the sun is doing, I am also doing in
the sense that I’m looking after things,
flowers, this that. I am also receiving presents
from you, I’m receiving this from you and
then see, I don’t receive anything. I don’t
have anything. I have no interest in it. But
you want to give for your joy, all right,
have it. You want to put flowers, all right,
you can have flowers. Even if there’s flowers
or not makes no difference to Me as a person,
I’m saying. But as Your Mother I love you.
All of you I love. But I don’t do anything
as such to love you. And everybody says, “Mother,
You love us so much.” When? When did I love
you. I never even kissed you. But you always
say I love you very much. So what is this.
Who is working it out, this? Is something
which is not Me, beyond Me. This is the state
in which, once we rise, we call it as Sahaja
Stithi. In the Sahaja Stithi you think you
are doing nothing. Everything is working out.
But at this stage if I tell you, you say,
“Oh, we are not doing anything. Why should
we spread Sahaja Yoga, it’s not our job?”
Just now, that’s not your stithi, that’s
why.
So you have to rise up to that state. That’s
only possible when you are in the knowledge
state, where you have self-knowledge, the
knowledge of the whole world. But if you go
beyond knowledge then you must have seen many
a times, I just say something. I just say
something and it is there. I never feel vibrations
of anyone or anything. I don’t feel My Kundalini,
either nor any chakras, nothing, but I know,
know automatically like a computer. But that
computer also I am not. Just it’s trouble,
it’s difficult to explain to you what is
this stithi is because you have to achieve
it. Once you achieve it then you are in a
very subtle state and that subtle state is
nothing but bliss. But that bliss also you
cannot enjoy. I don’t know how to enjoy
everything. Supposing now you say, “Jai
Mataji.” I forget even you are calling Me.
I also say, “Jai Mataji,” finished.
See it is such a simple thing one has to understand
that the state in which one has to rise is
a state where without doing anything, everything
works out. If that is your state, all right.
But it’s not so. So you have to rise up
to that state by doing. First you have to
do it. First you have to know and then knowledge
has no need, you don’t have to know, but
first that has to be worked out and brought
to that level.
Now Diwali has the significance that on Diwali
day, what we do, we put lights all over. So
that we put Sahaja Yoga everywhere. But does
the light know about itself? Does the candle
knows about itself? She enlightens everything
but she doesn’t know. Like the moon, which
is giving moonlight, does it know itself?
Does he enjoy? Nothing. In the same way it
happens that on a Diwali day you are, what
you are doing is enlightening people, you
are enlightening them, you are doing all this
for them, it’s a good idea. You must do
it. But also know that you have to become
the lamp yourself which doesn’t know yourself.
So there are two messages. The first one is
that we have to enlighten the world, we have
to enlighten others. This is the first one.
Then we have to become that which is the light
itself and light itself doesn’t know. Yesterday
you were singing, “You are the light,”
you are this thing. All right, so what? I
was just saying, ‘Yes, I am the light, I
don’t know Myself.” That’s the state
where you don’t know you are the light.
You just don’t know that. It doesn’t come
into your head. Even so many times you have
sung, you have said thousand names there are,
everything, but it doesn’t come into My
head that this is Me you are talking about.
Now when I say this I don’t know how you
will react. Because human beings are queer
birds, you see. You tell them something. Maybe
that your ego might come up and you say, “Yes,
yes, I am also just the same.” There are
many, many who came like that, that, “I
am higher than Mataji.” Ba, ba maybe, I
don’t know. There are many who said that,
“I am Kalki.” Nowadays there’s one fellow
going round saying, “I am Kalki, I am this,
I am that.” All right doesn’t matter.
You be that, very good idea.
But if I say I am Adi Shakti that means I
don’t know what I am, really. I had to say
because people said, “Mother, you have to
declare.” Declare what? Whatever I am, that
I am.
Now I find by declaration you people started
growing more, so all right, have it that way.
But there is no need for anyone to declare
anything or to say anything. That is the state
one has to achieve.
But to get to that state you have to work.
And work is to spread Sahaja Yoga. You have
to enlighten many lights. That means you will
realize that you are the light which is enlightening
all that, and then in a subtle way you will
realize that, “I am the light.” Many Sahaja
Yogis are doing a lot of work and working
it out, spreading Sahaja Yoga. It’s a very
great thing that has happened. In so many
countries, the way it has spread, it has removed
the darkness of religion which was outside.
It was darkness of so many – racialism,
thisism, thatism, all it has removed. So this
has worked out, the cleansing. For you to
have the clean water to swim.
Once you start doing that then you realize
gradually that now the sea is clean, we just
watch, we just see how it is working. I hope
in your lifetime only, you achieve this state
where you achieve your complete work of self-realization
to others.
Those who do not give self-realization to
others, who just come for the pujas, this
thing, are mediocres. They cannot rise very
high. This coming to puja is what, like, you
just rise higher with the puja then again
you go down.
But those who steadily grow will grow into
this state, I am sure, in My lifetime I should
be able to see such people who are such that
if they stand here they emit peace, they emit
light, they emit everything. Because they
are the light. They don’t have to enlighten,
but they are the light. Such a stage has to
be developed and to be worked out within yourself.
And this state has been described by so many
poets, so many saints and everything, but
they were at that stage and people thought,
what is this they are talking? They thought
they were mad. Even for Christ, they thought
He is to be crucified, because they couldn’t
understand it.
Now you are gradually growing one by one,
step by step, so now you understand this.
You understand Christ, you understand all
these people and at this stage you have still
to work. Those who do not work for Sahaja
Yoga cannot rise higher. You have to work
for Sahaja Yoga, you have to spread it more,
you have to work it out, enjoy each other,
this brotherhood, everything. All the qualities
of a beautiful personality should be there.
Unless and until you achieve that state, then
you can only rise higher to that stage which
I am describing is a Sahaja Stithi. In that
state you will be perfect.
But you must get rid of all these things and
today is a day, also of Maha Lakshmi. The
first thing is, I think, this madness about
money. This should be understood that it’s
real madness. Those who are rich have no money.
You ask a rich man, he’ll say, “Oh, I
have no money.” Why? What is all this? “This
is no money”.
You ask the poor man, he has no money. A rich
man has no money. So it’s a kind of a greed
which is never satisfied, which never helps
you. All these little, little things have
to first drop out. Then your work should cleanse
you. In your work you will know whether you
are cleansing or not.
In the work you will know how you are doing
your work. Once that is done, then I think
I am sure some of you will achieve that state
in My lifetime, in your lifetime.
That’s what I want today to tell you, on
a Diwali day, that we have to become subtler
and subtler and subtler.
We should not be influenced by outside things.
Like, the outside thing is that, some sort
of a fashion starts. People who follow fashions
are stupid. They are like blind mices. Anybody
can lead them into anything, now do this,
they do it. That, they do it.
So if you try to follow any kind of a thought
which is given to us by somebody else, in
that thought you’ll completely lose yourself
and you’ll become, “I am this, I am Christian,
I am Hindu, I am Muslim, I am Muss leman.”
Stupidity. You are yourself. You are the Spirit.
And when you become the Spirit then you start
knowing so much and that knowledge is very
important.
This is the gap between a saint and a normal
human being, which you have crossed gradually
so you know what are the problems of the human
beings are and dealing with human beings,
you know how to deal with them.
In Sahaja Yoga only the collective consciousness,
in modern times, has come. This collective
consciousness, also the saints had, but they
would not say. They would not say anything.
They would not bother.
All right, this fellow has this chakra, let
him go to hell. Doesn’t care. It’s not
a question of not caring, but not bothered.
They were sitting in a state which was just
recording, all right. An ugly man goes before
the mirror, all right, if a beautiful person
goes before the mirror is all right.
In the same way these people start allowing
people to pass through but we have to understand,
still we have to grow. We have to still grow
by working it out. Those people who are working
it out and spreading it all over are the ones
which are really very much there and to them,
I must say, the Paramchaitanya is just their
servant.
I have seen people who desire something, it
works out. They ask for something, it works
out. For that, now, what should we have, is
the point.
After getting realization, after getting everything,
what should we have that we develop is the
faith. Faith in yourself. Faith in that you
are the Spirit, that you have the light and
you have to enlighten others. This faith when
it grows deeper and deeper then you think,
oh, what I am. I am the Spirit. If you are
the Spirit then this whole nature is with
you. I know of some Sahaja Yogis. One of them
was a fisherman. He was doing Sahaja Yoga
work. He has tremendous faith in Me and somehow
he was going to another village to do Sahaja
Yoga work. When he came out of his little
hut he found it’s all full of clouds, black
clouds. So he raised his hand and said, “See
now, I’m going for Mother’s work. And
you dare not start raining. You keep as you
are, hanging there till I finish my work,”
you see. Because he was going by boat. And
other Sahaja Yogis thought, “What is he
talking about?” They all got into the boat,
they reached the other village. They gave
realization to others, he finished his lecturing,
everything, he came back on the shore and
he entered his house. When he was closing
the door, “All right, so go ahead,” he
said. And he managed.
So the complete faith that this Paramchaitanya
is like your servant, is all the time waiting
there to serve you. Whatever you say will
happen. But first you must have complete faith
in yourself that you are a Sahaja Yogi.
Even now I find, you see, people have some
lust, some sort of a horrible things in them.
So first you must be established in Dharma.
Dharma, is, as you know, is righteousness.
If you are in the righteousness, there’s
no question. There’s no question that this
Paramchaitanya won’t obey you. But supposing
you want today something and it doesn’t
work out, then even to get disappointed itself
is not a very good thing. Disappointment also
is a sign of your immaturity. What is there
to be disappointed? Maybe that that was good
for you.
Supposing I lose My way. I’m going this
way and I lose My way, I don’t know where
to go. So I get lost, it’s all right. What
is there? Wherever I am, I am there. How can
I be lost to Myself. And then what I find,
that I had to go that way because I was to
meet somebody, I’ve been wanting to meet
somebody and meet that person there. Can you
imagine? Such things happen with Me, and even
if I don’t meet, so what? I was to go that
side. I have to leave some vibrations, perhaps.
It’s like that.
So once you know that whatever you are doing
in command, full command, full faith, actually
the whole authority comes to you through your
faith which word is satta in Sanskrit, meaning
the truth.
The truth gives you the authority. If you
have the truth with you, you have the absolute
truth with you then you have the authority
and the authority is such that that authorizes
you, not others, but to you. This authority
that you have works and works. I’ve seen
with simple Sahaja Yogis, very simple uneducated
also, are very powerful Sahaja Yogis, are
very powerful Sahaja Yogis. But they have
one thing, is faith, complete faith.
Then another word in Sanskrit is titiksha,
means patience, suboori – patience. You
must have patience. If you don’t have patience,
you want immediately something to be done.
How will you see the whole thing working out?
Many people are extremely jittery and very
fast-running. This world is running so fast
and you are the ones who have stood out and
watching this rat race. You are not one of
them. So must have titiksha, means you must
have patience. So you must have faith in yourself
fully and also patience, how Sahaja Yoga is
working out or how this Paramchaitanya is
working out.
If it works this way, all right, that way,
all right. It is some meaning. If it works
this way, there’s some meaning. If it is
that way it has some meaning.
Now another thing which is important is the
faith in your guru. If you have faith in your
guru, Paramchaitanya is kind to you. It’s
very helpful. But if you doubt, then Paramchaitanya
also doubts you because Paramchaitanya knows
you through your guru, whether it is Me or
any other real guru, it’s the same. But
with Me, of course, because, you know, I’m
very forgiving so people start taking liberties.
With another guru, you see, he will beat them.
He’ll do all kinds of horrible things to
you if you are not there. So I’ve told you
many stories about the gurus, how they treat
– good gurus – their disciples.
But I forgive. I don’t say anything. Let
it be, it doesn’t matter. Because I think
by leaving them alone only, they will rise
and they will come up to this stage. But it
happens sometimes that it may work the other
way round, that if they are forgiven, then
they take it for granted. So the faith in
yourself is with patience you watch and do
not get disappointed with anything whatsoever.
Now, just imagine so many people have got
realization, so many saints in this world,
have you seen? Yesterday I was surprised the
way the French were singing so well. You know,
first time I had to take a harmonium to teach
them how to sing one line. Half an hour I
tried, I couldn’t do. The same French have
reached that state of creativity.
You see, all your potential will rise. It
will express itself, but be careful not to
get into ego about it. Gradually it will flower
and others who are surrounding you will get
the fragrance of it and they’ll come to
Sahaja Yoga. That is the blessing at that
time, the blessing of the real Divine will
be that you’ll be raised to the state which
we call as a perfect, ‘purnattwa’, complete.
That completeness will come. But you judge
yourself. Are you absolutely one with Sahaj?
Are you absolutely dedicated to Sahaj?
Or other things are more important to you
than Sahaja Yoga? Then, go ahead.
There is something to be understood very clearly
that there’s no competition in Sahaja Yoga.
Cannot be. There’s no competition. There’s
no envy, there is no back biting, nothing.
It is, you are different people. You are saints.
Your style is different. You are absolutely
above all these things. You cannot be dishonest,
you cannot cheat people, you cannot do this.
And if you are doing that, even now, then
please try to understand that you have still
to grow into it. Some big people think they
are very high up in Sahaja Yoga. It’s not
so, it’s not so. If by thinking what you
are, then you are lost. What you have to do
is to understand “What have I done? How
many people have I given realization, to how
many people have talked about it?” People
are shy, even, to talk about Sahaja Yoga.
I have seen one lady was traveling with Me.
Very hot. I said, “Ba, ba who is she, this
one? I don’t know.” So she told Me the
name of her guru. She said, “My guru is
like this, guru like that, like that.” I
said, “My God, this heat coming out of this
woman and she’s talking so much.” But
a Sahaja Yogi will not tell anybody what is
Sahaja Yoga. They feel shy. They’ll have
a hundred friends, they’ll meet a hundred
friends but they will never tell them what
Sahaja Yoga is. They’ll be shy to tell them.
Ah, they wouldn’t mind going to parties,
you see, if the others are drinking they’ll
say, “All right, I don’t drink.” But
they’ll not say, “I’m a Sahaja Yogi,
I cannot drink, by nature I cannot drink.”
They will not say that.
So this is the third point, one has to know
the announcement. You must have faith in yourself
and you must announce. All the saints announced.
They were killed for that, you saw how Socrates
was given poison. Doesn’t matter. Nobody’s
going to kill you now, in these modern times,
there’s fundamental rights to exist. So
nobody can kill you, take it from Me, but
you must announce. And the announcement should
be with full faith and understanding about
Sahaja Yoga, how important it is.
The purpose is to transform the whole world.
With your transformation the whole world transforms.
It’s a very complicated thing, otherwise,
Sahaja Yoga is extremely complicated because
how it works.
The other day, you remember, the mike had
failed completely and I was giving the lecture
and still I was talking. The mike had failed
but everybody was listening to Me. What had
happened? Did I enter into the ether? What
happened? I don’t know. I didn’t even
know that mike had failed. I was thinking
there is mike, that the way people were listening
to Me, but then they told that half lecture
was without the mike. And everybody was absolutely
listening to Me.
You see, it is something that one has to wonder
and appreciate what things are happening now,
where are we going. We are going into the
Kingdom of God and all the blessings, all
the bliss will be on you.
Then this bliss, knowledge, everything becomes
one, nothing but bliss and you are in that
state of bliss which you don’t even know,
you are just there. The greatest bliss is
that you don’t know even anything, you’re
just there.
I hope all of you achieve that state with
this Diwali being done in Portugal, which
is a special place, I think, of Maha Lakshmi
because She appeared here as they say and
also this swayambu that we have, also is that
of Maha Lakshmi face, so I’m sure it will
work out for all of you.
It’s a little subtle state I’m talking
about but it is, I have to tell you, that
one has to rise up to that state and that
state is very, very easy to achieve for you.
It slowly, gradually it – then you don’t
have to do anything, you go into a village
and everything would be there.
See, now, what happened. I went to Cairo.
Everybody was saluting Me. I was wondering,
what has happened to them? I went to Leningrad,
thousands came to My program. I asked them,
“How did you come to My program?” They
said, “It’s obvious from Your face, it’s
obvious.” They just saw a small, little
advertisement in the newspaper, “It’s
obvious that You are Divine.” That should
happen. And then you can announce that Sahaja
Yoga is the only way, then you can announce.
There’s no harm. People feel very shy to
say something to their friends and things.
And you must know that all of those who you
love, who you know, will go to hell or where
– they’ll hang in the limbo or what? If
you have achieved it you should pull them
out also. They may not. They may not be seekers,
doesn’t matter now. I think we are finished
with the seekers now, must be – we must
have people who are not so seeking, it looks
like that.
So may God bless you all.