Today, we have decided to
worship the Yogeshwara. I think that is the
greatest name of Shri Krishna for us. That
means He is the Ishwara of yoga. Yoga means
the union ,as you know, with the divine. But
also yoga has another meaning which means
yukti. In English language to translate it
properly is not possible. Yukti means the
trick. but trick is always connected with
something funny and bad. But this 'yukti'
means the technique. But 'technique' is mechanical.
So I couldn't find any proper word for 'yukti'.
But one can say that: to know the technique
and the trick of the technique is also another
meaning of yoga - yukti.
So, even if you are connected, if you do not
know the trick of the union then it is useless,
it is of no avail. So what one has to learn,
after getting realization, is not only the
technique but the trick of the technique.
At Krishna's level when we reach - it is an
incarnation after Shri Rama's. So Shri Rama
came as a 'Maryada Purushottama', which means
a person who is a complete ideal of maryadas
and a benevolent king.
But in the case of Shri Krishna it was a different
phase because people had become extremely
serious, very disciplined, and were leading
a life which was, we can say, over-dharmic.
And this had put the people at a level, fixed,
and they thought that "If we are doing all
these things every day then it's alright.
We have reached the last." So Shri Krishna
had to come - Himself, Shri Vishnu, came as
Shri Krishna - to tell us about the ascent,
and that - all this is just a play. But only
a person who is a master of the play can do
the play.
So to know the play. Supposing you have communication,
you have electrical communications. Now you
don't know how to play with it - play. Not
how to know or how to connect but to play.
Supposing only you know all the technique,
then it becomes quite a headache, because
all the time you think you are doing it. You
have to do this and, this is to be done, that
has to be done, and this connection is not
all right; that should be properly connected.
You get tired and bored. But if it's a play
for you, just a play. For any master it's
a play.
If it's just a play for you, then you don't
feel tired - it's fun, it's fun. And that
is what is Leela, that's why He is called
'Leeladhara' - because He is a master. He
came as a master, master not as a guru, but
master of all the arts of this yoga, yukti.
So He is so deft, He's so capable, that for
Him it's a play. All this is a play for Him.
And this is what one has to know, that, in
yoga, everything that you do should be just
a play. Say, getting up at 5 o'clock in the
morning, should be a play.
In the morning you get up. The sun has not
yet come, to suggest what you have to do,
and the moon has departed, and in that twilight
or a little darkness if you get up, it's very
beautiful. And at that time you sit down for
your dhyaan. But it's not a serious thing,
it's not something that is boring, it's a
play. But for that you have to be a master.
If you are the master of yoga, then it's a
play. So first Shri Rama's state has to be
there where you become really a Vishwa Nirmala
Dharmi - so that it becomes your play.
Now communication with the Divine has to go
to the whole world. The whole world has to
get this communication that you have received.
For this part Shri Krishna arranged something
in His lifetime in a very simple way, as a
child. It looks, very childlike. Like when
the Gopi's were taking their baths He hid
their clothes - I mean, Indian women are never
fully nude, never - He hid their saris and
all that and He could see their back, this
little boy. What is for a little boy? He's
sitting on a tree and is trying to raise their
Kundalini. They're coming out of the river
Jamuna which is being vibrated by Radha. Already
there are vibrations, you see - raising their
Kundalini.
Then they are taking the water and He breaks
their pitchers, from the back, which have
also got vibrated water in. So the vibrated
water falls on the backs of these ladies and
He tries to awaken their Kundalini. See the
play of a child, how He tried to play in His
childhood, just like a child. And then He
shows, later on, His child-like expertise
in dealing with politics, dealing with people,
with communication and everything. And His
power was Radha, Radha 'Ra' 'dha' . 'Ra' means
energy, 'Dha' means the one which sustains
- 'Ra-dha'. So the "Dha Re Di Dha Sa Ma" (???) as
they say. In the same way Radha 'Ra' 'Dha'
- the one who sustains the energy.
So the first quality that He got from Her
is - She's the 'Alaahda Dayini'. I couldn't
find a word in English for 'Alaahd'. 'Alaahd'
is when you suddenly see something nice and
joy starts. Just feel very happy. I mean,
there are very few words in English, as you
know, for joy or at the most happiness. But
'Alaahd' is a kind of a joy which, as you
get the fresh air - then how you feel. That
is Alaahd. So She is 'Alaahda Dayini'. She's
the one who is the giver of Alaahd.
And so with Her powers, He could work out
this Alaahd to all the people with whom He
was connected. So all the Gopas and Gopis
who were with Him had to do Rasa. 'Ra' is
'energy', 'Sa' means 'with'. To dance with
the energy that is Radhaji. He used to just
play the flute and She used to dance, the
energy used to pass through Her hands to all
the other people and the Kundalini would be
awakened. So this was another play that He
had. So in the play only He raised the Kundalini.
But in modern times it's very difficult, it
is not easy to raise Kundalinis in modern
times in that way. I mean, nobody will understand
also.
So in modern times when Sahaja Yoga is not
just raising the Kundalini but giving the
complete knowledge about Sahaja Yoga and also
empowering the person with the power to give
others realization, it was tremendous task.
And that's why we had to find out these methods
by which we could give realization to people.
In those days Kundalinis were awakened but
the Sahasrara was not broken. So Kundalini
must be somewhere hanging in the agnya, maybe
at heart, maybe somewhere. And such people
became the seekers and that's how we find,
today, people are here as Sahaja Yogis whose
Sahasrara's are open and they know all the
yukti of Sahaja Yoga.
But there are subtler and subtler yuktis of
Sahaja Yoga which you have to master. The
first is that His character was 'madhuriya',
meaning the sweetness. Sweetness. We always
say, "He's sweet like honey". So when He talked
to anyone or He communicated with anyone,
it was through sweetness; and this communication,
if you have not developed, then you are nowhere
near Yoga. To talk to someone sweetly, automatically.
Everything is madhuriya for Him, His talking,
His actions, His face. Everything is madhuriya.
So when we talk of communications first of
all the greatest thing is the communication
between human beings and when we have to think
of the communication with the human beings
many people think that by aggression you will
communicate better, which is not true. I mean
if somebody wants to get something out of
someone, say; so you go there and just talk,
"I have to have! How can you do it? This,
that!" As it is - it's no good. But if you
are sweet and start talking sweetly then 99%
will definitely dissolve. So to dissolve people
with sweetness - how to do it - that trick
one has to learn: how, with sweetness, you
can dissolve people. This is one of His special
qualities, that you talk to someone in such
a manner, genuinely, in a very sweet manner,
and the problem between you and that person
will be dissolved, absolutely.
Now there are many tricks and how to talk
to someone is one of the biggest things one
has to learn. First of all you must always
show that you are less intelligent than another
person. Like if I'm talking to a scientist
I will say, "I'm sorry I don't know any science
you know. I'm no good for a scientist." So
they feel "ahhhh, very good." If you have
to talk to some musician, you must say "I
don't know any music. No, I just have learned
a little bit, but not much." Musician feels
very happy. You may call it a pampering of
the ego. You may call it [that]. But there's
no harm in saying that "I'm nothing to compared
to you".
So the first trick is complete humility when
you talk to another person. It's the sign
of greatness, it's the sign of fulfilment.
As the trees, when they are laden with fruits
they bend down. So, first of all, if you say
"I am no one. I don't understand anything
but I would like to hear" this is first. The
first quality of communication is to be extremely
humble about yourself. The other person should
not know who you are. And there's a lot of
fun in it. Say for example now - I can say
about Myself that My husband was very highly
placed in India. But I met a friend in Delhi
- she was studying with Me in school and in
college - and She asked Me "where do you live?"
So, I told her, "In Meenabagh," which was
just a useless, small, little place meant
for very ordinary officers because they had
not allotted us any house or anything so,
temporarily, we were there. She said "what?
What is your husband doing?" I said "He's
some governments servant." I didn't tell her
[his position]! He came down, so he just looked
at Me and he smiled. She said "do you know
him?" I said "He's My husband". She was shocked,
"He's your husband? Oh my God! Why didn't
you tell me?" Immediately the whole thing
changed and she felt so ashamed of herself.
She had started looking down upon Me, "Ah,
Married to some clerk or someone."
So the best thing is to play down. Play down
everything. Now I know of certain Sahaja Yogis
they say, "oh Mother has giving me such powers.
I can do this, I can do that." This boastfullness
is of no use. "I haven't got any powers you
see. I'm just a Sahaja Yogi that's all. But
if you want I can try." So play down as much
as you can. Practice this at home, first practice
and then do it. So that is one of the greatest
qualities of communication with others.
Second thing: I think in the whole of Gita,
if you read it, there's one is very important
thing. He says " "krodho'bhijaayate sammohah"
[ The actual Gita quote is - "kaamaat krodho'bhijaayate,
Krodhaad bhavati sammohah" - from desire comes
anger, from anger comes delusion (Gita 2:61)].
You see among all the worst things that we
have - according to Him we have six enemies.
But in Gita He started with 'Krodha'. He said
- it starts with Krodha, means anger.
If you have anger within you then you are
not a master at all. There's no need for a
master to get angry because he can play about.
He can make you dance like this. What is the
need to lose your temper? But that mastery
if you don't have, of handling people, then
after five/six minutes of talk your voice
starts raising and something starts barking
- because that temper is still inside you,
burning.
But for a master there should be no temper
- no need. He has started with Krodha, that:
with the Krodha all problems start - from
one to another to another to another.
So we should watch out if we are angry people.
Anger comes from Vishuddhi. Starts from liver
- Vishnu - but is expressed through Vishuddhi.
The face becomes red, eyes become red. From
the mouth you start saying all kinds of horrible
things and the whole expression becomes so
different when you are angry.
So this anger is to be seen, "Where is it
within us? Where is it this anger? Liver?
alright, I'll put it right."
So to master it you have to face yourself
clearly. Many people I have seen people say
"Mother you know this lady is such a hot tempered
women, she is so dominating. She does this,
she does that." But if you tell her she says,
"No no, I don't do that way. No, no I'm very
good." "But how other's saying that?", "I
don't know but I'm very good" - finished!
If somebody is saying that then you watch
yourself - do you get into tempers or not?
Are you loosing your temper? It's very easy
to make it out then face it. So the trick
of the trade is to face yourself and see for
yourself how much you are lacking. So first
is humility, which should be genuine, and
secondly is equanimity - no temper. There
is no need to take to temper. At the most
you can say "What are you doing? Why are you
doing that way?" Now if you do something,
you know, maybe something I might say which
I would not like, so I don't want to say."
Like that - at the most! Up to that point
is alright; that you should say that, "I dislike
it", but not to go further with it.
If you just stop at a point, then this habit
of getting into temper will go away. This
arrogance will go away, which has to go. This
arrogance has to go, this temper has to go.
And then, you'll be surprised, you will feel
very much relieved. Because this anger, once
it comes in, reacts, and catches your left
Vishuddi, and you become guilty, you feel
very bad - "Why I said so, I should not have
said this." So Vishuddi's finished, left Vishuddhi,
means - it's a headache. It goes on accumulating
like a store house there - all your anger,
temper whatever you have - and this left Vishuddhi
catches, and you know the problems of left
Vishuddhi.
So if you get angry with someone, don't feel
guilty but go before the mirror and slap yourself
nicely, twice. Now you get angry with yourself,
"let me get angry!" Then stand before the
mirror, "shoo shoo shoo" [Mother pretends
to punch herself! Everybody laughs], like
that. In the same manner as you get angry
try to act, you'll never feel guilty. Or maybe
more angry - would be better. So you empty
out your left Vishuddhi. Next time you won't
do it. But feeling guilty means you will repeat
and repeat and repeat the same thing.
So this temper is expressed by men and women
differently. And I'm very much worried about
the women sometimes because they take to water
power - then I'm lost. But those who have
ego too much, cry much more. That's the sign,
I've seen. If you say anything to them immediately
they start crying, because already the left
Vishuddhi is there, full, like a full balloon
and when you touch them it becomes water.
But men, their temper is a different style,
as you know very well, that: when they get
angry they might fight with each other, box
everyone and then settle down nicely and have
something to drink. "Let us have it out!"
you see, they'll say. Take out. But women
don't, they keep it there and once they keep
it then it becomes tears, it starts coming
down. So, if these are just tears out of joy,
happiness, that's different, or out of feelings
for others - but it is not that, but it's
tears just to impress another person that
you are very sad or something.
So the second trick is how to master your
own temper and the third one is how to master
the temper of others - that's even better.
I don't know if I have told you the trick
of Gagangan Maharaj, when I went to him. He
is a very hot tempered avadhuta, sitting on
a tiger, and he's lost his legs, because he
was feeling hot so he was sitting in the water
all the time, so his feet are useless and
he goes on a tiger, they say. I never saw
the tiger, of course. But he knows about Me
and all that and he told everyone about Me
so I went to see him. And he's supposed to
control the rain. It was quite a steep climb
for about one and a half hours. And as soon
as I stepped in, it started raining, raining,
raining heavily throughout and he couldn't
stop it, so he felt very challenged! When
I went up he was sitting on his own stone
outside the cave, and he was doing like this
[twisting his head], with anger. He didn't
know what to do. I looked at him then I walked
into his cave and sat down nicely, then he
came, they brought him. He touched my feet,
everything he did and then he said, "You tell
me now - why did you not allow me to stop
the water? You got completely drenched. I'm
very angry with this rain I know. But why
did you do that? Is it to control my ego?"
I said "No, not at all I never knew you had
ego or anything," "Then why?" So - because
I'm a master as you know - I said "You see
you are a sanyasi and you brought a sari for
Me, that too of an orange colour, and I would
not take the orange colour sari from you.
Any sari I wouldn't take, because you're a
sanyasi. But I had to get drenched to get
the sari, isn't it?" Immediately - he melted
away.
But I had to be the master. First of all how
to melt him and secondly the master of his
mind. This is the subtler part of it. You
can be a master of a person. Like that you
can know what he has done for you, what he
has prepared for you, what is coming for you.
I wouldn't say that you'd know all the whole
future. But if you try just to know about
a person - you can know everything about that
person, very simple. So first try to understand
a person.
My father had lots of tricks with him, I know,
and a very humorous person. And one day My
brother told me, Babamama, that he has a friend
who sings very well. So I asked my father
"How does he sing?" "Oh, he is very courageous,"
he said. I said "Why?" "He sings whether he
knows or not - that's the trouble!" What an
exact description he gave Me of this gentleman!
"He's very courageous you see. He doesn't
know but he sings - quite alright, so he's
very courageous." I mean, he didn't say anything
against him - he said "He's courageous" - but
he gave Me the complete picture of the gentleman
that: "You have to be careful you see, he
might start singing in a funny way, you shouldn't
laugh." And, all that came in that 'courageous'
word.
In the same way, if you study someone then
you will just describe that person in an interesting
way, and you will not feel that this person
has these bad habits or those bad habits or
this is wrong with him, that is wrong, but
you'll describe - it's part of that person.
It's a way of knowing a person in totality
with all his defects, with all his qualities,
with everything and accepting that person
as he is.
If that mastery you can have. Now how will
you have? If your attention is not on his
qualities you'll only know his bad things.
And if you know his qualities then bad things
will be there, a little bit, but they'll just
be adding a little masala to his character.
You'll feel "ahhhh, that's it, you see, he
is a little bit like that." Little additional
swara (musical note) is added to his character.
And you wouldn't mind it so much, such a person.
You'll really enjoy.
Like my son-in-law is very fond of dogs and
his wife says, "no dog in the house," it's
a flat. So there is a fight between them for
the dog. So Prabhat said "You never meet me,"
I said "This is not proper but next time I
have decided to be a dog," Immediately he
took the point, you see.
So the way you talk to a person you can suggest
to him what is so special about that person
or the defects of that person. But you need
not say directly something to him. If you
say indirectly, in such a humorous manner
that the person will understand. So in communication
with others you have to be a very humorous
person. But mostly I've seen people have humour
if somebody cannot walk straight. If a physical
problem is there they'll laugh. If he has
not properly made his hair then they will
laugh. On some sort of a very superficial
thing they laugh. This is not humorous. This
is some sort of a criticism in laughter. Or
some people have a humour like this that they
say sarcastic things, that's no good. You
say one word to somebody, sarcastic; you think
you are brilliant, but you are lost forever
for that person. That person will remember
"He said such a such things to me."
So sarcasm is against you completely; against
Sahaja Yoga. If you have to say something,
say it in such a manner that it doesn't hurt
the person, and the person enjoys that subtle
humour and understands also that "This is
the problem with me". Now in a humorous way,
if I have to tell something to you - I need
not tell you directly, "You are like this,
you are like that," but I'll say, "There was
one crow which came to my house..." and, like
that, I can transfer all your qualities to
that crow and describe to you and say that,
"This crow did like this and did that." Immediately
you'll start thinking, "Is it about me Mother
was saying or about the crow?"
So transfer it to somebody else. Transfer
it to somebody else, that's the best way.
For example, if you want to say that: all
the names of the people who are coming to
the puja should be there at the right time.
So now, this time, Americans [are hosting].
Alright, "Americans have sent the word..."
- they have not - "...have sent the word that
all the names should be there." No harm telling
such lies, no harm. So that people will not
put it on you, they'll not be angry with you.
At the most they'll be angry with the Americans
- doesn't matter, for the time being. So transfer
it. And this transference is 'astantar' as
they call it. To transfer from one hand to
another hand, Shri Krishna was an expert.
There is a story about Him. He is called as
Ranchordas, means He ran away from the battlefield.
He doesn't mind "I ran away, so what?" The
reason was like this: there was a very bad
rakshasa who had all kinds of boons from Brahmadeva
and Shri Krishna didn't know how to overcome
that, nobody knew, and He was killing so many
people. So He thought of a trick, transfer
it to somebody else. He knew of another great
yogi you see, special type, who has meditated
and taken a boon from the same Brahmadeva
that: "If I'm sleeping and anybody disturbs
my sleep and, if I open my eyes and look at
that person, that person should become ashes
- bhasma (ashes)."
So Shri Krishna thought of Him, "Better transfer
the job from me to Him." So He started running
away from the field. So this Rakshasa also
followed Him. Then Shri Krishna stealthily
went into the cave of this avadhuta, and put
His own shawl on top of Him, covered Him,
and hid himself in the cave. Now this Rakshasa
came here, he thought this was Shri Krishna
who was sleeping, "Ahhh now you are tired,
you are sleeping. Now I'm going to see how
you can save yourself." And he started waking
[him] up. This avadhuta got up and looked
at him and he became bhasma.
So transfer your jobs to a more capable (Shri
Mataji laughs) person who can do this better,
than taking upon yourself straight-forward,
going, "Alright,come long, I'll fight with
you" - you cannot win. It's a guerrilla warfare
as you call it. Transfer it, and you can transfer
it to somebody, you can make friends with
that person, pamper his ego; do what you like.
But the main point is that you should get
rid of the ills, the bad, the rakshasas. So
you can transfer it to anyone.
And so many tricks He played. In the Mahabharata,
Bhishma had a blessing that, unless and until
he wants to die, nobody can kill him. So Shri
Krishna decided that He should use some tricks.
So He told Arjuna that you put him...He told
Arjuna not himself; He was just doing the
chariot drivers job - Sarathi. So Krishna
told him that you just make him sleep on the
arrows, let His body be on the arrows and
he has to decide that he will die. But Dronacharya
was a great guru, also of Arjuna, who was
siding with Kauravas. Now how can you kill
this Dhronacharya, big problem. Because you
see, he knew all the tricks of archery. How
are you going to save them? Because archery
is such a thing that he was the master of
archery, while Arjuna was his disciple.
So how to stop him, answering back the arrows
of Arjuna? How to do that, that he doesn't
answer back? Because he was a master. So Krishna
organized it, in a very special way. He got
a Shikhandi, a eunuch. What is the advantage
of having a eunuch? Of course it's a big story
how they became Shikhandi. But He got him
in front of Arjuna. A eunuch in India is regarded
as a woman, so Dhronacharya said, "I cannot
kill a woman," and that's how He killed Dhronacharya.
So [He played] these tricks, because to get
rid of ill is the main thing. To get rid of
the ill - if you are not capable - you better
tell somebody else to get rid. Because that
is very important - to get rid of the evil
- and if you can transfer this to somebody
else who is more capable, in your own humility,
you'll do much better than to directly attack
that person. That's Tomfoolery. No use.
So this was the trick of Shri Krishna throughout,
if you have seen Mahabharata. Shri Krishna
told Arjuna that, "Either you can the have
all of My army or you can have Me." Same He
told to the Kauravas. The Kauravas said, "We'll
have your army." But he (Arjuna) said, "You
will be mine, Krishna." He said "You'll be
on our side." But He said, "No, I'll be just
on the chariot. I'll not hold any weapon."
But He is a master of tricks. He does not
need any weapons with Him. Without weapons
also He can do everything. So Arjuna said,
"alright, You be my chariot driver," and He
was there.
Because Shri Krishna knew about each and every
thing, mostly He used to smile. Now, if somebody's
telling Me something, sometimes you will find
I also smile, but I try to control because
I don't want them to see. But I know what
they are doing, what they're up to, what is
their trick. Because you are such a trick
master you know all the tricks and you know
what they are playing with you. So you just
smile about it, just to smile in a very sweet
way, "ahhh, that's it. ahh ,of course, of
course, what you say is true, no doubt." But,
by this kind of thing, you'll be surprised,
your communications will improve very much
with others.
Now some people I've seen in Sahaja Yoga - very
common, very common, "Mother, they came and
told me, our leader told me, that you are
bhootish. What is bhootish?" Another one says,
"But he told me that you are a bhoot," - alright.
And somebody says, "Mother no he told me that
you have got a bhoot in you. Now what are
these three categories? Tell us." Why to tell
anybody you are bhootish or anything? There's
no need. If you know how to correct it, just
say "left Swadisthana" and correct it. Take
it out. Ask him, if he had any guru or anything.
Alright, if the person is good natured and
a good person then it's even more important.
You should say "It's nothing, you see, it's
just a badha from outside. We'll have to take
it out." But a person who has got agnya and
all these things, plus that he has got this
left Swadisthana, then, of course, you should
say, "Baba, we cannot help you," because you
know he is cunning. What's the use of playing
with that?
But in Sahaja Yoga we forget. Anybody who
comes "Alright, come along, come along, come
along." Everybody is not capable of Sahaja
Yoga, one has to know that. Not the whole
world. Sahaja Yoga can only be given to people
who are deserving, who are seekers and who
are courageous - viras. It's not meant for
ordinary people. So we open our door to everyone
and all such people walk in and then we work
very hard on them, do all kinds of things,
and we find that they create problems for
us. So first, only deal with people who are
simple, as Shri Krishna dealt with Gopas and
Gopis; and then we can see, in a collective
way, if we can face somebody who's complicated.
But no use transforming Hitler or Rajneesh,
not possible.
So one should not try to do impossible tasks
in Sahaja Yoga, which Shri Krishna has shown
in His own character by avoiding things which
He didn't want to do - no. And He did it because
He was such a master. Of course, for Him,
it was not necessary to face himself to master
himself, because He knew himself, He is the
Ishwara of yoga, He knew everything. When
you know everything there is no need for you
to master, what are you going to master? On
the contrary you sometimes get frightened
of yourself, that you know so much.
So, best is that, when we are dealing as human
beings in Sahaja Yoga, we have to know ourselves
very well - "Now oh that's my speciality."
In that you have to see: "How I face myself
all the time? Why do I say such a thing? What
is lurking in my mind?" Negativity is something
to be seen very clearly within yourself.
As I must have told you so many examples that
the western negativity is like this that,
their minds are all the time labor saving
devices. They don't like to work anyway. For
example, you tell them "You go and telephone
to someone." Immediately they will tell you
ten explanations: he may not be there, his
wife will shout, he might have gone to work,
it's ten o'clock, this, that. But if you telephone
he's there, but they won't telephone. Hundred
excuses. Now new excuses have started: "the
computer was not working, fax was not working."
Except for your brain everything works. But
the other way around it is: your brain is
not working and everything is not working.
"The lights were not working." I mean, whatever
it is. But you must learn, "Why can't I find
the solution? I must do something."
Like I have told you, the tip of a root - how
it manages to go round and round and seek
the source of water. In the same way, are
we doing something about it? Alright, if this
is not available, do that, if that is not
available do this. Out of nothing you can
do so many things. But if you want to find
out all the time "That cannot be done, that
cannot be done". [That was] not [the case]
with Shri Krishna! After all He was the incarnation
of Virata, the Master of Masters we should
say.
Like when Draupadi was in trouble - Draupadi
was actually Vishnumaya His sister - She thought
of Shri Krishna. She was holding onto her
sari, when it was pulled out by Duryodhana.
And She was holding it like this (with Her
teeth). "Kri", She wanted to say "Krishna"
but She thought, "If I say 'shna' it will
fall down." So She was holding on. As soon
as She dropped it, "shna", sari dropped out
(of Her mouth), then it's described, about
Shri Krishna, "Dwarika me shora bhayo, shor
bhayo bhare. Shankha chakra gadaa padma, Garuda
laysidhare." [Meaning:] that sound went into
Dwarika. Now where is Dwarika and where is
Hastinapur - at least a distance of two thousands
miles [apart]. But the sound went through
Chaitanya and made a big sound there; and
"Shankha Chakra Gadaa Padma". Shankha, Chakra
Gadaa, Padma are the weapons (of Vishnu) as
you know. All of them He took and came on
His Garuda to save the chastity of His sister
- immediately, spontaneously, that moment.
He could have said, "Alright let it be, let
one sari come out then I'll go later."
I'm sure He must have stolen My saris which
you give for My Pujas, which are too many!
That's what I feel, that, from where did He
get all these saris to give to Her? Must be
from My own storage I'm sure, and that's why
you are giving Me so many saris, so that He
can save the chastity of many women. All this
is so related, so connected, so one, so united.
There's such a big drama going on but you
can't see it.
But if you believe in yourself and if you
really believe that you are a Sahaja Yogi,
that: what are your qualities, what you are,
what's your value is, then I'm sure you can
become masters. But first of all we have no
value of our realization. We do not know what
we are capable of, what we can do. You still
think, "oh, I was such an ordinary person,
Mother has given me realization. I have never
been to university." Nobody has been to university.
I mean, if you see, Rama never went to any
university, Krishna never went into university,
Christ never went to any university - an ordinary
man, a son of a carpenter.
But you are realized souls but you don't realize
your worth and value. Once you realize it,
you will just smile at everything. Because
you don't know you are sitting on top of the
world. Once you know that - only then your
mastery will work. Otherwise imagine a master
sitting under the foot of a disciple, what
will it look like? But it's not that you dominate
but you are in charge, absolutely in charge.
You know everything, you know how to handle,
you know how to manage. This is the mastery
you have to get. This is possible, absolutely
possible, for all of you to do it. But the
first and foremost thing you have to know
is that we have to master ourselves.
But then immediately people say "Mother it's
the most difficult to master yourself." I
can't understand this. Why not? You try to
master everyone, why can't you master yourself?
Yourself is with you, you are with yourself,
it's your own, it's your own property. You
can correct the property of others, why can't
you correct your own property? It should be
the easiest thing to do but you're not sure
that this is your own, you do not know that
you are capable, but you are and now you have
Self-knowledge, so why should you not do it?
Why should you not try to watch yourself and
see for yourself? And then you will know that
you know all the tricks, the yukti. I don't
have to tell you "do this, do that," nothing!
You yourself will know "ha, come along!"
We know so many things, little little things,
about ordinary material things: something's
falling? Alright - put some support to it.
This is happening? Put it that way. But in
spiritual life it's the easiest thing because
you are in the ocean of knowledge. But if
you do not know that you are, in the ocean
of knowledge, you will not know the tricks,
of dealing with others. Because the main purpose
of our communication is to emancipate the
whole world, to emancipate them. To bring
them out of their ignorance.
So for that we have to develop this mastery
and not to get lost into nonsensical things
but this mastery has to be developed. For
that, meditation early in the morning is required
- to begin with. And then facing yourself
all the time, "Why did I say such a thing?"
"Aahhhh must be this. This is the word I picked
up from that person." So when you start facing
yourself, you will be surprised that you are
trying to avoid the reality and just using
your mind. See there, as I say, that this
mind cheats you and tells you, "all right,
forget it".
And the last, but not the least, is that Shri
Krishna is the one who is an expert of drama.
He creates drama, He acts in the drama, and
He's the spectator also. In these three forms
you should see yourself. You create the drama
of yourself, "aha this one now, see now, how
I'm acting here!" Then you become the spectator
also. Become the spectator of your own dramas,
then you will realize what you are doing,
how you are working out everything. Then the
deception that we have, all the time, against
ourselves, will just run away. Because if
an artist knows he's the spectator, if the
one who is acting knows he is the spectator,
he can never deceive himself, because He knows
this is acting. So this self-deception is
the one [that] one should try to avoid - "let
me face it."
But also there is another way out, people
find out. I mean, there are ways and ways.
Like you tell somebody, "why didn't you write
a letter?" "I know!" 'I know' means what?
"But don't you think you should have written
a letter to that person, who has done so much
for you?" "I know." "But don't you think it's
very bad and cruel on your part not to have
written the letter?" "I know." 'I know' means
what? "I know I'm bad. I know I have been
stupid. I know I should not have done it.
But I know also that." So what next? Because
they think that if they have confessed that
"I know," [it's] finished!
So this is a new escape which was not [there]
at the time of Shri Krishna, it's a new modern
one, where people say "I know, alright so
what?" "Ohhh alright I'm a sinner so what?"
This is the second side of it. First of all
"I know that I'm a sinner" and second is a
higher state is that: "so what, what's wrong?"
So this is how the derailment starts and one
goes from one to another. If I know something
then why shouldn't I correct myself? That's
what it should be. "I know I'm like that I
know it." If you know then you should also
know the trick - how to get rid of it. Because
you are detached from that personality about
which you know, you can correct yourself.
This is what yoga is, where all your attention
is one with the Divine and you are so detached
that you can see it. The attachment to all
the things are finished and now the force
that is coming to you is acting through you
and acting on these attachments also.
The situation changes, absolutely, in Sahaja
Yoga in a very different way, and if there
is one bad Sahaja Yogi who comes in, either
he's thrown out or he has to be alright. It's
the other way around. Anyone who is a bad
Sahaja Yogi, if he comes in Sahaja Yoga, then
he has to be corrected, otherwise thrown out.
It is a I think a more evolved state now than
it was at the time of Shri Krishna, because
He talked only to one - Arjuna. Now I'm talking
to thousands - this knowledge. That time He
just talked about it at the time of war. I'm
talking at the time of peace. And it's much
more evolved because Shri Krishna didn't give
him realization. But you have got the realization,
you've got the knowledge, you know everything.
You have all the subtle ideas.
So this is what it is today, as it is, the
situation, that: you have become part and
parcel of Virata already. You have not seen
the Virata (as Arjuna did), but you are part
and parcel of it. You are not watching it,
you are inside it. So that anymore of not
watching yourself, only thing will be that,
you'll be thrown out of Sahaja Yoga. Or else
you better watch yourself and correct yourself
and be one with the body of the Virata.
This is the sign of a Yogeshwara, and that's
how you have to be, in a mood which is very
smiling, knowing everything and not sarcastic,
but [with a] very paternal smile, very loving,
affectionate smile, that you should have for
all the other people and immediately they'll
recognize. I have seen small children are
like that. They are extremely patronising
sometimes, you know. They see their parents
and this and that. So they come and tell you
that, "don't worry everything will be all
right, after all God is there to look after
you." And they can be extremely, extremely
loving and kind and the way they talk they
will neutralize the whole thing.
So we have to learn a lot from our children,
from all the little babies that we have and
that we ourselves should have that Ganesha
principal within us, with innocence we should
work it out. Innocence is the most intelligent
thing and most effective thing. So I would
request you, all of you, to face yourself
and don't hate yourself but correct yourself,
respect yourself and try to evolve your own
glory.
May God bless you.