It is the vital energy, which has
one electromagnetic energy that you have.
What we call as a “Prana”
It is the energy from 5 elements.
It has the energy by which we are today human beings from amoeba
and it has the energy which creates desires within us.
It has the energy that can cure us
and redeems us
and the energy that can give us powers so we can do living work.
Sahaja yoga is with that energy which is in totality complete consciousness,
and it is a special time today. You can say in modern times, and there are so many people who are trying to think beyond,
we can say it is meta modernism,
no, no, meta modernism
and that is something which shows the wisdom of people who understand that we have to go beyond
and they are not satisfied with what they are but they have to go beyond
and there are so many who feel that their awareness is to be expanded.
In this short time as much as possible I am trying to give you a general picture about Sahaja yoga.
“Saha” means “with”, and “ja” is born,
so it is born with you to have this union with that all-pervading power, Sahaja you have.
It works on all living beings
and also on energies.
For example, you can improve your agriculture in Sahaja yoga 10 times more,
you can improve your ecological problem through Sahaja yoga,
you can make your animals much more healthier through Sahaja yoga
and you yourself become so dynamic
and so compassionate
that a scientist becomes a person who works only with all the understanding of limitations of science
and helps to create a new world.
I must say all the scientific discoveries have helped Sahaja yoga greatly.
Supposing there were no aeroplanes I did not have come to see you
if there were no microphones I could not have talked to you
and these microphones also carry vibrations.
Even on television one can give realization to people.
So all these discoveries you have made has been of such a great help to Sahaja yoga.
We have developed the watches to save time,
we save our time to waste it mostly,
and after self-realization, we use it for our spiritual ascent and spiritual growth, growth through meditation.
So I am very much thankful to you all scientists for making these devices which have made it possible to spread Sahajayoga all over the world.
The knowledge of Sahaja yoga is very deep,
our civilization has grown like a big tree,
but knowledge of Sahaja yoga is the knowledge of the roots
and if you do not have the knowledge of the roots this great development will be one day under a shock.
So it is important for us to know the knowledge of the roots if we have to survive
and to enjoy the blessings of science.
I am sorry in this short time I cannot say much but I will be very happy to answer your questions if you have any.
As a scientist, you have to understand everything whatever you do,
if somebody cures you and cannot explain how
then you should not accept as a scientist.
but I know that what happens.
This is something which is not dealt with by scientists so far,
only in the scriptures they have talked about the soul,
now soul, whatever I am telling you, again, you should accept it as a hypothesis.
Now soul is a composition of 5 elements, the causal of 5 elements
which is placed on the back side of our...it’s an energy form, it’s an energy form
and is placed on the backside of our spinal cord in 7 loops…
after self-realization you can even see the all-pervading power like small commas shining like light,
also you see a kind of loops circular things
and the Sahaja yogis ask Me: what is this?
I told them these are dead souls.
Now for example we talk of psychosomatic diseases,
also doctors have reached a certain point of understanding that most of the psychosomatic diseases
are caused by something that comes from our collective subconscious.
For example, cancer they say is triggered by a protein 53 and 58. It’s a name they've got.
And they say that it comes from the area which is built within us since our creation,
now, this area which is built within us is the area which we call as collective subconsciousness,
so all the plants which have gone out of the circulation of evolution or who have gone out of the circulation are all existing in that area of collective subconscious,
so when a person who practices what we call as black magic or mesmerism also uses the dead souls
which are around to captivate you.
And people do mesmerize without knowing what effects it will have on human beings.
Now what happens that if you put any such spirit, it can be without the knowledge
of the person who is doing it automatically. It becomes like a [ ] and then the spirit gets out to your system,
now recently they have found out in the science, scientific research that we have all got receptors
and in the receptors these seven loops that I am telling you about are reflected exactly the same way
I have seen..if you have seen the picture in the same that you see.
And when there are on these loops if there is any effect then what you call as dopamine is created.
Dopamine is a kind of a chemical which gives you epilepsy, it can give you madness can give you all mental problems also other virus and cancer, psychosomatic.
So I, I didn’t know that I would talk to scientists otherwise I would have brought these papers which I have got from America.
So we had about 10 people yesterday, who came from the same gentleman and were suffering from many diseases.
Some had their hands stuck like that they couldn’t walk, some children suddenly stopped talking,
some got their eyes completely scooped in, some got the brain paralysis.
So what happens that you can put one of their or many of these dead spirits on your back on the soul,
and they take over
and when they take over when they try to assert their personality,
so for the time being one may feel elated because there are so many personalities acting for a while,
but after sometime that person becomes exhausted and they recluse...
This is followed by many false gurus in India, we know about it very well because just
this black magic is too much in India.
But mainly what one has to know, I would say that as a Mother I would say what did you get out of it?
Only temporary curing is not the aim of life,
but you have to be empowered and you have to have full knowledge as to what you are going to be.
In Sahaja yoga you know all about the centres and it can be good to you.
You can even see with your naked eyes the pulsation of the kundalini,
this power which connects you to the mains.
You can see also sometimes the rising of the kundalini
you can feel the cool breeze coming out of your head, the actualisation of it,
and you can feel the all-pervading power.
You may be a doctor may not be a doctor but you can give diagnose to others what centres are in trouble.
There are three channels
which look after the sympathetic nervous system and parasympathetic nervous system,
and you can control them,
you can control your parasympathetic nervous system,
you can raise the kundalini of others,
you can cure others,
yourself you feel extremely peaceful, joyous and happy,
because you develop a new dimension of collective consciousness which Jung has written.
So you become complete knowledgeable like a laboratory you know everything,
it is not just "ah, it is happening. I don’t know how happening" - nothing of that kind...everything can be explained,
everything becomes logical,
so anything that just cures you is not sufficient,
in India this art is very well developed
but we know about it so much that we now don’t go to any false people,
so now they are exported all to America,
They are very gullible
Americans are very gullible people,
and these people have only interest in money they are money makers.
Now it’s a living process,
how can you pay for a living process,
how much do we pay to Mother Earth for sprouting a seed?
These people have all their interest in money,
and not in giving you the powers
and the knowledge
because they haven’t got it.
So first of all you must see
what are the disciples like?
What do they do?
What sort age they are? What sort of body they have?
How do they talk?
What is their health?
Do they know about all this?
Can they explain it?
How is their own life?
You can find out.
They have to be honest
and they have to be compassionate,
so be careful,
so many will come once you have lots of money, there will be a market,
so before anything happen, be careful.
I am a Mother and you have asked me the question I have to tell you the Truth.
Eighteen years back I have told this Truth but they would not listen to Me,
In America I told them about AIDS, I told them about UPI disease is going to come,
I told them about so many diseases they would not listen and now they are down with it.
So what can you do if they don’t want to listen to you, you can’t help it.
If they are bent upon their destruction then what can you do? They have all the freedom.
Or somebody asked me how to go to hell, all types of questions they ask,
I said take two running jumps and you are there.
So it is like this,
For getting your realization you have to first ask for it, I have to respect your freedom
and it’s not a guarantee that you will get it at first shot.
But if you are earnest it will work out
and then once you are fully connected, no problems of any kind.
I found Russians to be very wise people,
and I feel that a day will come when Russians will be most powerful people spiritually.
The country is not powerful by weapons but by the powerful peoples.
I have to .. his question is still not answered.
After realization, we become very sensible and satisfied people,
and we develop a balance
then we realize that the machines are for us and we are not for machines
so we produce as much as we want,
and whatever is necessary we produce through machines or we produce through our hands.
So a balance is.
As a result of that, the pollution goes down.
Now in Spain there are five motor factories,
now on the road you will find in car only one person is sitting, in every car,
because so many cars are produced every day, cars are cheap so they buy a car and an ego is saying: now I've got a car!
The father must have one car, mother must have one car, the child must have one car, the grandmother must have one car
and they never meet each other,
no rapport, no relationship,
they live with their cars with their pretty girls and with a suitcase.
So, after realization we become collective,
there may be three cars but everybody would like to go together in one car,
they want to live collectively
because they enjoy each other.
Now Sahaja yoga is working in forty nations,
and they want to live in Indian villages,
And light it with a spark. I mean you cannot do anything there,
but they enjoy it having their baths in the flowing rivers and living in the nature absolutely very happy and comfortable.
They wear few clothes of cotton or pure silk or cotton whatever they can afford, not too many things they don’t have in their house
like plastics,
mountains and mountains
and they don’t know how to destroy it,
and Sahaja yogis don’t drink,
so only one glass is sufficient for one man,
for drinking we have to have one..., another one, another one, another one,
and too many choices because of ego.
In the morning the mother will ask what will you have?
One child will say this, another this another that,
and if that is not in the fridge the child will start shouting,
Formally the mother used to cook for everyone the same thing
and everybody had to eat that and enjoy it,
because we have lost our collective enjoyment, we have become like this.
Now these entrepreneurs are also making fool of us,
first they will start that you should wear very tight pants,
so you develop varicose veins,
so they will say alright make pants with holes in it
so everybody starts wearing them,
they go on changing fashions because their machines have to run,
and we have no personality, we all want to be fashionable, what is the need?
So we have piles of clothes,
you go to an English home, as soon as you enter all pile will fall on you first of all.
So, this matter is only for one purpose,
is for expressing your love,
like today we had a birthday,
so we gave him a tea set,
and I got some necklaces for all of you,
and I enjoy very much giving them,
that’s the only advantage of matter,
otherwise possessions are headaches.
So, how ecological problems has come by? Because of greed and lust.
After Sahaja yoga, you get everything beautiful and enjoy everything,
because you feel that this has become a holy water now, everything becomes holy, auspicious,
only thing which are auspicious, which emit vibrations Sahaja yogis will have it,
all auspicious things are benevolent
so the ecological problem is solved.
So first question is that some diseases can be cured through Sahaja yoga  - as raising the kundalini.
Yesterday there was a lady with multiple sclerosis. And she could not stand on her..
and we raised her kundalini, she had problems on her centres,
we corrected the centres raised her kundalini, gave her realization and she got alright,
and then she still [ ] that she was sick so she was holding onto the chair
I said now you get up and walk, and she then started walking so fast, everybody saw.
Most of them get cured,
but some of them do not.
Now, first of all, you have to get your self-realization,
then you have to come to our collective program
and then you have to master Sahaja yoga
when you start do it, then you can cure others.
But Sahaja yoga is not for curing,
it is for self-realization
and when you get your self-realization as a bioproduct
then you can become alright because when the kundalini rises She passes through these centres and nourishes them.
Shri Mataji, if there were some psychological research done relating to influence Sahaja Yoga on people?
Is it possible to see the findings of this research? And may I get Your blessing to conduct such research in center of Sahaja Yoga in Moscow?
...here accepted for research but if you want to do it otherwise you can do it by using Sahaja yoga methods
to cure people who are suffering from psychosomatic diseases or depressions or anything by treating them and then noting down their improvements.
We have here a saint scientist doctor from England, he is here and he can tell you about it.
And we are all experimenting with many things. Is he here doctor Wells?
Alright, you come and see he is now running seven hospitals, London.
Now we have many doctors here and I think we should meet them who have come from abroad...we should call them.
aap aaiye( you please come), We have doctor Talwar? ..Dr. Talwar?
Dr Talwar from Delhi.
Now we have Dr Ramzad Ali,
He is from the U.K.
And he is a great student of medicines actually.
He has done a lot of studies.
Then we have Dr Neelam,
from India.
Then we have Dr Sarah,
then we have got a diplomat from UN, Gregoire.
Then in Russia, we have got Dr Bogdan.
Today is his Birthday.
He has sacrificed his job
in India and he is now here,
working it out for Russia.
We hope to see some sense of scientists also for you from America.
They’ll explain many more things to you,
also we will send you some papers that they have written.
And second - is Sahaja Yoga is universal science, which includes Hatha, Raja and other yogas or it is some new principle?
I should say I was born with this knowledge.
The second question is about all other yogas.
Now Hatha yoga is meaning “Ha” and “Tha” meaning the sun and the moon both lines, both energies,
but in modern times the Hatha yoga they are practising is only of one side,
moreover the one who started hatha yoga was known as Patanjali,
so thousands of years back he’s written a book so big as that so thick,
in that he has written that there are Ashtangas, there are eightfold of yoga, eight aspects, spiritual paths,
out of that yama niyama is the one which is just a wee bit,
yama niyama, is control and the laws
and out of that very wee bit are the exercises,
now we also use those exercises,
but later on throughout he has talked about Sahaja yoga,
first you get thoughtless awareness and then doubtless awareness.
In those days they used to only have one or two disciples,
and they cleansed their all centers and then raise their kundalini,
and it could take years together.
But now in the Sahaja yoga today,
I have evolved a method by which first you raise the Kundalini somehow,
and in that little light, give them little light they see what’s the problem with that
and just tell them how to correct
so they can correct their own problems.
In those days people have no time
and people are very obstinate also
so now supposing there’s darkness and you are holding the snake in your hand
and I say now there is a snake in your hand, you won’t listen to Me, you won’t throw it away till it bites you.
You will say it’s a rope,
so the best thing is to put little light,
so you see the snake and throw it away yourself.
This is today’s Sahaja yoga
but it’s the same what he achieved after so many years you can achieve it yourself in a very short time,
and also as we have developed speed I think kundalini has also developed speed.
We call it this as jet times and the kundalini is also a jet kundalini, we call it as a jet, Jet Times, jet. How do you translate this
I am myself surprised, it works en masse.
Yesterday there were 10,000 people,
and I think 95% of people got realization 95.
But we do tell you exercises when the kundalini rises, then we tell you if there is any physical problem what exercises to be done, it’s all scientific.
But this way these days the way people do hath yoga, they just take all the medicine from the medicine box without knowing what is to be taken without discretion.
Now another is Raja yoga.
I went down to California and I saw some doctors whom I knew have cut their tongue.
and they told me that they had to cut it to do a thing called “khechari” to take back the tongue
to raise the kundalini.
So now when the kundalini rises it is like the ignition of a car,
and when the car is ignited all the machinery works by itself, you don’t have to do anything.
So what they do is to put back the tongue thinking by doing that the kundalini will rise,
and poor things now can’t speak can’t eat very difficult,
so it is like moving the wheels without starting the car, will it move?
It’s all artificial,
nobody gets realization in that
because it’s a living process,
now there’s integral yoga,
that is all mental.
Talking about yoga how can you get your realization?
Supposing if you talk to the Mother Earth will she give us flowers?
Talk..talk..talk..talk..talk..that’s all.
People get fed up with that talks, books after books like this so many.
So far I have not written any book for the same reason,
then we have another one you call that one? It is transcendental meditation,
that is the worst I tell you
We had four people from transcendental,
the man was the director of a flying foundation in Scotland,
to get a mantra
and the mantras were told in secret
and the mantras were rare, funny ones “Inga, Pinga, Thinga”,
it has no meaning, it is not Sanskrit, it has no meaning but it has funny meaning also
Inga means the scorpion’s bite
and Pinga means when you get possessed you go round and round like that, that is Pinga
and Thinga means when you show like this to someone,
300 pounds for that,
and 6000 pounds for flying halfway.
What a stupidity, what is the need to fly halfway you already have traffic jams,
then they were given to drink the water which boiled which boiled potatoes for six days
then the rings of potato rings,
and the last day was given the potatoes to eat.
But this director, his wife, his daughter and a deputy director all got epilepsy,
so they came here.
Luckily my husband has gone on a tour so they stayed in my house
and with my treatment they got cured.
They had lost all their money, this man was a diamond merchant, he had lost all his money his wife was a granddaughter of a Duke, she has lost everything.
What is this lady…please tell her to sit down
and a granddaughter who was the granddaughter of a Duke and this man became bankrupt.
So and the director and the deputy director became bankrupts
and he is now gone to South Africa and writing a book.
The name of the book is “How we were befooled”.
This t.m. and now they begin Ayurveda.
They are marketing it now marketing it,
there is no need for them to market anybody can take to Ayurveda,
but for Ayurveda, you cannot do it here, you have to go to India because the herbs that are used for curing you cannot grow here.
So, just that just trying to I don’t know what are they up to, I just don’t know, they can’t bring Ayurveda here.
India, Indian medicine,
I mean it is a common sense everybody knows in India that you can’t do Ayurveda anywhere else but in India.
I think they will now give some sort of this to you in the name of Ayurveda and they will buy it.
or they give may be some water which has boiled the potatoes.
One should know all these things. There’s another one who gives diabetes, supposing.
only to people who are very big cheats in India
the horrible people who .. they are cheats.
If he is so good why doesn’t he solves our problem financial problem in India?
Why doesn’t he solves some  of our financial problem?
All these people who doing it get heart trouble.
I am telling you everything frankly,
they will never talk against each other.
Christ has said that the house of Satan will never speak against itself.
But they will speak against Me they do!
They make like that.
They may speak against Me and tell you that I must be a dark force or something, they might,
because it is their business, they will be using money when I am here.
Alright, Thank you very much.