exciting
Shri Mataji, the point that we were discussing this
morning, we discovered here, that is the section
which is quoted.
Now this is the section:
“ I also tell you that you are Peter and
on this rock  I will build My Church and the gates of Hades,
the gates of Hell shall not prevail against her” (the church)
“I will give you the keys of the kingdom of Heaven.
Whatever you bind on earth will be bound in Heaven.”
That was what you do on earth,
I will make sure it happens in Heaven! Nonsense!
“Whatever you allow on earth will be allowed in Heaven”.
Shri Mataji: This is nonsense.
Brian: This is nonsense. “Then He….”
Shri Mataji: You see, how could He say that?
Brian: How could He?
Brian:  It must be true, Mother, it’s in the Bible!
Shri Mataji: (unclear…) can you read there..(unclear)?
Brian: “Then He forbade the disciples to say to anyone He is the Christ”
So He wanted to keep it a secret or something, I don’t understand…
Yes, yes.
Shri Mataji:    What’s the meaning of Christ….(unclear) ?
Brian:  Christ is the sacrifice, the chosen one, the chosen one
of the chosen people.
It’s the Greek, the Greek equivalent of the Messiah.
Shri Mataji: It comes from Krishna….(inaudible)
Brian:  Krist.
Shri Mataji: And Yeshu comes from the…
Brian: Yeshoda
Shri Mataji: Yeshoda.
Brian:  It’s beautiful that. But not many Christians would believe it.
Shri Mataji: They wouldn’t agree with it.
Brian: No. No, they’d think that was sacrilege.