Mahari Ahoni Padharo Mahare Desh
Padharo Mahare Desh (2)
Nirmal Maa Ayee, Ahoni Padharo Mahare Desh
Mahri Nirmal Mataji, Ahoni Padharo Mahare Desh
Nirmal Nirmal, Main Karoon, Mari Nirmal Jeev Jaddi
Chuddian Uppar Band loon, To Bazu Ghaddi Ghaddi
Mahri Nirmal Mata Rani
Ahoni Padharo Mahare Desh, Padharo Mahare Desh
Padharo Mahare Desh
Nirmal Maa Mahri, Ahoni Padharo Mahare Desh
Mahri Nirmal Mataji, Ahoni Padharo Mahare Desh
Nirmal Nirmal, Main Karoon, Mari Nirmal Jeev Jaddi
Chuddian Uppar Band loon, To Bazu Ghaddi Ghaddi
Mahri Nirmal Mata Rani Ahoni
Padharo Mahare Desh, Padharo Mahare Desh (3)
NOT CLEAR
SY: He is chairman of Housing Board
Land allotment he has done. He is sardarji.
Shri Mataji:They eat money (take bribe) every where.
SY: In this case, they didn't take bribe.
Shri Mataji, Government gave the rebate.
In this case they gave the rebate. They did not take the money.
NOT CLEAR