[Music]
unfortunately or fortunately you are
born in these modern times and in these
modern times as you know it's a very
chaotic condition in these chaotic
conditions you don't know what is right
and what is wrong and there are all
kinds of attractions which can take of
your attention and reduce the energy of
your attention
it is possible more for the people who
are very right-sided also the left-sided
people can be very much affected the
right-sided people as you know go up to
a point and become extremely dry
self-opinionated and address all their
attention is in aggression while the
people who are on the left side are
indulging too much into their own both
sides can tear away your attention which
is the most important it is the most
valuable thing is your attention but the
attention cannot be controlled by a
person who doesn't have a weak mind or a
weak heart
in every field of life where there it is
political economic or any field of life
in which human beings are living there
is a very subtle problem which people
don't understand now if I say that there
is spirit within us which shines in our
heart
you need not believe need not
but our attention is not on the spirit
they call it at Mojave mook our
attention is outside at this stage at
the human awareness our attention is
outside outside in various things now
where should our attention go to evolve
for what to achieve what the firstly our
attention has now go towards our spirit
towards spiritual understanding so what
have you
first of all by God's grace as I told
you
you all are realized people so your
ascent is made in the center which is a
very very difficult thing absolutely
difficult notice but you should learn to
keep in the center but how to keep the
attention is in the center is the
problem for many people who are still
not above themselves
now when you meditate try to meditate in
a sustained way
first of all sustained then you find
that you are getting into the state of
Samadhi means at a state where you start
feeling the joy and the Bliss of God's
blessings and then you start saying for
God what a blessing what a blessing and
what a bliss once you have reached a
state then you have to realize Who am I
who are what are you are the spent after
establishing your sustained attention on
the spirit you will develop a state
where you will be in a complete state of
witnessing with joy
[Music]
you say something about maintaining our
attention to that stage that it should
customers asked a very practical
question is true that to keep the
attention where it should be you see for
everything you have to do some exercise
a bath not before realization after them
the best way is to learn how to watch
yourself just start sitting here just
put yourself into a position for where
you watch yourself now what am i doing
this is the bass this is the study apart
from mantras apart from anything the
abuse is the practice practice of
becoming a witness and the witness is
the spirit state their attention will
not go i mean you will see everything is
that attention will be inside try to
practice this a my business now say some
people say oh I had a horrible time
whether this happened that happened see
you are not a witness how can you have a
horrible time if you are the spirit you
only have a horrible time when you are
not the spirit if you can wash the whole
thing as a drama that is played then you
are not having a horrible time but this
outside of you is having horrible time
with your watch that's how the attention
can be fixed very well if you practice
of the Asura practice all the time to be
witness say you go up out you see
something just try see it not to think
about it be a witness of the world the
joy will be complete and also you will
become absolutely peaceful your
attention will be completely enlightened
and then the inspiration you will get me
the tremendous
oh we test is very different from paying
attention paying attention is a
deliberate thing you deliberately pay
attention see to something as I'm
talking you may not be realized you may
be realized you can pay attention to me
but witnessing is a state say I'll
submit myself what happens if there's a
problem or there's some calamity
something suddenly I find and we're
testing the whole thing like a drama
it's a state but you can develop it