The chakras, the energy centers
which are inside each and all of us.
Perhaps for new people I can give a very
quick summary of what was said then, and then go on.
Shri Mataji will be here quite soon.
You are here because there is a desire
to see, to understand, to know, to be with
something more than the day to day.
Some sort of reality, some sort of truth, some sort of
explanation,
some sort of all embracing
idea, concept, vision,
which places creation into a context,
somewhere there.
That seeking has taken us in many directions.
Some of us to
false and damaging teachers,
some to drugs,
some to opting out,
but
so, it’s led everybody else of course everybody here tonight
to this particular function.
Shri Mataji is offering an experience.
It's not self-certification, it's not like being
born again, I am born again, I am born again.
It's not a statement of belief,
it is an actual physical happening.
And that physical happening is known as Self-realization.
It's known as the Ruh to the Muslims,
it's known as the Moksha to the Hindus,
is known as enlightenment, liberation,
second birth.
There are a number of names for it.
Christ referred to it as the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost.
But it is all the same thing, it is
this experience which links the energy within us
to the all pervading energy of God.
The yoga, yoga means union,
and that union is in fact this,
the union of this energy here
which lies in the sacrum bone at the bottom of the spine,
is a physical thing, which in the presence of an authorised person
rises through the central channel
and piercing the top of the head, the fontanel bone,
actually comes from the top of the head as a cool breeze.
It also manifests on the hands as cool vibrations.
And another thing that happens then is,
that this, these cool vibrations
and this experience, makes one collectively conscious.
It is a new step, it is another step in evolution.
It is, perhaps to put it one way, a move from
the human being to a spiritual being.
Now what happens when this,
the Kundalini, this energy at the bottom of the spine rises?
It pierces a number of energy centers in the body.
Before we go on, looks we are going to have more people
here than seats.
Is it possible -
how are those seats linked together? Are they separate?
I am just wondering if there is any possibility of
perhaps just easing the seats back and anybody who
would like to come forward and sit on the floor here.
They are all linked.
Is there any chance of just easing the seats back,
is that practical? Just to give us a little more space here ine front.
The desire for creation came,
which is represented here by this left channel.
Then, what we with the Christian background know
as the Holy Ghost or Holy Spirit,
then became the force, that force of God
which brought about creation.
And creation is two parts, or two parts of it,
two aspects of it I should say. One is the desire
and the other is the creation itself.
So we have two
channels, on the left and the right.
One on the left and one on the right.
The left hand one is concerned with
yesterday, the past, the female aspect in us,
the emotional,
that sense of desire, introspection.
The right hand side is action.
That is tomorrow, that is
planning, that is organising, that is dominating,
that is being an outgoing personality,
that is putting the attention out all the time.
Taken to an extreme in the left
there is a tendency or extending the left rather,
one comes into the subconscious.
Everything that has happened in the past is here.
It is possible further one comes to the left
the more one comes involved in the past.
And it is possible on the right hand side
for this to go further and further into the right,
and so it becomes fanatical, dry
and that's the area of heart attacks and
those overactive diseases which are so prevalent in the West.
The West tends to be very active.
The Eastern countries tend to be more on the left.
Well, we talk about left and right, what does that mean?
I was pointing out the other night that if we say something,
"Oh I wish I hadn't said that to somebody,” now that's on the left,
"Oh I wish I hadn't said that.
Tomorrow when I see him again I will say this to him,”
that's on the right.
So we have gone, "Oh gee I am sorry",
and we have come over to the right for tomorrow I will do this.
At the point of crossing there is this little moment
right in the center and that is 'now',
when crossed from the past
from the past to the future,
there is a crossing point which is 'now'.
And that crossing point is this central channel
that the Kundalini, this energy,
rises up in the process of Self-realization.
Rising - this Mooladhara sits actually below,
the energy center sits below the source of the Kundalini,
where the Kundalini originates in the sacrum bone.
The first one up mentioned -
the next one is the Nabhi, the green one.
Nabhi is concerned with our sustenance. In other words
we are not, if you like to think of it in terms of evolution
the Mooladhara is concerned with that innocence
that original innocence.
Then comes the consciousness,
the need for food, for shelter, those basic needs,
that is the territory of the Nabhi.
That is also the area of our evolution.
The next chakra is the Swadhistan,
coming back, and why it's the second chakra,
because the Swadhistan circles around the Nabhi.
Swadhistan is concerned with,
the Swadhistan is concerned with
those aspects of creativity, the need to do something.
Have we got any seats down here?
Yes
Well I think we have still quite a lot of room down here,
if anybody would like to come forward and
and.. and sit.. and clear some seats.
Are you happy standing there at the back?
Here is still quite a bit of sitting room at the front here.
So, again quickly going through these,-
the Swadhistan on the left is concerned
with truth, aspects of truth
and understanding when - what happens
prior to realization is that these centers
as we become involved in various activities, day to day activities,
and they become damaged, they pick up
aspects of perhaps unrighteousness or
those adharmic things settle on to the chakras
and this is what Self-realization itself starts to clear.
In other words, Self-realization starts to cleanse the chakras.
It starts to mend the damages.
It starts to solve the problems.
So from the wisdom in Mooladhara
it comes to sense of evolution and sustenance in the Nabhi,
creativity here in the Swadhistan
and then there is this green circle which is
called various things,
the 'sea of illusion' it is frequently and poetically referred to.
It is that area which must be crossed
if we are to make the transition between the material world
and the spiritual world.
And we have all sorts of guides there like Moses and Abraham
and Lao Tzu and Confucius
and - and I think -
Here is Shri Mataji now!
Say a few words, you say first a few words then only I talk.
Good evening ladies and gentleman.
It's wonderful to see a capacity crowd here, I think that
Adelaide deserves the blessings of Shri Mataji and
tonight they are going to get it.
So many people came the other night on Saturday and
gained their Self-realization, they followed it up with
a beautiful workshop program on Sunday, and
many people are busily working it out.
It's a growing process, and
Sahaja Yoga is spreading very very strongly.
You see all of us have to attain that fulfilment
that we've been seeking for so many lives.
That fulfilment that is known in the scriptures
to the Christian as
being born again some people call it Self-realization.
In the Hindu philosophy it's called Atma Sakshat, Self-realization.
In the Mohammeden scriptures it's becoming a peer,
when they begin to feel this cool wind of the Holy Spirit,
they begin to feel it in their awareness
consciously on their hands and
coming from the top of their head,
feel it as vibrations of the unconscious.
And this vibration that they feel
is the verification and the manifestation that they have
at last made that connection with the unconscious.
This is the result and the reward of
so many lives when they have been seeking God.
And so many people here tonight are in that category.
There are so many negative forces which have been trying to stop us.
So much confusion in this age of darkness which is known,
and has been known as the Kali Yuga.
So much confusion and frustration of modern living in which
people begin to wonder which way to turn,
who is truth and who is falsehood,
who is the real teacher,
who is the false teacher.
Shri Mataji has come to do one job only,
and that is to awaken this subtle energy within us,
that energy which we can as
the reflection of the Holy Ghost within us.
She’s come to awaken it and put us
in touch with our Self, our Spirit.
When that happens
you begin
to feel the bliss and the joy
of that final aspect of your spiritual ascent.
So
be open minded for those people that have come for the first time,
be prepared to receive something great,
be prepared to assume
that you can become that higher being,
that you can in fact become a spiritual being.
There are so many anti-Christs,
there is so many forces of negativity, there is so much confusion
in the world today and so many
people have come on this earth whether as
I said anti-Christs
or else confused people to mislead us,
and to perhaps take us through the highways and byways
in our seeking.
Self-realization establishes something
within you in which you can discriminate.
In which you can know truth from falsehood.
In Sahaja Yoga which is what happens
when you get your realization -
Sahaja Yoga means spontaneous Self-realization -
when that happens
you become a collective being.
You become collectively conscious,
you start to feel on your finger tips
the centers of others, you start to feel in your awareness
what is happening within your own subtle body.
You can give realization to others.
You can discriminate between the people who are seekers
and the people who are false.
You can discriminate between those who
wish their spiritual ascent
and those who are opposing evolution.
And this is important because we have never had any yard stick
by which we could judge other than our mental activity,
other than our emotional activity.
Now, when you get your Self-realization you have that yard stick.
You have that immutable measure by which
you can assume truth.
When you begin to feel the truth
on your finger tips
as the cool wind of the Holy Spirit,
as that power that lies within you,
you know for certain that you have met
that aspect of your nature which is indeed truth.
There will always be people who try to persuade you otherwise,
there will always be the prophets of doom
that this world is going to be destroyed and so many things.
But just ask yourself if the God Almighty that
created this earth, is going to destroy His own creation.
We all have to get our Self-realization.
We all have to become part and parcel of the Kingdom of God.
We all have to become witness to the play of the Divine.
We all have to become like Christ.
We have to become the principle that is the Spirit.
And ultimately when we achieve that
the final joy of Self-realization,
begins it’s process
of taking us to that final union with God.
In Sahaja Yoga
the first experience of Self-realization may be very subtle,
it may be very slight, and you may be a little unconvinced.
Unconvinced rationally or in terms of perception.
Because as I said this subtle
cool wind that you begin to feel on your hand
may in fact be very very slight.
It may be because this chakra here is a little blocked because
of damage to that center,
so don't despair if you don't feel it the first time.
Know that inside yourself
something great has happened.
And when that great happening takes place
you owe it to yourself to develop it.
Thousands of people are developing it around the world.
In Australia it's growing
and it's growing very strongly.
Mother believes that Adelaide is going to be one of the centers
where it grows strongest.
Already so many people have got it.
Already so many of the real seekers
have come and had the blessings of Mother.
Already they are feeling
the Kundalini within themselves, they are feeling
the cool wind, they are attaining their Spirit.
This is what we have been all seeking.
This has been our goal whether we have been a Christian,
or a Jew or a Hindu or a Muslim,
whatever it may be, this has been the goal
and yet we are all one,
we are all part of God Almighty. There is no difference.
What the Buddha said is no different to what Christ has said.
What the Hindu scriptures and the saints
have said is no different
to what Mohammed has said.
They have all said the same thing.
So we have to become that integrating force
that is a realized soul.
We have to get the enlightenment, we have to awaken within ourselves
the divinity that has been sleeping there for so many births,
and we have to get the reward of all our seeking.
Mother is the one who can deliver the goods,
Mother is the one who can awaken the Kundalini.
She is the one who can slowly
and patiently and lovingly nourish Her children
after they get their Self-realization.
She is the one who is respected by the saints
as the Mother, as the Mataji
who has come on this earth to give the blessings of God
to the seekers, and to give the creation it's own meaning.
So without any further introduction from me
it gives me great pleasure ladies and gentlemen
to introduce to you again
Her Holiness Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi.
To all the seekers of truth, I bow.
We have to be the true seekers of truth,
which is a rare quality people think,
but I have found out that in this world
there are many
seekers who are honestly and earnestly seeking.
They are seeking the truth.
They are trying to find out
what is within them,
they are trying to find out what is being prophesied about them.
It has been prophesied that the day of judgment will come.
This is the day of judgment,
when you are going to be judged.
You are not going to be put into any scales
or there is no other measure by which you are going to be judged
but by knowing
how far truthful you are about your seeking
and how far you can gain something about it.
Today I had a chance
to be with some media people
and yesterday also.
I feel some of them just want to bring some controversy
to make it more interesting perhaps.
Whatever it is -
as a Mother I have to tell you that I have to take nothing from you.
I have come here to give you.
If you are identified with any organization
or you think you can fight for an organization
it would be very much better that you should not disturb us,
who are the people who are real seekers sitting down here.
It would be very civil of you to be
away from us, because we are not identified with any organization,
but with our own Self.
We have no organization you know in Sahaja Yoga.
And every type of a person is allowed to come in Sahaja Yoga,
so that he gets the full advantage of his destiny.
In My own
experiences I have found out
that people in the West are rather difficult
to get realization to begin with.
In India there can be six thousand people
and just in a split of a second
their Kundalini rises and they get their realization.
It’s a fact. But even when they get realization
they are not so seriously adhering to it
and they don't try to learn about the technique
of the laws of God's Love.
But in the West on the contrary,
though the first motion is very slow,
some people get it and lose it,
but they are very great seekers.
They get completely transformed.
I have seen people who have been drunkards, alcoholics,
who have been taking drugs and who have been homosexuals,
who led a very wretched life,
did all kinds of nonsensical things to ruin themselves.
Once they get realization they really become so
aware of themselves their self esteem rises
and they take to Sahaja Yoga
in a very proper auspicious way.
It's something surprising
that those who can get realization very fast
are not so good for giving realization to others.
They do not seem to understand
that it has to be given to other people.
While those who take more time,
those who have suffered so much,
those who have had a miserable life before,
those people who could be condemned as
the worst people on this earth
become so beautiful, not only that
but they take it upon themselves that this great
joy of God's Love must be given to others.
But of course, despite all that, we do have some
funny people in every proof sometimes who are
like dog in the manger,
they don't get their realization nor do they allow others to get it.
It's a - some feeling with very frivolous and flippant people,
who are harmed very badly,
still they don't want to have the blessings of God
and try to create problems for us.
It is a sad thing that it should happen
in a country where there are so many seekers who are already lost.
So many people who are God's own people are lost.
One must have some civil sense in understanding
that those who are lost are the people of God.
As William Blake has said
that the men of God will become prophets,
and those who will become prophets will make other prophets.
This is the first thing that happens to you
that you become a prophet.
In the sense that you become a saint,
in the sense that the energy of God which is all pervading
which is doing all living work starts flowing through you.
And when it starts flowing through you, you can use that power,
not only to correct yourself and improve yourself
but give this, the blessing of peace and bliss to God.
Please be seated properly,
if you can't sit you sit on the chair all right?
Now,
for us it is important to understand that I am here
talking about something that is extremely holy and auspicious.
It has not worked out before.
This is the first time in the history of spirituality,
so many people are taking their realization.
As I said, this is the time of last judgment.
This is the time of resurrection which Mohammed Sahib has described
that at that time your hands will be speaking.
How can hands speak?
Anybody can say that, "How can hands speak?"
But the Muslims don't think about it.
They just say, “Let us do namas all the time morning till evening,
do the exercise of namas and we will get realization.”
Christians think that they will get their
realization if they take their baptism.
It's not so.
All these religions were established much before
just to keep you in balance.
To live a life of moderation.
On the contrary human beings have gone to the extremes.
But I must tell you that the Divine is so generous,
is so kind, is working so fast
that despite all these things that you have done to yourself
and to your society,
and as human beings the way you have erred
or whatever you have done, it just forgets and forgives.
Because you are the children of God.
Because He is your Father.
He is the Father who is love,
who is truth, who is joy.
And He is anxious that His children should enter into His kingdom
and enjoy all the blissful thing that He has to give.
Now if you want to see
how you are made, you'll be surprised.
We must have self esteem.
We must understand that God has created us with very great care,
with very great love to become human beings.
And we should not for anything whatsoever,
whosoever it may be, the guru
or the cult or the religion or anything,
should neglect ourselves.
Then you will be responsible for your own neglect
and not God Almighty or any one of these prophets;
they have said that you can be saved.
Now as you see within us lies these subtle centers.
These subtle centers are
the ones which, who represent within us
a different stage of evolution.
First of all if you see the first center, is the Mooladhara.
Now this center is very important
because - for Australians I should say -
because in the universe this center is Australia.
Australia is the place
where this center we can consider as manifesting,
the powers of Mooladhara chakra.
It is the most powerful center in the whole being.
Because it is the power
of innocence in a human being.
The innocence that is the matter, matter is innocent,
animals are innocent,
because they haven’t developed their ego so far,
neither they have got those conditionings
by which we are supposed to be sinners.
A dog or a horse or a camel,
none of them think that they are sinners.
It's only we think that we are sinners
and we have done something wrong.
The reason for this is that God has given us freedom.
So whatever we have done in that freedom
we feel responsible for it
and we start condemning ourselves as sinners and all those things.
But who feels that he is a sinner is the ego and not the Spirit.
The Spirit does not commit any sin!
Is the purest of pure,
nothing can contaminate it,
nothing can destroy it,
nothing can make it absolutely invisible.
It is all the time there within our heart,
watching what we are doing.
As described in Gita is called as Kshetrajna,
the one who knows the field, who watches the field,
who is the witness of the field, which resides in our heart.
All these things whatever I've said has to happen to us,
otherwise it just becomes our mental activity.
I have nothing to bring in anything that is controversial,
everybody has brought out some sort of a thing
and said that this is this and this is this.
But one must know that once you get
your Self-realization it must work.
That's the point people do not understand,
that if you go to a guru,
did it work out your own powers?
Maybe they might be paying you for doing some work,
doesn't matter, that's another enterprise.
But did it give you the reality?
Did it give your absolute meaning?
It has given you your purpose or not?
Has it finished your seeking or not?
You must ask these questions to yourself and be truthful about it.
If not then you better get it.
Now to say that I am the only person doing this,
is all comes out of these people asking funny questions to you.
Now the thing is, she asked me a question:
“Are you the only person doing it?”
I said, I don't know of any other.
I mean you can twist it the way you like,
but so far I haven't met anyone who is giving mass-realization.
I have not met anyone and if I meet I will be very happy to retire.
Even if the sahaja yogis
who come up to that level can give mass-realization just like that
it would be a nice idea to retire
because now I am going to be 60 years of age
and I think I deserve retirement after the hard work of 14 years.
This one is the first center as I told you,
is this great country of
Ganesha - Australia.
The symbol of this is already expressed
in the place called as Ayers Rock.
Ayers Rock if you go and see
has the symbol which is embodying
the great deity that resides on this.
That has the same colour if you see there
and it has the same deity sitting down there
which is called as Shri Ganesha in the Sanskrit language.
Now this deity, innocent deity
or the one which is representing innocence,
incarnated on this earth
for our sake, for our salvation
as our Lord Jesus Christ.
He incarnated and He is bestowed upon
that center of Agnya which you see there
which is actually the body is made of the sun.
That's why most of the Christians are sun worshippers.
This great personality came on this earth
with a very great work because all others
also you can see, but today I would like to speak about Him.
I was told in Adelaide there are lots of churches.
But every human being is a church of God
and temple of God, in that resides Christ,
at this point which is the gate you can see very clearly,
in that gate He resides
and that is the cross which He has carried,
on which He was crucified,
because this cross was too tight,
and something had to pass through it.
His resurrection is the message to all the Christians
that the way He resurrected
you are going to be resurrected by God Almighty.
He came on this earth,
suffered for you and He died on the cross,
just to give you this special privilege of having this great
Agnya Chakra there which He adores.
This is the Agnya Chakra within us.
Now the mistake lies in one thing
that when we say of baptism, it is not an artificial process.
This is a living process.
Christ could not have talked of something artificial or ritualistic.
What He said, baptism was that the Kundalini should be awakened
and it should penetrate through this fontanel bone area,
and should give you the experience of the Holy Ghost.
Now this what I am saying
is also written in an Indian book about our Lord Jesus Christ,
and we do not read the right books in Sanskrit
because they are not translated.
What we are reading are the so called pseudo people
who came about from 50 years back and try to preach
about Hinduism or some sort of a "ism".
But about Christ nobody told.
When they came from other countries to visit India,
nobody told that He is the Maha Vishnu
because nobody knew about it. They could not relate it.
They could not relate, they could not tell
that He was the incarnation of the Maha Vishnu.
And Maha Vishnu is the one, if you read in the Devi Mahatmayam
everything tallies exactly with a character of Shri Jesus Christ.
If you read it you will be amazed how clearly He is described.
Even it is described that first He was an egg
and out of the egg, half egg was Shri Ganesha
and the half egg became Shri Jesus Christ.
And then, that's why on a Easter day if you know,
we always give eggs, meaning
we human beings are eggs at this time
as human beings, but we have to become the bird.
He came on this earth specially for creating a very special
type of device and an awareness within us.
Because this is the gate as I told you
to the Kingdom of God which is the limbic area within us.
Whatever is in the subtle is in the gross.
So this limbic area was
to be achieved through piercing through one gate that is
our Lord Jesus Christ.
Now how to pierce it was a problem because
if anybody tried to pierce it, he may just
go on the sides and become something else but a superconcious man.
So it was Jesus Christ who is the embodiment of
the Ruh, the All Pervading Power, the Chaitanya, the Omkara,
He came on this earth and He did that job for us,
because He resides there.
Now what He said by
the second birth or by baptism was
that this Kundalini which is lying
at the triangular bone there, has to rise.
Rise and penetrate through this center,
awaken Jesus Christ there.
Now the - what great miraculous thing
He has done that once you awaken this center within us,
these two institutions on the left and the right,
one is the ego, another is the super ego;
one is the ego which gives us
all ideas about ourselves which are not really self esteem
but something false.
And super ego is the
condition in which we human beings become conditioned,
in which we accept conditions: I am this, I am this, I am this.
Both the things are sucked in by the awakening
of the Kundalini of this great incarnation on this earth.
Once it is sucked in what you find that
on top of your head where you reach
this place, you find that it has become an open space now.
And suddenly you find the Kundalini is rising
and you can feel the breeze of the Holy Ghost.
In the bible about Holy Ghost very little is written,
for that you have go to Indian Scriptures were She is described
as the power of God Almighty, as Adi Shakti.
It is not proper to bind yourself like a horse
and see whatever is available but open yourself out
and see the references that are given about the great happening
of the advent of Shri Jesus Christ.
Now what relations He has with Shri Krishna, with Shri Rama
with other deities and other prophets
is to be seen later on. When you come to Sahaja Yoga
gradually you realize that they are all related to each other.
And Christ has openly
said that those who are not against are with Me.
The three people who went to
see Jesus when He was born were Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha.
Is described, were the three great people
who went to see Jesus He was born was
Shri Krishna as Vishnu
and Mahesha is Shiva,
and Brahma as Brahmadeva.
All these people went to worship.
Nobody knew from where they came,
who they were, they were called as the three wise men.
Now whatever I am saying has to be first experienced,
because if I say something need not be true;
as I would say that it is not essential
that you should believeevery word I say.
On the contrary blind faith is against Sahaja Yoga.
It should happen to you first,
once it happens then you will be amazed
that you yourself is a very great
miraculous instrument of God.
You will be amazed, how this instrument works.
Even the people who come to Me, say,
“Mother we are gone cases we are good for nothing,
we led a very bad life we are inauspicious.”
Every sort of thing, I said, "Now
let it be, you don't judge yourself.
Let the Divine judge you, let's see what happens to you.
Why are you after yourself?
Forget it, first of all you did mistakes,
doesn't matter, but now you are using that again to harm yourself.
So please forget all the mistakes, everything that has been done,
all wrong things you think you have done.
Only you get what you have."
I am here just to give that what you have.
Now this great happening takes place
in such a smooth way in people who are normal people.
But not in all people I would say.
Some people do not feel it because they have some abnormalities
in their different centers which are placed within you.
These are the subtle centers expressed outside as gross centers.
They are all the time there,
but the deities within them are not yet enlightened.
They only get enlightened when the Kundalini rises
and pierces through the fontanel bone area.
Now the Spirit resides in the heart.
The Spirit is the reflection of God Almighty,
and Holy Ghost is the Power of God,
the Shakti of God which manifest everything else.
You'll be amazed how in the gross these things can be seen,
absolutely into the grossest thing.
My son in law is a great photographer
and he was working on Himalaya, ultimately I said you take it
from some old books and find out about it.
So I gave him an idea that you go and see near Manasarovar.
There is a place called Manasarovar
where also you find the Sadashiva is kept,
just like a human face.
Twelve miles of area you can see that it's just a human being,
a face of a human being which is called as Dakshinamurthy,
which is looking towards the south.
And this one is just a - not melted at all,
nothing, is all the time there
and if you see the face there are two other
aspects of Him are shown on His head.
But I told him that in Manasarovar
if you go that is the super ego, Manasa.
Manasa means the emotional mind, you see,
English language is rather funny
but I tell you Manasa means the emotional mind.
There is this emotional mind represented as Manasarovar.
And after that I told him there must be another one.
He said yes there is another one which is called as Rakshastal.
Rakshasa you know, the word Rakshasa means a devil - Rakshastal.
And now that Rakshastal is so turbulent
despite the fact they are close to each other
and between them is placed this Sadhashiva's image,
but this Rakshastal is so turbulent
that one can't believe that the same,
at the same place these two are having a different type of nature.
And those people who went with him could not even touch that
water of that Rakshastal, because it represented the ego,
less they become ego oriented, so they would not touch it.
So this was nothing, you see there are so many things in the gross
you can make it out whatever is described in the old times
is there existing, it is there.
In the same way human beings are in the intermediate state
and if you go even subtler
you'll find all these centers are within you.
Now how can you prove through Kundalini
that what I am saying is true?
That we have to see for oneself because in the West
I have to go on convincing people, convincing people,
pleading them for their realization.
Just for getting realization I have to put all, put forward
all kinds of explanations, all kinds of suggestions
that they should believe that they can get Self-realization.
There are people also who say, “How can you get it so easily?”
But if I say you can, why not try it, what's the harm?
It is so difficult to convince a
mind which is all the time thinking about it,
you can't think about it.
You can't think about a sprouting of the seed, it just works out,
if you put a seed in the mother earth it just works out.
You don't have to think,
if you start thinking about it, will it sprout? It will not.
It is the capacity of the mother earth that does the job.
But that time we take it for granted.
In the same way if I say you can get your Self-realization,
people start being doubtful about it.
Another thing is, that it is the other way round,
it is you who has to take something
not that I have to take anything from you.
You cannot give Me anything, it's you who has to benefit by it,
not Me. So why there should be a question
when I am not selling anything,
when I am not acquiring anything out of you,
when there is no possibility of you being exploited
or plundered by Me or used by Me.
Why should you get this doubt in your mind?
Is it also that you feel doubtful about yourself?
But that is to be decided by the Divine and not by you.
So please first of all try to know that you are the Spirit
and that you have to become the Spirit
and that once you become the Spirit
you become collectively conscious.
Today only when I went for this interview for the ABC,
the gentleman was -
of course interviewed Me, when I came out there was a lady.
And I told the lady that you have got liver trouble.
She asked Me, "How do you know, did he tell you?"
I said, "Nobody told Me, but I know because I know."
So that's what happens to you, that you become
collectively conscious, you can feel it on your hands
what's wrong with others and with yourself.
Now when we come to this
point of realization, we have to know
that the problems of this world are due to one fact,
that we have not achieved our absolute.
Some people think by doing alternate work we’ll be happier.
If supposing somebody is a capitalist he’ll become a communist.
Then if he is the communist, he’ll become a socialist.
These are all manufactures of this brain.
But actually if you ask, I'm a
complete capitalist because I have all the powers
and I am a complete communist
because I can’t live without giving it to you.
So how the communism and capitalism, which is so artificial outside,
becomes a reality with you, that you become empowered
with your real powers and not unreal powers
because possessions and things are unreal.
They are not real powers,
and once you get these real powers you want to share it with others.
You want to give it to others, you want to work it out for others.
And under these modern circumstances where we think
we are very frustrated and we are unhappy,
that's why we are going to God, is a wrong statement.
You are coming to God because you have been seekers
of ages.
You have been seeking long time back
and this is the time, the fruit of it is coming.
I've met so many children, even in Australia, who are born realized.
Great saints are taking their birth today
just to do this God's work
and you will find that you are one of them who has been seeking.
In Nala Damayanthi Puran, which was written
I think sixteen thousand years back,
it is mentioned that this Nala got very angry with Kali -
Kali is the one who governs this modern times -
and He said, "I am going to kill you,
because you create confusion in the minds of people,
you create complete confusion of values,
and you make them destroy themselves.
So I better destroy you once for all,
so there is no problem for human beings."
So Kali said, "All right you can destroy Me
but I have some good points,
you must know also the importance of My being there."
He said, "What is your importance?" He said, "The importance is
that when I will come on this earth to rule
that time, these people who are now
wondering in the Himalayas, wondering in the hills
and dales all over the world who are seeking
outside the cities, outside the houses
will find the answer.
They will find the God Almighty.
They will find their Spirit!”
He said it about sixteen thousand years back
and that is today has started.
The point where we have to
be really sure is, that this is the time.
Because the signs and symptoms are like that.
You can’t imagine so many people seeking
anywhere in the world,
anytime. When even Christ came
it was so difficult to carry those twelve people with Him.
Nobody was seeking at the time.
He of course gave sermons, He talked about it
that is the last, we can say,
who was such a great Incarnation on this earth,
but nobody listened to Him.
After that Mohammed came. When He lived how people treated Him!
They tried to poison Him, they tried to torture Him
and He had such a miserable life
that the Muslims today when they behave in the same manner,
it is most surprising that whatever He has suffered
the people have to support, suffer at the hands of these Muslims.
There are other also ideas people have got
like we must suffer for our emancipation;
or we must cleanse ourselves.
Already somebody has suffered for us.
There is no need for you to suffer and do all these things.
As I said that Jews believed in it and they denied Christ.
Then they suffered, really they suffered,
but after that suffering was there any transformation?
On the contrary they were so embittered
the way they behave while killing these PLO-people,
you will be amazed, the same people who suffered so badly
forgot all that and became such cruel people
and they killed so many people.
So this kind of a suffering doesn't bring
any kind of transformation within you.
Transformation has to take place,
this is the condition of your Self.
If the Self is manifesting,
it is not that you believe in this and I believe in that,
It IS! It's no question of believing, IT IS so!
That is what it is, nothing to be believed into blindly
or to be professed into or to accept something,
but it is there within you and that is an absolute truth.
Even if there are ten small children sitting
and they are realized souls
and if you ask them, "What is the condition of this gentleman?"
They will all raise one finger. This means only one thing,
because they can feel it, on their finger something burning,
maybe something numb, maybe something heavy.
All of them, even if you tie their eyes, will say the same thing
because truth is the same.
As all of us are sitting here we know it's night
and that the colour of this thing is greenish or whatever it is.
In the same way, when you get your realization, the feeling,
the awareness comes in your feeling and this feeling
tells you exactly where you are and what you have to do.
It is a remarkable thing that you are a human being.
Is the greatest work of God,
the greatest creation of God is human being.
Of course you may think they are ugly
and you should have nothing to do with them.
There are some people who just believe that
human beings are the ugliest thing. But they are not!
Only thing, they have not been put to the mains,
this is yoga, is the union with the Divine.
Unless and until an instrument is put to the mains,
to its source, it has no meaning.
In the same way unless and until
you are put to the mains, you will have no meanings.
So the best thing is for you to be convinced
that you have to have your realization
and it can work out in a split of a second and let it work out.
Just work it out is the best for you that anyone can
suggest that you become the Self.
Now about the Self I have talked many a times, I told people
that Self is the one that is residing in your heart.
But the seat of the Self is here, the Sadhashiva.
He stands here and when the Kundalini rises and touches that,
the seat sends message to the Heart
and then the Heart starts feeling throwing those vibrations.
Actually it is not the Spirit that does
but it is the Kundalini after enlightenment starts pulsating.
It’s so clear-cut, you can’t imagine,
it is so beautiful, you can’t imagine.
Now the result of this Self-realization -
in this short time I have to cover many points
and that's why I am trying to cover it up -
is first of all you get your physical
fitness. People ask Me, "How could You cure physically?"
If you are doctors here, you will understand
that doctors do not know anything about
parasympathetic nervous system.
That is the expression of the central path
within us called as the Sushumna Nadi.
This parasympathetic nervous system gives us the balance,
the sustenance.
For example, if you are running fast your heartbeat increases.
But it is slowed down
by the action of parasympathetic nervous system.
When the Kundalini is awakened this parasympathetic nervous system
becomes evident in our awareness.
First time the Spirit starts becoming
one with our attention.
Our attention itself becomes enlightened.
Now when this Kundalini rises,
this parasympathetic nervous system starts manifesting itself
and whatever center is exhausted
by which an imbalance is created within us
in our physical body or in our emotional body
or in our mental body or in our spiritual body,
it starts absolutely
behaving in a manner as if we have reached our total blessings.
It just disappears, it just disappears.
And it is so surprising, that people don't want to believe it
because they have seen a person behaving this manner and that manner
and suddenly next day overnight they find
the person who is an alcoholic becomes a free bird.
They find a drug addict becoming a free bird,
they can’t believe it. It is fantastic!
Everything that God does is fantastic.
All His work we have taken for granted,
at least this living work of God
you can understand that it works within you.
It is beyond all your dogmas,
all your philosophies, all your complications.
Because it is unlimited,
while your brain is limited, your intelligence is limited.
And if you want to understand God
you cannot understand It
by this limited thing, which is your brain.
Of course logically you can come to conclusion.
You have to come to conclusion logically understanding that
you cannot pay for it, you cannot work it out,
it has to be spontaneous
and you cannot do it yourself.
Everything you can do it yourself,
but realization has to be worked out
by somebody who is an enlightened person.
For example if I work it out for any one of you,
that person can work it out for others.
This is so simple as that and I think
it is high time that we should go in for realization,
we have so many people and I won't be able to attend to you,
if I continue with the speech.
Is it all right for you to have the realization now?
Just open any window here, either air condition or anything.
If you do not treat yourself with respect,
nobody can treat you with respect.
So be respectful about it and try to
get the blessings of realization,
that would be a nice idea.
By the way we have now been able to
get some people to work in Adelaide
for you to go further with your realization
and understanding what it is,
to learn the technique of it.
And once you learn the technique
you will find it will help you a lot to help others.
And if you are intelligent enough you can do it very well.
Will you please all put your hands towards Me
like this, just like that.
Those who don't want to do it
should please go away and leave us alone,
I would request you those who don't want to do
meditation should go away
and don't disturb others because it spoils the vibrations of people,
so those who don't want to do it please go away.
You don't want to do it?
Can I ask a question?
No, no, no question today, I have had enough
of questions this morning, will you please go.
No you can write, all right.
You can write to Me, you see the questions I had too many
and I want to attend to everyone.
You remember last time how much I had to work
and I couldn't attend to everyone.
So it's better not to attend to anybody's personal questions,
it's not proper because I want to give attention to you all.
You see, if you have any questions you may write to Me
and I'll let you know. Please put your hands towards Me.
All of you should do it. Those who do not want to do it, again I say
please be civil and kind
and go away as proper people, and don't try to disturb us.
Please put your hands towards Us.
You may write your questions
and come and see Me tomorrow morning, all right?
If you have any questions, I'll give you special time.
You have also questions? All right,
so can you go out now and write down.
Why not? You cannot force yourself to be here,
it is very wrong. You want to force.
Why?
No that's not I am not going to waste any time with you, but
is very unkind of you to force us like that.
We never come to your meetings, why should you come to our meeting
and disturb us? It's not proper.
It's all right, forget it now!
We have, I have nothing to talk, no no it's all right,
don't disturb us, please, please will you behave yourself, or ask him to get out.
"Why do you call yourself God?”
All right, forget it just now,
you are God is it? What good have you done to anyone
that you are here to object Me?
Have you done any good to anyone so far? Not even to yourself.
Then, why don’t you allow Me to do good to others?
All right. Now don't talk!
Keep your hands like this.
I could see the way he is,
I could see that, immediately I pointed out,
you see among all. All right keep yourself shut!
You only know how to talk, you have a big mouth,
that’s all, nothing more.
Please close your eyes.
With both hands towards Me,
you just close your eyes and don't worry about others,
just think of yourself just now
that you have to have this experience.
So many people had experience in the last meeting
and you all should have it.
Even if you are thinking it does not matter.
Let loose your attention, don't put any pressure on your attention.
Just let loose your attention.
Now as I told you the left hand
is the power of your desire.
And the right side is the power of your action.
So with your left hand on your lap in a very relaxed manner
you raise your right hand to your heart, to your heart
and ask a question within yourself, not loudly,
'Mother am I the Spirit?'
Just put your hand right on your heart.
Left hand towards Me, left hand towards Me, just ask a question,
'Mother am I the Spirit?'
Now put this right hand on your stomach on the left hand side
which is the center of your
guru, the primordial master.
As you are the master of yourself,
you just say, 'Mother, I am the master.'
'Am I the master?' we asked the other day,
today you say, 'Mother, I am my own guru , I am my own master.’
With full confidence you should say.
You should understand it fully within yourself
that unless and until you become a master,
you cannot make out who is true, who is not true.
You cannot make it out! So first of all you become the master.
Put your right hand
on your stomach on the left hand side and ask a question,
if you have come today for the first time.
But those who've got realization
the other day must say, ’Mother, I am the master.
I am the guru.'
You don't need any guru because your Spirit is the guru.
Your Spirit is the guru! Just awaken your Spirit.
Now again raise your hand higher on the heart
and say,
'Mother, I am the Spirit.’  Just say that.
Now put this right hand
on the left side of your neck
which is another center of Vishuddhi.
You are yourself raising your own Kundalini.
At this center you have to say, 'Mother, I am not guilty.'
Say it again, not to feel guilty for anything
that you think you have done wrong.
Just say, 'Mother, I 'm not guilty.'
Because the instrument that you are
has to be cured by the Divine.
Because you have to do God's work. This is God's work!
Unless and until you feel
completely relieved of your guilt,
how can you work out God's things?
If you have said mantras or something in unauthorised way,
also you develop this trouble on the left side
which is a very dangerous thing to develop
and thus you develop a heart trouble
and can be at a very early age,
you might suffer from a heart trouble.
So better say, 'Mother, I'm not guilty.’ If you are the Spirit
then how can you be guilty?
There is another danger that lies while saying all these mantras
that one can develop diseases like cancer,
osteomalayetie and all these by saying wrong mantras,
guided by some wrong gurus.
So if you have done anything like that
you have to say, 'Mother, I'm not guilty.’
It can have very serious effects, very serious effects,
specially the muscular part can be absolutely
paralysed on the left side.
Now put your right hand across the forehead
and say,
'Mother, I forgive everyone.’
This you have to say with full heart and full understanding
because the other day, you remember
that when you said it, immediately you got your realization.
Before that it was all blocked up in the blockage.
You have to forgive, forgive others,
forgive others! If you have self esteem
then you will respect others also, otherwise you cannot have respect.
If you do not respect yourself, you cannot respect others.
The first thing is you must say, 'I forgive everyone.’
Not to get upset by what has happened
or what somebody does to you, but just to say, 'I forgive everyone.’
Some people say it is difficult to forgive
but I think it is a myth.
Because when you forgive what do you do? You just
are forgiving yourself
because you are not anymore suffering
from the embitterment from others.
Now put the same hand on top of your head.
First on top of your Sahasrara.
Now you have to see, it has to work, it has to work out,
it's not just talking, but it has to work out.
Now see for yourself,
raise your hand a little higher.
At this stage you have to ask for realization,
because I cannot cross your freedom.
So say, 'Mother, please give us realization" at this point.
just put your hand
parallel to your fontanel bone area.
Now put the other hand and see
if there is a cool breeze coming out.
Put your right hand towards Me,
just put your right hand towards Me,
whether you are sick or anything, you just work it out.
It's there, yes.
You have to convince yourself.
Nobody can convince you, it is you who has to convince yourself.
You have to feel it yourself.
If you are not feeling it, then there is something wrong with you.
Doesn't matter, we'll work it, it should, it should work out.
If you are not feeling it then is not correct.
Now you can also change again the hand and say that -
find for yourself,
and ask a question, 'Is this the
cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?' Ask a question.
Now rapport is established, just see for yourself.
See now how you are feeling cooler with the same
thing, is because you have become yourself an air conditioner.
That's why you all are feeling cooler
otherwise you all are feeling so hot.
Where is that heat gone now? Just see the proof.
If there is too much heat that means you are either
a liver patient or some disease there which is to be attended.
See for yourself.
If you, even if you are paid by some guru,
better get your realization
because they can give you only money,
which you can't take with you. Better take your realization,
to be wise and sensible, be good children.
Take your realization! This is the chance of lives!
Now put your both the hands like that
and ask a question in your heart,'Is this the
breeze of the Holy Ghost we are feeling?'
You will start feeling the cool breeze in your hands,
the sensation crawling down your hands.
All right? Now put your hands towards Me.
I'll also teach you how to give realization.
I'll try to teach you how to give yourself a realization
which is a very simple method of maintaining your realization.
Apart from that
there are going to be some sahaja yogis here
who are going to help you to progress further.
This hand is to be placed in front of your
Kundalini like this, this is the
fixed hand, you can say the fixed movement,
and this right hand is to be taken round like this.
higher in front and down. Everything should be intelligible,
you should understand why we do it. You see clockwise method
is better to raise the Kundalini. Now do it,
it's not just to tell some
mantras to someone and you jump like a frog,
it's really, it should happen in a way that is happening.
Now put your hands like that. Now take it down.
Again we have to give a knot up there,
it's the raising of the Kundalini. Let's do again.
The truth is so abounding, that you deny it is dishonesty,
is dishonesty, complete dishonesty!
Now take it up, one more. Now weave it up.
Do it one more, now thrice you have to do it, one,
two,
three. Now see for yourself.
All right?
You feel very peaceful.
The other day I had a lady who came quite stunned,
she could not believe that she is so much changed
and she said, “I have become a free person now.”
All right? Good.
So thank you very much and if you have any other problem
of some disease or anything
you can come and see Me now.