So first of all we’ll start talking about
energies.
Shri Mataji to someone: That, is that for
me?
These energies are moving within us and how
they activate and we’ll talk about the third
energy which is the one which has evolved
us within us and that’s how we are here.
And we’ll talk about your Self, the controlling
part, which is controlling you, the Spirit.
So if you go on an abstract line, it will
be very appealing [?] with it.
Then afterwards, you see, when we have talked
about energies, this, that, once the people-
that is within you- you see, sort of they’ll
feel ego, this ego: “we have these energies
we can utilize these energies, do this, do
that” and then you’ll bring them down
to Sahaja Yoga, later on.
But to begin with, better talk of abstract.
Because Indians are different, Western people
are different, they are fed up of religion,
they are fed up of all this.
So if you talk of religion, it gives, creates
a problem.
That’s why in the beginning, you see, Vedas,
they were written down.
They didn’t talk of God or Deities at all.
They talked about God, God the Creator, but
just about Brahmadeva, throughout Hiranyagarbha,
Brahmadeva, right side they talked, you see.
And the all thing is said, mantra is like
: “Bhur, Bhuvah, swaha”.
3 things.
Now, Bhur is actually the Mooladhara, is the
earth upper it, the Mooladhara.
Mooladhara chakra and Mooladhara itself.
Then Bhuvah.
Bhuvah is the one which is called the antariksha
[atmosphere, intermediate space], is the one
which is all created, in talks of Brahmadeva.
Then swaha.
Swaha is capacity to burn out, of the agny
[fire] you see?
It is so surprising and then they talk of
mahatapa, tapaha and maha.
“Bhur, Bhuvah, swaha, maha tapa”.
So when they talk of swaha, they talk of maha.
Maha is what you call the great, Allah Hou
Akbar, and of tapa.
Tapa is the one where you have to become a
tapasuy, means a person who is going into
penance, that of Christ.
And they say that you have to penetrate through
the Surya, that is this.
And the all thing is such an obstacle, and
then you get your moksha [liberation].
So they have talked of all the charkas.
But if you talk about the abstract part of
it, people have no objection, they listen
to it, listen as [inaudible] there’s no
religion as such.
[Cut in the audio?]
Today specially I’m talking about the Vedas
and these havanas we do.
When we do the havana it is a Yagnya.
Yagnya means “by which you know”.
Yagnya means to know.
Yagna.
And this is done where you use ‘Svaha’
as the word.
That means you use the principle of fire to
burn off all that is wrong in you, ‘Svaha’.
And you awaken it by taking the different
names of the God.
And it started at the time of Rama.Today is
Ram Navami.
I should say it was not started, we should
say, but it was very much invoked when Rama
lived and they used to do Yagnyas at that
time.
The reason was, the people had just started
realising that there is something higher and
you have to worship that higher Self, the
seers had said, and they thought that the
best thing is to do Yagnyas.
[Inaudible] On the left side, of course, the
people started the worship of God and the
dedication to God and all those things, that
is Bhakti[, [devotion] but mainly what they
did before Rama was the Yagnyas, the Vedas,
with which they prayed to different elements-
elements have made our charkas – and tried
to evoke the deities of the Elements.
But actually it amounts to the same.
So as a child, Rama was studying with a very
great saint, and when he was studying with
him, Vashishta was the name of the great saint.
And Vashishta had an ashram where Rama and
his brothers studied.
Shri Mataji to a lady: come along, come in,
come forward.
Give her a chair to sit down.
Can you, is there a seat here?
I think Gavin can go, lots of seats are there.
Rama was studing with this Vashishta and they
used to come for holidays to father’s place.
Then, he had the capacity to kill a demon
with only one arrow.
It’s called as Ekabani, one arrow was sufficient
of Sri Rama.
And he was a small little child, say about
seven-eight years of age and people were surprised
how he could do it.
So whenever they had a Yagnya- now these Yagnyas
were created to awaken, evoke the Deities
within the spinal column actually.
And for these Yagnyas they used to sit down
and do all these havanas the way we do it.
But at that time, the Rakshasas would come
and try to spoil the Yagnya.
Because Yagnyas are to be done with pure heart
and with cleanliness and with purity.
It should not be insulted, there is a protocol
about it.
While they thought that if we insult the Deities
there, then the Deities will disappear and
their Yagnyas will be spoiled.
Now these Yagnyas were done, in the olden
times even, even when Rama was not here.
But at the time of Rama also, there were some
Rakshasas who took a special pleasure in spoiling
these Yagnyas and Rama as a child would go
and protect them from the demons.
And the demons would take on some sort of
a funny form, and come like invisible creatures
and put some bones of animals and things like
that in the Yagnya.
And that would spoil the effects of the Yagnya.
And Rama would protect that, as a child.
Imagine, as a child he used to do that.
They would be doing the Yagnya and he would
be sitting outside with all his small brothers
around him and they would kill the demons
who would try to destroy the Yagnya.
This is the early life of Rama in which you
see how, as a child also, he showed us amount
of expertise, you can say, in arrow and bow,
you see.
So any time you see a statue, how to make
out if it’s Shri Rama’s statue?
Is to see if there’s an arrow and a bow,
then its a Rama’s statue.
Now his coming on this earth, gave us the
development of the right side and so the Yagnyas
were also on the right side.
Because first of all when human beings came
on this earth, they were frightened of all
the animals who would invade them and all
kinds of horrible Rakshasas and all those
people, and negative forces that would trouble
them.
In that state they needed to create a king,
a ruler, who was an ideal king and who would
rule according to the laws of dharma.
So He was the one in charge of that era, what
you call as Satya Yuga, but actually, He was
here in Treta Yuga.
That’s the time when He as here, that’s
Treta Yuga, and Krishna came at the lime of
Dwapara Yuga.
And today is the time, when I came, it was
Kali Yuga.
But now today the time is of Krita Yuga, the
Yuga where work will be done: “Krita”
means, “work will be done”.
This is the time where work will be done.
So how things have moved from one to another?
Now in the Dwapara [Shri Mataji means Treta]
Yuga when Shri Rama came, the idea of kingship
and rulership started.
So the greatest emphasis was on the goodwill
of the people.
The people had to have goodwill, for the people
and for the king, and for the betterment of
humanity.
The will: that is the right side.
So how to create the goodwill in people?
First the leader has to sacrifice and show
how far he can go in sacrificing to keep the
moral and the goodwill of the people.
So the right side was created by the advent
of Shri Rama, because he showed a path of
creating among people the awareness that they
should be ruled, that they should not be anarchists,
there should be one head who should be able
to organize, co-ordinate and work out a collective
thing.
You see, when we think of a king we want to
oust him because we don’t like the idea
of being ruled by him, because he’s not
a good king perhaps, or he doesn’t represent
that will of the people which is a common
will, which creates this king who rules for
the maintenance of that goodwill.
See it as a symbolic expression of your “goodwill”.
So when you create a law, it is also the expression,
common expression, of all the common people,
of the common feeling that they should abide
with law.
It doesn’t come to you that you are a slave,
or you have to be dominated, or you have to
be put down, but it is only your “common
will” which is good.
The desire of all the people which is the
good, the righteousness, incarnates as Shri
Rama and He looks after that will.
Because, supposing an individual may start
saying that: ‘This is not good, this is
not good”.
An individual might take a different attitude
about these things.
But you must have some symbol of that goodness
placed onto someone.
And those symbols were created to symbolise
your righteousness, your sense of good, so
that you can be saved yourself.
Supposing today somebody comes and hits you,
alright?
Now you can feel how bad it is to be hit by
someone or murdered by someone or else, so
you decide there should be a law protecting
you.
But tomorrow you may do the same thing.
So what you do is to take out your goodwill,
represent it as the kingdom or a king or a
governing body.
So, the government as it is represents, should
represent also its both ways, it’s not that
it always represents it, it may not at all
represent it, may not, possibly.
But the government itself should represent
the good in you, the purity in you, the pure
will to be good, to be protected and that
you also should abide by it.
It’s a very mutual thing.
But what happens, that once you start electing
someone like that, or making someone like
that, or appointing someone like that, as
usual he goes into an ego trip, simple thing
like that.
It’s absolutely a simple thing.
Ego trip.
The government gets into an ego trip, people
get, you see, amazed how people behave.
They’ll elect, supposing, a Prime Minister
and suddenly you find the Prime Minister behaves
like a brute.
You can’t understand.
“We have elected somebody like a Prime Minister
thinking that he will do the good to us.”
You see, it’s possible.
And then the revolutions take place while
people revolt, fight it out.
Again the will of the people fights it and
makes it alright.
Shri Mataji to someone: Come along.
Come here forward, you can come forward.
Ah.
So.
So we have to have something absolute, you
see, because all these values are changing
every moment, isn’t it ? We think that this
government did not do so well, for example,
we think like that, so, we want to demolish
this government.
Then you bring another one.
We find the same thing happening.
See, whether you bring a communist or you
bring a socialist or you bring a democrat
or you have a monarchy, whatever you may have.
But still, what happens actually is that,
all these things that come up and go away-
Shri Mataji to someone: Now, you’ll come
here, then you move forward a little bit so
that every body can see.
All these changes that take place, go on creating
a feeling in a man that he should be anarchist.
Why should we have any government ? Why should
we have any king?
Why should we be ruled by anyone ? Because
you find the person who’s ruling is not
up to the mark and he is just trying to deceive
you.
At that point you have to have some absolute
standards.
If you have an absolute standard then you
can always judge that this king is deviating
from the right path, is not doing what a king
should do.
A king has to be like Rama.
He has to be like Rama.
Representing your will, your goodwill, your
sense of proper judgement, fair play and righteousness.
If the king is not righteous then your collective
goodwill will go against the king.
Now you go and throwing one from another.
Say, I’ve seen now for example in France.
We had one kind of a Prime Minister.
He did lots of things which were not good
so he was thrown away.
So you had another one kind of, now he’s
doing another thing so he’s going to be
thrown away.
And we are just playing games you see.
First of all we have say Labour Government.
We don’t like it.
So then we have another Government, Conservative
Government.
We don’t like it so throw it away.
We go on playing with it all the time.
But in this relativity, we are improving.
Definitely we are more aware, understanding
the value of these people, and also the public
is understanding.
But then when, you see, too many such people
come in, who are negative, they also bring
down the will, the collective will very low.
And people start identifying themselves with
these autocrats or those people who are ego
orientated, who have no moral values, who
have no fear of God, who deny religion, who
deny evolution.
And the Government starts behaving in such
a manner that you are amazed that how this
is the Government?
Like in Chile and Argentina, the way the Government
is behaving and is putting down the people.
All these things are happening, you don’t
know.
It’s such a relative terminology.
Like El Salvador.
You don’t know what to do over there now.
Whom to support ? Whether to support the Americans,
or to support the Russians and all that.
Now under these circumstances a Sahaja Yogi
can stand and say: “now, should we join
this or that?”
All is a wasteful thing.
It’s just a game going on.
Let them break their heads.
They are good for nothing, useless people.
So you cannot solve these problems and you
are not supposed to solve them.
They must get their Realization and establish
the Kingdom of God.
So really Rama rules [must be] on this earth
and not these horrible kings who change their
morality every day, who change their ideas
every day, those whose will is sometimes for
something materialistic.
Like I would say now in our country [U.K.]
we thought that we’ll have Mrs. Thatcher.
Good, very good, she’s coming up well I
should say, certain good things she is saying,
like self-restrain and all that.
We think she’s talking good things.
But what about herself following this?
Shri Rama, not only propounded what was good
but he followed that.
He sacrificed for that and he established
his own symbol as a pure symbol of that righteous
will, that is within the people, which is
the collective righteous will.
Now, for example, you can see clearly how
the ego oriented things work out, you see,
first of all by the misidentifications we
can have.
“Now if you’re a communist, you have to
be out and out communist, you cannot have
compromise between democratic methods and
communist” They can’t find any integration.
They think: “If you have to be this you
have to be absolutely this.
If you have to be that, you have to be absolutely
that.”
But in Sahaja Yoga, what you find, is that
both are integrated.
Because you have the complete capitalism,
you have now to distribute it.
This is a complete integration here.
All these ‘isms’ are experiments of the
artificial of the mind, just a projection
of the mind, which is, whatever is man-made
is artificial, you know that.
But what is God made is all integrated, that
whatever you have within yourself, you must
give it to others.
Now see for administration also, what happens
after Sahaja Yoga.
Say, I am your Mother, here sitting down.
You like me to guide you.
You like me to govern you.
You like me to correct you, you like me to
scold you and to even go to a great extend
to see that your life improves.
Supposing I say: “Alright, I give up.
I don’t want to talk about it.”
You don’t like, none of you will like such
a situation, where I say: “Alright you are
a gone case, I have nothing to do.
You get out.”
Nobody will like such a situation.
You want me to govern you.
You want me to look after you.
You like that, automatically you have started
liking it.
There’s no domination, but you want my domination.
You want me to dominate you.
You want that all my desire should be dominating.
Automatically.
Why you feel that: “ it is alright, it is
very good if Mother takes interest in me,
corrects me, it’s a privilege.”
Why do you think like that?
Because by that there is a general good created.
It’s a general good created in you.
Because you have become integrated, your body,
your mind and your soul, all of them think
the same way, they all want the same, there’s
no difference.
Once there is integration, you’ll find that
Sahaja Yoga is the easiest way to live in.
But if there is not, then it is difficult.
For exemple, if you are a lazy person, say
for example, or you are a very hot tempered
person or you are a sort of a dual person,
or you are playing tricks with yourself, you
are playing games.
Then you won’t like Sahaja Yoga.
As long as these situations are in you, you
will not like Sahaja Yoga.
But once this situation is overcome, then
you will like it, because then you will know
that whatever is good for your Spirit is for
the well-being of you all, and of all the
people.
Once this well-being comes in, everyone feels
absolutely nourished and fresh.
So the governing part is enjoyable.
The correction part is even more enjoyable
and that you are in the attention of your
Mother is such a great feeling within yourself
that: “yes nothing will go wrong with me,
She’ll look after me.
She’s there to look after me”.
But this integration part comes very late
because of ego problems.
You have built up egos because of wrong type
of people administering you.
From your childhood, you might have had bad
parents who never talked of God, of good things
of life.
They themselves did not lead a life of sacrifice.
Very self indulgent parents can create a problem
like that.
They never gave you the right type of life,
a proper value system which should have been
there.
They never educated how to enjoy righteousness,
virtues in life.
Possibly, later on the country in which you
are born, the other people who surround you,
also might have done that.
Also, your government, whichever you have
known, must have done that.
So when these things change, when you find
that you have achieved that kind of integration
within you, that whatever your body likes,
is the good for your Spirit also.
Like say for example, I don’t like certain
things myself.
I don’t like things, I don’t like it.
I just don’t like it, nobody can tempt me.
I mean, no question of temptation, I just
don’t like.
I will hate the things which are really bad
for my Spirit.
Automatically.
I don’t have to tell myself; it’s just
there.
To tell lies I don’t like, allright, because
it harms me there.
I don’t like it.
Whatever is good for your Spirit will automatically
work out as soon as this integration takes
place, and this is the work of Sahaja Yoga
today.
That’s why I said it is Krita Yuga, is to
be done.
And this integration must be achieved within
ourselves, so sometimes you have to make your
body come to this level.
May be you are under the influence of some
bhoots.
Your body doesn’t help you.
Little bit of tapasyas or penance is needed
after Sahaja Yoga to make this possible and
then once you start enjoying, then you like
it.
Like driving a car.
In the beginning it’s difficult.
Or swimming.
Anything, when you try to do it, it’s rather
difficult in the beginning.
If I say you forget it now, whatever you have
done in the past now forget it’ You have
to get to the new things now.
You have to do it.
So you have to put your mind to it with all
your full zest.
That “Alright, if my body’s not helping
me then I’ll try to improve the body because
I’m not the body.
If my mind is not helping me, I must improve
my mind.
If my intellect is standing in the way I’ll
have to put my intellect right because after
all I have to be integrated.
If I am not integrated I’m not going to
enjoy anything nor am I going to do anything
good to myself or to others.
So why am I here ? Why am I trying to destroy
myself ?” But when you are disintegrated
you’ll be surprised.
your one action will destroy your second action
and your second action will destroy your third
action.
When you are disintegrated.
I’ll give you an example.
Supposing I am sitting here and somebody tells
me that this will burn you.
This is my own maya, but the body wants to
burn itself.
It says : no, don’t listen to this, just
go ahead.
Now, when I say this it sounds absurd.
But say, the mind says you should not take
to alcohol but still you’ll go to the pub.
Then you are disintegrated.
Gradually once you start listening to your
body too much, your mind gives in.
It just gives in.
In everything that you do, if you are integrated
you’ll be amazed that you’ll really become
dynamic.
Integration is nothing but your complete connection
with your Spirit.The Spirit starts flowing
into you.
In every walk of life you’ll be amazed how
dynamic you’ll become if you’re integrated.
Just the connection is to be absolutely achieved
with your Spirit.
Whenever you think of something: “Is it
good for my Spirit ? ”
Some people have a habit of thinking that
spiritual life is such that you hang by the
shoestrings somewhere in the air with no connection
to the day to day life.
So many people think like that.
They think: “Such a man should be a thin,
miserable creature hanging onto some tree
or something, and should be absolutely in
a paranoid state or something who is frightened
of the whole world, who cannot talk to anyone,
who is so much exclusive that he becomes a
recluse.
These absurd ideas should to be given up by
Sahaja Yogis.
You have to be very much there, absolutely
there between all of them, but something:
you should be rare, a different type, a unique
personality.
You are to be there with alI these things
that are going on.
Now people are frightened, you know, even
of Sahaja Yogis.
They re frightened of Sahaja Yogis, they see
somebody negative, they say: “Oh, this thing,
that thing.”
Now take a fight with that person.
Take a fight.
How could you dare to do this, such a thing?
You are a Sahaja Yogi.
Come up.
What do you mean by this?
You have to fight it out.
As long as possible you should try to salvage
a person, talk to him in that manner.
The other side of it is that when you talk
to others, when they come to you, then there
has to be a kind of a tremendous sincerity
within.
If you are doing with that sincerity, people
will know you are doing with sincerity.
When you talk to a person, they should know
that sincerity of heart is there.
For example, you may talk to that person very
sweetly, but your heart may not be there and
the person might think, “Oh, he’s just
giving me lectures.”
Alright?
But if you talk to someone with a sincerity
you’d say, “How could you do such a thing?
Can’t you see yourself?
Can’t you work it out?
That’s what it is.
You are here for that.”
Now in saying so, your sincerity, which is
coming from your heart, is to be seen, and
that’s what is Shri Rama’s character is,
that he was on the right side of the heart,
means the heart put to activity.
Do you understand that, where Kabira has said:
” Mana mamta ko thir kara Launga” I will
make my compassion of my heart, mana, from
my heart, the compassion, make it steady.
”Pancho tattva main Launga” and put them
into five elements.
See, in the same way, when you are in the
left hear, that’s your sincerity, it’s
your ‘heart-felt’ thing.
But the heartfelt thing, what’s the use,
you see.
There are many Sahaja Yogis who really feel,
this world is horrible and something must
be done, Sahaja Yoga must be brought in.
But how many of you are really putting that
into action?
Absolutely into action.
Without that, your Rama’s tattva cannot
be improved.
Rama’s tattva is only improved when you
put all the things into action; that’s exactly
Shri Rama did.
So in the ascent of man, when he came up to
Ramas place, the advent of Rama was not in
the centre, but on the right hand side.
He moved aside so much so, that he forgot
about his past.
It’s never mentioned that He’s an Incarnation.
He never told His father.
He never told his mother.
He never told anybody that He was an Incarnation.
Of course it was evident that he was.
His brother knew about it.
Now he had two brothers.
Very interesting.
I mean he had other brothers also, but Bharat
and another one Lakshmana, these two brothers,
now they show the two sides of a human being.
One was Lakshmana and he was a fiery type,
you see.
He couldn’t bear anybody misbehaving towards
Rama.
He couldn’t bear anybody talking in a very
mundane type to Shri Rama and he used to get
so angry with all these people that he would
just come out like a big thunderbolt on anybody
who tried to say anything about Shri Rama.
Even Parshurama, who was there, a contemporary
Incarnation of Shri Rama Himself was Parshurama,
there’s a very interesting story about that.But,
he could not bare Parshurama in any way.