I must thank Warren for such a nice speech
that he has given and all the Australians
the way they have taken to Sahaja Yoga. They
are all westernized in every sense of the
word. There’s something about them where
I feel that they are very quick at knowing
the truth. I don’t know how. They are not
that adamant against the truth. This opening
somehow I found.
Seeking is everywhere very strong I feel America,
England, Europe, everywhere the seeking is
very strong no doubt. There are seekers. Of
course there is also a fashion of seeking
apart from that. There are real seekers, no
doubt about it. And as he has said that ego
orientation is one of the characters in the
West. That also one would say that it is more
now in the developing countries because they
are supposed to be developed. But the way
these people have a special capacity to see
the truth, see the truth is a very big thing.
Even if you are a developing country or a
developed country, if you cannot perceive
the truth, you cannot assimilate it. That
perception some how was surprising, I found
in Australia, was surprising.
Now for example in England I worked very hard,
no doubt, years together. People are hard
nuts, you can say. Once they are cracked they
are wonderful scholars. They know how to completely
sort it out with their brains, everything
is there. But there are very few people who
do that.
At the time of Christ you can see how many
could recognize Him? Not even one, not even
one, believe Me. Except for John the Baptist,
of course he was a realized soul. So, I mean
he should not be in the question. The rest
of them were just sticking on to Him somehow,
as He said that you stick on to Me for some
time. And till He got His resurrection, they
could not see the truth at all. To perceive
it itself is a very big blessing I think.
And I do not know why people cannot perceive
it because I cannot go to the other side and
see Myself what’s the problem is?
For example in this country or in the West,
on the whole, the false people have come.
They have minted money. They have palaces
and they have huge big aircrafts and they
have material things and I mean immense wealth
they have collected out of the people who
are supposed to be westernized. But Sahaja
Yoga, you’ll be amazed even to crack a journalist
is a headache. A journalist doesn’t have
time for Me at all. It’s impossible to go
and talk to any newspaper person, leave alone
any television or anything like that. Radio
is an impossibility. Can you imagine, with
all these facilities God has given you, for
spreading the message fast for the wider world?
But it is impossible you can’t talk to them,
but let some, say a fake person coming, he’s
there. He’s on the televisions, he’s on
the radio, Pope will come and see him. Your
Archbishop of Canterbury will go and touch
his feet. And he is a fake, absolute fake.
Why?
Only thing is that we are very money oriented.
They come out with their money. They provide
lot of money for publication. They take money
and they use it. I mean if Christ was to be
here I tell you He would have no place even
a mike would’ve been difficult for Him being
a carpenter’s Son.
Sometimes I find it an impossible situation
to tell them that after all how are you impressed
by these people who are taking such a lot
of money out of you in the name of God? One
has to think about it that it is so money
oriented that any man who comes with money
impresses people. Amazing in the country,
which is so affluent, they are suffering from
affluence, that’s their disease. And there
they are impressed by people who are using
money as a purpose of propaganda of God Almighty.
Imagine the absurdity. I don’t know what
happens to their brains?
This time I went to Edinburgh and people told
Me that most of the young people are disciples
of a person who will not even be liked by
the servants of India, take it from Me. Even
our servants will take money to go to him.
He doesn’t know good English, even up to
that point you can say. He doesn’t know
anything, how to talk to people. He says he
is fourteen year old which he is not. He’s
married an eight-year-old girl. I mean all
kinds of things. He asked for Rolls Royces,
he has fifty-eight, he wanted a fifty ninth
so they starved themselves and collected money
and gave him the 59th. You the English have
done it, take it from Me.
Can you believe this stupidity? They have
starved themselves and have done it. They
are seekers, seekers of what? Of giving Rolls
Royce to this man? I mean I just can’t understand
how can it go to that stupid level? That’s
what I feel that in Australia people have
not accepted anyone like that. They have not
accepted. They are still you see, they did
this, they did that, He did everything – Warren,
[Bah Kari?] this that. He did everything that
is possible under the Sun. They know all the
gurus, all the gurus have gone to Australia
and they didn’t accept anyone. That’s
the main point. All the time they are shaky
like this and as soon as they saw the truth
they jumped on to it. We have to understand
that Spirit cannot be related to money by
any chance. It has nothing to do.
Christ was a Son of a carpenter. Just think
of that. He, the owner of all the properties
of the world, was born as a poor man. And
how can you relate this to money? I just fail
to understand and this little truth Australians
knew and I wish the English, the Americans
and the Europeans take out their attention
from money and the comfort so called that
money gives you. I am sure, I am sure this
country will rise. It has to rise. It has
to rise.
Unless and until England rises, the world
cannot rise. This is a definite thing. Absolutely
it is as definite as anything. England has
to rise first because it is the heart of the
Universe. And the English Sahaja Yogis have
to also awaken to their responsibilities,
which is very important. I will give all My
blood, all My energies, all that is possible
under the sun to awaken this country to its
responsibility as a Spiritual nature, as the
Spiritual being, as the Spiritual heart, as
the donor of blood, all over. And this is
what saddens Me to see how people are drowning
themselves into some sort of a illusion and
are not being able to see the truth.
Now as he has told you, that Sahaja Yoga is
fantastic, no doubt about, it because you
are fantastic yourself. You are the Spirit;
you are The Spirit. You have to just become
the Spirit is the point. Once you become the
Spirit you are dynamic; not dynamic but you
are the master of everything. You can control
things, you can enjoy everything, you become
blissful. You can do such a lot because you
are the Spirit and you have become the Spirit.
It is as simple as that. God Almighty has
placed this Power within us at the triangular
bone, it exits there.
It has to just rise and give you a real baptism
by which you feel your Spirit first time where
it flows like cool breeze in the hand. As
simple as that.
Now this happening is a very very strong happening.
For some people it’s a very strong happening
– first day, because you are seekers. You
are seekers. Believe Me you are seekers of
thousands of years. Born in this country to
get what you have been seeking. But what do
we expect?
I wish he had not mentioned you the word puja
because it can again give you the thing that
it is sort of a some one-person business.
It’s not that. Warren says puja because
all these centers have got Deities. Especially
this center is the center of Christ. You have
to make these Deities within you happy and
awaken them. And that awakening must take
place; you must understand where these Deities
exist. And these deities are nothing but are
incarnations of God’s aspect like you can
say Christ incarnated, who is placed at this
point where the optic chasma is between the
pituitary and pineal body. And when Christ
is awakened, when He gets into action within
you, then your two things that are shown there
– the blue and the yellow, the blue is the
superego and yellow is the ego, are sucked
in. Means all your karmas, all your doings,
your ego and superego are sucked in.
That means He has crucified Himself in such
a way that He has made within us a passage.
When He is awakened, He sucks that and all
our sins. Sins is nothing but conditionings
you can say and other things that we have
got within us. Everything is sucked in. When
it is sucked in, then only the Kundalini can
rise above that.
Now Sahaja Yogis know that Christ is one of
the aspects – is the Son aspect. And there
are aspects where He is a creator, where He
is a sustainer, where He is a Master you can
say and where He is the witness. All these
things, people never gave chance to Him to
speak. Now I’ve been speaking for seven
years in this country. But for four years
I could’ve hardly spoken even twice or thrice
because I was struggling with six of them.
So we can imagine you gave Him only three
years or say at the most four years to speak
about these things and how many things He
has spoken and how many these people who were
supposed to be his disciples have written
down, God alone knows. And whatever they have
communicated is so limited that it has created
problems for you. But every sentence, every
word that He has spoken is so deep and you
can only understand it when you get your Realization.
When there is no light what’s the use of
telling you there are these pictures; there
are flowers there and this picture there and
this is the color of the paper that is put
on these walls, what’s the use? There is
no light to see. When you get the light I
don’t have to tell you as He said, “The
knowledge start [tickling?] within, automatically.”
You are that Spirit and unless and until that
Spirit is manifested what else are you seeking?
A guru says, “I do this thing, I do that
thing.” All right so what? What about us?
What do we have got it from this temple? What
has he given us? You must find out. His disciples
are there. For example they went to the Ganeshpuri
this thing and there everybody was jumping.
‘Ha, ha, ha, hu, hu’, taking out clothes
and I don’t know and then taking all kinds
of drugs and this and that.
For jumping you don’t pay. You can jump
without paying. And drugs also they had to
pay. Even without payment he could not produce
any drugs. So one should understand that this
kind of a nonsense and down foolery is mockery
of yourself. Is just mockery. You are that
dignified, magnificent thing, which is the
Spirit. And you are befooled by these people.
You should see, this much at least, that anyone
who has given any powers to another person
should be accepted, isn’t it?
I mean supposing somebody says that a particular
thing is very good. Say – ‘this kind of
a lamp is very good.’ Then you see at least
how it works? If the one who says, “You
see the lamp”. You must at least see the
disciples of these gurus and then decide.
This is very much lacking. Like sheep they
follow and they fall into horrible ditches.
Doesn’t matter as far as God is concerned
He’s bent upon saving His creation. He’s
bent upon it. He will do it whatever you may
try to destroy. You try your level best to
destroy yourself and destroy the world that
He has created. But He is all-powerful. He
is all forgiving. He is all compassion. He
is going to save you whatever you may try.
Try your level best. But for a change why
not try to save yourself and save others?
This is what one has to seek.
Now when listening to Me also you should doubt
because you are in free condition. You are
not mesmerized by Me. If I was a real mesmerizer,
you could not have asked Me any questions.
You all would’ve fallen straight at My feet.
There would have been no questioning at all
because there are thousands who are doing
that stupidly. But you are free, you are free
to doubt, no doubt. But doubting what? One
has to think, “What are we doubting?”
As he said, “I am the most expensive person.”
[IT MAKES ME LAUGH?] Because you cannot pay
for it. It’s so expensive that all your
banks drained out cannot pay for it. All your
wealth that you have here so called wealth
that you have accumulated cannot purchase
it. It’s so expensive. It is invaluable.
Is the richest thing in the world that cannot
be purchased by any riches. It is, no doubt
but is not exclusive. It’s meant for everyone.
The doors are open now for everyone.
Now don’t you worry. Don’t count your
sins and your guilts and this and that, forget
that. It’s the grace that itself is anxious
as I told you and you all ought to get your
realization and should grow into it. You will
enjoy the complete bliss of your being which
is so beautiful. Like a diamond it is sparkling.
Only thing, you have to just unveil it. And
that is not difficult for you, not at all
difficult.
Now the things that he has told about the
physical side, that’s the minimum that should
happen. That’s the minimum of minimum that
should happen to anyone who comes to Sahaja
Yoga. Because if you are the temple of God
then it has to be cleansed before God is established
within you, before the Deity is sparkled in
you, it has to be cleansed. So the cleansing
takes place automatically; don’t have to
worry about that, that’s automatic. Even
a thing like cancer can be cured in no time.
A cancer can only be cured by Sahaja Yoga,
by nothing else take it from Me. It cannot
be cured. It may be that you may loose your
throat, sometimes nose, sometimes ears and
you may continue with the doctors but with
cancer you live in one body and get cured.
And there are some cancer patients here, sitting
down. They perhaps do not know and some of
them know also; have been completely cured
by Sahajayoga. The reason is that your body
is just ready, is waiting for that moment
when you get the light. As soon as you get
the light immediately you know where is the
problem and you start correcting it. Once
you start correcting it, it’s not you. But
this Power corrects it. Imagine this light
not only enlightens the room but also corrects
it. Think of such a thing that is God’s
love. That it loves you, it coordinates everything,
it makes you cooperate and it blesses you
with the highest.
This all pervading power has been described
in the scriptures. Everybody said, “There
is all pervading power.” Now you might say,
“Where is it? We can’t see. How are we
to believe?” Now as I always give an example
of a television, which I saw first time when
it came to India. That in a village people
were told that there is an ether around us
and you can, there are lots of dramas and
music and plays going on. They said, “How
can we believe it?” So they just put the
television to the mains and it started working
fantastically. And they were amazed, they
had to believe that is coming, there’s no
other connection, is coming, through this.
That’s what it is. You are an instrument.
Exquisitely made, beautifully, delicately
constructed. Just for this happening. Of course
you’ve ruined it. So many have ruined it
no doubt; you have tried in your childishness.
Doesn’t matter; makes no difference. You
will get your realization. You should have
no worry on that point. That’s My worry.
Once you get your realization then you can
give realizations to others.
Now about the lady that he told who got well
and was very sick. I must tell you that first
of all she was very very sick and she was
about to die. I was not there at that time.
Actually these people were there. Warren didn’t
want to say out of humility I think.
These people went there and put My photograph
there and gave her vibrations. And she came
to consciousness and they were surprised.
The one, who was going to die, has been declared
– going to die very soon, came to consciousness.
And they then thought there’s something
great about it. Then they came away. Still
the doctors couldn’t believe it. And the
relations also said, “How can that be? What
is it?” She again went into coma, when I
was there.
But a gentleman, who was related to her, was
connected with newspapers. Some how it worked
out and he published a lot that we have proof
to believe that Sahaja Yoga can cure people.
And that’s how it started and that’s how
worked out. But the first thing was done by
Warren and company, not by Mother.
So they themselves had the powers to cure,
to give realization, to do all that I can
do. And that’s what it is that once you
are enlightened you should manifest your own
powers. Otherwise the rest of the thing is
nothing but a joke. You jump or you stand
on your heads. That you can always do what
is so great about it? If it is some God’s
grace has to come upon you then you must manifest
something special. Not only curing but raising
of the Kundalini.
Now this triangular bone is called as sacrum,
meaning sacred bone that means these people,
who have given the name to it long time back,
must have known that this is a sacred bone.
Otherwise why did they call it sacrum? But
I think that knowledge was lost in Latin,
in Norway must have been, the knowledge was
lost and that’s how they do not know, they
just call it the sacrum. Now you can see with
your naked eyes, the pulsation of the Kundalini
and rising. You can feel the pulsation on
your head when it comes there and afterwards
you find complete it has become quiet. As
soon as becomes quiet you start feeling in
the hands. Of course this center should be
all right. If this center is not all right
you don’t feel in the hands but you feel
on the head. This center is to be corrected
then, then you can feel in your hands.
Now this you can do yourself when you are
realized. Its not only Me, you can do it also.
I mean in, say in Australia say, we can say
if there are two thousand people who have
got Realization, I could’ve given only to
about five hundred, the rest are done by these
people only.
You people can give Realization. But difference
in Australia and here is – now if an English
Sahaja Yogi tries to talk to someone about
Sahaja Yoga, the person says, “You are not
supposed to discuss religion”. I mean that’s
an etiquette, it is supposed to be. You can’t
discuss religion. This you can’t discuss
God. So they run away. Hard to get even two
people in, to talk about Sahaja Yoga. This
is the problem otherwise all of them are capable
of giving realization.
Now Douglas is sitting here. Talk to David
Frawl. I knew that he was doing TM and he
told him also. And here talking to him, David
Frawl feeling heated up, absolutely boiling.
And he was perspiring, is a fact. And when
he came to the thing, now he’s got Realization.
He is giving Realization to people when he
got cured. I mean you don’t need much brains
for that. You don’t need any accessories
of the world, which are regarded as very practical.
I would say that Douglas at that time was
one of the most impractical person. He had
taken drugs and he had taken all these things;
there are many who were like this. Some were,
some had come from lunatic asylum and they
started giving realization.
The other day in Norridge there were three
persons sitting in front row and were all
shaking up before Me. I said, “Now from
where these have come?” I asked them, “From
where they have come.” They said, “We
have come from lunatic asylum and we are certified
mad people.” I said, “You are certified
and you are here. How are you here? I mean
if you are certified mad you are not supposed
to be here”. They said, “One person came
to My program and got well. So the authorities
have sent us here for getting well, so we
are here.” And I won’t be surprised that
these three may start a Sahaja Yoga center
in Norridge, very soon. But I said, “You
better return the certificates to them”.
It is such a great thing you can imagine certified
mad people getting Realization and starting
a Sahaja Yoga center.
There are people who were cancer patients,
who got realization and have started a Sahaja
Yoga center. So you can imagine how tremendous
are the Powers of God and how carefully He
has made us to be that Spirit. We have no
idea; we have no esteem of ourselves. We do
not know what great thing we are and what
we have to achieve and what we have to enjoy.
Actually He is such a gracious Father, He’s
so generous and He’s so loving that He wants
to share His joy. He wants you to enter into
the kingdom of God. And to enjoy that bliss,
that happiness, that freedom which has been
promised to you in all the scriptures. It’s
as simple as that. It is so simple that I
don’t know how I’ve given four hundred
lectures about such a simple thing like Self
-Realization. And they say they are all wonderful
and one is better than the other.
But today’s lecture must be, has been a
more of an introduction because according
to them there are many new people today. Whatever
it is I would like to allow you to ask Me
some questions. And everybody should admit
that new people should ask questions and Sahaja
Yogis should not feel upset about it. Because
sometimes you know questions can be very aggressive
and they get upset. But there should be nothing
to worry about it. Its all right your Mother
knows how to handle everything. So nothing
to be upset about it because they have already
passed [ ? ] saying that no questions will
be allowed to ask to Mother. See if I am a
Mother, if I have patience, if I have love
then you should not worry. You should not
worry about it at all. I have to manage all
of them. Sometimes in the beginning everybody
is like that.
Just now Warren has told you how he was because
he was made to sleep on the cement. I mean
he was not made but he slipped out you see.
And next day he was down with very great agitation,
he was going back to Australia. But I caught
hold of his shirt, I said, “Can you wait
for sometime lets see it might work out?”
So it is like that. It’s a very sweet thing
you know and I know that children have a right
to get angry with Mother but not too much
of it. Because after all you are here for
a purpose and that purpose must be fulfilled.
That’s why I am here.
May God bless you all.
I would like to have really some questions
because sometimes these questions also help
a lot for Me to understand what’s the problem
is. Can I have some questions please? Yes
please.
Question: [Not Audible]
Yes, Yes. What Warren has told you is a caution
but I have, I know so many people who have
got Rrealization without any return. [NOT
AUDIBLE] I know so many people [NOT AUDIBLE].
Warren has given you a thing of caution because
he has seen some people that they drop out
because the Kundalini comes down and they
find little frustrating. But I have all the
patience and you should have patience but
I haven’t met anybody who has been with
us, doesn’t feel it. You may not feel the
vibrations but there are, Realization is there.
Because when you put your hand on your head
you definitely get the cool breeze coming
out and you give Realizations to others, that’s
the proof of it.
There’s someone who was always caught up
on all the fingers, he feels the tingling
all the time. But he gives Realization to
so many people. He has given himself, he’s
caught up.
Its something like this, you can say even
if it’s the fifth hand car it moves, once
started. You go on repairing it, but it moves,
no doubt it moves. So nothing to be upset
about it.
[NOT AUDIBLE]
When do we? Right now? Me-Me? I don’t know
how many thousand years. I was born with it.
Yes very much, very much, very much, very
much realized. I was born as a real great
great Grand Mother, I tell you. I knew everything
about [IT or HER] from My very childhood.
I was very conscious, over alert.
[NOT AUDIBLE]
Repeat! [NOT AUDIBLE]
Rare thing beware, beware yes beware, beware,
beware, yes true. Yes, it’s correct, correct
that’s true. [NOT AUDIBLE] Yes I must tell
you about that. You see the people who have
written about Kundalini. I started knowing
about them that there are people who have
written about Kundalini. And I was amazed
because they are absolutely ignorant, not
only ignorant but stupid people. I don’t
know from where did they get this knowledge
because people do not know about this, they
started printing it. Perhaps anything you
can print and isn’t it?
I’ve seen such a big book where the fellow
doesn’t know where the Kundalini is; he
says it is in the stomach. Then he says it
is in the back, he doesn’t know anything.
Now the trouble is this knowledge was a very
secret knowledge, thousands of years back
and it started descending – this knowledge
to people very slowly like on a tree there’s
only one flower or two flowers maybe.
Now in the sixth century, actually Christ
talked about it quite a lot. And other people
like Moses and all these people have talked
about it. But the ones, who wrote, never got
anything. [THEY HAVE?] Perhaps so they wrote
it in a very mystical way like, ‘I’ll
appear before you like tongues of flames or
the tree of fire’ and all that – indicative
of all that. But it so happened that in the
sixth century somebody in India called as
Adi Shankaracharya – He was actually Buddha
reborn, He started talking about it. Self-realization,
of course Buddha talked about it. Then He
started telling about these, all these nadis
and everything He described.
But there is a poet in India whose name is
Markdandeya who has written about this. They
say he was living in India about say ten thousand
years back – this poet, about that time.
So this knowledge was known to people but
was not put down on the paper, was not circulated,
was not for en masse.
Now these people who are writing about it
have no knowledge, have no authority and they
have tried these tricks. Actually this is
the holiest of holy – the sanctum sanctorum
within you. And a person who himself is authorized
by God can only do it. Authorized by God not
by any say theological college or all these
things. It cannot. God should authorize – like
Christ, like you can say John the Baptist,
like Moses, like that somebody authorized
by God can only do it.
So these people tried the tricks, which are
unauthorized, and they got results because
there’s a deity sitting in the last chakra
called as Mooladhara chakra, which is the
root – support of the root. That chakra,
He tries to excite your sympathetic by that
and when the sympathetic is excited you get
all these heats and this and that and the
boils and all. So it is not meant for people
who have no holiness in them. You have to
be a holy person, who should be able to raise
the Kundalini, you should be cleansed otherwise
you cannot do this work.
While there are people who are connecting
Kundalini, imagine, with sex. I mean it’s
an absurd thing; She’s your Mother. She
is your Mother and has been your Mother all
these ages and it’s like having a dirty
feeling for your Mother I would say that.
It’s such a filth. So God should punish
them [INAUDIBLE]. That’s how they have it
as a punishment. It’s not at all to be afraid
of your own Mother. Will you be? I mean that’s
one thing you are not afraid of, is your own
Mother. Should not be. I mean modern mothers
I don’t know. But that’s what it is. It
is they have no knowledge.
Now I must tell you that Sahaja Yoga must
have given realization I don’t know how
many thousands, tens of thousands of people.
Of course you may feel little heated up or
if you are possessed, you might feel little
bit shaken up. People who have been to TM,
one of them jumped about 20 ft., when they
heard My name. All these things may happen
to few people. But I mean such extreme cases
are very rare, that’s all. But nothing goes
wrong. I mean you are ultimately cured of
that. So you might get little effects of that.
But nothing serious. I am here to look after.
On the contrary it’s very blissful, very
blissful.
If one does not know about something, they
should not get into it, isn’t it?
Any other question?
[INAUDIBLE]
But you must get it, that’s the main point.
You see, this if you don’t get, you will
never be happy person. You have to get it
and it is your right. It is within you why
not get it? It just doesn’t cost you anything.
You have to have it. But people refuse to
have this, imagine refuse to be the Spirit.
Can you imagine?
They are satisfied. The other day I met a
lady who came and she said, “I am quite
satisfied with the simple life I lead, Mother”.
I said, “Now what am I to do? If you are
satisfied My child, I would only say that
a day will come and you’ll come back to
Me, but I may not be here”. You see all
these things recoil upon. What question of
sinfulness? Even a sort of a casual way towards
your Spirit, if you are casually interested
in your Spirit it tells upon you, because
Spirit resides in your heart and it recedes,
you have problems. And you all get into problems
with that. When they get into problems – I
mean a lady who came to Me, she said, “I
am not interested, this that.” And she said,
“I don’t want to do it.” But ultimately
she got cancer. When she came to Me and she
had a galloping cancer. We tried to help her,
we couldn’t help much, she died. It happens
with some people that they come at a stage
where we cannot help them at all.
So best thing is to get your own powers of
your Spirit and be all right, enjoy yourself.
You don’t have to pay bills of doctors.
You don’t have to worry about so many things.
And automatically the whole thing works out.
And also the petrol bill, as he said.
Krishna has said, “Yogakshema Vahamyaham”.
Means when you have the union – Yoga, when
you become united, with that Divine Power,
the well being is looked after. I mean all
the Sahaja Yogis who are here, have benefited
even monetarily, because within us lies also
the power, which gives us money. Which gives
us well being. There is a center within us,
which does that. And if that center is caught
up then people have problems with money. Once
it is cured, you don’t have. Not money as
such but material life, improves definitely.
[INAUDIBLE]
Chakras are the essences, you see, which create
our plexuses. And the plexuses are expressing
the nerves. So the chakras in any case are
the predecessors of the nerves, of the nervous
system. They are the predecessor. They are
the ones who supply the energy to the nerves.
They are the ones who guide the nerves – Chakras.
[INAUDIBLE]
Astral body – our body is made of various,
various cocoons we can say. These chakras
are say we are material being or physical
being, we are emotional being, we are mental
being, we are spiritual being and all these
are like our body. Now the astral being that
you know is actually the soul, we can say,
which is this whole body without the element
of Earth and Water, that’s the astral body.
Now this astral body you should not worry
much because that we get in any case when
we die. That you are going to get it. But
when we have the body then only we can get
our realization, not in the astral sense.
But people are trying lots of tricks with
these astral bodies, which is a very very
dangerous thing, and it has reached such dangerous
limits, because people have interest in this,
that I am really shocked the way it is working
out.
For example: there was a couple in Switzerland
and they had a relation – their mother in
America. And that lady was trying with one
of these astral body persons, those who work
on Spirits and she said that I would like
to talk to my grandson. And the grandson is
a living child and the child is in Switzerland.
It sounds very fantastic to people. That is
something great you see, the child is in there
without paying any airfare you can talk to
your child – grand child. It’s very dangerous.
And they used to try that on the child and
the child when it would sleep in the night,
it would be daytime in America. And she would
talk to him through this and she would hear
the voice of the child. They recorded all
that. One day this child was sleeping and
he never got up, he died. And the recording
said that it is too much strain for me, now
let me go grandma, let me go, let me go. She
said, “No, no, wait for a while, wait for
a while” and this spirit controlling woman
would not allow the Spirit to go back and
the child died, is a very common happening
now that the children suddenly die in their
beds.
So all these tricks we should not try. Whatever
is unknown is not Divine. You have the left
side and the right side. This is called as
the Adibhautik and it’s the Adidaivik, means
the collective subconscious and collective
supraconscious. There are all these dead Spirits.
Don’t play with them. Don’t get into this
nonsense of astral body and this and that.
There are some people who say that we want
to separate from our body and fly in the air.
Why, why do you want to do that? You want
to have your spirit or not? If you want to
have these experiences, I am not for that.
And I will ban it, if you ask Me. It’s absolutely
horrible. Of course people take money for
it and people like it to talk to spirits and
this and that but is very dangerous. You should
never try this with the spirits. Is a very
dangerous line when you do not know about
it, one should not get to it.
I have known people who have practiced these
things; their great grand children are suffering,
seven generations they suffer – seven generations.
Those even practice it. So it’s a very dangerous
game, one should never play it. What is the
need? You should live in the present not in
the future or not in the past. It’s the
present you have to achieve. So you just don’t
worry about these things. You become your
Spirit. You have to be born again and that
should happen to you, which should be an actualization
that should actually happen.
And what these Gurus are doing, are nothing
but putting the Spirits in you and are mesmerizing.
That’s how you behave like this. You are
no more yourself, you are something else.
This is the trick of the trade. They are all
using you for their own purposes by just mesmerizing
and mesmerism is manifested by using the Spirits,
which they are controlling. Especially for
Christians it is forbidden. I don’t know;
I don’t know how they don’t understand.
So lets have the experience now. It’s just
a split of a second needed for that, split
of a second. It depends on, if he, if the
landings are very good you won’t feel anything
else but the cool breeze suddenly but if it
is not smooth landing take little time. As
soon as the Kundalini pierces this, you feel
thoughtless. There is no thought. So you may
try to see just now put your hands towards
Me like this just because the centers are
here expressed of the sympathetic. Just put
your attention to Me and see if your thoughts
have stopped. And then close your eyes. If
that has happened that means Kundalini has
already gone above. It moves very fast, very
fast it moves.
Now few things you have to accept in Sahaja
Yoga. First of all you have to accept that
God is the ocean of forgiveness. That He’s
ocean of love, He is compassion and you are
not guilty in His eyes at all. And you should
not feel guilty before the ocean. So you have
to just say before starting your meditation
that ‘Mother’, in your heart, ‘I am
not guilty’, ‘Mother, I am not guilty’,
‘Mother, I am not guilty’. Thrice you
have to say.
Now you have to forgive. You must forgive
everyone. Just say that, ‘I forgive’.
Those who say, “It is very difficult to
forgive”, actually, not to forgive, what
to forgive is all mental activity. What do
you do by that, just torture yourself? So
please say that ‘I forgive’ and close
your eyes now. Say, ‘I forgive, Mother I
forgive everyone’. Just say, ‘Mother I
forgive everyone’. Keep your feet on the
ground both the sides touching and don’t
move much. Just say ‘Mother I forgive everyone’
say it thrice. Now put your right hand on
your heart where the Spirit resides. And without
feeling guilty, without feeling guilty, again
I say, without feeling guilty say that ‘if
we have done any mistakes, please forgive
us, please forgive me’. Say this thrice
from your heart – ‘if in my seeking, if
I have done mistake, if I have neglected my
Spirit or if I have neglected my duties towards
my Spirit, please forgive me’. Just go on
saying ‘please forgive me’. But don’t
feel guilty with it. You are not to feel guilty
about it. Just say it that ‘please forgive
me’.
I think you should again say, ‘I am not
guilty’ because as soon as you say that,
there’s a catch on the left Vishuddhi, so
you say ‘please forgive me and also forgive
me for being guilty’. That would be better.
Now you ask a question ‘Mother am I the
Spirit?’ Ask the question ‘Mother am I
the Spirit?’ Ask thrice – ‘Mother am
I the Spirit?’ You might feel cool breeze
coming in. You ask thrice. If not, now say
‘Mother please give me my realization’.
Say it thrice. Just say it thrice. Then it
would work out. You will start feeling the
cool breeze in the hand – left hand. Stretch
it towards Me, little bit. Stretch it. Ask
for realization. Now don’t feel guilty.
Are you are getting it now? Don’t feel guilty;
you are not to feel guilty. That’s the biggest
disease of the West.
Now you put your right hand on the head and
you might feel the cool breeze coming out
from your head. Just see if there’s a cool
breeze coming in. Raise it higher, see may
be? Is it? Not feeling. In the hand? Not yet.
Close your eyes and ask the question – ‘Mother
am I the Spirit?’ Thrice – ‘Mother am
I the Spirit? Mother am I the Spirit?’ Now
ask for realization – ‘Mother please give
me my realization’, thrice. Now you can
put your left hand on your head and right
hand towards Me. Let’s say some people have
this problem you see. Right hand towards Me.
Now, ask the question ‘Mother am I the Spirit?’
Ok thrice. Now you forgive, you just forgive,
forgive, forgive everyone. Say, ‘I forgive,
I forgive’ once again, ‘I forgive, I forgive,
I forgive’. Again, ‘I forgive’. All
right, getting it? Not yet? All right, if
you won’t, now, not yet? We’ll see.
Are you? Little bit on the hands, just see,
may be in the hand just see. It will work
out, it will work out. It takes little time
but it works out, works out, it works out.
Don’t you worry; don’t get desperate with
yourself. Keep your eyes shut. It will start
coming slowly, slowly, slowly; it will start
working. It is very subtle but it starts working.
Now. I think open those windows to pass out
some of these heats. Lot of heat is coming
out.
Now just see. Douglas, Douglas, see your neighbor,
has he got it on his head? Just see, here
him, just see him, not yet! He has got it,
he has got. That’s what I feel. Can you
see all of you? You have got it. I knew, you
got it long time back. Now see, what about
you? Just ask for forgiveness, a little bit,
all right, ask for forgiveness. Kathy, can
you see? Can you see the gentleman next to
you? John! We’ll work it out, somebody will
work it out. Don’t you be worried about
what they are doing because the Power is flowing
from them so they are just working it out.
Who are all the new people, please raise your
hands so they’ll come and help you. Just
go, come along. Ken, come along. Left Swadishtan
– you have to say the mantra of Nirmala
Vidya to get over the left Swadishtana, is
quite a lot.
[Mother speaks in Marathi].
It’s all right I think, a little liver,
a little. How is the lady? She has left, left
Nabhi. Ask her to put her right hand on the
left Nabhi. She’ll be all right.
[NOT AUDIBLE]
Felicity, are you all right, better? Please
do not feel guilty. If it has taken time,
don’t you feel guilty. What’s the matter?
Jamail, right heart. Please don’t feel guilty,
what are you guilty about, don’t feel guilty,
all right. There is nothing to feel guilty,
what is there to feel guilty? I mean what
crime have you committed? She has got it actually,
enjoying. Now, how is this gentleman, right
Vishuddhi? Left? You are feeling guilty, Mr.
all right. Yes, now put your left hand like
this towards Me. And now put your right hand
here and now say that you are not guilty at
all. ‘I am not guilty’, just say it to
yourself, say it thrice, again.