[Music]
collectivity doesn't mean that we all
should be stuck together with some glue
or something or we all become like
Gibraltar no it doesn't mean it means
wherever you are you are connected that
is collected but if you are not
connected and you are just glued
together it's very inconvenient to live
under such circumstances I think people
don't even understand the meaning of
collectivity where there's not the other
anon now there's not the other there's
no other personality these personalities
are separated from you because of left
and right or could be both
but you are yourself fully when you are
absolutely detached and your Kundalini
is dancing you are alone and never alone
this oneness with the whole gives you
all the security that you want all the
joy you want and that's why Kundalini
awakening means collectivity
unless and until you want pure
collectivity in your being
Kundalini won't rise
[Music]
so now let us see how do we miss out on
collecting it's a very practical
down-to-earth understanding first we
must know without collectivity we cannot
exist as the body has to be in
connection with a brain in the same way
without collectivity sahaja yoga cannot
exist once you understand that then you
have to work it out that collectivity is
absolutely established within and
without I do not know what thing comes
first in the human mind about another
person but the first thing is that these
are your real relations and nobody else
are your relations these children are
your children and these men are your
brothers and these ladies are your
sisters and we are one big family
together we are part and parcel of one
body as this hand cannot hit another
hand thank God it doesn't think
otherwise as human beings they might
start thinking against another hand but
they don't because they are connected to
one brain activity
[Music]
so you can see that when we ascend in
the collective consciousness and we have
collective living collective meeting at
the wish of the chakra Shri Krishna
established this all he manifested this
pure relationship of a sister in a
collective life that we have in the
ashram where we live where we move about
at sahaja Yogi's if we do not have this
basic principle within us there will be
a can of chaos complete loss
once this purity of relationship is
established that apart from my wife all
the rest are my sisters or mothers
it cannot be
a proper society and the chaos of the
social system of America is because they
have no sense of pure relationships once
you call somebody a sister she's a
sister and once you call somebody a
brother she's a brother it's not only
that you should be born of the same
parents it's not necessary but this is a
very important principle to have a very
pure society where every caddy can live
peacefully
[Music]
think of the tree which is say in a
turmoil or during earthquake it won't
grow when the earthquake stops
everything becomes quiet everything is
peaceful then only the tree can grow in
the same way our growth can only take
place if we are peaceful within
ourselves so for a Kundalini growing
wider and wider and rising higher and
higher
first thing is we must have peace within
ourselves but this peace is possible if
you can make ready peace with others if
you cannot make peace with others who
are in sahaja yoga who are in the
collective if you are in a turmoil this
Kundalini can never rise that is why
collectivity is so important
without collectivity usually cannot
offer and without connectivity you
cannot have the growth of your
spirituality if the growth of the
spirituality as they say the Tree of
Life is upside down and the roots are in
the brain and this Kundalini has to go
and water that brain as we bottle the
roots then it starts flowing downward
and that's how we start expanding
[Music]
now mother has said we have to have
compassion when away do you have our
compassion on the walls where do we use
our compassion where do we use our
compassion so Sergio guys to be
practiced doesn't mean that you sit down
with my photograph all the time doesn't
mean that it means you practice
compassion you practice that then you
have to practice love now how do you
practice love with others if you love
someone what do you do you try to please
that was small things can make people
very happy I know you all try to please
me very much and give me presents you'll
find out things which are good for me
you go out of the way bye sweet flowers
for me beautiful things you do to please
me I am over priest I am sorry but I am
more pleased much more pleased if you
understand collectivity and try to
please each other so now the practice
love where you practice I ask you a
question where do I practice love what
do I love believe love our house we love
our photographs of decorations
everything but do I practice this love
on my wife or my husband or another
sahaja Yogi's
[Music]
in our search culture we have to
practice compassion and love and thirdly
we have to practice patience I know some
children are maybe little more
mischievous some are less mischievous
maybe some people are very talkative
sometimes really they gave me also a
headache
they go on talking talking talking
talking so much sometimes I think it's
good because it's a rest for my mouth
one way of looking at it another way of
looking of it is just switch off your
mind let him talk take it out whatever
you want once he is finished with it in
fact out then he won't bother you much
and also it feels satisfied that
somebody has listened to his practice so
patience is needed and patience is
needed in such a way that others should
see your patience yesterday for example
I was sitting for about I think three
hours shaking hands with all sorts of
people and all types of problems and the
person who came last he said looking at
your patience I develop my own patience
and love gives you patience this love
nourishes you I am Telling You it
substituted down-to-earth method here I
have not mentioned that you trust God
I'm just saying trust yourself
absolutely down to earth because we are
talking about your brain
[Music]
so today's understanding should be that
we all should become collective from
itself
we should not grudge or grumble about
and enjoy the collectivity but the
second sight of collectivity is this
that do not try to exploit the
collectivity otherwise we'll be in
trouble like I've seen some people don't
know how to use their bathrooms when you
are collective you have to be respecting
the collectivity of others by your
presence another person should not by
any chance suffer or should not feel in
any way insulted or inconvenient
inconvenienced so when you are in the
collective it should be such that
another person should enjoy your company
enjoy your being there that's something
where there is no problem but if you are
demanding and if you are asking for
things and you think no end of yourself
you cannot collect you by any chance but
you will suffer for them automatically
you'll suffer if this is realized and
understood properly your are guess all
[Music]
like anger people always boast I'm very
angry with you boast but just make that
anger into forgiveness and you see the
person you serve you getting into
problems he will get into problems anger
will upset you
but forgiveness will upset him
automatically
it's the biggest weapon you have God is
to forgive and this is shown in buddha's
character throughout now we have been
saying that we have to forgive everyone
but we don't practice that small small
things like mad people we remember only
only I ever had heard that snake has
this capacity to remember if somebody
has hurt him but here I find human
beings have no less combatants
whatever has happened 13 years back 15
years back they all remember each and
everything whatever has hurt them but
how they have hurt others they don't
remember how they have been nasty to
others they are no no because this is a
human mind which has got the ego it can
go on hurting others it doesn't feel
anything and the super-ego which goes on
receiving all the hurts and always pray
complaining about
[Music]
don't criticize the collectivity till I
myself find it out and I'll put it right
keep to the collectivity wisely and
arresting and try to keep the
collectivity together try to help to
keep the people collective to enjoy
together
don't criticize each other only
criticize yourself if you lie if you are
in the habit of criticism better
criticize yourself is better because
these are habits also people especially
I have seen people in the West they
react to everything if they see this
cover-up I don't like it but this is not
yours you are not paid for you what have
you got to do with it now I don't like
it it's not yours
what's the question it's lying here and
why should you be so upset what I don't
like that person I don't like that dress
who are you I don't like this is not
allowed inside
I don't like there is the way of saying
things but there is no need to say
anything whatsoever
so all of these kind of bumptious nests
and showing off is against collectivity
[Music]
so try to appreciate everything
children are producing pictures
paintings enemy they make sometimes my
face is very funny when they draw not
the children even grown-ups
then what I appreciate is very good
wonderful very nice to encourage that
person so criticism should go out of our
mind but appreciation should be
practiced appreciation of others
children appreciation of other people is
very important but that doesn't mean
that you appreciate all others and
torture your wife or tortured your
husband that also is an environment
first responsibility is your family but
you should appreciate others and this
comes when you have no jealousies about
anyone this jealousy I don't know from
where it comes
I don't know this quality of jealousy
why there is jealousy so also if you
have jealousy you have to use it for the
right purpose and what is the right
purpose is that you should be jealous of
a person who is spiritually higher than
you and you practice it that you become
better if jealousy is for competition
then you compete with a person who is
more compassionate more loving more
sacrificing more patient so this
competition becomes a very healthy
competition and the collectivity becomes
very nourished
[Music]
the worst enemy of collectivities
aggressiveness some people are basically
addressing their style of talking is
extremely aggressive the way they say
things is ex aggressive maybe because
anything maybe they are better educated
maybe they come from a very aggressive
family maybe they are are having a kind
of air superiority complex or an inside
or too complex or a sense of insecurity
or maybe they are possessed they try to
dominate and show their very strong
feelings towards people of superiority
they may be inferior it's not necessary
but they took and this is something is
to be curved so what you have to
practice here is humility try to be able
humility is that in no way you try to
address others and if others are
aggressive you accept it as a childish
thing as a stupid thing as a foolish
thing has no meaning because you are so
powerful you can bear it that is
humility which you have to practice and
all these qualities if you have you will
really be surprised that you would lose
your selfishness
[Music]
only way to grow is to be collective
there's no other way out if people think
that by staying away from ashrams alone
living somewhere they will achieve much
that's not the way sahaja Yoga is meant
formerly people used to go to Himalayas
and most of them were separate it and
only one or two persons were chosen for
spiritual growth here it is not question
of spiritual growth is the question of
your collectivity growing in you that is
how you become a person who is
collective who enjoys collective who
works on collective and lives with
collective such a person develops new
kind of powers and these powers are such
that they are very subtle but they
penetrate into any molecule atom or
human beings anywhere and their
penetration is only possible if you have
a temperament which is collective
without being fully collective you
cannot achieve that height which is very
necessary today for sahaja yoga
[Music]
integration is not there that's why you
have to attend collective you know you
have to become more collective the body
has to be collective the thing is if you
don't if you are not a collective person
then sometimes you'll kill them on the
leg sometimes on the heart sometimes in
the head that's not a good thing you
should try to become more collective
should meet more people take more
interest you see the body of yours won't
work out efficiently unless and until
you use it because individually you see
if they individually if you work up it
will not develop collectively because
where are you using it you are
correcting yourself to give it to others
and if you don't give it if you do not
work it out in a collective way there's
no circulation
[Music]
meditating together is the best way to
feed the connectivity you can meditate
at home of course you are suppressing
for your depth but also you must
meditate together and when you meditate
together then the strength that you have
strengthens others and the strength of
the whole collectivity improves so much
we are meditating together is a very big
thing everyone has to understand that
whenever you get time you find out in
the morning times for example we'll go
to the ashram and meditate say Sunday
morning will just want me to take in the
ashram just for meditation you have to
come meditate and go away because I
reside in this ashram I'm here so leave
your homes come here and meditate
meditation will help you a lot wherever
you are together and with it but when
you are away from each other I am NOT
with you only in difficulties when you
are pushed into some places where I am
not that where you think I'm not there I
am there but if you deliberately are
keeping out of collectivity and not with
you so try to grow your collectivity
otherwise you cannot go deep into your
own depths you cannot become a great
sahaja yogi you cannot really be called
as such those who have a sense of
collectivity can only become that
[Music]
sangham sharanam gachami Sangha means
collectivity I surrender myself to the
collected so here in complete awareness
I mean you cannot be mesmerized
if you are mesmerized then you can do
whatever way you like but in complete
awareness and full understanding we have
to become collective but once you are
without ego means you have surrendered
yourself no one can cheat you can you
understand that
no one can cheat you because there is
some higher force which is looking after
this is the way we should understand
Buddha this is we should know our Buddha
qualities this is how our ego can be
dissolved when you say mother is
surrender to you that just means that
you give this horrible ego a complete
holiday it means that that is how this
ego disappears I think all your just now
raga eyes are open out most of you
somehow and then you would laugh at
everything you make fun of yourself just
enjoy everything
[Music]
last but not the least one must
understand that as all the seven chakras
I am working on are in a collective way
held by me my Murata the quality of
Virata gana is that that she creates
this universal awareness within us the
collectivity and if you do not realize
that in modern times we are in a
spiritual part in a collective way only
this is what it is because we have
reached to the state of Salaam and here
we have to have a collective working
only there's no other way out this is
the most important point we must know if
he cannot be collective because of
anything jealousy maybe inferiority
complex maybe any anything which is
coming from behind like a worm crawling
up then know that something wrong with
you nothing wrong with the collectivity
I hope you can understand my vision and
in stand by me come up to that I depend
on you entirely for my vision we have to
change this whole world into a beautiful
place for that not my sacrifice is
needed they are already blessed you
don't have to do much only thing is keep
your attention on the source of power
thank you but the essays we promise we
all say that
thank you very much
[Music]