Havan on the day of Puja to Shri Krishna as
Yogeshwara, 1982-08-15
Bahjan: Govinda Bolo
Child: what's happening?
…. Mother is coming.
Bahjan: Govinda Bolo
Indistinct voices of children
Sahaja Children: questioning Shri Mataji [Marathi?]
Shri Mataji: [Marathi?]
Her blue sweater, just find out from Olympia's
Mother.
…. [to the child] please sit there.
Child: Did Olympia's mother come?
Shri Mataji: [Marathi?]
Today is the combination of Shri Krishna,
this one (is) his face and this is his dress.
Ah, I think someone should go and find out
from...
Joan [Mother calls a Yogi].
Her sweater, her sweater is with … she said
she has given to Olympia her blue sweater.
Light blue
Child: Light blue
Shri Mataji: What are the words, Vishnu's
names, in English.
Better take it in English, better.
(Mother talks to a baby-child [Marathi?].
Ah, better take her.
Take the names.
In English they are easy to take I think.
Only the first, one should take them.
Ah, does somebody has a shawl, [Marathi?]
Ne, it's alright.
Actually we should have Rasaali (?) playing
with that, it would be nice, it doesn't matter.
These are the names of Vishnu, because Vishnu
only achieved the status of Shri Krishna who
in his own life time expresses his complete
form of Virata.
Complete form of Virata.
And this is a very good understanding, if
you know that you are also, start the dharma,
establish your Dharma and then you become
a witness, and then you become part and parcel
of the whole, the Virata.
The same pattern takes place in you also,
in the evolutionary process.
Now lets have (the names).
Yogis: Om Shri Ganesha, Shri Kalki sakshat,
Shri Ganesha Shri sakshat, Shri Parvati sakshat,
Shri Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi namoh namah.
Yogi: Om Krishna Swaha
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Krishna means the Universe.
Om Shri Vishnu Swaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Bhavya ...
Shri Mataji: Please put it properly … she
is just throwing, be careful.
Hmm.
Take them closer, hmm.
Yogi: Om Vasat-harya namoh namaha
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Butha Bhavya swaha
Yogi: Om Bhava-Prabhu Swaha
Shri Mataji: Ne, ne.
You should read it in English, the first name.
Is it given later on?
Yogi: yes Shri Mataji
Yogi: Butha Bhaavana, He originates, nourishes
the Buthas.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: Buta means " the past"... Hindu
only gives the names.
But, it's the meaning, that's better.
Yogi: Om Butha-Atma, namoh namah.
Means his Atma is pure.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The Param-Atma.
The parama Atma, the Supreme Atma
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Butam-paranama-Pratii namoh namah.
The Ultimate Goal attended by the liberated
Shri Mataji:Ultimate Goal, attended by the
liberated, that is you people
Yogi: There is no Aviaiya.
There is no viaiya, that means there is no
destruction or change by him
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Purusha namoh namah.
He exists in the Pura or in the body
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Saatchi.
He sees everything directly without distraction
Shri Mataji: Witness
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Kshitra-Agnya.
Kshitra is the body, and He is the One who
knows the body
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Haksharaa namoh namaha.
He who is Kshetra-agnya himself, does not
(///?)
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Yoga namoh namaha.
The One who controls all the iyanenitras...
yanendrias along with the mind
Shri Mataji: which he controls.
Yanendrias are the senses organs
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Yoga Vidanmeta namoh namah.
Those who know (/// yoga /////) … Vidya,
the chief of them is Yoga Vidanmeta
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: … please just sit here.....sit
here....
Today I want you to do it with understanding.
Yogi: Om Pradana Purusheshvara namoh namaha.
Pradana is Prakruti or Maya, Purusha is Deva.
The Lord of them is Pradana Purusheshvara
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Narasinvha-papu namoh namaha.
The One who
has a body with the limbs of a man and of
a lion
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Shri Ma namoh namaha.
He upon whose breasts Shri, that is Lakshmi,
Shri Ma, who is carrying, lives permanently
Shri Ma
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Kesheva namoh namaha.
He who has handsome hair, is Kesheva
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Purush'ottama namoh namaha.
The best of (all ?) Purushas
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Sarva namoh namah.
As He is the origin and the end of all that
exists, he has knowledge of all at all the
time, He is called Sarva
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Sharva namoh namah.
The One who destroys all with his bowl (?). Of
course (?) being destroyed at the time of
Kranala
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: That 's why ... don't put too
much gee, You should control it
Yogi: Om Shivana namoh namaha.
The Pure and devoted of the three Gunas of
Lord Shiva
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Staanu namoh namaha.
He is permanently fixed.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Buta-Adi namoh namaha.
The original cause of all beings
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Nittii namoh namaha.
The One who'll more return at the time of
Kalaya
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Vaviayia namoh namaha.
That needy which is undying
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Sanbhavana namoh namaha.
He manifests by his own will
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Bahavana namoh namaha.
He dispenses the truth of actions toward who
enjoy them
Yogis: Om Swaha.
Yogi: Om Bartaa namoh namaha.
The Supporter of the world
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Prabhaavahaa namoh namaha.
All the great Butas, the elements arise from
him
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Praphu namoh namaha.
He is keen in all actions
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Vishvarah namoh namaha.
His Lordship is not limited
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Swayambu namoh namaha.
He born and manifests himself by himself
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Sambu namoh namaha.
He gives his devotees beneficence
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Maha-Ditya namoh namaha.
He is the Golden Purusha, the Solar All
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Pushkar'aaksha namoh namaha.
His eyes are like lotus
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Maha Shivana namoh namaha.
His resound is powerful
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Maa-Nadini-Tanaa namoh namaha.
He has neither birth no distraction
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Dhatah namoh namaha.
He is the One who supports the Universe
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Vidata namoh namaha.
He gives his action and dispenses the truth
of action
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Daaturu-Tamah namoh namaha.
He is superior, with Datu that is (?) and
knowledge
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Buttamah namoh namaha.
The most superior of all
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Om Ma-Pramea namoh namaha.
The void of sound and all sense, sensation
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: and He cannot be known by any analogy.
Om Krushiikesha namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Rishi-Kasadindria, He is the Lord of
senses' organs, He controls the senses
Om Pradmaha Namoh Namah.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: His Navel is the cause of the entire
Universe.
Om Ammara Prapu namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the Lord of the immotus.
Om Vishavakarma namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the one who has created the universe.
Om Manu namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the one who does all the thinking.
Om Twastaa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He reduces every thing to subtle form,
in time of kalaya.
Om Stawista namoh namaha
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Very stout ancient and firm.
Om Kruva namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is permanent.
Om Akhraya namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Cannot be crossed by the organs of action.
Om Sashvata namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is Sashvat at all the times.
Om Krishna namoh namah
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: These are the nature of Sat, Chitta,
Ananda: intelligence, knowledge and bliss.
Om Lolitaksha namoh namah
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: His eyes are red.
Om Pratunaardana namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He (?) all beings in the time of kalaya.
Om Praputa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Abounded entirely with excellent qualities
such as wisdom, eminence.
Om Trikaku namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: His adobe is all the three regions.
Om Prabitah namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: That by which one is purified.
Om Mangalamparam namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The Beneficent, the Auspicious Form
of all beings the Highest.
Om Hishana namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He controls all things.
Om Pranadha namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He gives the vital breath to everything.
Om Pranaha namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The One who breathes.
Om Jaystaa namoh namah
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The Oldest.
Om Stresta namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the One most to be praised.
Om Prajapati namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The Lord of all beings.
Om Hiranya-Garbha namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: These are the names of Brahamadeva
actually, but why He is called, because Brahamadeva
came out of him.
You see, out of his navel Brahmadeva came
out that's why he is called, otherwise Prajapati,
Vishvakarma, Hiranya-Garbha, are the name
of the Maha Brahamadeva.
Maha Brahamadeva is the primordial Brahamadeva
which came out of the navel of Shri Vishnu.
Yogi: Om Prubagharba namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: His womb is the Earth.
Om Bahajavana namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The housband of Maa.
Om Maadusudana namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: [Marathi?]
Yogi: (?) …. Om Vishvaarah namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He posses infinite part.
Om Vikkrani namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The one who has (?). Om Dharvi namoh
namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He has a bow, like Lord Rama.
Om Metahavii namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is scholarly.
Om Vikramah namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He measures the entire Universe.
Om Kramaa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the one who walks.
Om Annutama namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: … the right hand... take it
in that side...
Yogi: None is beyond him.
Om Duradarshana namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He cannot be (?) by (?) or anybody.
Om Pusadynya namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He knows all the actions of all creatures,
meritorial and otherwise.
Om Krutti namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the basis of every action.
Om Atmavan namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is established in his own glory.
Om Surisha namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The Lord of Devas.
Om Sharanam namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He removes the pains of the afflicted.
Om Sharanmaa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: These are the forms of supreme bliss.
Om Vishvarita namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the cause of the Universe.
Om Prajapavaa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He from all beings arise.
Om Amvaha namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is lumines, like the day.
Om Sarvatsalah namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He stands in the form of time.
Om Vyalaa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He cannot be crossed with the mind.
Om Prataya namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the consciousness.
Sarva-darshana namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is the Witness of everything.
Om Ajaa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Ruthless and very (agraestum?).
Om Sarveshvara namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The Lord of all Lords.
Om Sitta namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Eternal and Full.
Om Siddhii namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: Siddih is what?
Eternal?
Yogi: Siddih is Eternal and Full … (?) He
sit in the form of wisdom in all objects
Yogi: Om Sarvadihi namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: The primordial cause of all beings.
Om Ajyuta namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He does not fall.
Om Brushakapi namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: Dharma is called brusha and it rains
all desires; ka stands for water, so it means
He protects and lifts the Earth as Varaha.
Om Amayat namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: His nature cannot be measured.
Om Sarvayoga-vinishittra namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is devoid of all attachments.
Om Vasu namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All beings are biding him.
Om Vasumanah namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He whose mind is excellent.
Om Sattia namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is on the form of True.
Om Sama-atma namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is equanimus, has no attachments.
Om Asam-mittaa namoh namaha.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: He is beyond pleasure.
[speaking to Shri Mataji, not clear: Hundreds
names...]
Shri Mataji: what's the time?
… so it's the time of his birth has come
now, even according to Hindu timing and...
(?) all the badas and everything.
It will take sometime and put the whole thing
now, mix it up and put it the whole thing.
Have you finished with the … lets put these
things, what ever is there, one person should
hold it together in the hand and put the all
thing inside, in the hand should be taken.
(silence) Next time you should do (with the
English ?) names like that, it's better, they
should understand.
You all should read it at home, you see, even
if he is reading in Sanskrit, you all can
buy one book each, (?), when you come to the
program you should bring it so that you will
have the meanings and you will know what means.
You see, is better to read it in Sanskrit,
no doubt, but it takes more time, I want you
to do it with understanding, that is very
important.
All the mantras have an effect, there is no
doubt, but to understand is better that you
can have a manual (handbook) to read, all
right?
Yogi: All the badas and impurity of thought
and action
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: See there are badas and all form
in the centers and they are growth (?), you
see?
Dedication to Mother, just say that, I's better.
Yogi: All the badas in the centers of Sahaja
Yoga
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas which prevent dedication
to Mother for all Sahaja Yogis
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas which make Sahaja Yogis
(? go on their own)
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas which make Sahaja Yogis
feel diffident
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas which make Sahaja Yogis
feel they are special
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas which prevent us from
knowing our Mother
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas which prevent us having
confidence
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas which prevent us having
trust in Mother
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: All the badas of the relations
or object to Sahaja Yoga
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas of the relations or object
to Sahaja Yoga
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: and the badas of all the seekers
Yogi: All the badas of all the seekers
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: and the badas of all non-seekers
who do not seek
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas of all those who are not
seekers
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas of all media which have
objection to Sahaja Yoga
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All the badas of Caxton Hill
Yogi: All the badas of all public meetings
of Sahaja Yoga
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: all the badas of inauspicious behaviors
Yogi: all the badas which offend protocol
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: all the badas which make Sahaja Yogis
hasty
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi:all the badas which make Sahaja Yogis
(?)
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: the badas which make you dominate
or to behave in a manner which is not appropriate
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: all the badas of lethargy
Yogi: all the badas of cowardice
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: all the badas of feeling guilty
Shri Mataji: also badas of thinking great
about oneself
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: all badas there is in mist and
humidity
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: all badas against love and understanding
Shri Mataji: for the whole world of all these
badas must be rid
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: I shouldn't really, I shouldn't
say it, because my saying has no meaning
Yogi: all the badas of all Sahaja Yogis who
(do not?)
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: all the badas of (?)
Yogi: all the badas that stop us having vibrations
Yogi: all the badas that stop us feeling vibrations
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: all the badas that gives us excuses
and (meditating ?) properly
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: now, what else?
Yogi: all the badas that make us judge others
Shri Mataji: of what?
Yogi: judging others
Shri Mataji: who says that?
Yogis: all laughing, more than one answers:
Harry
Shri Mataji: all right
Om Swaha
Yogi: all the badas that make us see others....
as others.
Mother and Yogis: laughing everybody
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: You are all part and parcel of
yourself, and if something is wrong is better
you judge yourself, that's the best part.
How much do you love, how much do you respect,
discipline, of Sahaja Yoga.
You have to sacrifice something for Sahaja
Yogis, is it?
Lets count how many things have you sacrificed
so far for Sahaja Yoga.
You have gained a lot, but you have to sacrifice.
How much have you sacrificed for sahaja yoga,
you cant even sacrifice little comfort.
All badas against sacrifice.
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: All badas against forbearing
Shri Mataji: All badas against wisdom
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: (? loving each other when there
is no ?) All badas against that
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: All badas against teasing your
Mother
Yogis: Om Swaha
Shri Mataji: I just want you to love each
other, that's all.
Nothing else
Yogi: all badas against resentment and jealousy
Yogis: Om Swaha
Yogi: All badas of (?)
Shri Mataji: and also those who are organizing
should not be dominating.
They should be understanding and should know
they must respect the freedom of everyone.
It should be mutual, it should be no something
with a rod.
Sahaja Yoga cannot be done through a rod,
but if someone is trying that, you better
accept it for the time being.
Is not good for the person who is trying such
thing, to be using the rod all the time.
Try to have a reasonable attitude for everything,
reasonable, there is nothing to fight, there
is nothing to quarrel, there is nothing to
ahh... think that somebody is more dear to
me and somebody is not.
You see, those who look dear maybe they are
not.
So don't do all that.
Just try to be kind to each other, try to
understand, try to help, try to guide, somebody
has some weaknesses, all right, try to help
that person.
If somebody has weaknesses, you should not
capitalize all that.
It should be worthy, but I can see (?) is
coming now.
So I don't want miss the moment, I can feel
it, that's coming, no doubt.
Some how I have a feeling now, and I have
seldom (felt ?) in my feelings.
So some golden (age ?) I can see (along the
lines ?). I am sure something great is going
to happen.
May God bless you for this day.
It was a great day and the birth of Shri Krishna,
should be within us, within ourselves, so
our Vishuddi should be all right balanced
witnessing and control our ego and superego
in such a manner that the Kundalini is kept
above on to a higher level, attention on to
a higher level.
I think from today I'll stop calling you anymore.
And I have a feeling now we have to go very
fast, and once we have started very fast,
then you will have to run fast then you will
have no time to quarrel.
May God bless you
Yogi: Om Shri (Radanna Pratini) Nirmala Devi
Ki Jai
Shri Mataji: May God bless you all.
Thank you very much for celebrating this birthday
of mine.
Thank you very much.
Yogi: Thank you for coming on this Earth
Shri Mataji: You see, according to Indian
(?), they count even the first day of birth,
like if you have to say how many years you
have, according to them I am already 60 and
I am going to be 61 and after 61 you can take
sanyasa, so it's a big freedom.
Thank you very much to all
Yogis: thank you