I could not accommodate all of you in my house
then I thought better to come here all of
you would fit here!
And today is the last day for our Sahaj Yogis
(before Mother’s trip to India).
We have to understand certain very, very important
things about ourselves and our organisation
that is Divine.
Now, in broad lines I can tell you, not individual
problems and individual things because you
are no more individuals now.
You have become part and parcel of the Divine
Being and you are awakened cells and so in
a broad way we must understand what we have
to do about it.
First thing we have to know [is] that we are
Realised-souls, and that you have got Realisation
and that you are saints; that you have all
the powers that a saint could have.
No saint ever had more powers than you have,
as it is, which is manifesting.
No saint had any knowledge that you have today.
You’ll be amazed – none of the books which
have been written so far have been able to
tell you about the spiritual being that is
within you as you have come to know through
Sahaja Yoga.
One has to accept it.
It is so.
Any one of them, whosoever has written any
books – even, I would say, Adi Shankaracharya,
he could not explain so many things which
you know.
But the quality of Adi Shankaracharya is very
great, or people of his type – Markandeya
or Buddha.
The quality is very high because they are
extremely pure people – purity.
They have achieved individual salvation of
a very high degree.
While you have achieved your collective salvation
better.
But individually they are of a very, very
high quality.
I mean, they had no doubts about Divine Power,
they had no doubts about God.
They never had any doubts and they were very
dignified.
And they never bothered as to their petty
problems of life.
For them this was too petty to think about.
Anything which is so petty, we spent so much
time over it.
I know we had to do it because, after all,
we are human beings and are coming into Sahaja
Yoga with our human awareness and then we
got our Realisation.
So the purification time is very, very short.
And while they had such a lot of time to purify
themselves.
Now, for example, Moses was an incarnation,
a very pure form of a personality or, you
can say, Jesus was an incarnation, absolutely
purest form of incarnation.
But they are there to be our ideals while
what we have done is to become, from human
beings, a prophet.
So you understand both the things very well,
what the weaknesses human beings have, what
are their problems, how they get away from
reality, how they are deluded.
But still we do not use our vibratory power
as we should use.
And this is the point I want to tell you – that
you all have vibratory powers.
When we start using our vibratory powers also
we do not know what dignity, protocol we should
have for using this power.
It is the power of the Deities within us and
it’s a ritual by which we get their power
working in us.
As you know that people of ancient times did
lot of miracles through this power but they
were very dignified people.
There was no frivolousness in their character
and not useless problems within them, absolutely
of no spiritual value.
When you use your vibratory awareness you
should not use them for useless powers like,
for example, going to a cinema and there’s
a traffic and you think that there’s a traffic
so you must use your vibratory powers to reach
that place.
Because it’s frivolous; it does not matter.
In Sahaja Yoga it does not matter whether
you go to a cinema or not.
What matters is: what are your spiritual powers,
how far you have come in your spirituality.
It (the cinema) does not matter at all.
You are a saint, and what saintliness you
are achieving within you is the main problem.
Otherwise, all the rest of the things that
you have, has no meaning.
Or all these problems have no meaning in spirituality.
So all the Sahaja Yogis must realise that
you are now newly born and you are people
of new awareness and you have to have that
dignity.
I’ll just give an example because I was
discussing with someone today.
When you give somebody a sort of a bandhan
you just turn your hand like this or like
that.
This is not the way it should be done.
Your hands itself are to be respected because
these are the hands of a saint.
And all the deities reside on your hands and
fingers so when you have to give them bandhan
or anything, you have to use them properly.
Use them in such a way that it’s dignified
to do it.
Any indignity or cheap behaviour should be
absolutely avoided.
Then dealing with each other you have to know
that you are all now in the circulation of
Divine Power.
You have to respect each other and really
love each other.
You must respect because you are all saints.
Every saint must respect another saint.
That’s the minimum of minimum.
And if you do not respect each other, your
chakras will go out of order, especially Vishuddhi
because it’s the collective thing.
And also Mother’s Chakra will go out because
your sense of security is your collectivity.
And the love between each other has to be
not only looked after but is to be nourished
and to be worshipped and it should be a virtue.
You should not treat each other as human beings
treat each other.
No!
It’s a precious thing.
And even while talking to anyone very close
– say your brother, sister, husband, wife
– you must respect, you must respect, otherwise,
it has no meaning.
You must respect your parents much more than
you ever respected because they are Sahaja
Yogis, because they are saints and they are
your parents.
Respect is the keynote of relationship with
each other to begin with.
And respect without love has no meaning.
Respect and love for each other.
Whether somebody is highly placed in life,
somebody is lowly placed in life, in Sahaja
Yoga it does not matter.
How much you earn, what is your position in
life, where you live is not important.
The main important thing is that we are one
and we are the people who have become now
prophets and we are the ones who have got
the powers to raise the Kundalini of others
and such a power has come into us because
our Mother loves us very much and it is our
duty that we should love each other.
And how I respect you?
I need not because you know that there’s
a big gap between you and me.
But I respect you because you are saints.
And where the saints are not respected that
country goes to dogs.
So first of all you must learn how to respect
each other.
And that is a very, very important training
we should have.
Whether he’s your husband or wife, whether
he’s your brother or sister, father, mother
or child, because he’s a saint – respect!
But I do not know how you will react to this
one that immediately you start thinking about
people who do not respect you.
Think how many people you do not respect.
It’s a typical ego-oriented reaction that
immediately we start thinking, “Oh, that
man does not respect me!
That man does not respect!”
But just think how many people you have not
respected yourself.
When I am not here, I am here much more.
I have not been to Australia, and you know
how tremendously these people have come up
– so pure and so good and so fantastic.
But that has not happened so much here because
I had to work, really labour here.
Not that England is that bad.
But all the time to feel that, “Mother is
around.
We’ll put all our problems to Her and She
can solve them.
” Even small, small problems you bring to
me – it’s all right – but now you are
capable of solving your problems as well as
solving the problems of others.
Unless it is something fundamental you need
not bother about me and you need not also
ask me about it.
You can go ahead with it.
But you must think everything in the terms
of Sahaja Yoga by which – how much, by that,
you are doing for Sahaja Yoga?
How much you are working out for Sahaja Yoga?
This was the meeting of the Sahaja Yogis today.
And fundamentally we have to understand one
thing: that we have to grow and we have to
let others grow with our growth.
Not by curbing our growth, but with our growth.
You’ll only grow if you make others grow
with you.
Otherwise, there will be no growth.
Now, whatever I say goes into the books, sometimes
into the brains of the people.
It has to go into the heart.
The whole Sahaja Yoga system works on the
heart; that is the Spirit.
Spirit is the thing I’m talking about.
It’s the Spirit [that] is happy by that.
Some people, I am told, are using their hands
like a weapon and all that.
This is very dangerous!
You are not supposed to do all this for yourself.
You are still saints, you are not yet gods!
So don’t try such things.
Some people have a habit of also hitting a
person with the hand like that.
In my presence, if I say, it’s all right.
But otherwise you should not.
You have to respect.
Use all tender and gentle methods, never anything
by which you show any disrespect to a saint.
Of course, you are hitting the negativity
in another person, I know that.
But you have no business to do that or to
discard anyone or to put somebody out of this
thing.
You will go down very much.
This is a serious thing one must understand.
You have all the powers you know how far to
go.
You must keep to your maryadas.
Don’t go beyond, because these things give
you ego, and ego is the most dangerous thing
which we face always.
Try to improve your language.
Be gentle.
Be very gentle with each other.
I expect that you’ll have many more people
by the time I come.
I expect fantastic things from you.
I don’t know if I should but I have given
you something so fantastic, so tremendous.
It is unbelievable.
I expect it from you, no doubt, because you
are specially selected and I have worked with
you for years together.
You have got the tapes in English.
French people, poor things, they don’t have
tapes in French and they have to be translated.
They haven’t got a book in French and they
have big problems of understanding me.
But how dedicated they were, how deep they
are.
Each one of them came and said, “Mother,
I love You very much.
I love You.
” “I have many defects and I offer myself
to You.
Will you accept me?”
All of them said this way.
Just imagine!
I mean, I was surprised how they were saying
all these things to me and the way they were
understanding their defects within themselves.
Now, we have to change our mode of behaviour
towards financial, material, emotional, physical
and all these things.
For example, say, one is married – marriages
should be successful.
If your marriage is not successful and happy,
you are not going to be blessed, not at all.
Try to make your marriage very happy and successful.
That’s very important.
Marriage is the institution established by
Adi Shakti.
You cannot dishonour it.
Do not play frivolously with your marriages.
Then you must also allow the children to be
born to you so that you get great souls coming
down on this earth by which we are giving
them a chance, a very good chance, to lead
a very happy life.
But if husbands, wives are not happy, and
even if Realised-souls are born, they have
a trouble with you and they do not prosper
well and they have problems.
So, first of all, create a family of happiness
and joy.
Some people think if they get away from Sahaja
Yogis, they’ll make a good, happy married
life.
It’s absolutely wrong!
Absolutely wrong!
If you cannot make a happy married life in
the ashram, you cannot make it anywhere else.
First try in the ashram.
[It’s] worth trying.
Otherwise, you cannot make it.
Because then you understand how you share
your life with others and your married life.
Any such thing like any material thing, like
getting a house or getting this thing, that
thing is not so important.
Your house should be clean within yourself,
your temple of your heart.
We are not here to build houses, not to accumulate
money.
We are here to build our temples within ourselves.
The real temples which are growing, which
are the living temples of living God within
us.
So these material things are important up
to a point, not more than that.
Most important is not how you are substantiated
by Sahaja Yoga but how much you have substantiated
Sahaja Yog through you.
Many people think, “We should get a good
house because we have come to Mataji.
” Yes, you do get.
You get good jobs.
All right.
You get it.
You get your financial conditions improved.
All right.
Everything happens to you.
But how much have you given to Sahaja Yog?
In the way [that] – how much have you substantiated?
People think sometimes that if they donate
money that’s sufficient.
It’s not.
To enrich it with your heart, with your lovingness,
with your friendship, with your sweet understanding
of each other, enjoyment of each other’s
company in the purest form, not with any purpose
or with any intention of getting any low type
of joy or low type of happiness from someone
ego-oriented or sex-oriented.
But it’s pure joy, pure joy.
Purity is the theme we have to take to.
We have to try to be purer and purer.
And the purity will be shown brilliantly on
your faces, in your behaviour, in the whole
being as you would be.
Your presence itself will show that you are
Sahaja Yogis.
You won’t have to certify.
You won’t have to wear some special dresses
to say, but people will know from your faces
that you are saints, from your behaviour.
You have to stand back in the last queue.
You should be the people who should look at
things.
You should not be the first, [that] you need
to get into the thing first, to getting into
the queue first.
No!
You are the last because you are with yourself.
They are not.
They have not [got] their own securities.
They are trying to find securities in these
things.
You have your own securities.
Change, according to the Spirit, all your
priorities, and then joy is your own.
I really expect fantastic things from you
and I hope you all will join together and
work it out and create something fantastic.
I don’t know how to tell individually about
things but as it is I have already spoken
to these Sahaja Yogis in Paris and I have
told them that Sahaja Yoga is a very speedy
thing.
And it’s very speedy.
It’s such a speed and if you do not keep
with the speed of Sahaja Yoga you’ll be
thrown out.
You have to keep to the speed of Sahaja Yoga.
Those who cannot keep by some method or other,
or [who] get locked up by something or some
misidentification, will drop out.
You’ll only grow when you will keep to the
speed of Sahaja Yoga.
It is going to be tremendous in India.
I know these five years are going to be tremendous
in Australia.
England may be, depending on your people putting
up the speed.
It’s going to be tremendously speedy and
you have to understand that – drop out all
your shackles and drop out all your misidentifications,
all nonsenses of fanaticism or of misidentifications
that you are British, this, that, all this.
And just become Sahaja Yogis and universal
beings.
It’s very important.
The time has come now.
From next year it will start.
So I wish you a very Happy New Year and a
very, very happy and cheerful Christmas.
May God bless you!
Now we have to await for other people who
will be coming now but [if] any Sahaja Yogis
have any problems or any questions should
ask now till other programme will start.
Can you have some chair nearby to talk to
them?
I think a simple one will do, it’s too elaborate
to more.
Douglas wants to move the whole big thing?
Just an ordinary chair, Douglas, is alright
for me.
He wants to move the big one.
Ask me questions, very important, on to small,
small things.
Later on, “Mother said so,” or, “Mother
said so,” should not be there.
Sahaja Yogis should ask because new people
who have come, who have not got yet Realisation
should wait for a while because I am just
dealing with the Sahaja Yogis.
And then we’ll start our programme after
just, say, ten minutes.
Is it all right for new people?
Just put it (the chair) here.
Douglas Fry: Should we bring it further forward?
Shri Mataji: No, no, no.
I am alright.
Just bring it nearer here.
Now, I want Sahaja Yogis to ask me questions.
It is important.
Sahaja yogis should ask me questions.
Please.
You have to do everything with consultation
with each other.
No group should be formed separately.
Ask me questions.
Come along!
What’s the matter?
Don.
You’re getting thoughtless.
Then, “Mother said like this,” and “Mother
says like this,” and “Mother has told.
.
” – this should be stopped.
You see, actually we think outside going,
outside doing is the way.
No!
Inside!
Grow inside.
Certain things I am going to write it down
so that there’s no confusion about things
but, till I come back, the ashram system should
go as it is today.
Then when I come back we’ll change it.
But just now it’s all right as it is.
Nobody should take new steps.
If you get a house or something, all right,
you take a house.
But better thing is to stick on to ashram
for the time being, look after it and substantiate.
I mean [if] somebody is allotting you a house,
it’s all right.
But you need not take a house on rent or something
to get out of ashram.
That’s the escape.
Ray Harris: I often find that it’s better
to – after telling them the basics of Sahaja
Yoga – to wait for them to tell you.
And in what they say and their vibrations,
what is it that they want to know, rather
than really telling them everything.
Shri Mataji: No, no.
You should be very discreet.
As I have told you in one of My lectures that
there are three groups of Sahaja Yogis.
One are the people who are in the inner circle.
Most of you are here.
You need not tell them many things.
Everything need not be told.
That is being not dishonest but that you are
discreet.
I mean, you need not tell everything.
That’s a wrong thing.
Discretion is to be used.
Then the second type are the people who are
Sahaja Yogis but yet not there.
Still [who] are doubting and still are not
so developed.
Their Kundalini is not up there.
They are still [a] funny type.
These are the people you have to be careful
about.
You need not tell them everything because
they can’t bear the Truth.
They are not yet ready.
Unless and until the Kundalini has reached
a certain stage they cannot bear it.
The sooner you start doing that, the worse
they will become.
Their doubts will be more because this is
too much for them to bear.
So you have to wait, wait and see for yourself.
That should not be done.
Just talk about Sahaja Yoga, direct.
You need not talk about me.
Now how will they understand me?
I mean, you cannot understand me, how can
they understand?
The other day somebody asked me that, “Kundalini
rises with such difficulties, and they had
to purify yourself and all that, and here
how my Kundalini has risen like this.
Mother?
How could it be?”
I said, “It has risen or not?”
He said, “Yes.
” “You feel it?”
“Yes, yes, I have.
It is risen.
” Then I said, “There must be something
with me.
All right?”
He said, “That’s what I was wondering
that must be something about Mother.
How is it that She’s done it?”
I said, “There is something.
All right.
So just now you need not find out.
Just now you find out about yourself.
Let it grow.
Because I do not want to shock you.
There is something about me, no doubt.
”
And one of them was saying that, “It’s
such a miraculous thing that my sinus has
gone, I am feeling so much better.
My drugs I have given up.
I’m so much better and so fantastic that
I can’t believe it.
How can it be?
I tried all kinds of medicines, I went to
the hospital, I did this, I did that, I had
an operation.
Nothing worked out.
And how is it this simple thing like Sahaja
Yoga has worked out?”
I said, “It is too simple but it is to the
point.
It’s so precise.
It acts.
It is something that acts.
” “But how is it?”
I said, “It does!”
Like we were going to Paris.
They announced that the temperature of Paris
is zero degrees.
So, Christine was sitting next to me rather
worried.
I said, “Don’t you worry!
It is going to improve.
” Within fifteen days they said, “Suddenly
the temperature has gone up five degrees!”
Today London’s temperature has gone up after
my coming here.
It works but they are surprised how it is
working.
After all, all these things are promised.
The time has come.
But you need not tell them!
No, don’t shock.
It’s correct, Ray, what you say.
It’s very discreet.
Ray is a very discreet person.
No doubt about it.
He has tremendous discretion.
And that’s what you should use: What to
say to anyone and how far to say.
It’s a very discreet method.
And you must know how to compromise also.
You should not be something like a cynic.
You must learn to compromise.
And understand [that] they are people who
are not yet Realised.
You are Realised, you are grown into it, you
are much more matured.
So you have to be much more gentle with them
and not to show off to them [that] they feel
small.
Like somebody is asking a question, maybe
stupid, may be, possibly.
Doesn’t matter, he’s not Realised.
And if you laugh at him sarcastically or make
fun of him, naturally you lose him.
You are not to lose these people.
You have to get them in, and that is their
right, they are seekers.
They are seekers.
We have to really understand this with great
compassion and love for them.
They are seekers.
We have to work it on them, not to just laugh
at them or make fun of them or in any way
to put them down.
On the contrary, show them due respect because
they are seekers as you were.
Before that what we were?
What sort of people we were?
How many arguments we have had with Mother?
How stupid we have been?
We just forget all that and suddenly we become
very wise.
No!
Wisdom lies in understanding that they have
to have their enlightenment.
They haven’t got it as yet.
They have to grow in that light.
This is the problem.
Now you have to use your discretion.
There’s no need to ask me.
I will know from your mistakes, where you
have done mistakes.
But consult each other, consult each other.
Talk to each other absolutely freely.
There’s nothing to be hidden amongst Sahaja
Yogis.
Nothing to be hidden among Sahaja Yogis.
But with elders, with other people, be respectful.
Maybe you being young are more active in Sahaja
Yoga.
Maybe children are still not so developed
in it.
We have to take all of them together, not
to be unkind by any kind of sarcasm because
I have told you a hundred times and hundred
and eight times now: sarcasm has no place
in Sahaja Yoga.
This is no way of joking!
It’s a very sly method.
Nobody should beat also, in the same way.
It’s just the same, other side of the coin.
Beating or shouting or putting up your head
like this on other people, like this.
Many people have a habit of putting their
heads like this when they talk to others.
Or French people have a very bad habit of
putting their face like this.
I was surprised.
Anybody you talk to … means nothing goes
into his head.
I said, “What’s happening here?”
Is he like a duck?
And you say anything, again they will say
another thing.
I mean, everything has a tail coming out.
So is that these are our tails?
We should understand that.
We should not put up ourselves to such barriers
but accept things as they are.
And those who have, who come to you, don’t
get angry with them because by talking or
argument you are not going to convince them
but by only by Sahaja Yoga.
Try to give them Realisation.
Do not argue!
Some people think, “If you talk to them
sweetly, if you are sympathetic.
” No!
Also that doesn’t work out.
You go on wasting your time with them, and
they’ll go away.
They’ll not be there.
Where is their Kundalini?
How far is it rising?
That’s the point you should see.
Instead of just trying to be very nice to
them, then discussion, then this.
No use!
Waste of time.
In the same way if you are angry with that
person and argue; it’s also wrong.
Both are a waste of time.
But be gentle and kind and see where is the
Kundalini.
Best is to use photographs.
And please do not start curing people.
Otherwise, I’ll find all the sick patients
in Sahaja Yoga.
They are not to cure.
It’s finished now.
Better not do it.
What’s the use of curing these people?
They are so ungrateful.
They have no sense at all and they don’t
want to do Sahaja Yoga.
We are not interested in such useless people.
Those who come to Sahaja Yoga will improve
in their health automatically.
You don’t have to give them any treatment.
They can work it out on the photograph, that’s
all.
That’s the end of it.
Sit down!
Now, what any other?
Maureen?
Mark [Rossi], ask some sensible questions.
You are good.
They have been a very good husband and wife,
I must say.
Very happy with them.
They are a good, ideal couple and I hope they
keep it up.
Also there are some people I know who are
very much interested in getting everyone married.
Now stop it!
Till I come back you don’t have all these
things.
Otherwise the mind, it becomes a marriage
bureau.
Some people have a specialty about it.
Instead of loving others’ children, also
create your own children.
Some people like to play with others’ children.
It’s also not good.
Better have your own children.
That doesn’t mean you just love your own
children.
But that’s how they get that thing satisfied
and they don’t want to have children and
then who’s going to bear the children who
want to come on this earth?
That’s a big responsibility.
What else?
Ask one or two questions.
Gavin, please ask some questions.
It’s two minutes more.
Gavin Brown: How do we prevent Sahaja Yoga
from becoming a cult?
Shri Mataji: What is it?
Gavin Brown: How do we prevent Sahaja Yoga
from becoming a cult?
Shri Mataji: Yes, it’s possible.
Because, you see, you think, “I’m catching.
I’m catching.
” This madness has come also in Sahaja Yogis.
This will become really cultish stuff!
It will really become a cult.
Nonsense!
What are you catching?
You are pure vibrations.
You give Realisation to anyone – none of
your chakras catch anybody else.
Everybody thinks, “I’m pure,” – what
it is they say?
Holier than holy!
What is catching?
What?
All such dainty darlings are no good.
“I am catching.
I ! You have to be brave warriors.
What is catching?
“I don’t want to give vibrations with
this catching.
I don’t want to do it.
” All right, use the photograph to begin
with.
But if you have to do it, you should not be
frightened.
You are swords!
It is true, Gavin, what you said.
It’s very true.
But you look after that part – that none
of them should become that, “I am catching
this and I am catching that.
” And “I don’t like this and I don’t
like Sahaja Yogis doing this.
” This is all wrong.
This will make a big cult out of it.
Of course, that’s not possible.
You try such tricks and you will know what
it means!
That won’t be possible though.
But be careful; you will go out of gear.
Nobody has to form a cult.
Everybody who is coming to Sahaja Yoga has
to be absolutely with both the arms stretched
out, “Come along!”
Just like your Mother.
I should be the greatest cult myself.
Why should I bother about anybody else?
This catching business should drop out from
your mouth.
Everybody comes and says, “I caught it from
him.
” “I caught up from them.
” I am amazed!
How can you catch up from anyone?
What are you?
A dainty darling or what?
Now no more it is going to be tolerated!
“I caught up from that.
” Go and beat yourself with shoes.
If you are such a dainty darling that’s
what you deserve!
You know how to do it!
(laughing)
Nobody should say, “I am catching.
” Also neglect these things completely.
The more your attention you pay them, the
more they will sit on your head.
Just neglect and go ahead.
What Paul has pointed out is true.
This is very common in England, not in India.
Nobody says that, nobody.
I’ve not heard one person saying, “I am
catching from that person.
” Never!
They say, “This is my weakness so I must
have felt for that.
” They never say like that.
This is [your] speciality – putting the
blame on others.
This is typical ego style business.
Put the blame on others!
As if you are pure and you have caught up
from another.
It’s your weakness.
That’s all what you should think about.
You are brave people.
You have to be very, very brave.
Without bravery how are we going to do Sahaja
Yoga?
Just tell me.
You have to love with bravery.
In love you don’t think and consider and
all these things – you just go ahead.
Such a powerful thing to love someone.
That “Such person should not be there and
such person should not do that” – nothing!
Now those people who come for the first time,
or are not so much – they may not have proper
protocol – that doesn’t mean that you
get after their heads.
Otherwise, it will become a cult.
The first thing is consideration of others!
And understanding that they are not Realised,
they are not enlightened.
This is very important.
You must understand this.
They are not enlightened as yet.
They have not got their vibrations.
They haven’t got their vibratory awareness.
To get angry with them is wrong, absolutely
wrong.
What else now?
That’s a good point.
One more point you can ask me because some
people are coming.
Also do not allow your weaknesses to sit on
your heads.
For example, some people have a habit of telling
me, “Mother I had this, I was this, I went
there and still that is lingering into me.
” Then you are absolutely useless!
Why don’t you take it out?
Finish off.
Like that.
“Still I have been to this yogi, I’ve
been to that yogi.
I have done this, I have done that.
” It’s done!
Finished!
In the present time you are pure Spirit.
Become that.
What is there to be proud of these nonsensical
things?
They are no parallel to Spirit.
When the Spirit shines the darkness has to
go away.
If there is still darkness that means something
wrong with you, and if you are wrong, then
what are you boasting about?
I mean, people have a habit of boasting!
Try to be alert and loving; loving and alert.
You have to be really alert.
What else?
Yogini: [unclear]
Shri Mataji: It’s a little personal question,
isn’t it?
I’ll tell you separately, all right?
Because this is not the problem of many, all
right?
General problems should be solved.
This is very personal.
It’s pertaining to you.
What else?
Man: If I follow you, do I have to give up
friends who…?
Shri Mataji: No, no, no, not at all.
Why should you?
On the contrary you’ll want all your friends
to come and join us.
You don’t follow me; you follow your Self
only.
It’s a question of not giving up but your
priorities change because your awareness changes.
Like I could say that if you take a horse
through the streets of Paris, he would not
notice anything.
For him any dirty place, filthy place, is
the same as the any street.
If you take a man or a woman, she will notice
prostitutes standing on the street.
He may be repelled towards them, may not be
repelled also, possibly.
Mostly he would not be repelled.
But if you take a saint or a Sahaja Yogi,
he’ll have compassion for a prostitute but
he will know that she has to learn herself.
And he won’t go near her.
When she will come to him, he can pardon her
and look after her.
But there is no involvement in her, in no
way.
So the awareness changes.
You start giving up things which are not spontaneous,
which are not living, which are dead.
You start living a living life.
It automatically works out.
You don’t give-up.
On the contrary you get new friends, lots
of.
They are all your friends and brothers once
you get it.
Because the language changes, the style changes.
You have the light; they are dark and black.
They are still in darkness.
So they are fumbling, while you see the things
straight.
You can help them.
But if they are fumbling and trying pull you
down, you will say, “No, I can’t come
that way.
Now I’m changed.
” You are changed, and they are not yet
changed – that’s the point.
It’s transformation, actual, that happens
within us.
You don’t have to give up, not at all.
On the contrary, you must meet other people,
you must talk to other people.
But, for example, if you have other friends
who are anti-God, you won’t be able to tolerate
their company and they won’t be friends
anymore.
I will think, “They are not my friends.
They are anti-God.
They are anti-love.
” You would not like to waste your time
with them, having a whisky party or something.
You would not like.
What a waste!
But you may be with them but you may not like.
Many people do like that, I have seen.
Many people even after coming to Sahaja Yoga
try to spend their time with other people.
Some of them do it because they have to do
it.
I know, I have a double life myself.
But My life is such that wherever I am, I
am with myself.
But Sahaja Yogis try to change, I have seen.
They spend more time with Sahaja Yogis than
with other people like brothers, sisters,
cousins.
They start changing that.
Either the brothers, sisters, cousins try
taking more interest in Sahaja Yoga, or they
don’t enjoy their company.
It’s just they may go just to visit or to
see someone but they don’t like their company,
they don’t enjoy their company so much.
It happens like that, because you are enlightened
people.
Like drunkards: they don’t like non-drinking
And non-drinking people don’t like drunkards.
If you go with the drunkards, you are frightened.
And mad people like mad people.
It’s like that.
So then the company changes.
And if you don’t change, you really don’t
enjoy Sahaja Yoga really into its fullest
extent.
But there’s no cult as such.
You are saintly people.
You are saints.
So saints talk in different language.
Yes, they are much more congenial and happy
with the saints.
But they would like to meet people and talk
to them and try to bring them, because we
have to bring such a lot of people to Sahaja
Yoga.
But you should not waste your energies with
people who do not matter in God’s work.
You don’t feel like.
I mean, I don’t say that “You don’t!”If
you have to go to see somebody, I don’t
say, “You don’t!”
But it happens with some people.
And such people can go down because they have
influences on these people, and it happens
like that.
Your priorities change.
You only then start enjoying whatever is God’s
style.
You don’t like something which is anti-God.
Like I don’t say, “Don’t drink!”
I don’t say Ten Commandments, nothing.
But it happens to you.
There were so many people who were drug addicts
who came to Sahaja Yoga.
They gave up drugs.
Now, how can they be with people who are taking
drugs?
So they started going to them and talking
to them and they said, “We have given up
drugs.
” All right?
There’s somebody in Paris whose husband
is drinking such a lot, and he is still a
drug addict, and she is a Sahaja Yogini.
But he comes to My programme, and I told that
she should be very kind to him and gentle
because he wants to give up.
But a person who is dragging her, “You must
also take a drug!”
Then you don’t like that aggression.
I mean, you should be allowed to be non-smoking
also, if you don’t want to smoke.
But they don’t allow!
For them it is difficult.
They’ll force you, “You must drink.
You must smoke!”
I mean, you must be knowing this that, if
you go to any party, and if you don’t drink,
they think you are mad!
And they’ll go on asking, “Why don’t
you drink?
At least take this, at least take this.
” If you tell them even once, “Why do
you drink?”
“Oh, you don’t drink?”
– finished.
Then you are the most anti-social person,
you have no manners, nothing.
I mean you are telling something nice but
they’ll go on forcing on you.
You have to go on telling them that, “Oh,
we don’t drink.
I don’t drink.
I don’t like it.
The Doctor has told me.
” All sorts of lies you tell them but they’ll
go on forcing you.
But even if you say once that, “Why do you
drink?” or “Please don’t drink.
” – finished.
You are the worst person in the whole world.
This is such an aggression!
Such an aggression.
It’s a very subtle aggression of these people
who are licentious.
It’s funny sometimes, I tell you.
Like we went to a party, and at that party
there was a funny couple came in – that
was a woman who was a keep and this and that,
and it was a party of married women and married
men.
And the way the woman was on with everyone,
I mean, nobody liked it, neither the women
nor the men.
And we didn’t like that the man – why
should he bring his keep there because it
was not a party of keeps?
But it’s aggression.
And she was so aggressive!
She was saying, “What’s the use of being
married to a man after all?”
She was just saying all kinds of things against
us, those who were married women.
“There’s no use marrying men.
I am very happy.
I am a keep.
He looks after me better.
You better give up your husband and live as
a keep with them.
” She was just giving us a lecture on her
status!
And we could not say anything to her.
But if we say that it’s nice to be a married
woman and to be virtuous, “Oh, they are
the worst women.
You are victorian!
You are old-fashioned hag!” and all sorts
of things will come on you!
There’s a very big aggression on saints.
They can’t talk.
They can’t say anything.
While even your own brothers and sisters and
mother and father and children will do that,
“Oh, you are very old-fashioned.
It’s nonsense!”
Like that.
It’s not easy to exist with virtue in this
country especially, and in the Western countries
because now I know what it is.
My husband also doesn’t drink so they tell
him, “Oh, is it your wife who has forced
you not to drink?”
I mean, he said, “She doesn’t say anything
like that.
Why do you blame Her?”
Immediately [they say].
I mean, there’s no shame about it of saying
such a dirty thing!
I mean, there is shamelessness, complete shamelessness
about it.
And not only drinking – all sorts of shamelessness
goes about.
You ask a lady, “Are you married?”
“No!
Why should I?
I am not a fool like you!”
It’s a typical answer.
I mean, because you are married you have to
look like a criminal!
Because you are virtuous you should be crucified
immediately.
When you change that, with these people, you
give up, naturally.
I mean, you don’t want to meet such people.
And then they might say that you are cultish
but it doesn’t matter.
I mean, we have to save ourselves.
I mean, we do not want certificates from them!
The certificate has to come from God, not
from these people.
They are incapable of giving us certificates.
That you know very well.
So should we start?
Something else?