[Music]
[Applause]
my idea of coming to conduct me for
Shibuya
was this that Shiva represents the
spirit and the spirit is residing in all
of you in your hearts
the seat of Sadashiva is on top of your
head but is reflected in your heart
now your brain is the bitter
so to bring spirit to your brain means
enlightenment of your brain
enlightenment of your brain means the
limited capacity of your brain has to
become unlimited in its capacity to
realize God we I will not use the word
understand to realize God how powerful
is how miraculous is how greatly
the another is that the brain of man can
create of course out of the dead
but when T Spirit comes into brain
then you create living things living
work of Kundalini
even the dead start behaving like living
because you touch the spirit in the dead
like
the nucleus inside every atom or a
molecule has the spirit of that molecule
and if you become useful we can say the
brain of
a molecule or an atom is like the
nucleus body of the nucleus but the one
that controls a nucleus is the spirit
that resides within the nucleus so now
you have got the attention of the body
the whole body of the atom then the
nucleus and inside the nucleus is the
spirit in the same way we have this body
the attention of the body
and then we have the we have
the nucleus
is the brain
and the Spirit is in the heart so the
brain is controlled through the spirit
how that around the heart there are
seven auras
which can be multiplied into any number
seven raised to power 1600 which are
once
which
much
the seven chakras needs to power 16 and
eight
16000 sorry
now this
spirit is watching through this aura
watching I'm again Singh watching
through this aura this aura is watching
the behavior of your seven centers in
your brain is also watching all the
nerves that are working into being
watching again but when you bring the
spirit
into your brain then you go to step side
because when you have CUDA linearizes
she catches the Sadashiva and Sadashiva
informs the spirit informs the self
reflects in the spirit so that's the
first state where the watching or us
start communicating through your
different chakras in the brain and
integrating it but when you bring your
spirit to your brain this is the second
state
then you really become self-realized in
the food in the food because then your
scent that is the spirit becomes your
brain action is very dynamic
it opens then the fifth dimension in the
human being first when you become
realized collectively conscious and
start raising the Kundalini you are in
you cross the fourth dimension when your
spirit comes into your brain then you
become the fifth dimension means you
become the doer
our brain now for example says alright
lift this thing up when you touch it
with your hands you lift it you have the
door but when the brain becomes the
spirit the Spirit is the world and when
spirit is the doer then you become
a complete Shiva self-realized
in that state if you get angry you are
not attached
you are not an attached person to
anything what sir if you possess
anything you are not attached
you cannot attach because Felicity - not
completely you don't bother about any
attachments whatsoever even for a second
you are not attached
now I would say to understand the
detachment of spirit we should study
ourselves very well clearly how are we
attached we are attached firstly by our
brain mostly by our brain because all
our conditionings are in the our brain
and all over ego is also in our place
so all emotional attachments are through
our brain and all our egoistical
attachments also are through our brain
that's why it is said that after
realization one must try to practice the
Shiva tattva by practicing detachment
now you just watch your attention where
is it one watches as soon as you start
watching yourself your attention you
will become more identified with your
spirit because if you have to watch your
attention you have to be your strength
otherwise how will you watch it
the detachment is to be watched and seen
through your own attachments
now because you are realized Souls not
yet the spirit has not come into your
brain of course but still you're
realized Souls so what you have you can
do is at least to watch your attention
you can do that you can watch your
attention very clearly by seeing where
your attention is way
and then controlling your attention also
isn't very simple
to control your attention you have to
just remove your attention from this to
that try to change your priorities all
this has to be done now so the spirit is
like the ocean which has the light in it
and when this ocean pours into the
little cup of your brain the cup loses
its identity and everything becomes
virtually everything so it's the ocean
that is the spirit well your brain is
limited so the detachment from your
limited brain has to be brought in all
limitations of brain should be broken so
that when this ocean fills that brain
will break that
little captain and every bit of that Cup
she'll become colorful the whole
atmosphere everything whatever relocate
should be colorful color of the spirit
with her life to the spirit and this
light of the Spirit acts works thinks
coordinates does everything
this is the reason today
I decided to bring Shiva tattva to the
blade
the first procedure is to take your
brain towards the shooter by telling it
see where are you going mr. brain
putting attention to this reporting
attention to that getting involved on
detach become the brain yourself only
the brain detach and then take this
detached brain completely filled with
the color of the spirit it will
automatically happen so today I hope we
all pray that O Lord give us strength
and that source of attraction by which
we give up all the refractions of all
the pleasures of joy of ego of
everything that we think of but we
should fall into the pure joy form of
the sheer thought oh absolutely
you got richer
[Music]