It is such a honor for all of us to pay this
homage to the great poet, printer and a prophet
that was William Blake.
When I first came to England, they have been
telling Me that England is a place of scholarship
and you can see lots of museums and exhibitions
and suddenly I told the Sahaja yogis that
I would like to go and see Tate Gallery for
William Blake's paintings. They were surprised
because I seldom go to any one of them, specially
the libraries and the books. And when I went
there, I saw this great poet, this great personality,
pouring out His heart with such concern, with
such honesty, with such understanding and
perception of the Divine to the people of
England, to understand the great powers of
Divinity. But to My surprise there were some
funny people; they had brought some magnifying
glasses and they were looking at the drawings
and were watching the private parts of people.
I said, " Look at these wretched, absolutely
baser people, who cannot see the sublime,
the highest, which He wanted to paint," and
they were taking photographs.
I was surprised the way people reacted and
then I realized how tormented He must have
been in His lifetime to live with such people,
who have no sense of Divine. He must have
cried in the wilderness; He must have wept;
He could not have been accepted, it's impossible.
Such low level minds cannot accept something
that's sublime and great and My heart bled
with pain. Oh God! Why did He take His birth
in a place like this? To torment Himself,
to torture Himself, saying something which
cannot be accepted. But it's not so. I knew
who He was, what He is doing, why He was here.
We do not know about Him much, because from
the books you can't understand who He could
have been.
He was an Incarnation., of Bhairavanath. That's
whom you call the St. Michael, or St. George,
who is as you know the Saint - Angel of England.
That's why He had to incarnate and for Him,
this was His role, to talk about Divine in
a open, fearless manner. He had to use symbolic
language, He had to use. It's not difficult
to understand Him at all; if you are a realized
soul, you'll read through it, sometimes laughing,
sometimes weeping, enjoying the whole drama,
what He has tried to explain. When I read
Him I am amazed at His sense of humor; how
He openly comes out with such remarks. I feel
He is like Markandeya in India, or Kabir Dass
in India, who slashed the whole society with
their sword all the time to see that they
are brought to the proper shape, without fear.
But so gentle, if you read the Song of the
Thel, it's so gentle; and all of them who
were Him perhaps or of the same style, extremely
open, straightforward, you can say even blatant
and extremely gentle.
The vision of Christ, that He has described,
is the one which He sees through His own enlightened
eyes and He sees that the vision is completely
distorted, is the opposite of what Christ
was. I also felt the same way. I took My birth
in a Protestant, Christian family and I was
shocked the way the Christians were. I said
" Are these the Christians?" Now the point
He brings forth is very clear cut, you can
understand, that in the mannerism if you are
gentle, " I'm sorry" , "I'm afraid" , " I
doubt." Just look at that. It's very commonly
we use this language. He says that Christ
was not a gentleman of that kind. I also say
I'm not seeking election, I'm not here to
please you, but I am here to make you please
yourself; to enjoy yourself, to have your
all wealth, enjoyed, manifested.
That is how He also put the vision of Christ
before you, that He was not a gentle man,
who would go around and be extremely gentle
to people and nice to them, superficially,
only the mannerism of it, but He would be
so gentle with the people who are lowly. He
created Divinity out of fishermen, who were
ordinary people, uneducated, absolutely we
can say, people who were one of the lowest
in the strata of society. He picked them up
and made them Divine. He didn't go to the
ministers and the prime ministers and the
governors. He did not. When you see all the
great people who are supposed to be looking
after the religion part of it, they are busy
only with governors and they are only busy
with the kings and the queens; who must go
and bow to them. They are politically activated
people.
How can a Divine person get into this mess
of politics which human beings have created?
But we don't understand it, because we try
to rationalize everything and thank God He's
the one who talked against rationality; and
against all the intellectual ideas of putting
down Christ to the mere level of a human being,
because He was Himself Divine and He could
understand Christ. He was so much pestered
and actually persecuted that He used to get
depression sometimes and He had problems of
money, problems of convincing His brother
and sister, everybody trying to make Him feel
uneasy. Such a fine soul came on this earth
to talk of Jerusalem. What did He mean by
Jerusalem? What is Jerusalem? We go to Jerusalem
for pilgrimage. Why? Because Christ was born
there. England will become Jerusalem when
Christ will be born here. But how many of
English people today care for the spirit?
English language itself is such a funny one,
that we use the word spirit for drinking,
the spirit that you call alcohol; spirit for
the dead souls, which hang around, many more
here, and spirit for the atma, the spirit.
When He came on this earth, the industrial
revolution had not taken its respite. People
were still entering into those 'mills' as
he calls them and He saw the scribes how they
were behaving and He saw the whole myth of
religion. He does not know that all the religions
were doing the same nonsense everywhere, not
only Christianity. You go to any other country
and see every religion is the same style of
a nonsense, which is opposite of what the
prophets told them, of what the incarnations
told them, of what all the great sages told
them. This is not only about Christianity,
but still nobody can forgive it, because Christianity
has a special fervor, has a special role,
has a special meaning, that's what He's tried
to also say, that Moses came on this earth
to lay down the code of conduct, morality,
the moral thing, and also He describes Milton
as a person who describes a Deity who is above
everything, a puritanical Deity. But He describes
the Divine humanity. Also He describes the
Christ who came on this earth for the emancipation
of human beings; not to tell them, "Don't
do this and don't do that." That was all right
at the time of Moses in the beginning of it,
the code of it, and He calls it a 'moral'
Christianity, meaning 'immoral' must be, because
if you force someone, into something and pass
such laws and regulations at this time, modern
times, it's going to be impossible for human
beings to follow and they'll fall into some
other traps.
Strict rules of anything, imposed on people
who are not realized souls, can push them
into some sort of problems, they can become
criminals, they can become violent as a reaction
and we see the reaction today acting, that
the hypocrisy of the whole thing is exposed.
Like in India or anywhere else, they will
say, "You should not be attached to money,
give the money to the church, to the temple,
to the mosque, to all the people to enjoy
it." The kind of life people led in those
days in the name of God, was no model for
anyone and that's how poets like Him were
born again and again. I would say that in
Lebanon a great poet, like Kahlil Gibran,
was born, and then in India we had so many
such poets, who just lashed the society and
lashed all these ideas of the intellectuals,
the ideas of the religions, the ones who were
trying to curb them. Because there was no
genuineness, there was no sincerity. If we
are honest people, we really mean it, then
let us face it and see for ourselves what
we have to achieve.
So that is how He came as a poet, a remarkable
poet, the way He rhymes it and the sense of
humor He has and the way He unfolds the beauty
of words as any poet should do. In Sanskrit
it is said, vakyam rasatmakam kavyam - poetry
is full of rasats; rasats means the essences,
the explosion of essences through words. If
it could be done, then the magic of it is
called as poetry and that's what you find
in Blake. Such a great poet; poetry is only
great when it talks of the Divine and when
it talks of the baser things, takes you to
the baser things. The other day I heard one
Australian poet and I was amazed at his bathroom
singing, it was horrible; how can you call
it a poetry which sings of baser things of
life, which takes you to the baser things
and pleasures? But He has very clearly, if
you can understand Him, has said, "What are
these books for? This is to collect money
out of them." Now how do you collect money?
By playing on the weaknesses of the people,
pampering their ego, pampering their greed.
All these things, if you can do, you can very
nicely befool them and they feel very happy
and nice, that oh what a book it is. As we
have had great writers also in this country.
I would say Shakespeare was a great evolved
soul, but the deterioration you see later
on, like people like Hemingway and all those
coming up. I don't know how, after Somerset
Maugham and all that, suddenly these horrible
Hemingway people coming up and people buying
their books like hot cakes. We've lost all
our moorings, we have lost all our roots,
but one thing good has happened out of this,
leading the way of Freud, making him Christ;
all that has led to problems and people now
realize, now realize, that's why the prophecy
was there, that's why He was a Prophet. He
warned people of what is going to happen,
but who is bothered? He was treated as an
insane personality. If you go to the lunatic
asylum, everybody will think you are insane,
that's the way lunatics look at a sane personality.
His wisdom was condemned. People thought that
He is getting all these hallucinations, He's
talking out of His hat, because they have
no brains to understand, they have no enlightenment,
they have no perception, that's why they treated
Him that way.
Now He is dead, of course they're selling
His books, making big money; selling His plates,
what He painted, but when He lived, nobody
bothered. And now they can use Him the way
they like. I've met some very funny people
here, in this respect, the way they have shown
great interest in Blake in saying that, "He
says that a naked woman is the best." I said,
"Where? How could He say such a thing? He
was innocent." Now we do not understand what
His is innocence also. Just like Markandeya
describing His mother, her breast and everything,
like a little child. A child doesn't see,
sex in a naked body, he does not see. And
the beauty of a woman He describes. That means
all women are walking nude, everywhere, now.
Are you exciting the innocence of people,
or are you exciting the baser self of the
people? We have to be natural, are you natural?
All these perversions and all these diversifications
has come because man does not have a simple
mind, he's a crooked person. This 'crookery'
has to go from the mind. That is important;
but if I say that , I'm not doing My job here,
I know that. I know for definite that is not
the way it is going to work out. That's why
Christ, the One who said, "Forgive, forgive
them." Otherwise how can God meet man, with
this 'crookery', with all this kind of cunning,
how can God reach man without forgiveness?
He cannot reach man if he listens to Moses,
can He? He cannot. If He has to come to human
beings, He has to forgive and that's what
is in Sahaja Yoga in the beginning. We tell,
you must forgive everyone, you forgive yourself,
don't feel guilty. Now in Christianity just
the opposite has been done, let us face it
and know for yourself that you have to go
and confess to the priest. The priest also
gets mad with your confession, you are already
mad. What is there to confess in the ocean
of forgiveness? It just dissolves.
What a message Christ gave us that the greatest
weapon we have got is to forgive others and
forgive ourselves because God forgives us
and this is the message we have to know, that
we have to forgive ourselves. Instead of that,
for all that we do wrong, all that we try
to do against our spirit, we feel guilty and
moreover if the teachings are such, that "you
better feel guilty", all the time what we
are doing is to feel guilty and catch on this
chakra on the Left Vishuddhi, to such an extent,
that in the West wherever I go I tell them,
first of all, you just say one mantra, "Mother,
I am not guilty." Take it out of you, who
are you to feel guilty? When God loves you
so much, He has made you the epitome of evolution,
you are at the highest point, why should you
judge yourself and feel guilty? Is He not
capable of forgiving you? Have you no faith
in His ocean of love? But this is the basics
of the mistakes that are committed in the
name of Christ. I'm telling to the priests,
now who is a priest here, coming from theological
college, can you learn about Divinity in the
theological college? Did Christ go to any
theological college? How did He get it, how
did He get the knowledge - through enlightenment,
enlightenment has to be there. The way He
has clearly stated everything, nobody liked
it, because of vested interest. Everybody
has vested interest. Nobody is sincere, honest,
and they want to exploit others to make money.
You cannot make money in the name of God.
Is sin. Such people can never enter into the
kingdom of God. That's why Christ has said,
"You'll be calling Me, Christ, Christ, I won't
recognize you." That's a fact.
So if you have to be a truthful person, just
a truthful person, do not feel guilty about
it. Do not feel you have committed sin. There's
a little story in India that one missionary
came to a village in India. Indian people
are in the villages very simple, you know,
they are not so sophisticated. So when he
was going, they praised him a lot, "Sir, we
are thankful to you that you have told us
what is sin and that we are sinners." They
didn't know they were sinning. And this is
one of the things that Blake brought forth
for us to show that Christ was a person who
brought a new message over Moses. Of course
Moses was needed at the time when Jews had
to come up, that was the time they needed
it and He brought these shariat laws; it was
Moses who started but Muslims are following
them. Now when today we are in this twentieth
century, sitting down here, we have to see
what is the prophecy of this great man, William
Blake. Can you imagine, His birthday was in
this month, Guru Nanaka's birthday in this
month, Mohammed Sahib's birthday on this month,
all these great people were born on this month.
Now, this month also we celebrated the Diwali.
Such a great month is this one and in this
month those who are born have to be great
people.
In the whole understanding of Blake, I find
a single lonely man, plowing this land with
the seeds of wisdom. I'm here just to reap
it; He's the one who planted, watered, made
ready by Shakespeare, you can say; you have
had many great poets here, Wordsworth another
one who really is enchanting and beautiful.
I think Wordsworth must have seen the fate
of William Blake and he said better describe
the nature, forget about human beings; he
must have thought of it, thinking it to be
an incorrigible land where He cannot sow anything.
But whatever it is, what Blake has done is
to give you a new vision and a new idea, because
in the West, Christ has been shrunk to a position
of someone who was just a human being and
now, when you hear the way people describe
Him, I'm amazed. From where did they get this
vision? Have they got eyes or are they blind
to talk like this about Him? I hear the bishops
talking like that, all your archbishops talking
like that. Have they no fear of God? What's
going to happen to this country if you talk
about Christ like that? And you are going
to have now pictures and films showing Him
to be a unrighteous personality, showing His
Mother naked. No respect. Even Blake, I don't
know if you have noticed it, He paints human
beings naked all right, but not gods. Christ
He never painted, He never paints them that
way, the respect. While we, the great intellectuals
of modern times are trying all these tricks,
just to bring forth the wrath of God upon
ourselves.
The second point about Him was that He was
a printer. We should think why did He become
a printer? Why Blake took to printing? He
has described Himself the hell where the books
were created and how He has described, how
at every chakra we created a devil and put
them in the libraries. I'm ... that's why
against the books very much, Myself. But why
did He become a printer? It's very important
to know and why He wrote so much about printing.
We see the media today. The media, that's
the devil He described. The media is the one
has ruined you completely believe Me - just
to make money out of you, playing upon your
weaknesses, making your children and you weaker
and weaker, the society completely being destroyed,
systematically. This is the media He wanted
to hit, that's why He took His birth and became
a printer. He could have been anything else.
No poet was a printer in England or anywhere
else. It was Blake, who became that. The reason
was He wanted to show that this media is the
one and let Him cut it at its root.
But as you know, evil grows, whether you like
it or not and today's media we cannot understand
to what extent it has destroyed us, our roots,
our faiths, all our sublime and righteous
visions. I know that I Myself was asked by
your television people and all that, to come
down and talk to them. But amazed at the way
the people told Me that an Anglo Saxon brain,
God knows who made that brain, cannot understand
anything that can be done without money. I
said you first get your realization, otherwise
I'm not coming to your programs, or to your
televisions. That's the triumphant pride of
Christ you can see in His crucifixion. He
didn't care, He could have gone fallen at
the feet, you see, as our politicians do,
morning 'til evening, moving from one place
to another. He would have gone to the scribes
and the Pharisees and said, "Oh, please forgive,
I will serve you all My life, I'll sell everything."
He would not accept that bribe. He went with
that triumphant pride on the cross. But what
does it show? What does it show? That we,
the stupid, crucified that great Personality
and today are we not again crucifying Him?
That's why I'll say that He was a great Prophet,
because He makes prophecies that, if you do
not take to the right path, if you do not
take to the higher seeking, all these things
will show. Now we have to understand, because
it concerns us. This is what is happening
to us, to us, to our children, to our families,
to our society, to our country. Let us face
it and understand that compassion of God can
fail in such horrible, blazing hearts, which
doesn't have any understanding of the spirit.
Sahaja Yoga came on this earth long time back,
much before I came on this earth, and today
it has come to England. We should say I came
here twelve years back. It took fourteen years
for Blake to write Jerusalem and I think after
fourteen years also if I could really feel
satisfied that I've been able to do some justice
to Him in this Jerusalem that He wanted to
build, I'll be very much grateful to you all.
But it's not so, it's a very disappointing
thing. People don't want to listen anything,
they want to listen to something that they
like, that you have to play on their weaknesses;
all the time tell them that whatever wrong
you are doing is a good thing; go ahead with
it.
Now the compassion and love of Christ can
work out miracles, no doubt. It can work out,
because He came for us. The whole universe
was created for us. It is for us to receive
all the blessings of the Divine. It is we
who are going to become the spirit. As He
said, "You are to be born again". But the
conditioning, of the subtle conditionings
of these ... surroundings and the atmosphere,
the history and all that, is so much embedded
in us, but we don't realize and are not aware,
that we have to look upward.
Blake's life was another crucifixion, I feel.
When I read Him, tears fall continuously sometimes.
What a Son of a great Father, who said Christ
was not bothered about His parents. He ran
away from the house at the age of twelve years.
That means all the boys are now running from
their houses at twelve years taking to drugs;
that's the best way we can pay homage to Him,
by running away from the houses taking to
drugs, because Christ ran away from the house
at the age of twelve years. And He said, "This
is My Father's business," that's what He writes,
"What do I care for the parents?" That does
not mean that you should not respect your
parents, but it means that, "I am at a higher
seeking, I have a higher seeking, I have to
move in another direction. You have lived
in this direction, whatever it is you have
balanced your life, but I have to ascend."
And this is the message He has tried to put
forward before you, very clearly. That is
so obvious, so clear cut. Wherever He's so
fiery, wherever He's so compassionate, wherever
He's so gentle, wherever He's so modest, the
inner line is one that, "Achieve your ascent;
achieve your higher being; become that." He
has prepared grounds for us here in England.
As I have told you many a times, England is
a very important part of the universe, which
I don't know how many Englishmen realize.
It is the heart of the universe; it is small,
but so important. But what do we get from
the heart? What do we have in the heart? Racialism.
If Christ comes here, you'll throw Him out
because He's not English, or do you believe
that He was English?
What do we get ? We can't love our children,
we kill our children, we ill-treat them. You
are sitting in the heart of the universe.
This is the heart of the universe and what
do you have to give to the world? The spirit.
The spirit resides in your heart and that's
why Blake said that England has to become
Jerusalem, because it is the heart. That means
spirit has to come in the attention of the
universe, otherwise things won't work out,
but from where is it going to come, this spirit,
where is going to be awakened? It is going
to be awakened in the human beings, and where
are those human beings - in the heart? Where
are they living? Even those who have come
here, immigrants and all that, they are gone
cases, useless, good for nothing. And those
who are living here are already lethargic;
the heart is lethargic, it cannot pump anything
out of it. First it was over pumping, tried
to impress the whole world, and now after
the impression, it is in depression.
This heart has to awaken, to make the whole
world a spiritual being. Do we realize our
responsibility? Do we understand this - what
is the role we have to play as a spiritual
being? You have to play a role as a spiritual
being now; but we are not, we are busy with
all other nonsensical things, but with the
spirit. I have labored for twelve years, as
I said, and I think I'll have to stay here
for two years more, fourteen years, and then
only maybe, I hope so, Jerusalem will start
showing its results in this country. You can
do it, you are the only ones who can do it,
nobody else. You are entitled to that. God
has chosen you to be born here, with a purpose.
But you can't talk to any one about religion,
they don't discuss religion. But what religion?
Religion which contains all the religions
of the world. Religion which is the inner
balance, the tranquility within you, which
gives you the ascent and we don't discuss
it. This is out of etiquette, we can discuss
all the drunkards and all the pubs of the
world, but we cannot discuss such a horrible
thing like religion, which is so innate and
within ourselves.
You cannot have anything in the newspaper
about it. But, He has described all the fake
gurus and all the satanic people with such
a strong description of all these and you
see them and thousands follow these nonsensical
people, pay them money, become beggars, but
they don't want to come to reality. Why, I
ask Myself, why it's happening like this?
No use going to any excuses. Here is someone
who has given you such a lot of explanation.
Holy Ghost, He says, and Holy Ghost ... a
vacuum. You ask anyone, I was surprised, when
it was asked to some very big bishop, "What
do you think of Holy Ghost?" He says, "I'm
agnostic, agnostic." Then ... from India ... asks
him, "Then what are you doing here?" He said,
"I am doing my job, as you are doing your
job." [unknown name and word] it's all quiet.
He's agnostic, he doesn't know anything about
Holy Ghost.
What is Holy Ghost? William Blake has said,
"It resides within you." Why don't we find
out where does it reside? ... Why not we go
out of the way to find out? Bible cannot contain
Christ, the whole universe cannot contain
Christ. Let us go out and find out what others
have to say about it. But we are very insular
self-opinionated, great people sitting here
in complete lethargy. We have no time, we
don't think anybody to be considered about
it, let us go out and see. What is Holy Ghost
is very simple; Holy Ghost is the Kundalini.
See, you use logic, not rationality but logic,
is different. If you use your logic, you will
see that we have a Trinity, Holy Trinity.
We have God Almighty, all right, and we have
the Son and the Holy Ghost. Have you heard
of any father having a son without the mother?
Then who is the Holy Ghost is the Primordial
Mother. Automatically you come to that conclusion,
but Mother should not be mentioned.
That's why Blake has said about the daughters
of Albion, because He knew the way the women
were suppressed in this life. Very sophisticated
ways. In Sanskrit it is said, yatra narya
pujyante tatra ramente devata "Where the women
are worshipped, there remains the domain of
the deities." Where they are worshipped, and
they have to be worshipful, not the harlots,
in the brothels and the women who walk nude
and show off their nudity to excite the baser
self, but the ones who are worshipful, where
they reside, reside the gods. So these women
were suppressed and suppressed to such an
extent that they did not want to talk about
God as a Woman, anywhere. So Holy Ghost is
something abstract, a dove. All right, it's
a dove, then what. What does it do the dove?
Why is it so important that we should have
blessings from the dove? Nobody explains,
it's a mystery.
We have to live with a mystery; everything
is a mystery, the banking is a mystery here,
the where does the money go is also a mystery.
It has something to do with the mafia, that's
also a mystery, then the Masonic people are
organizing the Switzerland bank is also a
mystery. Everything mysterious and hidden
and kept aside, "Oh, that is not to be said,
this is just 'overseas banking' Oh good, very
good name." It's 'overseas banking', it is
this, it is that, and we carry on with this
hypocrisy, we carry on with all these false
notions, "Oh that's all right, that's all
right, that part is all right." This is not
forgiveness. What is the forgiveness for the
cunning? What is the forgiveness for the crooked?
What is the forgiveness for satan? Discrimination
is needed when we talk of forgiveness. Forgiveness
is for the people who think they have committed
sins. It's only in thinking you commit sins,
otherwise you do not. Look at a dog, look
at a tiger, look at all these people, if tiger
has to eat the cow, it eats; does it commit
any sin? It does not know about a sin. "Now
I didn't know what is sin is," he will say
that, "I didn't know it was a sin, you see
I just ate it, but what is the sin?"
Just to condemn someone all the time, "You
are the sinners, you did this sin, you did
that sin." Human beings, they are the temple
of God. With what care, with love, affection,
delicacy they are created. For what? This
lotus has been brought out of the mire of
illusion for what? To be condemned? To be
trampled? To be ill-treated in this way, that
too in the name of God? Lotuses are created
to be offered to the Gods, with their fragrance,
to illuminate the whole world. They are the
poetic genius of the Lord, as He has described.
While we look at human beings as something
to be exploited, to be suppressed, to be oppressed
and so, as He says, there are two types of
people, and He has given horrible names to
them, who try to oppress the people, who try
to devour the people and He calls that the
religion now has become the compromise between
the two.
While the innocent suffer, while the simple
suffer, while the seekers suffer, while the
good suffer, that's the fact. Let us all of
us join together now and get our realization.
Become the spirit. Is the easiest thing to
do for you, because the Holy Ghost, which
is the Kundalini, is within you. In the triangular
bone She resides and She can be awakened.
Now one may say that, "Why didn't He talk
about Kundalini? Whatever He talked, who listened
to him? Whatever He said, who tried to understand;
till today I don't find many people have understood
Him. Whatever He manifested, who bothered
to know about it? And if He had talked of
something more, it would have been obscure.
But He says, "I don't care for the idiots
for whom My sayings are obscure." He says
clearly. He has used only thrice the word
'idiot' I think, many times 'stupid' and so
many times 'the fools'. Above all that, to
Me, all of them are God's own children. I
know how He was angry. I know why He was angry
and I also understand Him that He thought
that, before Sahaja Yoga coming here, let
Me scold them, let Me give them a thump, let
Me open them with a big blow, so they are
ready. But in His criticism, I read, they
said He was not acceptable because He went
too far.
Same with Me. People don't accept Me because
I go too far. I must try to please them. Am
I seeking your votes that I should try to
please you? I have to tell you the truth,
whether you like it or not. I want you to
accept it because that's what I am here for.
I'm here for that, that you accept the truth
and get it. I'll do my level best. I can make
food for you, I can give you good food to
you, I can give you presents, I can do whatever
a Mother can do for Her children. But when
it doesn't work out, She has to shout sometimes.
She has to say things clearly, because you
have to get it. Now you cannot force it on
people, this is the biggest problem is. You
cannot force Self-realization on to people,
you cannot do it by force. Say if the ... supposing
Russians tell Me they are very much interested
to know about Sahaja Yoga. No doubt. But if
they tell Me that, "You come to our government
and give them realization", I cannot, I cannot
do it. You have to be free people. When you
are free, then you are abandoned, see, the
wages of freedom we are paying. Nobody is
free, in New York if you go, I have to take
out all these ornaments, which I am supposed
to wear because of My family. I have to go
there without a purse, I have to tie up my
purse inside here see something, otherwise
they'll rob it. Nothing is safe.
So this kind of a freedom which leads to violence,
to butchery; actually the way we have butchered
our children, butchered our elders, the way
insulted every one of them, all that goes
hand in hand with freedom. This is no freedom,
this is absolutely unleashed abandonment of
the brutal self within us. So whether you
go to Russia or to here Sahaja Yoga is in
a problem, whether you go to the left or to
the right, I just don't understand, where
will it prosper, where freedom is used with
wisdom, with respect. If you cannot respect
the freedom of others you do not have the
freedom at all, you have never known the freedom,
you have never enjoyed the freedom. So the
freedom of human beings has to be respected
and when this freedom is respected, then only
you can get your realization and then only
you can enter into higher freedom, into complete
liberty that Blake has described.
There are seekers, so many seekers in this
country, and so many are lost, so many are
lost. There have been people who are saved
by Sahaja Yoga, who have been taking drugs,
overnight they gave up, overnight. How? It's
a mechanism within you, God has built that,
that power of the spirit when it enlightens
you, you just become so powerful, you give
up. But beforehand if I say, "Don't have this
and don't have that", you cannot do it. You
do not have that power of the spirit. Most
of the incarnations who came before Christ
didn't realize this point, that human beings
are not enlightened, they don't have the power
of the spirit within them. Christ realized
it and He said it openly, "You are to be born
again." Not only that, but He said, "First
of all forgive, talk of forgiveness." So that
they settle down, that they are not paranoid,
that they are not upset. Let them be settled
down in peace and in compassion and then awaken
their kundalini and then give them realization.
So then you have the power, then there is
no temptation, nothing like that. Will you
tempt Christ with anything? You cannot. In
the same way you do not get enslaved to any
temptations. You rise in your own beauty and
glory, and your own strength and power. You
don't have to get subdued to anything. This
is what is Self-realization. Sahaja Yoga came
to London about twelve years back when I came.
Now I am not an immigrant for your information,
at all. I just came by chance, I should say,
or by God's ordained programming. My husband
got elected to this job out of hundred and
thirty-four nations, you see. He was elected
, we came here, just because he was elected,
not even appointed, but elected, and elected
four times unanimously. He is the senior most
senior secretary-general. So we had to come
here, and that's how I'm here, otherwise I
may not have ever come to England to teach
Sahaja Yoga.
With Blake, One feels compelled to try and
try and try to establish Jerusalem, whatever
may be the case, whatever may be the disappointment,
whatever may be the disgust, doesn't matter.
One has to do it. He had such faith in the
England's soil that we have to build the Jerusalem.
But first, everyone of you who are here must
get your realization and humble down before
your realization. You are not to be arrogant
with it. He said Christ was not humble before
human beings, but before God He was. Before
His Father He was. In the same way, you have
to be humble before your spirit and before
your Self-realization and you have to get
to the higher state. It's surprising that
in India, we had all this knowledge all these
years, but we were supposed to be heathens,
I don't know what else they called us. We
were supposed to be slaves. Nobody wanted
to know anything about it, the knowledge of
the roots existed and our intellectuals also
never bothered, they always followed Oxford
and Cambridge traditions. With this Oxbridge
business, we never got through people to tell
them about this great knowledge we had in
that country and everything subsided.
This knowledge is not meant for India, is
not meant for any particular place, is meant
for the whole world, as your knowledge of
science, all the knowledge of the tree is
meant for the whole world, which you gave
it to us, or to give it to all the eastern
countries and people accept it. What's the
harm in accepting the knowledge which comes
to you for your benevolence; only because
it is from the eastern side you feel so insecure
about it? From where did Christ come? He came
from America? I think He must have run away.
Despite that I must say among all of them,
British are the most matured. But we run after
Americans, we run after French, we run after
everyone, not being aware of ourselves, what
we are, we are wisdom. We are the people who
represent the heart of the universe and time
has taken, from Him to this time, that we
have matured now. I hope we have matured enough
to understand that there has to be a breakthrough.
When they published My handbills, you see,
somehow it so happened that My face has come
out quite black in that. I said, "Forget it,
nobody will come to our program, if you show
such a black face they'll say, 'oh, somebody
coming from Africa is trying to teach us what
is Jerusalem'." So they had to re-do it, to
show that I am not that black. What difference
does it make, the skin deep color? The color
comes from the heart, the beauty comes from
the heart, the exuberance of the heart expresses
that beauty on your being and the beauty of
the truth is that, that it acts, it works.
It just doesn't decorate itself, it doesn't
try to take to ways and methods of luring
people but it acts, whether you like it or
not it acts. Let us work it out. Is simple.
Instead of going into intellectual feats and
going into the direction of finite understanding
through your brains, let us go to the infinite;
that's only possible when you get to your
spirit, which is infinite, which creates the
collective consciousness within. Which creates,
I say, which means knowledge, but knowledge
does not mean what you know through your brain,
but what you know through your central nervous
system; that you can feel it, that you can
feel the chakras of everyone on your fingertips.
Mohammed Sahib has said, "At the time of resurrection
your hands will speak". But look at the Muslims,
they never, never talk of the resurrection,
when most of Koran is nothing but resurrection.
They talk of the doomsday because they have
to make money by frightening people. Beware
of the doomsday, you give the money, we'll
save you, we'll give a certificate; at the
doomsday you stand with the certificate, you'll
be saved. First they will go down in the doomsday.
This is for every religion, people have used
it for very baser things, making money, creating
political ideas. I can't understand how can
diamonds be thrown into dirt like this, and
covered with that, and the fragrance turned
into filth. It is beyond Me. The powers of
human beings sometimes supercede that of God,
you can see the way they can change the forms,
they change the beauty, change everything
that is reality, into something nonsensical
and stupid. And they live with it, they don't
want to know about it; they enjoy it. "We
are very happy people, what's wrong." What
a waste, one feels, of this creation. One
feels with what aspirations and visions these
human beings were created on this earth. And
then what should we do to make them understand
what they are, to make them aware with that
perception, with that vision of the Divine
that they are? Sometimes, I also cry in the
wilderness and share some of the pathos of
all these poets who came on this earth and
suffered, and suffered, and suffered.
I hope today, with all this anguish, whatever
I am telling you, you will try to see that
sincerity is the only way you can understand
yourself. No books , nothing, no conditioning,
no denial, nothing can convince you but the
sincerity to know the spirit, which is within
you and this sincerity I call it as the pure
desire. If you have that pure desire, which
is the power of your kundalini, you will get
your realization. Now, just now, the shoot.
That's all is needed, the pure desire to be
the spirit, nothing more than that. But when
it is awakened, then it is to be looked after,
that's very important; it has to be looked
after, it has to be kept burning, it has to
be maneuvered and kept at a point that you
start growing more and more. I need not tell
you all about Sahaja Yoga, it's going to be
too much for you, but how Blake has worked
for us. So many poets have done this job and
now the new great poets are coming to finish
us off, to please the media, to make money,
befool us, using flowery words, pleasing sentences,
taking us to hell directly. Beware of them,
beware, save your children from them, save
the whole community. The whole of England
has to be saved because if the heart dies,
the whole universe will die.
May God bless you.
The Sahaja yogis didn't want Me to allow you
to ask Me questions but I think better ask
Me some questions.
Q.....about the chakras....
Shri Mataji: Yes sir. That's what I said,
that I didn't talk about them because it would
be too long a lecture but we have got a book
on this, a little book and there it is all
written though I say that before realization
don't even read that book, can create problems.
You can know all about the subtle side, the
chakras and everything without paying anything,
without any effort. There are people now in
England, you will be surprised, so many of
them are excellent Sahaja yogis who are experts
and they will tell you all about it very clearly.
We have got books to explain. As you see there
are seven chakras are shown here. The lowermost
is the Mooladhara Chakra, is the innocence.
Q:...can you see it with your eyes, outside
the body, can you see it?
Shri Mataji: If you see something then you
are not that. And people have seen it because
they were not that, because they moved on
the sides, on the sympathetic nervous system,
what we call the Ida and Pingala. When you
go on sympathetic nervous system you can see
it from outside. Like this building you can
see it from outside, but when you are in it
you don't see it, you see only the inside.
So that's what it is, when you ascend, you
need not see anything, you become, you get
the powers. People have seen it no doubt,
but that one should not ask for. I can see
the glass - better to drink the water. Now
what else?
Q:....what do You do with all Your wealth,
all your money?
Shri Mataji: My money? Are you from the bank?
What I do with My money - what do you want
Me to do? What sort of a question is this?
Ask a simple straightforward question madam
I don't understand what do I do with My money,
I don't do anything with it. Actually My husband
manages his money, I ask him whatever I like.
Of course he earns a lot no doubt, he earns
very much. I sometimes tell him, "I'm ashamed
the way they give you money," because he doesn't
even pay any tax you know. Of course I do
spend some money on Sahaja Yoga, I must confess
I have to sometimes, what to do? One has to
and these people have their own ashrams, where
they stay, and look after it. For this hall
they must have collected some money I don't
know, I don't know what do they do with their
money, I don't know, I have no idea, I've
never seen that. They are honest people, they
all know all about it. I don't know anything,
I have nothing to do with it. This is the
aggressiveness, "What do I do with My money"
Just look at this. Yes sir?
Q....a man has mental illness, he wants to
know whether he'll have it after he dies....
Shri Mataji: No, no, no, just now you can
cure it. Why to think of death? You can be
cured of your mental illness at least, minimum,
that could be done.
Q....How can you tell that it's Self-realization?
You feel a breeze but how does it become...
Shri Mataji: You see, when you feel the cool
breeze is the beginning of it, all right?
Now you have to see what this cool breeze
is, all right? Now if you go to a college
of science or a college of medicine what you
have to do is to see what it is, isn't it;
and to see whatever it says does it prove.
Now, when you see the cool breeze in your
hand, what happens that it is, as I said,
is the compassion of God say for example,
you just believe in the hypothesis just now.
Now what is this compassion doing, is made
you a computer. On the fingertips you can
tell what centers are catching, of yours and
of others, so you become the diagnosis. Now
if you know a little few gestures by which
you can handle this power, you can cure them.
That's the minimum, all right? You can know
from this whether you have mental problem
or you have emotional problem, or you have
physical problem and of what nature. This
is how is the self-knowledge starts, from
the very basics.
What's your problem with you, first let us
see the problem on the centers, all right?
Then you move forward when you go with it,
then you understand what's the problem with
others; then what's the problem in the collective;
then what's the problem of this country; and
if you know how to solve them, sitting down
here, you can do it, you can solve it. But
this is the breeze which has to be felt first
because this is the breeze which we call as
the all-pervading power of God. Now, just
because I say you should not believe Me, because
blind faith is of no use, but you can experiment
and see for yourself. Even little children
know. They can tell you what is catching in
you, what chakras are catching. You can have
ten children, 'fold' their eyes, put them
before a gentleman, immediately they'll raise
this finger or this finger. Supposing they
raise this finger, means this person feels
terribly guilty. He must be a Catholic that
he feels so guilty. That the children won't
say but you will know that this is the chakra
is caught up here because he's feeling guilty.
Like that you can go on finding on your own
being like a laboratory the whole thing becomes
like a computer because it is knowledge, knowledge
through your central nervous system, through
your evolutionary process. But you have to
practice and understand what it is. If I give
you a car, how will you know it moves unless
and until you get into it and know how to
drive it, isn't it. You have to give some
time, not much, but you enjoy, best part of
it you enjoy doing the whole thing. It just
flows automatically, you don't have to do
anything about it.
But one has to learn, little bit, what it
is. Before realization you don't have to do
anything, it just forms spontaneously as the
seed is sown in the Mother Earth, all right?
Then when it comes out, then you have to look
after it; the same way you have to look after
your realization, respect it. Then you become
the masters. We have one master standing here
and we have so many. They are just like you
to look at, but they know so much and they
are so humble. They don't go about with a
big plate on their heads "I am the master
of this and master of that" nothing. They
are doing all their jobs, they are doing very
well, they are blessed and also they are helping
people to get their realization. You'll be
surprised in Sahaja Yoga very difficult to
get an unemployed person. All of them are
employed. If they are unemployed they get
employment with God also. Basically they are
employed by God. All right?
Q... is this the only way to get realization?
Shri Mataji: Yes, of course; there cannot
be another, God could not make thousand and
one, could He? That would be too much of a
headache , like as you sprout the seed, how
do you do it? Spontaneously. Sahaja Yoga means
spontaneous, living process is always spontaneous.
Now supposing we want to sprout a seed and
we take out the primule, push it out and push
it inside the Mother Earth, will it sprout
- no. You have to take advantage of the powers
of the Mother Earth, to sprout a seed, isn't
it?
Q. ...saying she has not come across Sahaja
Yoga in the religions, that there are many
religions.
Shri Mataji: In the religions there's no ... religions
are no religions, that's the trouble is. I
have told you all this just now that there
is nothing, they will never mention that is
sensible, but it's not so. I would say Sikhism,
we can say is the latest religion. I mean
there are so many verses about, much later
than Islam, Sikhism came on this earth and
they have said that, complete description,
I mean you don't understand Hindi otherwise
I would have told you - Ida, Pingala, Sushumna
- everything they have described - Kabira
has described at such length that we have
in India a great poet Gyaneshwara and He has
described all about kundalini. If you go in
Maharashtra and tell them that somebody is
going to awaken the kundalini, they'll all
rush, they know all about it.
How many years did Christ live? How many times
He could talk to people? How many of them
accepted Him and how many of them understood
Him? He went to a wrong place, I tell you;
all were deaf, dumb and brainless. How will
they understand? How could He talk about Kundalini
when everybody was after His life? But He
did talk of Holy Ghost, He talked of the Comforter
He was going to send. He talked of so many
things in that short time. Do you know for
four years I was struggling with seven hippies
in London; for four years. I must say, it's
very creditable for Him in three and a half
years to talk so much. How many years Blake
had to work hard to talk to you? Is it easy
to talk to people about truth? Very difficult;
everybody is extremely intelligent and wise,
nobody want to listen to anything, do they?
But in India we have a tradition; we know
it; that you have to ascend. The whole thing
works out that way. If they talk of kundalini,
not in the North so much, but in Maharashtra,
if you go, if you go in the South, you'll
be amazed six thousand people, seven thousand
people come in a village. They have seen it,
these people have seen it, they come in bullock
carts, they come in, any way that is possible
for them, buses, and trains, and they walk
miles together when they hear I'm there.
Once I was coming from a program in the night
and suddenly I found lots of people lying
on the road. I said, "Who are these people?"
They said, "Mother we couldn't reach Your
program, we were late, You give us realization
here." I said: "All right, have it." They
had it, they are the ones who'll get much
faster than anyone else, I know, that's why
I don't mind spending some time here. Once
I go there, you will see the whole country
would be ablaze, I'm not telling you lies,
you ask the people who have been there. They
are very different type of people, to them
most important is their spirit. If you tell
them what, the way we talk about Christ here,
so disrespectfully, without understanding,
they are shocked. Any Indian who is a Christian
or a Muslim or a Hindu, doesn't treat the
way you treat Bible. The respect they have
has come to them traditionally. Of course
you don't judge Indians by the Indians who
have come here. They like your company, they
are this type, they are materialistic, they
want to have money, they have come here to
earn money, but the people who are in India
in the villages, not in the cities, are still
seeking, seeking God, they're very simple
people, humble people.
Traditionally we have known for thousands
of years. I talk of Markandeya who was there
twelve thousand years back, who incarnated
here as William Blake. Twelve thousand years
back He said the same thing which is said
in England after twelve thousand years, because
that time I don't know what was here, may
be only jungles, I think. And that is also
waste, isn't it, tell Me, isn't it? How much
could Christ talk about kundalini? He talked
of Holy Ghost. But why stick on to that, now
I have come to talk to you. Better take your
realization; when He came, they talked of
Moses, when Moses came they talked of Abraham.
What about the present, I am with you, why
not have your realization? All religions were
built for this day, that you get your realization,
to give you the balance, to give you that
property by which you ascend. Like when we
have an aeroplane, we fix it up properly;
in the same way they wanted to fix you up,
but the religions went astray, they made people
crooked, the things they fixed, wrong bolts
into wrong places, the whole aeroplane is
in a tattered condition if it flies, it will
all fall down. Better give up all those ideas.
But kundalini is such a great force, it's
such a great force; it comforts you, it cures
you, it builds up all your centers and slowly
moves upward and when if you get realization,
also it goes back, attends to all these problems
that
you have. It's such a mother she is. Any other
question, please?
Q. Why are you to be known as Mataji, Mother?
Shri Mataji: I didn't follow.
Yogi: Nor did I. Why are You to be known as
Mataji?
Shri Mataji: As Shri Mataji? That's the title
they gave Me, what can I do? In India. You
have to be an Indian to understand that. There
are certain things described, about Shri Mataji.
If you have read any books, of Adi Shankaracharya,
or of Markandeya Himself, then you will know
and the qualities described there of such
a person, if they find it in someone, they
call that person by that name, isn't it? Like
Gandhiji was called as Mahatma Gandhi. Mahatma
means a bigger spirit than others, because
he had that. He didn't care for himself or
his own family, everything for his own, but
he thought of the whole country; that's why
he was called Mahatma. Now, but I didn't call
Myself; if others want to call I think is
all right, I have no objection. You can call
anything, whatever you see, you can call that.
By calling that, what is your objection? Can
I ask you this question? Beg pardon? [No objection]
No objection. All right, that's all right.
See, then it's all right, if you understand
that it is must be some reason also.
(Further question from same person)
Q. Do you have some divine power?
Shri Mataji: That you better find out; I am
not going to be tactless on that. Christ said
what was the truth, that He was the Son of
God, all right, but they crucified Him. I
don't want to get crucified so soon.
[INAUDIBLE Q:] But the one who is an Indian,
who is an Indian and Englishman. [Hindi].
You see
it is for an ... Indians understand it better.
[Hindi]
I'm sorry I'm speaking in Hindi because I
have to little bit chastise the Indians here,
I hope you don't mind. [Hindi]
Now, what is another question please? Yes
please?
Q. Yogi: Mother, she is
asking if you can cure physical ailment, I
mean the answer's yes, that comes from Self-realization,
no question.
Shri Mataji with your permission, the majority
of people have come for the experience and
are anxious to have, I may be mistaken, but
I think most people would like to stop questions
and ...
Shri Mataji: But sometimes you know those
who want to ask, let them ask, otherwise the
brain will again put out a question. Now madam,
what is it..?
(SY. She's asking You, Mother, what life was
like for You as a child)?
Shri Mataji: As a child? I mean that's another
story; you come and see Me, I'll tell you
all about it. Why do you want to know about
My past and future? Let us at the present
time to get your realization; makes no difference
what I was as a child, or what I was as an
old woman.
Yogi: ... She's asking whether you have an
opinion about the growth of interest in spirituality
in England...
Shri Mataji: What spirituality?
Yogi asks questioner: spiritualism or spirituality?
Questioner answers: spiritualism.
Shri Mataji: That's the witchcraft, revived;
very, very dangerous. Ah, is very dangerous,
never go near that, all this parapsychology
and all those things. We have described all
these things in our book; you can have a look
at it. Is a very comprehensive thing, Sahaja
Yoga is. Is the witchcraft, you may call it
spirituality, because a spirit can be also
a dead soul as I told you, in English language.
There is no 'ism' about God. It's infinite.
'Isms' are all finite things.
Q. SY: she's praising Your lecture, Mother,
and saying now that....she'll go back to read
Blake again.
Shri Mataji: I'm very happy, I'm very happy
that you say that, madam, it's really such
a great poet, but you'll be surprised in India,
none of them brought Blake. We never read
Blake there, never; you see we studied English
language, we studied Shakespeare, we studied
so many things, but never they mentioned Blake,
you know. I don't know why. In the whole education
system of India, they never mentioned Blake.
[another inaudible question ...]
Shri Mataji: That's very nice, such books
you must read. Such books you must read.
[Here someone disclaims in Sanskrit]
You see there's a Sanskrit scholar here, but
the greatest Guru is the Mother, don't you
think so? The Mother is the Guru of the gurus.
But it's very difficult, because guru is a
hard stuff, you see. A mother has to be very
soft, kind, gentle to manage the show, but
the guru can be very hard and they are very
hard people, but Mother as a guru is a difficult
task, it's very enjoyable.
Now I have given at least eleven lectures
on Guru tattwa, all right? So you can take
tapes from them, you can read it and you will
enjoy it very well. Here the Guru tattwa is
expressed in the Void, there, where the ten
Gurus actually incarnated basically and they
reincarnated. Say we can start from Adi Nath,
then we can come to other ones like Nanaka,
Janaka. Janaka was much earlier, then we can
say Abraham, Moses. All these were Guru tattwa,
Socrates, all these were Guru tattwa people,
the people who came as Prophets; the ones
who came on this earth to teach us balance,
to teach us the code of life. That was also
important part, but that was forgot. Why?
Why the code, why the religion? Religion is
for the ascent, to build you up.
Q. ?Tattwa
Shri Mataji: Tattwam assi, that's what is
the tattwa there; tattwa is there; tattwa
is nothing but your kundalini is your tattwa,
is the principle....
Q: [INAUDIBLE] Parvati, Shiva; She's also
called as Kundalini.
Shri Mataji: Of course. Yes, yes, it is all
over, same thing. I'm just giving you the
gist of it.
SY: She's asking, Mother, who was Mother Durga,
she's asking about who was Mother Durga?
Shri Mataji: A very direct question; I told
you, I'm very tactful, I'm not going to confess
anything. You better find out, it's better
to find out. It's nice, isn't it? To find
out yourself.
Yogi: ...I'll explain, Mother, the program
is that tonight will be the experience of
realization and we have another program on
Saturday evening, here in the same place,
which will be for this knowledge part; after
realization, the knowledge makes more sense,
so it's better to get the experience...
Shri Mataji: But our experience is very funny,
I must tell you that for My program, even
if there may be one thousand people, for getting
realization, after that they just get lost,
never grow. That's only more in England, they
just don't ... they'll get lost, I think they
must be going to the pub after that. I can't
explain why it happens but they just get lost,
they don't want to know anything anymore.
I don't know why, I cannot explain, I mean,
is something I cannot explain. All right,
let's have it now.
So now, if we are all settled down, it's very
simple, Sahaj also means simple, Sahaj; saha
means 'with' ja means 'born'; is born with
you, this right to get this union, this yoga,
is born with you, is within you and is the
living process of the living God so it is
spontaneous. Everything that is living is
spontaneous and should happen to all of you,
no doubt about it. You don't have to do anything
as I said but you have to receive the power
within yourself, to invite the kundalini to
rise. Now first thing I have to request, I
hope it is not too much of it, that we have
to take out our shoes to touch the Mother
Earth. Is very important because the Mother
Earth is the one which sucks in, for a while.
I don't know, is there a carpet there? Be
in a mood of reception, and also of well-being,
in a happy mood, because this is the greatest
moment of our lives.
Now as I said that these fingers, here five,
six and seven, on the same way this way, represent
the two sides of the chakras within us, the
sympathetic sides, so we have to put our hands
like this, just like this, simple as that.
And sit, not crossed legged but putting both
the feet with respect, towards the Mother
Earth, in parallel to each other. Now maybe
some of you must have started feeling the
cool breeze, I don't know, might have, because
today's lecture was rather too terrific and
William Blake must have worked it out I'm
sure. But otherwise is very simple. Now we
have to do is to ourselves awaken our own
kundalini, which is very simple, which I will
tell you. In the heart resides the spirit
so first we'll have to put our hand to our
heart. I will tell you one by one. And then
in the upper part of your stomach where the
guru tattwa is here, the principle of guru
is there. Then in the lower part of the abdomen,
where it is the divine, or we can say the
pure knowledge that exists and which works.
This is the center through which the pure
knowledge, the pure technique, works. Then
we take this hand again back, same way, up
to this point where, it is here, when we are
guilty we catch this chakra. Now here works
our self-confidence, our faith in God that
He forgives us. Then we put our hand on top
of our head - this is the Agnya Chakra, which
is very important. Here we forgive everyone;
then at the back of the Agnya Chakra again,
where we have to say that, "If we done any
mistake, oh God forgive us". These are the
two sides of the Agnya Chakra. And then you
put your hand, stretch it, put this part on
the fontanel bone area, the soft bone which
was on top of our head and press it hard and
move it hard, for a while. That's all one
has to do. I'll tell you one by one.
First and foremost thing is, we have to close
our eyes, because eyes take out our attention;
but attention will be sucked inside our body
in the sense it will go through the - just
like this cloth - it is spread out, but as
kundalini rises, She sucks it in and then
pierces through this attention, enlight[en]ing
all of that. It's a happening that takes place
without any trouble whatsoever. As a result
of that, what you get is the cool breeze coming
out of your head; you can also feel the cool
breeze in your fingertips; then later on in
your hands and you get that shine on your
skin. Christ has said, "The face that does
not shine cannot become the star." And then
you get that glint of shine of the spirit
in your eyes. That's all, is not the point,
is much, much, much, much more but just a
wee bit that we have to today testify and
later on to find out have we got realization
all right, then can we work it out, can we
do this, because later on we have to play
our role now as a spiritual being, that's
the point one has to understand.
So now, have respect for yourself first of
all; and not to feel guilty at all. You are
the temple of God, really believe Me you are
made that way, only the light is to be kindled
and that is in your heart. When the kundalini
rises, she's something like an energy that
does that because when she pierces through,
this is the place where the God Almighty resides,
who is reflected in our heart as the spirit
and the all-pervading power, which is the
Primordial Mother, the Holy Ghost, this vibrations
that you feel, the power of God, the love
of God which is represented within us as the
kundalini, rises and unites us, our attention
to the Divine. The spirit enlightens the attention
and by that enlightenment you know, on your
fingertips, on your central nervous system,
through your new collective consciousness
about yourself and about others. Through Sahaja
Yoga you know how to cure, improve, and through
this happening, through the spirit you enjoy
because spirit - the nature of spirit is satchidanand,
means it is the truth, it becomes the attention
and it is the source of joy. Without getting
realization you can be happy and unhappy but
you cannot be joy, which has no dualism. You
become the source of joy. Such a person, when
he meets someone; he sees someone, he looks
at someone, just a kataksh is sufficient to
raise the kundalini - just a glance is sufficient
to cure that person; just a thought, can give
comfort to the other person. Miracles after
miracles, so many miracles that as Sahaja
yogis say, "miracle' has lost its meaning
Mother, in Sahaja Yoga," that's true. So miracles
of miracles and every moment you feel that
God is looking after you.
When this great volcano burst, exploded in
Mexico, a miracle happened they say, that
the children were saved. The wrath - no this
was not in Mexico but later on more in Colombia,
because Colombia is sending all kinds of these
horrible things all over the world, making
money out of it. The wrath of the Mother Earth
poured that mud and the people were drowned
but the children survived. Their heads were
above the mud, the body inside the mud. The
same Mother Earth looked after them because
they should not be burned so She covered them
with the mud, why? Because of the innocence
in them. Those who have even the slightest
innocence in them will become realized souls,
no doubt about it - slightest, a very wee
bit. All the seekers are a special category
of people and they have to become realized
souls.
So forget about the past, forget whatever
you have done in your seeking, whatever you
are told, whatever you are branded with, just
forget it and forgive yourself, once for all.
This is I am telling you this because this
is one of the biggest problems of the West
that everybody sits down with a bad, horrible
trouble here and sometimes I feel it so much
that I can't even hear people. Is terrible.
This portion is so bad here so I have to request
you that please forgive yourself. You are
the glory of God, without you God has no meaning
also. It is He who is anxious, much more then
you are, to give you realization. Just help
Him out a little.
All right. Let us see. So we put our both
the hands like this, close our eyes. Now you
have to keep the left hand all the time towards
Me, because is the desire, is expressed through
it is the power of desire in the left hand
which expresses that you want to have realization.
The right hand is the power of action so you
move your right hand but don't open your eyes.
You have to keep your eyes all the time shut,
just the opposite of mesmerism as you can
see. Now please close your eyes; now put your
right hand on your heart.
Now here you have to say, or ask Me a question,
"Mother am I the spirit?" You may call Me
Shri Mataji or Mother, whatever suits you.
"Mother am I the spirit?" is a fundamental
question and if you are a computer it will
answer. "Mother am I the spirit?" Ask the
question three times please. Put your left
hand properly, please close your eyes; everybody
should do it, please. It's uncivil not to
close your eyes; please close your eyes because
others may feel self-conscious so please close
your eyes, to be courteous.
Now you have to take down your right hand
on the upper part of your stomach, on the
left hand side, we are working only on the
left hand side. Here is the principle of the
master. If you are the spirit, automatically
you have to ask the second question, "Mother
am I my own master? Mother am I my own guru?"
Please ask this question, you have to ask
this question three times again, without fear,
with all confidence you ask this question,
you are the spirit, you are your master.
Now move your right hand on the lower part
of your abdomen on the left hand side, lower
part of your abdomen on the left hand side.
This is the center of the divine work, of
the divine knowledge or the pure knowledge,
of the technique of divine manifestation.
At this point I cannot force you to do anything,
as I told you, you have to be free, I can
only request you and here I say that you have
to ask for the divine knowledge, you have
to ask for the pure knowledge and when you
ask for it the kundalini will start moving.
Here with sincere heart, in a humble way you
have to say, "Mother may I have the pure knowledge,
Mother may I have the divine technique?" Ask
this question six times because this center
has got six petals.
Now to make the way easy for kundalini, we
go along the same centers upwards so you put
your right hand on the upper part of your
abdomen, to make it easy for the kundalini
to rise you have to open this center by asserting,
by saying "Mother I am my own master", by
saying "Mother I am my own master", ten times
because there are ten petals, ten Sat gurus
basically who incarnate ten times, of Prophets,
the Masters.
Now raise your right hand on your heart, press
it. With the same confidence you have to say
twelve times "Mother I am the spirit, I am
the spirit, I am the spirit". Just assert,
that's a fact, that's the truth. Press it
with your fingers. Now, twelve times, have
full confidence in you, believe Me you are
the spirit, you have to just become in the
sense it has to come in your attention on
to your central nervous system.
Now raise the right hand on the left hand
side of your neck, in the corner where the
neck and the shoulder meet, press it hard,
take it backwards, press it hard. This is
the most difficult center in the West, as
I told you, that we feel guilty all the time
but as I have told you, God is the ocean of
love, ocean of compassion, but above all He
is the ocean of forgiveness. He's the ocean
of forgiveness. When He's the ocean of forgiveness,
what guilt can we have that He cannot wash
away or dissolve it? So just you have to say
sixteen times because there are sixteen petals,
to say sixteen times with full belief in yourself,
"Mother I'm not guilty, Mother, I'm not guilty,
Mother, I'm not guilty" sixteen times will
you please say that "Shri Mataji I'm not guilty".
If you still feel you are guilty and you can't
forgive yourself, better say it to punish
yourself hundred and eight times, if that
pleases you.
When you forgive yourself you have to forgive
others and so the greatest message of Christ,
that we have to forgive others you have to
put your hand to the center which is the adornment
or we should say which adorns Christ, on the
Agnya Chakra on your forehead, please put
your right hand across,. Press it hard and
here you have to say with full belief in yourself
and in your powers that, "Shri Mataji I forgive
everyone". Some may say that's very difficult
but what do we do when we forgive or not forgive
- no logic in it. But when we say that, then
we are out of the clutches of other people,
so please say, "Shri Mataji I forgive everyone.
Now say it with your whole heart, how many
times is not the point, please say it with
your whole heart. Now you move your hand backwards
onto the back side of the same center - Agnya
- press it hard. Now here, you have to say
once only without feeling guilty at all, without
feeling no remorse, no condemnation, to God,
one for your satisfaction, "Oh Lord, if I
have done anything wrong, please forgive me"
but don't feel guilty, that's very important.
Even without saying He has forgiven you. Better.
Now raise your right hand on top of your head,
stretch your ... stretch your palm, press
it hard on the fontanel bone area, which was
the soft bone in your childhood, press it
hard, move it seven times. Again here I cannot
force anything on you. You have to say that
you want your Self-realization that, "Mother,
please give us our realization. We want our
Self-realization. Please give me my Self-realization"
and press it hard and move it seven times
and say that. I'm sure it will work out.
Now bring down your hand, slowly, and bend
your head a little bit and feel with your
left hand if there's a cool breeze coming
out of your fontanel bone area. Try to bend
your head a little, little bit and about four
inches above the head, bend it a little, that
works out better sometimes. With your left
hand, right hand towards Me and with the left
hand you see the breeze. Right hand towards
Me and then with the left hand you see, you
can feel it better, with the left hand on
top of your head; first with the left hand.
Aah. Now put the left hand towards Me and
with the right hand just see if it is blowing
because it should come in both the hands.
Open your eyes, open slowly and watch Me without
thinking. Let us see if you can do it - just
without thinking, just watch Me, without thinking.
There's no thought in your mind, no thought.
Now just put your hands like this, are you
feeling the cool breeze in the hand?
Now put your hands up in the air, like this,
and in your heart ask a question, "Is this
the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?" Ask the
question, put it up nicely, ask the question
three times: "Is this the cool breeze of the
Holy Ghost? Is this the brahma shakti? Is
this the all-pervading power of God? Ask the
question. Now put down your hands and see
for yourself if you feel the cool breeze.
All those who have felt the cool breeze on
the head, coming out of the head, or on their
fingertips or in the hands please raise your
hands, both the hands. That's Blake. You all
have become Blake. May God bless you.
So many. May God bless you. But I must warn
you, after this don't talk about it because
it is beyond reasoning. Secondly you must
come back, must all of you come back and work
it out. Those who haven't got realization
will also receive it. Those who have got it,
will establish it. Please come back. You will
enjoy the silence, the stillness within. But
that's just the beginning of it. We have to
go further. Otherwise you won't be able to
manifest it properly. It has to be looked
after. It's just a shoot that has come out,
a little shoot we have to look after it. May
God bless you all. Thank-you very much. Why
not sing Jerusalem to them ... will be good
idea.
Yogi: Mother with Your permission the music
group would like to sing one song for You
but before that we have a little memento of
this evening which we would like to present.
Shri Mataji: You want to sing, all right?
You have all the arrangements here. All right.
If you don't mind, just sit down for five
minutes.
Yogi: So Garuda take wing.
While we were preparing the program of Blake's
Birthday Festival Mother, we found out there
was an Exhibition of Blake's work in London
in one of the galleries and we very much wanted
to give You something that was made by His
own Hands and with the good wishes of all
the Sahaja yogis of England we've been able
to do it for You.
Shri Mataji: Oh that's too much, that's too
much Gavin, that's too much.
Yogi: No it's something special Mother, we
hope that it'll be our pledge to try to do
some justice to You as You've tried to do
some justice to Blake.
Shri Mataji: I'm so proud of Him, really.
Can you - I am not good at opening. Done so
well. Ohh. What a beautiful one. Trigunatmika.
Do you see the trigunatmika is there? What
a vision. I mean how can you understand Him
without Sahaja Yoga ... picture, you cannot
... May God bless you. Thank-you very much
Yogi: This is the engraving of
the Daughters of Job from the illustrations
to Book of Job.
Shri Mataji: What is?
Yogi: Daughters of Job.
Shri Mataji: Trigunatmika. Three Powers - the
Comforter, and the Counselor and the Redeemer,
three Powers, which you will know, later on.
We have those three Powers within ourselves.
Go ahead.
Yogi: [INAUDIBLE]
Shri Mataji: Thank you very much.
[The mike is not all right. Loudly.]
Song: 'Seek and You Will Find'.
Song: 'Jerusalem.' Yogi: We'd like everyone
to stand up to sing Jerusalem.
Shri Mataji: May God bless you all and bless
this country. God bless you.