Oh
[Music]
I bow to all the seekers of
you have to know that truth is what it
is we cannot conceptualize it with our
human awareness we cannot order it we
cannot manipulate it we cannot organize
it it is what it is has been unveiled
and what is the truth truth is that we
are surrounded or we are penetrated or
we are nourished looked after and loved
by a very subtle energy which is the
energy of divine love the second truth
is that we are not this body this mind
these conditionings this ego but we are
the spirit you don't have to accept what
I am saying blindly because blind
well-trained leads to fanaticism but as
scientists you must keep your mind open
and see for yourself what I am saying if
it is so honestly you must accept it
we know so much through science about
our civilization our advancement this is
the advancement of a tree which has
grown outside very much but if you do
not know our roots will be destroyed so
it is important to know about our roots
and this is what it is that I would say
are our roots as you can see there are
seven centers within us
and these subtle centers are placed in
the spinal cord and in the brain these
cater to our physical mental emotional
and spiritual needs on the physical side
they manifest the energy for the use of
our plexuses which look after our
physical problems that is on the right
side this energy which is supplied by
this yellow line
a subtle Channel we call it as the
Pingala Nadi this supplies energy for
our physical and mental actions so this
is the power of action within us which
also caters to the Wrights sympathetic
nervous system the another channel you
see on the left hand side is the channel
by which we desire put our energy to our
desire so this is the power of desire
and looks after our emotions this is the
one which looks after our conditionings
also at the end of these two channels
they create two institutions one on the
right side crosses over and the yellow
balloon that you see is the ego is the
balloon of ego that we have and the left
hand side one that which conditions our
mind is the balloon of super-ego
as we start growing in age by the time
we are 12 years of age these two
completely meet and the soft bone in our
head becomes completely calcified now
there's third energy within us which is
in the center and this Center central
energy is the one which has made us
human beings and these centers are the
milestones of our evolution so now the
last jumping is left out it has reached
up to the limbic area now only thing is
it has to break through the soft bone in
the on the head and break through that
which is the actualization of baptism
baptism is not an artificial thing it is
an actualization but the energy that
does it is we call it sleeping energy in
the triangular bone called as sacrum
that means the Greeks knew that this is
a sacred bone that we called it sacrum
this energy has to rise and break
through that fontanel bone area and
connect us to that subtle divine power
which we have never felt during human
awareness
thus we get connected to this divine
power and we start feeling it on our
fingertips is described in the Quran
that at the time of resurrection your
hands will speak and they will give
witness against you that is you start
feeling your own centers these are five
six and seven centers and they indicate
what's wrong with you
within yourself what's the problem also
you can feel the cool breeze coming out
of your head cool breeze of the Holy
Ghost because this sleeping power which
is called as the Kundalini Kundalini is
coiled it's the power of pure desire
within us
[Music]
you