Mahakali Puja
France
July 11, 1993
Today we have decided to have the Puja of
the Devi. This time we are not talking about
Adi Shakti, about Kundalini or about Saraswati,
Mahalakshmi. We are talking about the Mahakali.
That's the Goddess which is the first one,
which comes first and establishes Shri Ganesha
in the form of Gauri. She’s the complete
form of Mahasaraswati and Mahalakshmi. Out
of Her only these energies emit.
So She’s the one who is the Power of desire
of God. Within us also She creates desires.
These desires within us start emitting outside
and we develop a kind of a reaction to all
our desires. The first and foremost desire,
as you know very much, the most primitive,
is to feed yourself. And this is given to
us by the Goddess. She gives us the desire
to feed ourselves. Now if we don't feed ourselves,
then we cannot survive, we have to have food.
It is very important that we should feed ourselves
sufficiently enough to exist on this Earth.
And also we have seen that when this kind
of desire grows very much more than normal,
then you become slaves of this desire and
any amount of food cannot satisfy you. All
the time you think of nothing else but food.
I have told you many a times that the French
are very particular as to what they should
eat. You see, they take at least forty-five
minutes on a dinner table to decide what they
will eat. Ultimately, it's just the same.
I mean, I don't understand how can you need
forty-five minutes to decide what you want
to eat. But this desire starts acting through
your ego. So it satisfies you. And also those
people who are manufacturing food or who are
supplying food in hotels and all that know
how to satisfy your desires. So they bring
it in a way, show it round and then place
it before you, so that you approve of it and
when you approve of it then they serve. They
know how to befool you and you feel quite
happy, “Oh, it’s very good.” Even the
wine is given for testing first of all and,
whether you like it or not, you have to say,
“It's very good,” and you better show
that you like it.
So this desire gets completely controlled
by your ego and when it becomes a kind of
a collective desire and a collective ego expression,
then we become like gluttons, you see, I would
say sophisticated. They are sophisticated,
but we are gluttons. Now with that, other
things also people want to have, like proper
sort of a table lying and linen, this, that.
Of course, if ego is not there, then people
would like to see, to please others by feeding
them. This desire reacts. And then the new
desire comes in through the blessings of the
Mahakali that you like to see others eating
the food. You enjoy when others eat the food
cooked by you, served by you, given by you.
Just want to watch. That gives you satisfaction.
But food, to any extent you may go, you will
never be satisfied. Today you’ll ask for
this, tomorrow for that. This, that.
Now, in the Western life today, it has become
very important to ask the child every day,
“What will you have?” In olden days the
food was cooked for all the family, everybody
would eat the same food. But now you must
ask the child, “What will you have?” Then
the child has to say, “I'll have this.”
Now, supposing you don't have that in the
fridge, you are finished. Early in the morning
there will be no shop open, nothing. How will
you please that boy in his ego because he
wants a particular thing, so gradually we
build up even the ego of our children. We
have to say, “This is cooked, this is nice
and you eat this.” Is the duty of parents
not to allow children to grow their ego by
what they want. You should know what they
have to have. Then it starts growing and growing
and growing till they become quite grown up,
but very primitive.
So, actually, the blessings of the Devi on
this point is that She gives you a desire
that you should serve others. Also you then
get concerned about people who are starving,
want to find out why they are starving. The
another extreme of this could be that some
people think we should not eat so much, a
kind of a sacrificing nonsense. Whatever one
has to eat, one should eat. Then they say,
“Why should we eat so much, Mother? After
all, there are people who are starving.”
By your eating less or more, you cannot save
those who are starving, can you? So there’s
no wisdom in this kind of austerity. And when
the people enter into this kind of austerity,
then they have sufferings and troubles and
such people become extremely, I should say,
ascetic and hot-tempered and you should never
go near a person who is of that kind without
a barge pole. God knows when he’ll jump
on you. So a person who is hungry is as bad
as a person who is overfed. I think hungry
is worse.
Now if you look at yourself, the second desire
that comes to you is that everyone should
love you. This comes because that makes you
good person. You know that everybody likes
goodness. So people try to be good to others,
nice to others, say a hundred times, “Thank
you,” do all kinds of things to please others.
By pleasing others, they think others will
like us very much. But then it develops again
out of bounds and then all the time you try
to please others so that you become absolutely
slavish. You become so artificial that people
can make out that it’s nothing natural is
this gentleman. He’s just trying to please
us.
Now, with that, the pleasing behind is some
sort of an advantage out of it. If you please
another one with a detached mind, not expecting
anything that should be done for you or that
could be achieved through that pleasing, is
very pure pleasing and is very good. That
makes you really righteous and good. But supposing
you try to please others only just to take
advantage of that person, then you develop
hypocrisy – hypocrisy of the worst type.
And you get lost. People mock at you, laugh
at you. They are never pleased. They know
that you are a hypocrite and you are doing
it for some sort of an advantage or an exploitation.
You are not doing it because you want to be
good really, to be nice.
A person who is good, automatically pleases
others. But he doesn’t try to please. He’s
just – his nature is such, his temperament
is such that he just pleases people. This,
when taken over again by Mister Ego, then
really you can't beat it. Such … then they
become diplomats, you see, could be politicians,
all these doomed classes they become and they
cannot get out of it. They get so much used
to it, that they cannot get out of it.
Now what does the Devi do? She brings the
truth before them. She shows that what you
have been doing for a particular exploitation
doesn’t work out. Up to a point it does.
She exposes them. The exposure starts and
with that exposure, they are surprised, “How
am I exposed? How am I caught, how people
know?” This is the job of the power of Mahakali.
She exposes all that is wrong, all that is
falsehood, that is untruth, She exposes.
Then the third desire people have is to possess
material things, from which materialism has
come. But there’s no end to it. End can
never come because they have no satisfaction
in getting one thing. Supposing today, “ I
want to have this carpet. All right, I'll
get this one.” Then I want to have another
one. Then want to have another one. Then I
want to have a car and then I want to have
a helicopter, then an aeroplane. I don't know
what I want to have then.
So it goes on and on and on and on until you
reach a time where people start thinking,
“What's the matter with him?” And you
cannot enjoy anything that you get. This is
also a human failing and this human failing
creates economics, you know that. Economics
is created because wants, in general, are
not satiable. They are not satiable. So what
happens, we go on from jumping from one to
another to another to another
and another. So then you become slaves of
entrepreneurs, so much so, that you lose your
individuality completely.
For example, an entrepreneur produces a funny
kind of a dress, one, one year. So everybody
wants to wear the same, without thinking,
if it is necessary or not. Then he brings
in another form. Next year everything is given
up, buy the another one. Third year another
one. So, pile of all these clothes are there,
and nicely the manufacturer has become a great
man of designs – he’s very good designs,
how to befool human beings. He has become
a rich man and you have become poor with all
these kind of clothes which has no meaning
for you anymore.
About the same thing, about everything, something
is fashionable. That means you have no individuality.
We talk of individuality, but we want to do
things which everybody is doing. I mean, you
know that all kinds of absurd things people
have done in the name of fashion and specially
people who are not traditionally bound, who
have had no traditions like Americans, I would
say. They go on changing after every six months.
Every year you go, you find a new type of
people there, new type of clothes. It's very
surprising how they change so fast without
even thinking whether this will suit me or
not. Somebody says wear tight clothes, they’ll
go with tight clothes. Then they develop varicose
veins, so they wear with the holes. Then they
develop some other problem, then they wear
another kind. Nobody wants to think, “Why
should I change my dress?” Like, say, in
India we wear saris, finished. Nothing doing.
No problem with the tailor, nothing doing.
Whatever sari we like, we’ll buy. And a
sari came called as mini sari in India, which
was up to here maybe, I don't know, not six
inches, but at least up to the knee. It came
for about, I think, eight, seven days in Bombay
and went back. People said, “Get lost. We
don't want it.”
So this headache of all the time getting into
a fashion like herds without any sense in
the head has to be understood properly. Why
people do it? Because they have no brains.
They are brainless people. They’re not intelligent
to see that we are befooled every year. But,
for Sahaja yogis, the Mahakali power works
and She teaches them that “All right, this
dress suits you. Have this one.” And it's
the best for you. Once for all, your lifelong
problem is solved. With this kind of blouse,
I started wearing from the very beginning
perhaps and I've been wearing it and now I
find everybody wears the same style.
Why to waste your energy in changing every
day this blouse starting from here to here,
to here and going back again like this, you
see. Is such a waste of energy, such a waste
of cloth. And we make ourselves so cheap running
with this race of reducing the sleeves, reducing
this, reducing that – or increasing. Is
all a desire to impress people that we are
very up-to-date. Who wants to know? Who wants
to find out that you are up-to-date or not?
And we have no courage to keep to our own
dress that we have purchased. Why to waste
so much money? We never even think, go on
changing, changing, changing for nothing at
all. So this is desire is there to impress
others with our outside things. So many things
like dress there are, which we try to impress.
Now, hairstyle: I read an article. They said
that these hairstyles are responsible for
many divorces. I was wondering, “How can
it be hairstyles be responsible for divorces?”
Because they had made a survey: a man had
liked a hairstyle of his fiancée and then
she changed her hairstyle, so he divorced
her. And the other way round. When it is so
cheap way of disposing of such a deep relationship
of husband and wife.
Now certain fads start. I also saw one documentary
about a lady who’d said that – it was
in the one of the advertisements, something,
sort of a thing appeared that your legs should
be of this shape and what you should do. So
poor thing spent so much time, energy, ran
up and down to make the legs. I mean what
is the importance of these legs, except for
walking? So, she went to make the shape like
that, you see. She used to measure it – would
be always something missing here or there.
Then many people joined. They had a class
for it. And a group joined to make legs like
that. And, ultimately, they found out that
that leg was made out of wood. And they spent
so much money, so much energy to make legs
like that. For what? What is the purpose?
If anybody says, “You run like this,”
they start running. They say, “Jump like
this,” they start jumping. But why? Have
we gone all nuts in our heads that we should
accept whatever one says, we start doing that.
What is the purpose?
So this kind of stupidity comes in our heads
when we start using our ego. With the ego
a person becomes absolutely stupid. Because
he’ll say, “What's wrong? What's wrong
if I have just a little hair here? What's
wrong?”
“If I just try to wear a very short dress
here, what's wrong?”
The wrong is, why are you wearing? Why don't
you ask a question? Why are you wearing? If
you ask a question to yourself,” Why do
I have this kind of hairstyle? Why do I do
like this?” It is really difficult to tell
people to do right things, but wrong things
people take to like that. For example, I told
everyone that you put oil, if not every day,
just before bath, lot of oil in your head
and wash. Now I find many people getting bald.
But they didn't put the oil. What can I do
about it? But such a simple thing they won't
have. Such a simple thing they would not believe,
that you need something for your nourishment.
But they will do something which is absurd,
nonsensical without even thinking, “What
is going to harm us?”
Here the Mahakali, what does She do? She punishes
you. Your body is punished. If you wear very
tight clothes, you develop problems of your
legs. If you wear holey pants, then you get
cramps. Anything you do abnormal, you have
to pay for it. First you have to pay for doing
it and then you have to pay for it physically.
So many things can be avoided if we just have
a simple life, decide once for all that, “I
will have this kind of dress for this lifetime,”
finished. Every day to change, itself, is
a headache. But that satisfies the ego, not
your Self.
So the Mahalakshmi Principle in us raises
higher and higher. Despite that, we are pulled
down. Then this Mahakali, She comes forward
and shows what wrong we have done, how we
have gone wrong, how we have missed the point.
Instead of think, “What is wrong?” She
teaches you it is wrong.
Then another thing She does, which is a very
beautiful thing She does, I think sometimes,
that She creates a illusion to test your intelligence,
to test your sensibility, She creates an illusion,
Bhranti rupena samstita. She makes a bhranti
in your head. Illusion. So you become illusive
or others become illusive or a situation becomes
illusive. And you are lost in it. Then you
really did understand that “It's wrong thing
I have done.”
It's a very nice story about Narada. Narada
was under an impression about himself and
ultimately he became ego-oriented and he started
saying, “Oh, look at me. I’m never enticed
by any woman. Even Shiva was enticed by Cupid.
I am never enticed. I am the highest, of highest,
brahmachari.” So Vishnu sent two gandharvas
to entice him. So they met him in a forest
and told him, “Oh, Narada, you are such
a handsome man, such a beautiful man and all
your beauty’s wasted. You must test your
beauty. You must see how beautiful you are.
You are so handsome.”
He said, “Really?”
“Yes,” she said. “There’s a very simple
way of testing.”
“Is how?”
She said, “There’s a wedding coming up
of a very beautiful woman. She is the princess
of the beauty … city, is called Rupadaka
– and you should go there and see how she
will appreciate you.”
So he, in his ego, became so stupid that he
went there. And he was sitting and lots of
people were coming, big, big maharajas, rajas,
all of them were sitting and he was thinking,
“Oh, I’m the best among all of them. Who
are these? The princess will just garland
me, no doubt about it.”
And these two were, you see, putting that
illusion into his head, bhranti. With the
Agnya, you get bhranti. This princess came
round. She looked at him and she laughed aloud.
She couldn't control herself and she moved
on giggling. Couldn't understand why she laughed
at him. She didn’t garland him or nothing
but she just laughed. So couldn’t understand,
“I’m such a handsome man,” this thing.
So these two gandharvas told him, “Oh, doesn’t
matter. You see, she doesn’t understand.
She'll come back,” this, that. Then they
went out and near a lake and he sat down to
wash his face and looked at in the water his
reflection. He, looked like a monkey. He looked
at these two and he cursed them.
He said, “I look like a monkey.”
Said, “To us, you look like very handsome.”
“But I really look like a monkey.”
So this bhranti, this illusion was created
in his mind by his ego. But this power, itself,
Mahakali’s power, She puts this ego right
by creating illusion, bhranti. And this is
responsible for many illusions we run after.
It’s a mirage, running after it, running
after it. Once we are satisfied within ourselves,
then we don't run after mirages. This illusion,
if it is not created, people would be so egoistical
that whole world will be finished.
So this is the great work of Mahakali Power
within us, that She creates illusions. Many
people talk of maya. “This is, Mother, maya.
This is maya. That is maya.” Is the work
of Mahakali. She wants to test you. She wants
to test you. But in Sahaja Yoga it's not such
a strong one.
For example, you know Abraham had a son. One
son He had after a long time. And God asked
Him that He should sacrifice his son. His
wife said, “ I also was feeling terrible
that He has to sacrifice His son.” So He
went down to the place where the child was
to be sacrificed. He made a fire, everything
and He was about to put the child on that
pyre of fire when the voice came, “This
is Mahakali, that you don’t have to sacrifice
your child.”
We have many such stories in Indian mythology
also where they were tested. So to test Sahaja
yogis also, this Mahakali helps you. There
was a gentleman who was very egoistical, so
I told him to come to Delhi because I didn’t
know how to do it here. Came to Delhi and
he told everybody, “See, Mother told me
to come here just to cure Her.”
I said, “All right. Come along.”
He came.
I said, “What’s wrong with Me?”
He said, “Mother, Your Nabhi is very bad.”
I said, “Really? You put a bandhan to yourself
and now see for yourself.”
“Oh my God, what’s happening to me here?”
I said, “That’s My Nabhi.”
So this is how the illusion corrects you.
If there is no illusion, you would not ever
be corrected directly. Supposing I say, “Don't
do this.” You may not like. Of course, mostly
you like, but sometimes you don't. And then
the illusion works and then you realize, “Where
was I and where am I now? I should not have
done this. How is it I have landed into this
problem? What has made me so stupid?” So
this is something which She does.
Another is She's the one who relaxes you completely.
When you are tired and fed up, when you don't
know what to do, then She makes you sleep.
She’s the one who gives you sleep. All day's
work you do, ultimately the Mahakali power
acts on you as sleep. She makes you sleep,
sleep like a child. You know, at that time,
all that wrong we have done to ourselves and
to others are forgiven. In Her lap we sleep
nicely, quietly and all our problems are solved.
In those dreams, when you are, She brings
forth solutions to you. I know so many people
told Me, “Mother, you came in my dream and
told me that this is the medicine you should
take.” “You came in my dream and You told
me that this particular type of life will
suit you.” They see Me clearly coming, but
there it is not whole of Me, but I think the
Mahakali Power acts. Into very deep sleep
you are, it is called, as the sushupti. There
She appears.
One lady came to Me and she said, “Mother,
You came in my dream and you said that “I’m
here in Bombay.” Nobody told me.
So, so many things happen like this. In the
dream She guides you and tells you. Now what
happens sometimes, people tell Me that I had
such and such dream, which is all falsehood,
I know. They never dreamt like that. They
never saw like this. But, just to impress
Me, they tell Me that “Oh, I had a dream,”
this, that. I just show complete ignorance,
“Ya, must be.” Then they are put into
again bhranti, means illusion. Gradually,
they realize that it was wrong to tell lies
to Mother. So the correction part takes place.
But the greatest thing that She does is to
give you the sense of chastity and security.
When the children are born, they have sense
of chastity, shame, decency, decorous behavior.
But gradually, when they start others misbehaving,
they start misbehaving. To them, decency becomes
a bondage. But, naturally, She's there to
tell you that “This is indecent. You shouldn't
do it. This is wrong. This is not the proper
thing to do." But gradually, you grow up and
mature, then you go, “What’s wrong?”
You start disrespecting your chastity and
you start becoming like immature, stupid people.
All this, if is understood through meditation,
the Mahakali helps you a lot. In meditation,
She helps you a lot because She's the one
who creates the proper passage for kundalini
to rise. Mahakali is the same as the kundalini
because She is the residual energy of Mahakali
Power, full of it there. But the function
is different. The function of Mahakali is
to protect you, is to guide you, to give you
wisdom. And the function of the kundalini
is to cleanse you, to clear it out, not to
play about with you, to forgive you and help
you to grow properly.
Now in your life, as Sahaja yogis, you will
see how Mahakali helps you in every way. It
is so interesting to watch Her work, how She
brings forth all kinds of satisfactions to
you. The greed goes away. The temptations
go away. The temper goes away. All these things
disappear. The most helpful thing She does,
that you get rid of your bad habits. Absolutely.
Automatically, in the light of Mahakali's
power, you just do not want anything destructive
to be practiced. If you have been practicing
anything destructive, you try to get rid of
it. Just you stop it. “I don’t want to
have it.” I never tell you, “Don’t do
this. Don’t do that.”
It's the Mahakali power within you which is
awakened, does all these things. And She has
made you so beautiful, so angelic. She has,
by Her corrections and by Her illusions, She
has made you like this so you don't get so
much attached to money, to greed, to lust,
all these things which are responsible for
putting you down; also possessiveness for
children, possessiveness for husband, possessiveness
of matter. You just start understanding that
the joy is in sharing. You want to share everything
with others and that sharing starts when this
Mahakali Powers start giving you blessings
of joy, of sharing, of being collective, of
being pure. These blessings come to you from
the Mahakali Power.
So today we are going to worship that Mahakali
Power.
May God bless you!