I
bow to all the seekers of truth.
I bow to them because they are a special category
of human beings which is described by William
Blake as the men of God who will become prophets
and they will have powers to make others prophets.
This is what is described by many other seers
in India also.
All over the world people have talked about
the resurrection time. Mohammed Sahib in His
Koran has described that at the time of resurrection
your hands will speak. Like when the disciples
of Christ got their blessings of Self realization
from the Holy Ghost which came as a cool breeze
upon Him they started using their hands because
they felt the power flowing through them and
they started speaking the language which was
strange. That was the language of the chakras
and that's why people thought they were off
their minds, they didn't understand. But today
we are in a special time which I call as the
blossom time. We do not have only twelve people
who are seeking, twelve hundred who are seeking,
but thousands and thousands, millions and
millions. This seeking has come to us from
ages, we have been seekers from ages, though
in the western contries the tradition of seeking
has lost its meaning very much because of
industralisation. It has grown like a tree
which does not know about its roots. In India
the climate was very gentle, I think, and
it's a very old country. Since long people
have been seeking why we are on this earth,
why God has made us human beings, why should
we be in such incomplete state.
Still we are living in a relative world if
you understand. We do not what is right and
wrong is. Shri Krishna has said that there
are three types of people in this world which
create problems. The first type is the type
which always takes to something wrong, destructive,
and run after it and destroys oneself, emotional
things. He gets emotional attachments to wrong
things, he doesn't value his life much relatively,
and he destroys himself. Then the second type
of people who are which he calls as the rajasikas
who are futuristic, the first are the ones
who live in the past, are the rajasikas, are
the people who are futuristic, as we are in
the West, very much futuristic. We are planning
all the time what we are going to do next
moment, but this moment, when we are here,
we are not there. They are not capable of
knowing what is right and wrong. Sometimes
they may do right but mostly they go towards
wrong because they do not know what is right
and what is wrong.
The reason why we go towards wrong much more
is this: that we have come from carbon, say
earlier, from matter. Matter always fights
the spirit. Say for example, we get used to
anything that is material, a chair, we cannot
sit on the ground. If you are used to a bed
we cannot sleep on the ground. So the matter
is always trying to give us habits. It is
trying to overpower us, and that's how we
start getting into a comfortable understanding
that we have to be dominated by matter. So
such people who are on the rajasic side, we
call them the rightsided people, are guided
by the ego that developed because they convert
matter into some form and they think they
achieved a lot. As I said, a tree dies and
they create a chair and that chair sits on
your head and you think you have achieved
a lot. So this is what happens that the ego,
as you see on the right hand side, starts
developing and when it develops it guides
you. It can misguide you many a times, because
when there is ego pampering we feel happy
and when there is no ego pampering we feel
unhappy. Like if you tell somebody, "Oh I
like that". Even a person, whom I met, who
was trying to hijack some plane. So I said,
"Why are you doing it, why do you want to
hijack a plane?" He said, "For the heck of
it, for the heck of it." I said, "But don't
you think you'll be putting so many people
into trouble this?" He said, "But I'll appear
in the newspapers as a great hero."
So the concept of the goodness is not there.
Benevolence is not there, but the concept
of something standing out, something out of
the blue, they want to show off that they
are something greater. And in London we have
a kind of funny people, I don't know you might
be having them here also. They call themselves
punks and they came to Me, to My program with
pins here and pins there. All pins actually,
in the noses, all over pins, and with the
hair dyed. I asked them, "Why do you do it?"
They said, "What's wrong?" There's no answer
to it, what's wrong? But what's so good about
it? Why to waste your energy on this nonsenical
thing? "I like it." If you like it then that's
the last word, "I like it." That's how we
live and thats how we grow with it. But one
must understand we are neither our conditionings,
which is the superego which is the psyche
as described by this horrible fellow Freud,
or we are the ego as described by other people,
say, Sartre, and all this. When he denied
that you should not get into any conditioning,
he had no discretion of any kind. Because
if you have no conditioning what do you have?
Is nothing but pure ego, pure ego. There's
something like good conditioning also and
that good condition makes us to stay in the
center, binds us to that central path which
is described by Buddha. You have to keep to
the central path.
That is, you keep with your ten valencies.
Carbon has got four, you've got ten valencies.
These ten valencies of balance are very important.
Once you go into imbalances because of your
superego, of your conditioning, or because
of your too much of ego, you land up first
of all into physical problems, then into mental
problems, then into spiritual problems, and
lastly it's finished, it's complete destruction.
Now the problems we are facing in the West
are coming more from the right side than from
the left side. To overcome this I thought
Christ was the solution because He came as
an antidote for that. On the contrary, in
all the Christian nations if you find, people
have been extremely aggressive on other races.
Can you believe it, they are supposed to be
Christians taking Bible in one hand and pistol
in another hand. That was really so misguiding
that in India those who were great people,
sages, they never understood Christ because
is described that such and such a personality
is going to be born. He is the one who's the
support of the universe. He is the one who
will die and establish the principle of eternal
life. All being described very nicely in the
Devi Mahatmayan, a book written about fourteen
thousand years back, you'll be surprised.
But when they saw these people with the bible
in the hand and the revolver in another hand,
or a gun, or sometimes a cannon, they said,
"This cannot be because He is supposed to
be saumya: means mild, mildness. That's why
they gave up the hope. We too must understand
the knowledge of the tree is not sufficient,
we have to have knowledge of the roots, and
that's why I say the seekers are a special
category of human beings who feel that they
have to still know about the roots, about
the region from where they are going to be
nourished.
The third type of people are the seekers,
the sattva gunis. They try to avoid extremes,
they try to keep in the center, they are the
ones who are best seekers. Of course in seeking
also people go astray. They go astray in so
many ways. Like, they may like a person because
he is giving them some sort of a workshop
to work out, they like to work, they want
to achieve something through work. They don't
like something that is easily available. Sahaja
Yoga, saha means 'with' and ja is 'born' with
you. Sahaja Yoga is a spontaneous, living
happening of the evolutionary process within
you, of the living God, is the living energy
within you, which is this kundalini, which
is the true desire within you to become the
Divine. How can you pay for this kundalini,
she doesn't understand money, like the Mother
Earth [the sound drops out where Shri Mataji
is telling the story of how Mother Earth germinates
the seed]. In the same way, the kundalini
in her own nature awakens because she is your
own mother. She is like a tape recorder which
has taped everything that was your past. She's
the one who is waiting for a chance to give
you your second birth. This is what you have
within yourself.
Now when I'm telling you about these things
you need not also believe in Me with blind
faith, not necessary at all. You may not deny,
but you should understand that whatever I'm
saying is like a hypothesis a scientist can
put before you. But keep your minds open like
a scientist has. Supposing a scientist already
knows about everything then what's the use
of telling anything to the scientist but as
he keeps his mind open, in the same way you
keep your minds open you'll understand this
is a hypothesis and this hypothesis if it
is proved, then you have to believe in it.
But we believe into things about, in nothing
is known to us, any kind of a mental projection
comes in, we just believe in. I'm surprised
how people have changed so many of their habits
suddenly because some sort of a mental projection
has come forward, that you must wear this
kind of dresses, that is good for you, you
must eat this kind of food, that is good for
you. Like, I went to Switzerland I was surprised
they were eating cottonseed. I was shocked,
cottonseeds, how can human beings consume,
only in India buffaloes eat. How can you eat
cottonseed?
They said, "This is a special now diet created
for our health."
I said, "I tell you will end up very fast
with this because your intestines are not
that sturdy as the buffalo has, you are a
delicate human being, how can you eat this?"
They said, "No, this is what it is said."
But I said, "Whenever somebody has said it,
why do you accept it readily like that? See
some people who are eating it first of all,
what happens to them. If they give it to say
some sort of animals and if they can digest
it that doesn't mean you can digest also."
Any sort of a fad, any sort of a new mental
idea comes to a rajasic's personality, he
accepts. He likes to have change all the time.
Change that what it wants to such an extent
that they'll change their hairstyles and everybody
will be wearing the same hairstyles. Then
again a second time you will see them having
another style and that is a fashion goes on.
They don't know by doing this they are really
creating not an individualistic taste at all,
but quite a common stuff goes on. The problem
is that we are looking at ourselves as something
superficial, something very outside. If you
dress up like this, like some people dressed
up just like a primitive people came to Me.
I asked them, "Why are you like this, why
do you dress up like this primitive people
like this, and all your dress is so dirty."
He said, "We want to be primitive."
Now by dressing up like that can you become
primitive? Your brain is so modern how can
you become primitive by dressing up like that?
This is the problem with us, we think by doing
something superficial we will get something
within ourselves and this is one of the biggest
hurdles in your seeking. You have to know
that by changing your name, by chanting something,
by doing all this madness that people are
doing, some people start jumping, screaming,
shouting, this all you can do otherwise also.
Also this is not the way it's going to happen.
It is antar yoga, the inner yoga. The inner
yoga has to take place, kundalini has to rise,
you have to get your realization as an experience
on your central nervous system. Like as on
your central nervous system you have got the
rest of your evolution. You are a human being,
now with your own eyes you can see things,
more than the animals can see. You can feel
the dirt and filth much more than an animal
can feel. If you want a dog to pass through
a dirty lane he passes through. But not you.
You cannot do it because you are a human being,
you have developed a new "experiencer" within
you, a new "experiencer", which knows the
experience of the dirt and filth, and of cleanliness.
So you are so clean, you wash yourself, you're
keeping everything clean, you can't bear bad
smells and things like that. In some way the
evolution if it has to take place within you,
you have to develop an "experiencer" of goodness,
of righteoness, of virtue by which I don't
have to tell you, you do this, you do that,
or nobody has to tell you, but you yourself
become that. That yourself, themselves, develop
that special capacity, that special experience
that makes you a good person. We talk of peace,
big organisations, My husband himself is a
Secretary General of one of them and he says
no use because people have to be transformed.
Unless and until they are transformed there's
no use doing it, they are just the same. Unless
and until there's peace within yourselves
what's the use of talking about peace? We
need that transformation for which, you'll
be surprised, we are specially made. The instrument
is here like any instrument you can see, this
is an instrument, unless and until I put it
to the mains it doesn't work. Unless and until
you are put to the mains you do not work.
The energy doesn't flow through you. Let the
energy which is all-pervading, which is doing
all the living work.
Actually we don't do anything, but what we
do is a dead work. All the living work which
is transforming, say, of flowers in the fruits,
can we do that? For example, I say but thousand
and one, like even looking after our breathing,
pumping our hearts regularly. If you run fast,
then sympathetic goes into action, that we
control but it comes to normal, automatically.
How does it happen? What works it out? They
call it of course, doctors are very good at
giving names, our autonomic nervous system.
Now who is this auto? Auto is the spirit.
Auto is the spirit, they don't want to say
spirit. They don't want to use that word,
but it means that, otherwise tell us, who
is the auto. This, one has to understand,
that within us this special instrument placed.
One after another these centers were created
at a different stage of our evolution.
For example at the first red spot is the carbon
situation. Then as you started evolving more
and more these are the milestones within us.
Specially created within us, this kundalini
is there, which is the pure desire of becoming
one with the Divine. All other desires are
absolutely not desires, because if they were
we would have been satisfied with them. Economics
says that in general wants are not satiable.
So all our wants are something, unsatiable
stuffs. So why run after that? What is that
desire which is going to really make us satisfied
is this desire, is the kundalini. So this
exists within us, it is within us this all
has been made, specially.You are a special
instrument.
Now this instrument must be put to the mains.
That's the only job. Then why deny it? Why
should we deny this? Because we have become
human beings with all these things within
us, so why not put it to the mains, and once
you put it to the mains you are amazed that
your own instrument what you are. You don't
know what you are, you think you're just an
ordinary person you see hobnobbing with other
things of life? No, actually you are a special
instrument, made specially to enter into the
Kingdom of God. But only thing is, when we
are naive or when we are ignorant, we don't
understand our own value, like in the Indian
village if you take, say, a TV set and say
that you can see all kinds of dramas and plays
and music out of this, they'll say, "What?
This box how can it be?" Then you put it to
the mains, he's aghast, what's this magic?
To him this is a magic. For some people raising
the kundalini is magic. They always ask me
how can it be so simple. It has to be simple.
It is so vital. As when we breathe. What do
we do? Do we go to any guru or do we read
any book or anything? If you had to do that,
how many of us would exist. Whatever is vital
has to be simple. Whatever is living is simple.
We don't know how many things we are blessed
with. The powers of God cannot be described,
but one can say that if you see, looking at
things, see an Australian gets a child looks
like an Australian; Indian gets a child looks
like an Indian, and also the face. And if
you see to the microscopic way, how it works
out, how it develops, how the choices take
place, is something a fantastic work. You
cannot go into that. Is like an ocean. When
you start seeing the reality, is like an ocean.
When you start discernng it, finding it out.
It's too
much. So what is best to make your drop an
ocean. Just to dissolve it into the ocean.
Then people think that you have to surrender.
You don't have to surrender. What is there
to surrender? Only your ego, which has bound
you, only your superego which has bound you,
has to be sucked in. Let the kundalini pass
through and you become one with the Divine.
The problems of health are really shattering.
I say we'll not be destroyed by atom bomb
because whatever human beings create they
know what it is, like the atom bomb itself
has become a devil for them. They are all
worried. The Americans are worried that if
they start it the Russians will destroy them,
and the Russians are worried if they start
it American will destroy them. So let them
be busy with each other. But they are not
worried as to the real destruction which is
bubbling through. The destruction that is
bubbling through in America is not through
atomic bomb, but through their own mental
disturbances, extreme behaviours, their "What's
wrong?" business. Russia same thing. Why?
The presidents are dying, what's the reason,
have you been able to find out? They are not
murdered. In America, they're murdered. The
reason, they are dealing in parapsychology,
they are dealing with all left-sided things.
Because they're dealing with these, all these
spirits are getting hold of them. That's why
they cannot go further. So in both ways they
are not aware so to what is going to destroy
them. But as Australia is a neutral country,
let's see a neutral point of view, that we
do not want to be destroyed by our stupidity,
nor by our foolhardiness, but let us have
our own wisdom to underdstand how we construct
ourselves into human beings who will be wise
people.
Now specially for Australians, I have a special
feeling for them because this first red center
is Australia, and this represents the innocence.
So whatever Australians may try to destroy
their innocence, they cannot go very far because
you have rooted into innocence. You are blessed
with innocence. You cannot go too far and
it's here it will start, you will see one
day, the wisdom, because this is the centre
of wisdom too. This is the centre of as we
call Shri Ganesha, the deity of innocence,
who is the giver of wisdom. So this wisdom
to give balance in this nonsensical world,
which is busy fighting and not constructing
themselves into better realms, will definitely
one day come through Australia, no doubt about
it. But Australians also must put down both
the feet down on the ground and don't try
to follow others, not try to copy others.
If you have faith in yourself try to develop
your own wisdom and understand that you could
one day do such a great thing that none of
these so called successful and great countries
have been able to. It's all right to have
dollar in a collapsable state, you can have
something else, but to have people who are
wise, who are not going to be deterred by
nonsense, to create such people is possible
in Australia.
Though my visits to Australia have been few,
I should say only three times, this the third
time here I am here. I wish I could come many
more times, but My own opinion is this, that
I have been laboring in that England, which
is the heart of universe, for the last twelve
years. I haven't achieved much as I have done
it here in only four years, is surprising.
You must know your own nature, you must know
what you are. You are Australians and you
have a special wisdom about it. Take to that
wisdom, understand that, respect it, and work
it out. I'm sure that will take no time for
you to understand that in your wisdom, you
must become that instrument that you are.
You have to become the spirit, that's what
are. You are not this temporary phase in which
you are indulging, you are not to destroy
yourself. You're not to destroy your own progenies,
but you have to save the whole world out of
this island of great people. So may God bless
you.
We take out our shoes to respect the Mother
Earth in a way, but also you must know that
all these centers are made of different elements,
and specially the kundalini rests in the sacrum
bone which is a sacred bone which means that
the Greeks knew about it, that it is a sacred
bone and is made specially of the earth element.
So one has to understand that we have to take
a special help from the Mother Earth and that's
why I said Australia is something special
for us.
Regarding questions also, just now we are
in a mood, you see, to get our realization,
is better to keep the mood on. Questions,
whatever you think, you can ask Me tomorrow;
but ask sensible questions, because you have
to be constructive and wise and there's no
need to be aggressive with Me. The other day
there was somebody who just for nothing at
all just got in a mood of shouting at Me,
for what I don't know, I didn't even hear
him what he was talking. This is not
the way to behave. After all you all have
this instrument. Now I
have come here to give you what you have,
your own properties. I'm just to hand over
your own keys to you. What is there to fight
with Me for that? Is it something sensible
to do? But it happens. I don't know why it
happens like that: with some people go off
their heads, they can't see things properly.
Whatever it is you please write down all your
questions and hand them over and I'll answer
them tomorrow if specifically possible, otherwise
in My lectures. I'm here only for two days,
that is today and tomorrow, so you must take
full advantage of Me, I think, whatever is
possible than to waste your time here and
there.
Now we have a very simple method of raising
our kundalini. So what do we do first day
is to raise our own kundalini. We put the
left hand on the lap like this, which is the
side which we call is the power of desire,
on the lap just like this, towards Me, just
like, simple, like that on the lap very comfortably.
Sit comfortably, there's no need to push back
your head much or bend down, nothing keep
it absolutely normal. Actually you have to
lead a very normal life. Somebody asked Me,
"You have to be celibate and all that?" Nothing
of the kind. You have to be married, very
happily married, you have to have children,
and you will know how to lead a very sane,
sensible married life, and how to look after
your children, and you will have children
who are great sages. So I would suggest that
you shouldn't have all these ideas that you
have to do this or anything, as you are sitting
you will get your realization and then you
will have just to find out what problems you
have, what exercise you may have to do if
you have a very bad problem of some physical
side. If you have any problem, say of mental
side, or any other problem of family life
or anything, they will tell you the method,
the technique, how through your spiritual
powers you can solve them. So we have to have
our own kundalini awakened.
Put left hand towards Me. Now the right hand
has to go on different centers on the left
hand side of your body, on the left hand side.
Now the right hand is the power of action.
This is our hand we have to use because I
said you are fantastic and the fact is, the
greatest thing is that you can get your kundalini
awakened this way. So put your left hand towards
Me on the lap, very comfortably you sit down,
and the right hand you have to use for the
different centers.
I show you which ones, and then I'll tell
you later on when you close your eyes. So
I want to tell you first, on the heart, then
on the upper part of the stomach, then in
the lower part of the stomach, then again
back on the upper part of the stomach, all
on the left hand side, then on the heart,
then on the neck, here, little on the back
side, goes here, is very important just now
this is the worst of all, because when you
feel guilty this catches. Now one here [front
agnya], then here [back agnya], and then here
[fontanelle], but I'll tell you every time
where you have to put it. At the very outset
I have to request you that you should tell
yourself very clearly that "I'm not guilty
at all of anything." Forgive yourself, that's
very important. I said you are the temple
of God, you are a special category. Why do
you want to debase yourself by feeling guilty?
In My lecture if I've said something, forget
it. Just tell yourself that "I'm not at all
guilty" very clearly with all confidence,
that's one of the things you have to do. All
right.
Now, we close our eyes and we don't open our
eyes till I tell you. Don't open your eyes
till I tell you because the kundalini has
to rise. Everyone must do it. Those who don't
want to do it should please go away. Please
be civil, don't do it, please go away. Nobody
can force this on you and this is no show
on, so please go away. Secondly, those who
are doing meditation should sit till you get
your realization. It will not take much time,
about fifteen minutes at the most. But some
people have a habit of suddenly shooting off
like jack-in-the-box and disturbing others.
So you have to be pleasant about it. You have
to be pleasant, it's nothing serious. You
are going to enter into the kingdom of God,
you are invited. There is an invitation, so
be pleasant about it and I'm sure it will
work out. Now, please close your eyes and
the doubting Thomas, you put him outside for
the time being. The doubting Thomas is not
going to help you. Just don't doubt yourself.
You are quite capable of getting realization,
all of you are quite capable of getting realization,
believe Me, there. Now please put your right
[hand], with all your respect to your person,
on your heart. In the heart resides the Spirit.
So you ask Me a question, without feeling
guilty, with full confidence, a question to
be asked in your heart, you can call Me Shri
Mataji, or Mother, whatever suits you, "Mother,
am I the spirit?". Ask the question three
times because you are like a computer and
the answer comes to you as vibrations. Ask
the question three times. Believing in yourself.
"Mother, am I the spirit?"
Regarding feet I must tell you, you must sit
in a way the feet are parallel but not touching
each other, but touching the Mother Earth.
They should be parallel to each other, sit
in such a way that they are parallel, touching
the Mother Earth. Not touching each other.
Ask a question, please ask a question three
times, "Mother, am I the spirit?"
Please don't feel guilty. This question is
followed by another question that if you are
the spirit, you are your own guide, you are
your own guru, you are your own master. So
now, please take this right hand down on the
left hand side on the upper part of your stomach.
Now slowly press it there. Don't say any mantras,
don't chant anything, nothing of the kind,
just don't force your mind to do anything,
it will happen automatically. Now at this
point, you have to ask another question to
Me three times, "Mother, am I my own guru?
Mother, am I my own master. Mother, am I my
own guide?"
All right. Now you take down your hand on
the lower part of your abdomen, your stomach,
in the left hand side, and push it there.
This center is very important, because this
is the beginning of asking for the true knowledge,
for the technique, how to maneuver this power
of God's love. So here I cannot cross your
freedom. You have to say that you want the
true knowledge, the pure knowledge. So please
say six times, because there are six petals
to this chakra, "Mother, may I have the true
knowledge?" or "Mother, please give me the
pure knowledge." Six times please. Please
don't get up halfway. It's not proper to disturb
others. Please be seated, please be seated.
Now take this hand again back to the center
of the guru principle, that is in the upper
part of your abdomen. On the left hand side,
in the upper part of the abdomen, on the left
hand side. Now as you have asked for your
true technique, the kundalini has started
moving. To give her a proper cooperation,
now you have to say, with full confidence,
with full assertion, "Mother, I am my own
master. Mother, I am my own guide. Mother
I am my own guru." Please say this. When you
say this, the kundalini will rise higher.
At this point you have to say ten times. As
I said there are ten valencies, ten guru principles,
within us. You shouldn't have any fear, any
fear whatsoever, about kundalini. This kundalini
is your mother and she is going to bear all
the brunt upon herself to give you this realization,
because this she has been waiting for ages.
You are not going to be troubled at all. There
is not going to be any trouble whatsoever.
So now what we have, please close your eyes,
now what we have to do is to put this hand
on the heart again, back on the heart, left
hand towards Me and right hand on the heart.
Take out your shoes please. Put your left
Take out your spectacles, please. Now keep
your eyes shut. At this point you have to
say, assert with full confidence in you, "Mother,
"I am the spirit", you are the spirit. All
right. Say twelve times "Mother, I am the
spirit."
Now you have to know that God is the ocean
of compassion, ocean of Divine love, ocean
of grace, bliss, joy, everything. Apart from
that He is the ocean of forgiveness. Whatever
you might have done He is the ocean, everything
engulfs, dissolves into His ocean of forgiveness.
So please forgive yourself first of all, and
now raise your right hand in the corner of
your neck and the shoulder. Little backwards.
This is the center you catch. This is the
center you catch when you feel guilty. So
now please say with full understanding about
yourself. Please put the hand from the front
on the chest you put it, not backwards, put
it from the, on the chest, the hand on the
chest and then put it down, otherwise it will
pain. Yes. Now press it hard, press it hard,
and here you say sixteen times, with all faith
in yourself, "Mother, I am not guilty." Say
it sixteen times, "Mother, I am not guilty."
You have to be pleasant, you have to be happy,
you have to be joyous. Not to feel guilty
and miserable. Please say, "Mother, I am not
guilty at all." That will really help. This
the worst center you have today, worst, is
very painful, please say, "Mother, I'm not
guilty." If you still believe that you are
guilty of doing something wrong for nothing
at all, I would say better get a punishment
of saying hundred and eight times. That will
release you of your worries, of feeling guilty.
What do you do about it, it's a myth to feel
that way, isn't it? Ah, better. So now please
say it sixteen times, "Mother, I am not guilty."
Now raise this hand on your forehead across,
across and hold it tight and press it hard,
as if when you have headache, you press it
the same way. At this point you have to say,
is the mantra for this center, is, that "Mother,
I forgive everyone, Mother, I forgive everyone."
Now many people think that is very diffiult
to say, actually it's a myth, it's a myth
because we do not do anything whether we forgive
or we do not forgive. But if we do not forgive
others we play into the hand of others. So
please say, "Mother, I forgive everyone",
from your heart. How many times is not the
point. From your heart please say, "Mother,
I forgive everyone." From your heart.
Now take your hand on the backside of your
head, backside, on the optic lobe, hold it
tight. Here because you feel so guilty please
say, once and for all, "Oh Lord, if I have
done anything in the glory of Divine which
is wrong, please forgive me." Just once with
full understanding and heart, please say that,
"Forgive me. If I have done anything wrong,
please forgive me." All right. Now take this
hand on top of your head, and put your palm
on top of your head and press it hard and
move it clockwise, on the area that was soft
in your childhood. Press it hard and move
it. Your palm, palm, not fingers, and move
it clockwise. [Shri Mataji gives the cool
breeze through the microphone.]
Now please take down your hand, slowly, take
down your hand on your lap, right hand. Now
open your eyes. Slowly, very slowly. Now watch
Me without thinking, watch Me without thinking.
Though there is air conditioning, you'll find
the cool breeze coming out of your head. If
you put your right hand towards Me and left
hand on top of your head. See, now is there
cool breeze coming? Little higher. It's a
very very subtle thing, don't doubt it, little
here, little here, please take. Put right
hand towards Me, little raise the right hand
maybe, hmm, good. Move it like that and see,
just see for yourself. Move it little bit,
see now. There is the cool breeze, not the
breeze from top. Don't doubt it, because this
is the breeze which will enpower you to cure
others, to cure yourself, so it's not the
airconditioner, just see this. Now, all right,
quite a blast. Now you put back the other
hand toward Me, now, again see the
right hand, left hand towards Me. With the
right hand you see, right hand you see, left
hand towards Me and with the right hand you
see. Enjoying so much, just see it's a miracle,
that's the real thing that you can't do. You
can jump, you can change your clothes, cut
your hair, cut your nose, do everything, but
you cannot get this cool breeze out of your
head.
This is the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost.
Holy Ghost is within us, reflected as the
kundalini. See now, raise it higher, it's
good. It's there, it's there. Now put both
the hands towards Me. See if the cool breeze
is coming in the hand. Should, but if it is
not, we'll try something else, and don't think.
It did not happen with thinking. Now put your
hands like that. Now you can push both your
hands like this towards the sky. Push back
your neck also like this and ask a question,
"Mother, is this the breeze of the Holy Ghost?
Mother, is this the all-pervading power of
God? Mother is this the Brahma?" Ask a question,
push back your head. Push back your head,
and just ask. Now you're feeling the air conditioner,
but actually also you are feeling this breeze.
Put your hands towards Me. Now see, you'll
feel the breeze coming from Me. All right?
Now take it down, see in your hands, are you
feeling the cool breeze?
Yes, there it is. One more thing we have to
do now we have got our realization. Most of
us have felt it. Those who have not felt it,
doesn't matter, because of this center sometimes
you do not feel it, doesn't matter, but tomorrow
again you have to come and I'll establish
it. The one thing we have to do is protect
ourselves. Before we go out. Tomorrow also
before going out of the house you protect
yourself, in the night you protect yourself,
very simple, because now the power is flowing
through your hands. Now what you do is to
put left hand towards Me like this, or when
in the house just like this. Now with the
right hand you have to protect your auras
so no negative forces can trouble you. So
what you do is to raise from here to the top
of your head. Let's do seven times to seven
chakras. One, everybody should do it. I don't
want you to be caught up again, is two, and
everybody, whether you got realization or
not, is, three, again, is, four, five, six,
and is seven.
Now the last thing I have to tell you is how
to raise your own kundalini. You have to put
this hand, I am showing now only, before your
kundalini and move your hand in such a way
that it is first above, front, lower and back,
it's like that. Put the left hand straight,
moving like that, and this has to move like
that, clockwise. Now let's put it nearer the
kundalini, lower, lower, now start moving
it, that's how it moves, the hand, one hand,
moves straight, another goes round it. Now
the kundalini is up. Now make your shoulders
loose, put your head back, and give it a twist,
now you have tying the kundalini up there.
Let's do second time again. This is how you
do it. Three times, again you raise it. Now
you see it. The left hand will move much faster,
now you push back your head, push back your
shoulders, and just give it a second twist.
Third time you have to give it three knots,
so again please raise it higher, push back
your head, give it one twist, then the second
twist, and the third one with a big knot.
Now feel it in your hands. See now, the instrument
will work better. Like you see we have made
our connections better. Right, that's it.
Now feel this experience. This is the experience
of the spirit. Now what to do about it. How
to work it out, all those things...
May God bless you.