He was son of God and He came on this Earth
with a very great message that you are to
be resurrected.
It is not only that you have to maintain yourself,
and you don’t eat this and don’t do that
and all those Ten Commandments, but He came
to give us a message of our rebirth.
We are to be born again; not by any just a
ritual or some sort of a ceremony we go through,
but there has to be something living that
has to take place.
He has always talked about [the] living God.
So something living must happen and what happens
when it is something living?
When it is something living we start finding
the transformation taking place.
For example: you sow a seed and the living
process starts; the tree starts transforming
into the root and a shoot; and then the shoot
start transforming itself into leaves and
then into fruits.
It’s not static: not that we take one piece
from here and keep it there and it is transformed,
but there is something that happens within,
something very spontaneous which brings forth
this transformation and you see it with your
own eyes.
And this transformation has to take place
within you.
Now, in a case as I told you of Cathy or someone
like that one can say all right you must have
consoled or you give her love and this and
that she be consoled, but that’s not the
point.
As I told you there are many people who have
got everything, still they are unhappy.
And if you ask them they will say, “No,
we don’t know.
We are not happy.
We don’t feel happy.
There’s no joy in our lives.
We have lost our heart."
They can’t explain but it is there.
What have they lost?
The time has come for the whole world to know
their Spirit.
This is the time which is prophesised even
by William Blake where he describes England
is the Jerusalem.
The time has come for you to know your Spirit.
That has to happen.
It’s not a thing by which I tell you, you
stand on your heads or hold your nose or start
taking some names, like a one track mind going
on chanting some names like madcaps.
It’s not that, but something that must happen
within yourself and that must transform you.
Of course, one must understand [that] if it
is a living process, you cannot pay for it.
How can you pay for a seed to sprout?
The seed doesn’t understand; the living
process doesn’t understand money.
It’s the dead work of human beings.
How can you organise it also?
You cannot! It’s spontaneous.
There is no technique.
It’s all built-in.
The technique is built: in the little seed
that you see, the whole technique of its growth
is built-in.
The technique is built-in and all its maps,
how it is going to be, what tree it is going
to be, how the tree is going to grow, in what
height, in what thickness, everything is inside
that seed.
In the same way it is a spontaneous thing,
which has to happen within you and if it is
so we have to find out.
That’s how the search started: people went
to India, went all over the places to find
out.
They thought we cannot find the solution here
let us go up there.
It has to be that way, because if you grow
too much outside you have to find out your
roots.
Because you develop that fear that you may
not be able to sustain this outward growth
unless and until you find out the depth or
the source on which this is to be sustained.
So people started searching and searching.
I have met many of them, many thousands, and
I find they were misled many a times.
They were really misled.
They were so anxious to get to it that whatever
somebody said they just accepted blindfolded.
People asked for money, all right take money.
They starved themselves, collected money and
gave this to these swindlers and these cheats
and thugs.
How can anybody exchange money for the Spirit?
It’s absurd! It’s illogical.
But we understand money to such a great extent,
I was amazed, that we think that Spirit can
be bought by giving some money to someone,
or some sort of a material thing.
Logically all these things have to be understood.
Now to say that logically you cannot understand
God, is wrong.
You can, logically; not rationally but logically.
There’s a difference between the two.
For example, if you have not come to London,
you have not seen London, I have not been
to Newbury, I did not know it’s a beautiful
place like this, then I cannot understand
it.
But if I have come here, then I see with my
own eyes, “Yes it is so."
Then I have to say, “Yes I have seen it.
It’s so."
I have seen it, I have felt it.
I know it is so.
Then it becomes, the whole thing becomes logical.
But rationally if I sit in India somewhere
in the corner and think of Newbury, “Now
I am going to Newbury."
Just putting my wings of imagination outside:
will I come to Newbury?
But if I come, this is very important to understand,
if I come here, actually I come here, in person,
then I know the place and I know the people
of Newbury and I know it.
That means it has to be an actualisation.
If it is not an actualisation then whatever
you decide about it, this way or that, way
is absolutely illogical, because you have
not been there; very simple as that.
Some people say, “We believe in God."
Some people say, “We don’t believe in
God."
Both ways, whatever they are saying, they
are doing it I don’t know how.
If they believe in God, maybe it’s innately
built in us to believe in God.
But even they don’t believe in God, it’s
all right, because they don’t understand;
they have not been there.
But you must keep yourself open: open to understand
that if something has to happen to us, which
is a living process, some transformation has
to take place within us.
It has to be an actualisation, not a lecture
to you or a sermon to you, or some sort of
a service and then you disperse.
You must start feeling some transformation
coming within.
In the Bible itself, it is written: “I will
appear before you like tongues of flames."
Nobody can explain what it is like; they cannot.
It is written that: “The Tree of Life will
be fed by the water of life."
It’s a prophecy.
Now what is Tree of Life?
Where is it?
Where does it exist within us?
Nobody has tried to find out.
They say, “You must have faith."
“Yes, whatever is said is true.
You must have faith."
But if you have faith, after some time you
will be disillusioned.
That’s blind, absolutely blind.
Because where is that Tree of Life, you have
not seen, felt or it has not manifested.
For this we can refer to other scriptures
also, specially in India where people have
been more meditative.
As you have been more outward and seeking
[the] overpowering of matter, in India people
tried to find out what’s happening within.
I mean there are genuine people also, not
all are thugs.
They are not in the market.
They are hiding themselves somewhere in Himalayas
and all these places.
But in the sixth century only, we have the
description of The Tree of Life.
And the Tree of Life is shown here as you
see.
Now you are not to have blind faith in what
I am saying, there’s no need.
But you should not also deny me.
You should try to understand what I am saying
and see for yourself [if] it works out or
not.
If it does not work out we give another chance
to you.
Because you must know that I have come here
to give you something, not take anything from
you.
I cannot take, that’s my nature.
That’s how God has made me.
It’s something funny, but I cannot take
anything.
If I have come to give you then there’s
nothing selling, there’s no shop.
Try! If you should be open it would help you
better to understand what I am trying to tell
you.
Here now, you see the Tree of Life (chakra
chart) and when this Tree of Life is given
the water of life then what happens?
How the nourishment reaches?
And how it starts activating?
It is as simple as connecting this machine
to the mains.
Any machine, say a television is there, once
it is connected to the mains you can see the
manifestation of the machine very clearly.
And you are amazed [that] for a villager,
if you show, that he is surprised, and he
cannot understand how this is happening, how
are these pictures coming, from where these
music is coming, how these colours have been
shown.
He can’t understand it.
In the same way, once your machine becomes
connected, connected, with the Divine you
start finding Its manifestation.
Now in this picture we have shown you here
the subtle being that exists within us: just
like a structure of a seed you can say.
As in the seed there is a primule of the germinating
power.
In the same way, in that triangular bone is
the power which is going to give us rebirth.
This is your own.
This is your Mother who is going to give you
your rebirth.
She exists in all of us.
She is dormant, but She knows everything about
you.
She is like a tape recorder.
She knows all your past and She knows your
seeking and She knows you value.
She knows your defects and She knows what
mistakes you have committed, who has troubled
you and who has looted you, and who has deceived
you.
She knows everything.
But She is dormant.
She lies there in a dormant stage and She
is called as ‘Kundalini’ in the Sanskrit
language.
Kundalini is the word [which] comes from the
coiled.
The word ‘Kundalini’ means ‘the coil’.
And She is in three and a half coils, coiled
together, and just like, they call it like
a serpent, She is lying down there.
But you have seen mostly, most of the energies
are kept in a coil, because if any chord has
to be used we put it in a coil always.
The one end has to come out so it is kept
coiled up there.
Why this three and half is also a big mathematics
which, of course later on, you can find out
what is the meaning of this three and half
coils.
Just now, I will just give you a very, very
short description, an outline, about this
power that resides within us.
It resides in the triangular bone called as
sacrum.
That is at the back of us, our backbone, at
the lowest point.
You can see there is a triangular bone behind.
Now see this is called as sacrum.
Sacrum means ‘sacred bone’.
It has been found out that when the human
body burns this bone does not burn.
That is why they call it sacrum long time
back.
But the reason is the Kundalini is inside
that bone.
Now above that, you find there are six centres:
one, two, three, four, five and six.
And the lowest one is below that.
All these centres are subtle centres which
manifest outside our plexuses, the physical
plexuses that we know of.
These centres exist as energy pockets and
they supply the two lines: you see the blue
and the yellow line.
They try to balance and arrange the power
to flow into these two channels.
These two channels represent within us, on
the left hand side, the one which comes as
the blue line which you see comes actually
from the right side on top and comes down
and meets the first centre there.
This is the line of Ida channel which controls
our emotional line.
It controls our past and is also called as
moon line.
It is, it represents our desiring power, our
desiring power.
The another line you see is the yellow line
which represents our power of action, through
which we act.
First we desire, we want to have something
and then we act.
So this line represents your physical and
mental being which goes in the front side
and the left side of the brain and forms the
ego, which is a by-product of our activities
for our actions.
The first power of desire or the emotional
power, when it acts, for example say Cathy
was emotionally disturbed: her this power
was acting too much and was using all the
power from all the body and was creating a
superego there.
So actually on the left hand side and in the
front is the ego and on the right hand side
and the back is the superego, covering our
limbic area which is in the brain above this
centre.
This centre, Agnya, is the centre of Christ.
Christ resides there.
People say Christ is within us.
Where is He?
Which part?
Where is He placed?
He is placed in this centre.
Now when I say that He is placed in there,
we can prove it.
It can easily proved, because when the Kundalini
rises and if She stops at that centre — which
you can see and feel it, that it has stopped
there — you have to take the name of Christ
and request Him that, “Please allow the
Kundalini to pass."
If He is awakened, of course, that can only
be done by a person who is a realised-soul.
Any Dick, Tom, Harry cannot do it: you cannot
call Christ or anyone because what is the
right you have got?
There has to be a protocol, a connection by
which you can call Him.
Any such person when he calls Christ, He can
be awakened and the Kundalini rises from there:
that’s how you know this is the centre of
Christ.
What is the mantra of this centre?
Surprisingly, it is our, Lord’s prayer.
It’s the mantra.
It’s not only the Lord’s prayer, it’s
a mantra for this centre.
And the weapon of Christ is forgiveness.
When the Kundalini stops here, that means
you think too much.
Imagine all the Christians, or I can say the
Christian nations, think too much.
It’s surprising! We should not think at
all.
I mean Christ has done that for us.
We are not supposed to think.
But we think about everything, we plan about
everything.
We are mad with thinking.
I mean, it grows like a mad weed.
I was in Switzerland, there was a doctor who
came to see me and he said, “Mother, you
can cut my neck or you can break my teeth,
do what you like but stop my thinking!”
He just could not stop thinking.
What is the solution for this thinking in
Sahaja Yoga is you have to forgive.
You have to forgive.
If you forgive, then this centre can be resolved.
But forgiveness is just a myth, because what
are you doing?
If you are troubled by another person, if
you do not forgive that person, that person
is successful.
Because you go on worrying about it, crying
about it, weeping about it, and whatever he
wanted to trouble you for, you are just a
complete proof of it.
So forgiveness means what?
What you are doing is to get rid of his power
over you.
And this is what Christ has said that, “Forgive”
and the greatest thing He did on the cross
was to say that, “Forgive."
Because these people really committed the
real crime of crucifying the Son of God.
But still He said, “Forgive for they do
not know what they are doing”.
They do not know what they are doing, that
He was the Son of God.
It was impossible for people to believe Son
of God.
Imagine! Is He Son of God?
What makes Him that?
His resurrection proved it.
Till then nobody believed Him.
His disciples never believed Him.
He looked like a very ordinary person, carpenter’s
son, having hardly two robes to wear, living
in a very poor condition.
What made Him feel that He was the Son of
God?
His own knowledge about Himself.
Now supposing, somebody is the Son of God,
what should He do to prove it to human beings
are just like walls?
Sometimes I find I am talking to walls, absolutely,
or to some people are looking this side, that
side, and they are not understanding what
I am talking.
How are we to prove that He was the Son of
God?
It’s an impossibility.
And if He was born in modern times He would
have been crucified only when He was five
years of age I can tell you! Because now we
are so ego-oriented.
That time people were stupid but now we think
we are very intelligent: “We know everything!
We know God.
We can organise Him!” There are many who
say that, “We don’t believe in God.
We have created this world.
We are the scientists.
We are this."
Oh God! In this mad world, thank God He was
not born, otherwise He would have been crucified
much earlier.
So, was is impossible to convince at the time
that He was Son of God, but today we can prove
it! Because at that time human beings had
not reached that stage that they could be
given Realisation.
Today, Realisation is working en-masse.
Even in England we have now quite a lot of
people: “Even in England,” and I say.
England itself is really a great country.
It’s the heart of the universe.
It’s the greatest country, as far as the
articulation is concerned.
And the source of all that is good comes from
this country.
But the people, English people, have lost
their self-esteem completely I feel sometimes,
the way they copy French and Americans and
things like that.
If they could have their self-esteem, I still
say that the English youth are the best in
the whole world.
Surprisingly in my own experience I found
that they are the best.
But rather difficult nuts to be cracked! If
they are cracked they are the best.
And once they are there they sort it out because
they understand.
They are very scholarly.
I think by temperament that they understand
when I say, “You cannot pay money for that."
You cannot organise God, and something has
to happen within you.
Some actualisation has to take place.
This is what you should understand if you
are really an Englishman.
Because anything stupid and illogical should
be shunned completely.
Now what is the transformation takes place
[is] that, when this Kundalini rises, She
passes through these different centres which
are already exhausted within us.
For example the second centre that is within
us is the centre for our activity.
Supposing, you think too much, your brains
cells are to be replaced.
This poor little centre has to work very hard
to replace those cells in your brain.
It starts working a bit too hard and neglects
all other duties it has to do.
For example, it has to look after the liver,
the spleen, the pancreas, the kidneys and
the uterus.
But when people indiscriminately just go on
thinking like mad — even thinking about
God — what is it?
It’s like, as I told you, not coming to
Newbury and just thinking about it.
It’s that mad.
Then this centre it gets so tired, and so
tired, it’s so exhausted that diseases like
diabetes, liver and other complications, even
[the] blood centre of this spleen can be so
crazy with this kind of activity that one
can develop blood cancer.
For example, now we are supposed to be running
a rat race.
I mean we are supposed to be.
We are in a race somehow.
Everybody is in a race.
Whether it is in the modern race or in any
other race: we have to belong to a cult or
some sort of a group where everybody is running
a race, you see.
In that racing we forget about the way we
eat our food, then we rush about.
We don’t even give rest to our different
organs as it is required to balance its activities,
[so] what happens that a thing like spleen
get so upset, it’s so upset, that it does
not know when to create more blood cells and
when not to create.
You are eating your food suddenly a telephone
call comes in, you have to get the telephone.
There’s a little child crying, you are looking
after the child.
Now you have to go to the office just leave
your food halfway or whatever you have eaten
and you just rush out.
You run to the bus and the bus is missing
so you run to another bus.
All this madness make this poor spleen really
mad because it does not understand what to
do, how to supply the new blood cells, and
the result is you develop blood cancer.
It’s a very simple reason why people develop
blood cancer.
And then blood cancer we say is curable through
Sahaja Yoga.
It is.
Actually cancer does not settle in to people
who are realised.
But it’s absolutely curable through Sahaj
Yoga.
All kinds of cancers can be cured through
Sahaj Yoga, no doubt, but we are not here
to cure people.
Only those who are seekers the Divine is interested
in.
You will be surprised, a very rich man, I
would say one of the wealthiest men from India,
brought somebody to be cured and I said, “I
am sorry Sir, I cannot cure this person."
And he said, “Why not?
If you cure I’ll build a hospital for you,
I can give an Ashram for you."
I said, “You may do whatever you like, but
I am sorry he cannot be cured."
I did not tell him the reason for that, but
the reason is this: this man has exploited
many people, he’s tortured his wife, he’s
tortured his children.
He’s a horrible fellow.
He has never sought anything good.
He has no compassion.
He has no love.
He’s for himself, a very selfish and a tyrannical
person.
Tomorrow if Hitler comes and say, “Mother,
you give me Realisation."
Do you think Divine is supposed to give him
Realisation, because he thinks no end of himself?
It is for the Divine to decide for you.
It is not for you to decide for the Divine.
The Divine has to say that you are all right.
It’s just the other way round.
Because you may do whatever you like.
You may think that you must get all the blessings
from God, but God has to know that whether
He is going to be gracious on you or not.
Even His anger is His graciousness.
Because that is what you deserve and through
His anger and wrath He is going to cure you
and improve you.
Sometimes we have wrong ideas also about our
seeking.
The seeking comes to us from the third centre
which is in the navel.
We call as ‘Nabhi Chakra’.
Is the navel point.
But it’s all in the spinal cord.
Now this third centre is the centre which
gives us seeking from the very beginning when
we were amoeba.
We started seeking food then, as we became
higher and higher and higher in our seeking
of food, we became human beings, then we started
seeking say, money, position, power, fame.
Then the spiritual seeking came: we started
seeking in religions outside us, organising
religions, calling God, devotion, dedication,
but nothing worked out.
So we started a deeper seeking, meditating.
At this time also, people came down from all
over the world to teach you meditation.
Now meditation cannot be taught, it’s a
happening, when you are in meditation.
You cannot go to meditation: it’s not like
a small little house or a temple or a building
where you can enter into.
It’s a happening.
You are pushed into it.
You just become in meditation.
And this happening take place only when this
Kundalini pierces this fontanel bone area
and you get an actual baptism — actual,
not artificial.
You can see with your naked eyes, the pulsation
of this Kundalini, the rising of this Kundalini
and also the pulsation on the head here, till
it stops and you start feeling the cool breeze
coming simultaneously.
That should happen to you; otherwise don’t
believe in any tall stories.
For which you cannot pay.
For which you cannot think.
For which you cannot organise.
You cannot put in any effort.
It has to happen spontaneously.
So the question comes in: how?
How it happens?
It’s all in, in there.
It’s your own, within yourself.
But say there’s a light, say this is a candle
which has got a wick which has got a wax,
it’s just ready to be enlightened.
Then what you do?
You take one enlightened candle and bring
it nearer the other and you get the results,
finished.
What do you do?
The enlightened candle just acts as a catalytic
agent, and enlightens the another candle without
any effort, without any trouble.
In the same way an enlightened person can
enlighten another person.
It’s very simple.
But that person has to be enlightened.
And the enlightened person must know how to
maintain your enlightenment for the time being.
Like a seed you sprout: now the children may
sprout the seeds and they would not know what
do with it.
But a gardener knows: which sprouts the seed,
then it takes all the saplings separately,
looks after it, allows it to grow, then again
puts it in the soil properly, watches for
its growth till it comes to its maturity.
He looks after it.
In the same way the person who enlightened
should be able to guide you up to that point.
Such a person is called as ‘guru’ in Sanskrit
language but he has to be a guru who should
be able to raise your Kundalini.
Because these days if you say the name of
‘guru’, horrible names and horrible faces
start coming before me and they are not gurus
they are just like satanic forces.
They are horrible people.
How can they be a guru, those who live on
your money: parasites of the worst type! You
should see that.
I mean, if I ask you come and live with me,
for no money at all, will you accept such
a situation?
And these are even worse.
And much worse than any dog, I would say.
Even the dog eats food at your house at least
looks after your house! This is only one way
traffic.
You have to go on giving them money, money,
money, money, becoming poorer and poorer and
what do you get?
Nothing! You must see their lifestyle, it’s
absurd.
They live on your money, they have all the
weaknesses that a scoundrel can have and after
few years you find they’ll land up in the
prison.
Already we have problems with the prison.
So don’t allow any of those gurus come down
here.
Where will you put them?
Like in Switzerland I went and saw one gentleman
there.
He told me that, “There’s a horrible guru
who lives here.
Mother please come and just pay attention
to his ashram."
I said, “All right."
I went with him in his car, and looked at
the place: a huge lavish place he has created
for himself, with very tall walls like a big
palace! And you could see from outside the
amount of money this fellow must have gathered.
And within eight days a nurse fell in love
with a policeman, and this nurse was the private
secretary of this guru who had used that nurse
to poison some oranges to kill some people.
And so the guru, the great, now is in jail
for 14 years.
All such horrid people what have they got
to do with Divine?
But they mesmerise, and once you are mesmerised
your seeking becomes absolutely stupid and
foolish.
You cannot see you are mesmerised.
You cannot understand how you are mesmerised.
You don’t want anything for yourself.
There’s another one who was coming here
the other day, and he said that, “If you
give me a Rolls Royce I’ll come."
Imagine! He was to come from America.
He had already got 58 Rolls Royce from you
people, from you, the English, very wise.
I must say the wisest people in the whole
world, have given 58 Rolls Royces to this
14 year old fellow! Now he has become yankee
in America, taken away all your money, befooling
you.
He has 58 Rolls Royces, he wants 59th.
I don’t know why he wants one more.
Poor boys and girls, they don’t have so
much money now.
Here the young people don’t have much money.
Like in our country maybe rich people’s
children get a lot of money, but here I find
that the young people have to find their own
way.
They starved themselves, ate only potatoes
and fasted, did all kinds of things to save
money to buy a Rolls Royce for this scoundrel,
just think of it! These are all seekers who
did it.
So foolish and stupid! And when he came they
presented him with this Rolls Royce.
My heart really weeps and I really don’t
know what to say to this kind of foolishness
people are doing.
Naturally your parents do not believe in you!
They think: what stupidity you are doing?
I can understand.
Even if they doubt me, I wouldn’t mind,
because really this kind of stupidity you
have done.
And how can you believe such stupid fellow
who asked for a Rolls Royce?
You should have really given him a toy Rolls
Royce and 3, 4 slaps on the face and he would
gone back.
That’s what he deserves.
Now he got this Rolls Royce very nicely, he
cheated you all and went back.
And he’ll come back next year and you will
be again doing the same thing for him!
Now when some of the Sahaja Yogis went and
asked these people that, “Why did you do
it?” They said, “He has given us something
so great.
This is metal.
If we give him the metal and if he gives us
the Spirit why not do it?” It’s foolishness!
Can you get Spirit for giving some metal?
Can you?
Spirit, can you purchase it or could exchange
it?
But
from where this kind of stupidity walks into
your heads?
I mean you are not such stupid people.
Most of them are educated in university: Oxford,
Cambridge.
Did you learn all these stupidity there?
No! It’s some sort of a mesmerism I feel.
Some stupid spirits have entered into their
minds.
That’s the only solution I can get.
I cannot understand what is the reason for
these people to go about buying Rolls Royces
for their gurus.
Then another guru comes up here and tells
you, “I will make you fly."
Very big, big people are out to fly.
But why do you want to fly?
Do you want to become birds?
Have you to become birds now?
You have to become a superior human being,
with superior value systems, built within
you.
You want to fly.
I mean it is stupidity.
Even if somebody gives you ideas like that,
better ask him to fly himself, drop him from
this leaning tower of Pisa and see where does
he lie, which part.
Why do you believe such stupid things, I can’t
understand.
You are supposed to be English.
I mean at least Indians have great ideas about
your brains.
H.
G.
Wells has said that English will have one
day having only heads and no bodies.
But I don’t think that’s going to happen
with the advent of all these stupid gurus
coming here and you people passing out all
your money to them.
I don’t know what is going to happen.
As it is we are suffering from so many other
things, plus this kind of a nonsense coming
all the spirits coming down.
All this negativity working into us I don’t
know what is going to happen to this country
of ours.
I don’t know.
I can’t understand.
Now everybody is meditating in this country,
trying to fly.
Imagine! Doing nothing, sitting at home, meditating:
lethargy of the worst type! Trying to fly.
This is what it is.
That’s what has happened to our seeking
in various ways, in this way or that way or
that way.
No, this is not to happen anymore, enough
of it.
You must get your Realisation.
That’s what you have to have.
The Kundalini has to rise and you have to
get it because you are seekers of ages, ancient
times.
You are born today, here, to get your Realisation.
That’s your right to have it, and not to
be befooled by these people who just come
here and exploit you and have floated a market
and enterprises.
Now this Kundalinis thing comes to you through
that centre.
When it comes to awakening centre, that centre
of your seeking.
Then you start seeing what you are seeking.
You are seeking the joy of your Spirit, the
bliss of peace within yourself.
When the Kundalini rises and shoots off, the
seeking is complete because you have found
it: you are just there, no questions.
Supposing you enlighten the light then what
does the light do?
First, she is asking for the light, all right,
“I must have the light.
I must have the light,” [then] she gives
light — finished.
Then you don’t sit there, you sit here with
me and you give vibrations to people, you
raise their Kundalinis, you awaken them and
give them Realisation.
Yes, it happens.
You all have those powers.
In a split of a second you get that and you
become that.
That’s your style [because] you are human
beings, you are not worms.
You are created out of the billions and billions
of creatures, special ones, the chosen ones,
to bestow this bliss upon you so that you
enter into the Kingdom of your Father, the
God Almighty, and enjoy your being and that’s
what you are.
Why are you wasting and frittering away your
energy on these nonsensical people?
Pay attention to yourself.
Just find out what you are.
It’s a very easy thing: it should happen
to you.
It has happened to so many in this country
and should happen to people in Newbury.
It is Cathy who has brought me here.
Actually now I am on my way to India and you
had this idea not to go out of London, because
I have really travelling too much in Europe.
Of course, I must say Europeans are also very
sensible people: they can see through now.
But I think you have to go through all that
otherwise you would have never understood
the value of Sahaj Yoga.
Perhaps that was necessary for them to spend
a lot of money on these gurus and to suffer
from all kinds of diseases.
There are some here sitting, from there only
suffering from epilepsy and all kinds of horrible
diseases like blood cancer.
They are here, some of them sitting.
Then you will realise the value of Sahaja
Yoga which gives you bliss, joy and happiness.
First of all it gives you the physical well
being.
It just gives you the physical well being.
Like any place where God has to be brought
in, you clean that place.
So the Kundalini cleanses your physical being.
That’s how you get your diseases cured.
Cancer is very simple, extremely simple, to
be cured, very simple to be cured.
But for doctors it is impossible to accept
that there is God, in the real sense of the
word.
Ah, they will have a photograph of Christ
in the house.
They might wear a cross, you see, that’s
at the most.
But to believe that you can cure cancer through
Divine power is an impossibility for them.
But we have some doctors also here.
But if they come to me they think they are
all mad.
Cancer is a simple disease.
Now they have reached a point where they are
coming nearer to Sahaj Yoga.
On the left hand side and the right hand side
we have certain areas, and now they are talking
about these areas which exist within us and
they say there is an attack from these areas
which are built within us from the time of
our creation, and these areas have those deposits
and they send forth some protein matter, which
we cannot identify otherwise, which might
have gone out of circulation of evolution.
When they attack us cancer is triggered.
And now this I have said at least ten years
back.
I have been saying that there are entities
who enter into us.
’Us’ meaning the central path, the middle
path, the middle road.
They come from the sides and attack us.
But actually when we go to the extremes of
the left or to the right, we ourselves become
vulnerable and we are attacked and that’s
how cancer is set in.
So down below is the hell, the left side is
the collective subconscious, the right side
is the collective supraconscious, which is
the future side of it.
In the top is the Divine Power, which is the
superconsciousness we can call it, or the
collective unconscious as they call it, which
becomes conscious as soon as the Kundalini
touches it.
Your attention goes there and the whole thing
is lifted just like the tent being lifted
up, and you find that nothing can enter into
your attention anymore.
You are in that area where you cannot get
attacked.
And this is what has happened to you, to many
of you, and is going to happen to the rest
of the people who have come here for the first
time.
I must say, Newbury, I must find out about
it much more, because I find this place has
tremendous vibrations.
Only when our car arrived here I asked them,
“Where is the water somewhere here?” I
was not dousing but I can feel vibrations
of the water somewhere.
And the place has tremendous vibrations.
Actually I was thinking, “How am I going
to speak?” because as soon as I reached
this place my whole body started emitting
all kinds of energies from the body and I
was really very much worried as to, “What’s
going to happen now?
What am I going to speak?” But this has
worked out and I hope you have been able to
understand it.
Now for the rest of the details you just don’t
worry.
We have all the books and everything for your
information which you can read later on.
It’s is a simple thing, like coming in the
room, you ask me how to put on the lights.
I have to just tell you, “Just press the
switch and it will be on."
In the same way everything is built within
you, you don’t have to do anything about
it.
It will work out in no time.
But once it is worked out then you [should]
try to understand it, what it is, and try
to maintain it for a while.
And you will be amazed that, here in Newbury,
you can start a centre of your own of Sahaj
Yoga, giving Realisation to many people.
May God bless you! Thank you.
If you have any questions you can ask me.
Yes, please.
Man: Yeah I have got a question okay.
Earlier on you were going on about if you
have family, children, and such as, who interrupt
you and the telephone.
What were you trying to say?
Do you want us just ignore this?
Shri Mataji: Oh, not at all! If you are not
married you cannot get Realisation.
Man: Then what do you mean by this?
I tend to think you are you trying to say
that you must try and ignore household attractions
and this…
Shri Mataji: When did I say that?
Man: I don’t quite know.
I had a job to hear everything you say but…
Shri Mataji: No, no, no! Who said that?
Not at all!
Man: What did you mean when you say, “The
telephone rings.."
What do you mean, “You must suddenly stop
and answer the telephone,” but what do you
mean?
Yogini: Mother, it’s when you were talking
about the spleen.
You said that the trouble is that there are
so many distractions that the spleen can’t
handle it, and I think he’s misunderstood
you.
Man: Yeah, that’s right.
Shri Mataji: Ah! No, no, no, you should only
look after your child and not the telephone,
I was meaning.
You must have your priorities properly built
up.
Ours are not.
What I was trying to say a child is lying
there, you are eating your food, a telephone
is coming, now you have to rush out, the child
is neglected, you run away, you are worried
about the child — never that [what you were
suggesting].
You don’t know in Sahaja Yoga you have to
be married.
There’s a centre of marriage.
You will be amazed.
If you are a so called ascetic, I can’t
give you Realisation.
Another man: You can’t what?
Shri Mataji: You can’t get your Realisation
if you are an ascetic.
So called.
Asceticism is within yourself.
A person like Guru Nanaka and all these great
people they were all married people.
It doesn’t mean that you have to give up
your family at all.
On the contrary, we have to have families,
beautiful families and beautiful children
and we are having Sahaja Yoga marriages.
Do you know there are three or four couples
here who were married through Sahaj Yoga.
And they are beautiful people, they have beautiful
children.
And moreover I must tell you a greater news:
that there are lots of realised-souls who
are born in this country.
And you have to be married so that they are
born to you also.
Now this child is a realised-soul, she is
sitting, towards me.
To be sitting that quietly is not possible
unless and until they are realised.
This Alison is born-realised.
Man: My children, my three children: They
are not realised and they are sitting here
all quiet!
Shri Mataji: Who?
Man: My children, my 3 children, they are
not realised so you are taking…
Shri Mataji: How do you know?
Let me see where are they?
Man: One, two, three.
Shri Mataji: They must be born-realised, I
am sure.
Man: They are not! They are not!
Shri Mataji: How do you know?
How do you know?
We’ll tell them.
You don’t know, you are not yet realised
but they are, must be I am sure, 100%.
Man: Well it seems that anything you say,
goes.
Shri Mataji: We’ll teach you how to know.
We’ll teach you how to know.
You should get your Realisation.
Where are they?
I would love to see them.
I can’t see them.
Man: But they are quiet all the time.
I say it’s instinct.
Shri Mataji: Come along, come, come.
They must be born-realised to be quiet like
that.
I would like to see them.
I am sure.
How would you know their value?
I would love to see them.
Oh that, she is realised 100%.
Are you doubting her Realisation?
She is born-realised.
She is born as a realised-soul.
She is born-realised, no doubt.
I mean I knew, I was going to ask about her.
How do you know?
You are a great person to have three children
born-realised, I must say.
For example, the little one there is a born-realised
and the little in that corner is a born-realised.
And there are many born-realised people, also
there are people who are there.
Where is Alan is he there?
Man: It’s just natural it doesn’t need
a big word for it, does it!
Shri Mataji: They are born-realised because
they got their Realisation in their previous
lives.
It is a very big thing for people who are
not realised.
Man: What do they know about previous lives?
They don’t know anything about previous
lives.
Shri Mataji: That’s what I am going to tell
them.
That’s why I am here.
They are born because I am here.
Do you know that?
I am going to tell them what it is.
See these, these are all born-realised [those]
two people [who] are coming.
Ask them about it.
I never gave them Realisation they are born-realised
but I gave them the knowledge about what they
are.
(Sit down my child, sit down.) They are all
realised-souls, no doubt about it! Not [just]
realised-souls but they could be very great
souls born on this Earth.
It is not [that] they are quiet because they
are told to be.
If they were not realised-souls they would
have run away.
They would not have been sitting because they
are enjoying it.
Their Spirit is enjoying it.
You will know it very soon.
Man: They will sit quietly anywhere!
Shri Mataji: No, no, they might because they
are realised-souls.
Man: No, it doesn’t mean they are realised-souls,
it just means they are children.
Shri Mataji: They are very different types
of children, very different type, something
so unique.
Once you get your Realisation you will start
seeing their beauty much better.
Oh! They know such a lot you can’t imagine.
My four grandchildren are born-realised but
my own daughters were not.
What am I to do?
And four of them are great people, but my
own daughters were not.
What to do?
They are born-realised.
You will see that.
They are that.
You should be a proud man.
But you better get your Realisation, all right.
I am happy you are so concerned about your
children.
I am very happy.
May God bless you.
Any other questions?
Seeker: I am very impressed with what you
said about Christ having done thinking for
us and we ourselves are trying to think too
much.
Isn’t there a danger, if we all become child-like
trusters, that we could be exploited?
Shri Mataji: Yes, it is a danger, of course.
I mean you are already exploited 100%.
There is a danger, no doubt.
I have already told you about the danger.
But to become child-like is not easy.
You can be befooled but to be child-like is
the best thing.
Innocence is the most powerful thing.
If you are innocent nobody can touch you.
But very difficult to be innocent.
The centre of innocence has to be awakened
within us, then you will be like children.
Now would you say that Christ was exploited,
many people feel that way that He was exploited:
no! It was all planned very well.
He just played a drama.
Such people do not suffer.
I do not suffer, never.
Even if I say that I am suffering it’s just
a joke.
Never take that seriously.
It’s a drama.
Such people don’t suffer.
He never suffered, in the sense you understand
suffering.
Of course, with the physical body you do feel
little pain here and there.
But you just see it as a witness.
You are not really in it.
And when you become that, yourself, a witness,
nobody can exploit you.
Because what happens you develop a new type
of a dimension, an awareness, which is called
as vibratory awareness.
By this enlightenment of your fingers you
become collectively conscious.
Immediately you know who is who, what is what.
Children know it, those who are realised-souls
specially know it.
Any funny man comes in they start crying and
weeping.
Like this girl’s father and mother were
involved in a nonsense.
They are here now.
Both suffered a lot the mother became epileptic
and all that.
And this child used to scream whenever she
saw their revered guru, and she used to shout
and resist and she used to kick him.
She is just a child but she knew how to protect.
And these people with all their intelligence
and education and this and that, were absolutely
useless! Because you develop that new awareness
within you by which you can feel a person,
you know.
You cannot be exploited.
All right.
That has to happen to you.
That’s a happening.
Such a powerful personality develops, such
a powerful personality.
That way, many of our Sahaj Yogis also think
that I am a quite an innocent person, I mean
they think so, but now they know I know everything.
I may look such a fool, but I am not.
And the powerfulness is such, that first the
compassion, the compassion itself is so powerful,
so engulfing, it’s so rewarding.
Then you are not bothered about anyone.
What are they going to do to you?
Like in India when I started, right and left
criticising, all these gurus, taking their
names.
I started saying, “Now these people are
like this.
These people, they are making money and befooling
you."
Some of the guru’s people, who were [become]
Sahaja Yogis, one of them was some Raja or
some place, he came to me and said, “Mother,
what are you doing?
They will kill You."
I said, “This time let them try killing
me! Who is going to kill me, I’ll see?
That was done once for all.
Now let me see who is going to kill me."
I said, “Let them lift their hands towards
me, if they can they’ll shake.
They cannot kill me."
It’s the most powerful thing is your innocence
which we have lost sometimes foolishly.
It is the highest thing.
And nobody can exploit an innocent person,
nobody can befool.
You have seen simple village folk, how do
they exist with all the cunning of the very
well educated and sophisticated people, how
do they exist?
They can manage them just like this (clicks
Her fingers) And you must see the intentions
of the person: why a person should exploit,
what is the need of the person.
People don’t even see the credibility of
a personality who comes here.
It’s very surprising.
Like one guru came here.
I would say, it’s something, another foolishness
who was living in a tin shed, that is what
Peter told me in South Africa, and thousands
and thousands of people are his disciples.
To such an extent you will be surprised.
I mean, I don’t know what to say, this is
complete blindness.
I went to Norwich, so far away.
This fellow has come to London only.
And I met three elderly ladies who were his
disciples and this gentleman was later on
found to be having whisky every night and
using women, and he had all kinds of things.
And his private secretary herself disclosed
everything about him.
And then they found it out and they verified
it.
But these three foolish women still said,
“Whatever it is Mother we cannot give him
up, we love him."
Now what to do to with such stupid women?
You just tell me.
I mean the question of you also wanting to
get exploited! I mean he is exposed, everybody
knows about it, this gentleman about whom
I told you who was asking for a Rolls Royce,
was caught for smuggling three hundred watches
in India.
I mean how can a man like that be interested
in smuggling?
Just think of that! But all these people who
carried those watches went to the police and
said, “We brought it for ourselves."
Three hundred watches this fellow was carrying!
And they would not give in.
And when he went to jail, they put a big show,
and the Indian government did not know what
to do so they said, “All right you take
him away.
We don’t want to keep him in jail that otherwise
your government will come and say why our
three hundred Britishers are arrested,”
imagine! So they sent all the bad lock, stock
and barrel back.
So he came back here.
From here he has gone to America.
Now if you don’t want to see: I mean, isn’t
it clear cut what I said?
So clear cut.
If you don’t want to see it what can you
do?
I mean I tell you, sometimes I feel it is
the people who want to get exploited or they
don’t want to see it.
Now I would like one of them to speak to you
it would be a good idea.
Because you will know how he was caught and
how he was disillusioned.
Peter (Pierce)?
Is he there, just tell him.
So you will know how he was befooled.
He was supposed to be a great, he is, he was,
a great diamond merchant from South Africa;
married a granddaughter of a Duke of your
country, and that the granddaughter is also
here.
Peter?
Where is he?
I would like you to tell them what happened
with you and how you got exploited.
That would be a better idea.
You have it from your own kith and kin.
Just tell them.
(End of Amruta recording)
Shri Mataji: No, but the question is like
this you were out, I must ask you the question
is that, “Why did you get exploited like
that?
What happened actually, what happened to you
people that you accept this kind of a situation,
is the point, isn’t it?” Ah! That’s
the question.