I bow to all the seekers of truth. At the
very outset we have to understand that truth
is what it is. We can not conceptualize it.
We can not organize it and we can not know
it at human awareness. If we had known that
truth at human awareness there would have
been no problem. There would have been no
second opinion and there would have been no
quarrel, no problems and we all would have
been in the realm of peace and joy. But what
we see today is that we are moving towards
some sort of derailment and we do not know
where we are going and what is the end of
our civilization.
These are modern times and special times where
so many are aware of this kind of a destructive
force working on us and suddenly they have
become alerted and they want to know what
is beyond it. What is the truth? As I have
already stated that you can not know the truth
at human awareness. Of course, whatever I
am going to tell you, you have to keep an
open mind about it. Like Scientist you must
listen to Me as if it's some sort of a hypotheses.
But If I prove it then I am sure as honest
people you have to accept because it is for
your benevolence, it is for the benevolence
of this country, benevolence of the whole
world.
It's a understanding that I want you to be
at, that we have to know something more about
ourselves and about the whole collective problem
that is today before us. So the knowledge
that I am going to give you about is the knowledge
of the roots. You have the knowledge of the
tree that the civilization has grown like
a very, very big tree and if we do not know
our roots this civilization can be completely
destroyed. In the eyes of the divine no body
is divided like Indians, Canadians, English.
They are all the same creation of the divine
power. Now we talk of God, we talk of Love,
I was reading God is love. But by saying that
why should people believe you? Is there God
or not? Is it true or not? We have to establish
it. We have to prove it and unless and until
we prove it, it is not going to be accepted
by the progeny. Nobody is going to take it
as if some sort of a blind faith. All right
you were born in this religion so you follow
it whether it is Christianity, Hinduism, Islam
or anything.
So we have to awaken ourselves into that new
awareness by which we can know the absolute
truth and we can know that divine power which
is surrounding us. All this compartments that
we have made around ourselves will break and
we'll see the dawn of a new era where we will
know that all of us are capable of achieving
that great height of awareness. Of course,
you can not pay for it. Nowadays there are
so many in the market who are selling divine
gifts. You can not sell it. As Christians
we have to realize that Christ didn't sell
anything. On the contrary, he took a big hunter
to hit the people who were selling things
at the gate of the temple. So those people
who are selling or marketing things can not
be anywhere near divinity because divine doesn't
know money. Money is a creation of human being
and this is where I fail to see in the West
a response to Sahaja Yog. I mean actually
people told Me that we can not understand
anything which does not require money. We
have to little bit get out of this and understand
that divine can not be purchased, can not
be sold, it is just to be enjoyed.
There is a system built-in within us. I don't
know if they have shown you ... yes, it is
there. Inside ourselves there is a very beautiful
system built-in during our evolutionary process.
One by one gradually it was built-in within
us and that is how now we have become human
beings. There is a little bit more gap we
have to cross over so that we jump into that
new awareness. As they must have told you
about, that there is a power within us, which
is called as the Kundalini. And if it is awakened,
it passes through six centers, piercing through
our fontanel bone area and gives you Self
Realization, meaning like this instrument
is here and unless and until it is connected
to the mains it has no meaning. In the same
way we are to be connected to that force which
has created us. And that has to be, that has
to extremely simple because it is so vital.
Like our breathing is so important, so it
is so vital and it is absolutely free. We
don't have to go and read books for that.
Especially happening of this Kundalini is
an extremely easy thing and it works out very
fast and in thousands and thousands of people
it has worked and I am sure in Canada it has
to work. It is rather the desire to become
a Self-Realized soul than anything else that
is important. If you have a strong desire
to be connected with that divine power by
which you know absolute truth. That's all
is needed and it works so fast because this
power is the power of pure desire. All our
desires that we seek are not satiable, in
general. One desire gets satisfied we run
after another, another desire gets satisfied
we run after another. So now there is a desire
within us which if is satisfied then we get
the satisfaction that we wanted.
With this awakening of the Kundalini, which
has been worked out now for eighteen years
because I have been working for the last eighteen
years, I should say twenty years as such because
I started my work in 1970. We have seen that
people get cured of incurable diseases. How
does it happen, that these centers which are
the sources of energy within us are exhausted
when we use them too much either on the left
or on the right. As the result of that exhaustion
causes physical, mental, emotional diseases
from which we suffer. So now supposing you
have any physical disease that physical disease
can be cured if energy supplied to that part
of the body. So when the Kundalini rises this
center gets nourished which is being exhausted
and when the Kundalini is connected to the
mains, all the time the energy is flowing
within you, you get all right. And there are
diseases, which are somatic and there are
diseases, which are psycho. That is the diseases
are caused by, supposing you go to a wrong
guru there will be a problem, a person who
spoils your psyche. There are so many ways
these days we spoil our psyche, drugs and
other things that we do which spoil the psyche
and the person start going into the habit
of getting more and more dominated by those
habits.
So when the Kundalini rises She brings the
attention in the center, by which the left
side habits are cured. And so your psychic
troubles are also cured. Your habits are cured
and then there is another type of disease
we have, what we call as psychosomatic, these
are the diseases like cancer, say Aids, all
viruses, all kinds of multiple sclerosis and
all such diseases, they are also caused by
the imbalance in your attention, by the imbalance
in your being. So when you come into balance
these can be cured, very easily without taking
any medicines, without going to any doctor,
without doing anything special.
The whole system is built-in within you, which
works it out. But you have to take it up seriously
because supposing you have to go for medicine.
I don't know what is the course here is. But
in India if you have to do medicine you have
to put in really fourteen to fifteen years,
precious fourteen-fifteen years of life to
get only a graduation. But for this you don't
have to because once the Kundalini rises and
you get balanced and then you feel the joy
and the peace within yourself. Gradually you
settle down and you become a master. You become
yourself knowledgeable because on your finger
tips you start feeling the cool breeze and
you can feel it in another person, what's
the matter with his Chakras or what is the
problem he is facing, on your finger tips
and it's all said in Quran, imagine, Mohammed
Saab has said that at the time of resurrection
your hands will speak, of course the Muslims
are not worried about the future part, they
want to just talk about the past and they
don't want to think of resurrection, same
about the Christians. Christ has said I will
send you the Holy Ghost. But they are not
looking out for the Holy Ghost. Same about
Hinduism, in every religion it is said that
such and such time will come when you will
get your Self-Realization. But people are
not looking for that because those who are
in-charge are money oriented. And they want
to mislead you by saying that if you don't
do this you are a sinner, if you don't do
that is a sinner but they don't give any solutions
to the problem and there is a very big solution
within us, this one and that really helps
us to overcome all this ignorance which is
created by the vested interest.
Now this Kundalini when it rises it as I told
you it solves your physical, mental, emotional
problems, also it solves your social problems
because you start understanding the relationship
of other people. Like, now, you are sitting
here and there is no light. We don't know
how we relate to each other. But when there
is light we can see for ourselves how we are
related, how we are trodding on another's
freedom, how we are behaving and the whole
thing becomes a very enlightening experience
and that enlightenment is not harsh, it's
beautiful, it is love. And, then you realize
that you have got the power to feel like a
computer the absolute truth. You can feel
it on your fingertips what's wrong with you,
what's wrong with others. Now if you know
how to correct it you are all right, not only
that but you become a powerful personality,
a dynamic personality without feeling any
tension about it. Tension comes because you
have imbalances but when you are balanced
and when you are connected to the mains and
all the time the energy is flowing into you
there is no question of tensions. We have
no tensions and you are in a joyous condition
because you become Self-Realized means you
become the truth that is that you are the
Spirit. You become the Spirit. And when you
become the Spirit, the Spirit as it is said,
it's a fact that is the source, first of all
of knowledge. Like a person comes, say, it's
happened, I've seen many people who came from
jail, they have no credibility of any kind,
they wear some sort of a funny dress, appear
in the square and people just start calling
him a guru and such a guru starts minting
money out of you and head along people go
towards that person and think it is a very
big thing. Another one comes and says that
I am such and such and I have these powers
and that power you just believe into that
person, pay him money and get lost.
Like these there are no norms to find out
what is the truth and what is not the truth
but of course, you can find out one thing,
that a person who takes money, how can he
be related to God? How can he be related to
Divine? Anything that works on money cannot
be relationship with God. Of course, now for
example, this hall has to be, say, hired,
all right, the Canadian Sahaja Yogis, we have
many have hired it. Formally, in the beginning
I used to hire them but now they are hiring
it, that's a different point but for Self-Realization
you cannot pay. That happening is absolutely
a living process of our evolution. And this
evolution, that we are at a human level we
haven't paid anything. So why should we pay
for anything that beyond this. It is a living
process, of a living energy, of a living God.
So one has to understand, first of all, that
at a very ordinary level also that you can
not pay for God. You can not pay for Divine.
You can not purchase it and the second is
you can not put any effort. It's an effortless
happening, just like sprouting of a seed.
It is an effortless happening which takes
place and when it takes place, then you just
know yourself, you certify yourself. You don't
have to have others to certify that this is
this, this is that. And you don't take false
certificate. For example, somebody might say,
"All right, I am born again." By taking such
a certificate you do not become. It is not
that any organization can give a certificate.
It's a state of be-ing. You have to be that
in that state, only, honestly you have to
be that otherwise just to say that I am such
and such, it's cheating yourself. What's the
use? It's not going to help you. It's not
going to help others.
So first of all you must understand that it
is the becoming that is important. It's not
what people are saying about themselves, talking
about themselves. Like there are some people,
the other day I met who were selling lots
of Geeta. I asked what's the use of reading
Geeta? It's all bookish knowledge. To read
Geeta also you have to have Self-Realization.
And then I met some people who were selling
Bibles. Now we have been selling Bibles for
ages. What's the use? To read Bible also,
to understand Christ also, you have to have
Self-Realization. Otherwise you can not understand
what He said and all of them have said one
thing that you must have your second birth.
You are to be born again. But that again one
can use it as a placard saying we are born
again. So we should not cheat ourselves. What's
the use of cheating ourselves? Tomorrow some
disease comes in, some trouble comes in, tomorrow
our children take to drugs or do something
wrong, they go and murder people, all kinds
of violence then who is responsible? We, because
we have avoided to know about the truth and
it's all there built-in within us, it's just
there, which we have to have.
So now, the first quality of the Spirit is
that you become knowledgeable, Knowledgeable
about anything. For example, somebody says
that there is no God. Say, in Russia I went,
of course, the Russians are some or other,
the government is horrible but the people
are really their attention is so good that
they just touched it, and thousands and thousands.
You won't believe that in Moscow I never had
less than fourteen thousand people or Leningrad
same thing. In Kiev I had nothing less than
five thousand to six thousand people. And
the Government itself took it so seriously
that, I mean they invited about six hundred
doctors. I read it in the paper they have
put it only three hundred, it may sound big
but the fact is about six hundred doctors
came in and two hundred great scientists who
have done Sputnik and all that and they all
surprisingly asked for one thing 'Mother give
us Realization. We want to have our Self-Realization.'
So what I feel, whatever I've read about Russian
writers is that there has been always a soul
searching within themselves. If you read any
one of them you will find there is a soul
searching and they find out what am I doing?
Is it correct? Why should I do it? What is
the problem? And that soul searching within
themselves is because they have no choices,
like we have here in our countries all kinds
of freedom. We waste our energy in finding
out what breakfast we will have, what lunch
we will have, what dinner we have, what sort
of a blouse we should wear. I mean such a
lot of waste of energy, it's a joyless pursuit.
While they don't have that chance not that
they are not well off, I would say they dress
up well, they have good clothes. They live
well. They have all nice houses. Everybody
who is married gets a house. But they always
felt that they are not free to get to their
Spirit. And that's what they were struggling.
As soon as they saw Me, there is no place
for false gurus. Nobody wants them. When I
spoke to them in one of the seminars they
had a yoga seminar, when I walked out everybody
came out and there were other gurus who had
come, nobody was there in the hall to talk
to them. They are so keen and so alert that
they know that you can not pay for it. And
there is no hanky panky about it just telling
stories this will happen that will happen.
And now in all Eastern Block you will be surprised
Sahaja Yoga is spreading very fast. Bulgaria
we had fifteen thousand people, fifteen thousand
people in Bulgaria, so you can imagine. I
have to also go to Romania, I've not been
there but there are, those Sahaja Yogis who
went there have written to Me that they got
five thousand people. Sahaja Yogis got it.
So you can imagine how fast they are moving
and the day may come they might become very
powerful people than we are.
We have become weak. We have become very weak
internally. Externally we have money, we have
good roads, good telephones, everything but
internally we are weak because first of all
we can not get over our habits. Secondly there
are all kinds of negative forces working on
us. And we are so vulnerable we do not know
how to fight it out. So it's better that we
become the Spirit to know the knowledge, to
have the knowledge about what is good and
what is bad.
The second thing about Spirit is that when
it comes into your attention you become enlightened,
in the sense there is light and you see the
truth. For example, you are standing with
a snake in your hand and it's all darkness,
you can't see, I tell you it's a snake throw
it away but you will not listen to Me. You
will say why, why, what's wrong. I mean many
people have told Me what's wrong, what's wrong
if you are doing this what's wrong, till that
snake bites them they will hold it on. So
you put on the light. As soon as you put on
the light they will drop the snake by themselves.
This is what I say that you become your own
guru and you follow your own understanding
with the light of the Spirit within you, which
is your own. But this enlightened attention
works, it acts. You can close your eyes and
find out about anyone what's the matter with
that person. And if you know how to cure that
person it can work out. You do not know how
this Divine power works. This, all pervading
Divine power is the most efficient government,
the most efficient, we can call the housewife,
the most efficient father, mother everything.
Anything that you need is done so beautifully
that you are amazed and so many miracles happened
that you are amazed, how, what have I done,
why am I so much blessed.
I had asked people to write about their miracles
because they used to write letters after letters
and I've no time to write so I said you write
to somebody about the miracles and let him
take out a book. Now the pile has gone this
way and this way and it lost in that pile.
He said Mother what am I to do, is such a
lot. So we have to know that we are special
people. Human beings are at the epitome of
the evolution and that a little more is going
to give you the meaning of what you are. So
this enlightened attention makes you aware
of your powers also by which you can give
Realizations to others. You can correct them,
you can cure them, and you can give them peace
and joy as you have the joy.
Now you see these people they are mostly Canadians
here or Americans. Now to teach one sentence
of English is very easy and to teach the whole
of English also is easier but to teach one
word of Sanskrit is so difficult to an English
man. They ruled us for three hundred years
and we tried our level best to teach them
some English and whenever they would come
up and speak something we would say what language
are they speaking. We couldn't understand
the language. So it so very difficult to pronounce
this Sanskrit as well as the Indian languages.
But the way these people sing, I mean in India
people can't understand how they have picked
up this difficult language, this difficult
music, this difficult rhythm. How they have
done it and they sing, if you hear from outside,
you won't believe that they are Canadians
were singing. You think they are just some
Indians some very good singers from India
singing. How have they got it?
It is because of the new dynamism they have
developed in their creativity and we have
so many artists and musicians who have really,
as you say touch the roof, they have hit the
roof, like in their fame, in their success,
in their creativity. So you become extremely
creative but you become very humble. You are
not egotistical, you do not force your things
on to others, but automatically because you
are so good that you shine. There are so many
artists especially in India musicians who
have achieved great heights with Sahaja Yoga.
And it has to work out everywhere that we
should understand the essence of music and
how it really soothes human beings by which
you will, not for success but it is just for
expression, work out but automatically it
becomes successful. Now this is not only that
I'm trying to lure you to some ideas. But
what I am trying to tell you within you lies
all these powers and if you have not utilize
and if you have not make use of that and then
you are unhappy no body can help it. It is
all there which you have to have.
Now the Spirit gives you the knowledge of
truth. Spirit gives your attention the light
and Spirit is the source of joy, as if you
were getting drown in the waves of your thoughts
and worries and problems. Suddenly you find
you are in a boat and you are enjoying everything.
You are seeing it. When you see your problem
you can solve it better and there is the Divine
power to solve all the problems that you have,
then you learn how to swim. You can jump into
the same waves, which have bothered you and
save other people and so a new dynamic personality
you develop because you become collectively
conscious about which Jung has written that
now human beings will become collectively
conscious. It is the consciousness, which
is expressed in our central nervous system
by which you can feel the other.
Now my hand, this hand if it is hurt the another
hand can feel it, the whole body will feels
it and tries to help. Now who is the other
when everybody is a part and parcel of the
whole, who is the other? For example, we were
going to have a program here and you will
be amazed we have people even from Austria
who just came, they had holidays so they just
came running to help the Canadian people here
that they are very few. So better run down
and help them. We have people all over the
world. Sahaja Yoga is working in forty countries.
And when I went to Russia it is so gratifying
to know that the first people who came to
Russia to help the Russians were twenty five
Germans. And the Germans were so gentle, so
beautiful you won't believe that their fore
fathers fought with that horrible fellow Hitler.
No, they are so gentle, so beautiful and when
I saw them working on these Russians with
such love, with such attention, with such
understanding. I felt that it's another world
they're existing, which is so beautiful and
so nice.
In one program I don't know how much I can
tell you about it and we have here a proper
Ashram where you can go. We have here people
who have their programs where you can go.
But their complaints are that Mother when
You come, I don't know what happens they come
to Your program all right but after that they
never come and they get lost. I just don't
know why is it so because you just what I
can do today is like a sprouting of the seed
but after that you have to grow into a tree.
Unless and until you grow into the tree it's
a myth as in your Parable of Christ some fell
on the rocky areas. Some fell in the marshy
areas like that. It should not be. It should
be it fell into areas where people prospered
and became great trees. Let Canada take over.
I think Americans I'm quite disappointed.
I don't know what's wrong with them. They
only like falsehood.
All the false gurus are prospering there.
All kinds of false things they like. A lady
is there. She is been into lesbianism, put
some sort of a drama and they are all attracted
towards her, can't understand how can lesbianism
anything to do with Kundalini. Kundalini doesn't
understand these things. No where in the ancient
books written like this about Kundalini. But
this lady is out of the blue has started using
all these ticks and there are so many running
after her, paying her money. She has built
up big, huge amount of properties and things
like that, and this is not the way to do it.
Why, when I say I don't take money they will
immediately ask Me then what about who pays
for your travel? Mostly My husband pays, no
doubt, he has been paying. Well, you don't
want Me to pay for your salvation, like if
I go to Russia they pay for My travel. The
government pays for Me, but otherwise wherever
I go I have to pay for Myself, most of the
time. But even then they come to this that
even when you eat your food who pays for that?
It is like this. So where they have to criticize
they do not. Where they don't have to criticize
they criticize.
And head along, thousands have gone to this
TM business. Now this TM is another horrible
thing that has killed so many people has made
them recluses. I have got so many patients
from there who are suffering from all kinds
of troubles. But people go head along to such
things which has money you have to pay such
a lot they don't mind. As I belong to another
life also, you must be knowing. Ah! In that
life, I find I just keep quiet listening to
people. They say, "Oh! That guru is good but
you know he is very expensive but he is quite
good. He is expensive."
So, a sort of a guru shopping is going on.
We should not be stupid in life. Stupidity
never pays, never pays. We have to be alert.
God has given us brains to understand and
we should not waste our precious lives this
human life, like this. I have to just tell
you that I feel sometimes so unhappy even
when I went to Russia and Eastern block I
saw so many people getting Realization and
working it out, thousands of them. We don't
know how to manage. The government is giving
us all the help, everything still we don't
know how to put them up, in a big, say in
a stadium, always we have programs. So how
to manage all that big group and how to create
people who will go and work it out. It's such
a problem for us.
But in the West I find people have no value
for that, no value at all. It's such a beautiful
life, just awaiting at your door but we have
no value, no value, waste it on useless things.
I have to tell you as a Mother that please
be concerned about it. What's happening to
our children? What's happening to our families,
what's happening to our nation? This Ecological
problem, all these can be solved in no time
once you reach that state and we have to have
more people to reach that state and to get
to it.
So May God bless you, in this short time whatever
was possible I have told you. I would like
to also have some questions from you but the
questions should be relevant. I have not come
here to take any money. I have not come here
to take anything from you. I am not asking
for votes. I am not a politician. I have come
here to give you what you have. This is your
own. This is your own property, which I have
come to give you, to tell you about it. So
it should be relevant and sensible and I would
like to answer your questions and then we
can have the session of Realization, which
will take hardly ten minutes. So please have
patience with yourself. I have lot of patience
but you must have patience and just ask Me
questions which are sensible, not aggressive.
Thank you very much.
Questions and answers - (Questions can not
be heard but Shri Mataji is answering to a
question.)
Ah! There is nothing to be done, just now.
It will be all awakened just now. After that,
once the Kundalini is awakened you have to
see where you are lacking in, what centers
are not all right, which you will yourself
know. You have to come to our programs that
they have here and you have to see for yourself
what's wrong with you and you should correct
yourself. Then gradually you become the master.
To give an analogy I'll tell you like this,
first you get into the car to learn driving,
all right, so there is an accelerator and
also there is a brake. So first you start
accelerator, break both and you go I mean
in every way wrong and then gradually you
start improving on it. And when you improve
on it you find it suddenly that you have become
a driver. Now you can drive. You can balance
both the things left and right side but still
you are a driver. So there is the master sitting
behind. Now that master is telling you do
this, go there, here there. Suddenly while
doing all that you become the master and when
you become the master you see within yourself
the driver, the brake and the accelerator
and you know how to handle the whole situation.
It's like this. So it is a gradual development
within you, which you do it and you have to
come to our center, carefully and pay some
time, that's all. You have to give some time.
Time is very important. But is the most important
because you have to now use it for your inner
development.
We have watches in the hand. All the time
watching one minute, two minutes, three minutes
and what do we do with it? Where do we spend
the time? Either may be in the pub or in the
ball or maligning somebody or doing all kinds
of nonsensical, destructive things. But, if
we have watches, it is for what? It is for
us to save time for meditation. But meditation
is needed only about five-seven minutes in
the morning and ten minutes in the evening,
not much time. But you must come to the collective,
because it's a happening in the collective.
Like, supposing My nail is broken and I take
it out, then the body doesn't look after it.
So, there is where people do not understand
and they do not come back and then they get
lost.
Next program I come in, they said, "Mother
you cured me. All right, of this thing I was
cured, but now I have got this problem."
So, all My life I'm curing them and all My
time is wasted like that. So best thing is
that you become the doctor; you become everything.
Why don't you become? You all can become that;
you all have that power. So you get it. So
you don't have to do anything just now. You
all have to ... I'll just tell you how we
are going to nourish our centers and we are
going to get our Realization. I am very happy
to know that you are anxious to do something
about it.
May God bless you!
Nice to see such people!
Question: For somebody who is not here and
who is really sick, can You help them?
Shri Mataji: I can, but main thing is, you
see, that such a person you can help him.
First of all, you get all right. You know
all about it and then you can go and help
that person, because the best thing is that
your knowledge will improve as you help that
person, gradually. It's very practical, and
it all helps. All right?
Question: You talk about our habits and weakness
and how to overcome that. Can You talk a little
bit more about it?
Shri Mataji: See, we are weak because we are
ignorant first of all. As I told you, we are
holding the snake and there's darkness and
in that darkness we don't see that this is
going to bite us. But, when you become enlightened,
you become a very powerful, dynamic person,
absolutely. And you separate yourself from
your habits. You see it very clearly. Then
you don't talk that "I have this habit or
that habit." You don't say like that.
Like a person would come and say, "Mother,
you know, my Agnya is catching; this chakra
is catching. That means I have too much ego."
But they don't say, "I have ego." I mean if
you tell somebody, "You have ego," they'll
hit you hard, isn't it? But if a person gets
it, he feels it. And he says, "Mother, I have
too much problem with the Agnya Chakra so
please clear it up."
So, if you have any habits - say supposing
there are people who used to take drugs. In
the beginning I had horrible people in England,
about seven of them, all drug addicts and
things. Of course, very well-educated, professors
and things, but all drug addicts, hippies
and violent people, really. When they came
to Me, it was not easy to handle them. But
they are today the foundation of Sahaja Yoga.
Wonderful people they are. Now what happened,
they said, "We want to get rid of it but we
can't. We just can't help it."
But you will be amazed, overnight they gave
up, overnight. Just it happens because you
see the light and you throw the snake, just
happens. You don't have to think about it,
just happens. I never tell them these Ten
Commandments - don't do this, don't do that.
Don't tell them. Just it works from within.
Why should I tell them? Why should I give
them a lecture? There's no need. They themselves
become their own master and the mastery is
that the master cures and gives you powers.
You develop that dignity; it's remarkable
what happens. To Me, it's not a surprise because
I know what you are. You are so glorious.
It's like you take a small little, say a television
to a remote corner of India and in some village
and show them and say that "Here is a place,
this box will show you all the kinds of music
and all kinds of dramas and this."
They say, "What? This box? How is it going
to work out?"
And, you put it to the mains and it starts
working and they say, "It's fantastic."
It's like that. We are fantastic, we are glorious
but we have yet to be connected, that's all.
It just happens, you don't have to force yourself,
you don't have to do anything. It just works.
The inner force works it out.
Anything else?
Such nice people have come today, I am very
happy. They are asking such nice questions.
[Applause]
Really, wonderful! But you must promise that
you all will prosper in a proper way and work
it out because it's a waste then I feel. You
know I was so enamored by the Russians and
the Eastern Bloc people because not that they
only come to My lecture, not that they only
listen to Me, but they work it out. And they
are moving everywhere. Now people have moved
to Siberia and all these far-fetched places.
They have taken the whole map. They brought
the whole map before Me and said, "Mother,
now tell us where should we go."
They have gone all out. So must understand
the importance of it. It's not just like going
to one lecture or to another lecture. This
is one thing you have to promise in your heart
that "Mother, we'll all become great trees."
You have such great trees here. God has created
such beautiful thing here. Why not in Canada
we should have some great personalities, great
saints? Now, any other question?
Question: In order to develop realization,
if you're not living somewhere close to where
there is a center then what do we do?
Shri Mataji: There's no need to depend on
Me. We have people here who are experts, who
have really become masters. And, they will
definitely help you so it doesn't matter.
I am always with you. Whenever you think of
Me, you'll know I am with you and you can
always write to Me. There's nothing to feel
that I'm away from you, that ... maybe that
is the reason people don't go further with
it. But as you trust Me, you trust yourself.
You must trust yourself. You must have faith
in yourself that you are quite capable and
you can do it. You can do it and that there
are people who will help you. They are very
humble, sweet, beautiful people. You will
like them and they'll all help you till you
become perfect. Such love, I tell you.
Same thing [someone interrupts]. Children?
Children are the best, children are the best
for Sahaja Yoga. They take to Sahaja Yoga
in no time. Most of the children these days
are born realized and we have to just understand
them. So many children are born realized.
Children are the best to understand Sahaja
Yoga, to work it out and they just of a very
high level, I should say. Like the other day
there was a child who was receiving a phone.
He said, "Oh, it's all right. You are not
a yogi." Puts it down the phone.
So I said, "How do you know?"
"Mother, he had no vibrations. How could I
know? Why should I talk to him? Let it be,
I put down the phone."
Question: Mother, is it a symbol of Your photograph
that gives vibrations? The willpower [can't
understand the rest of the question]
Shri Mataji: It's true. My photograph luckily
has some sort of a coefficience that it emits
vibrations. I mean, I would like anybody else's
photograph if it does, because it's a good
idea; but I don't think there's anyone like
that, because none of the incarnations and
none of the saints were photographed. It's
very surprising, nobody was photographed.
At the most, and also, nobody was portrayed
in their lifetime, because you know what happened
to all the saints and to all the incarnations:
when they lived, everybody was after their
lives. No question of having so many people.
I mean, even Christ had hardly twelve people
and how they tortured His life! Actually,
if you see His public life, He lived hardly
for three and a half years and they crucified
Him.
So, this is what the world was. It's not so
bad now. I mean, nobody is going to crucify
Me, but still there were no photographs. So,
the modern times has another advantage that
they have photographs, and they will show
you lots of beautiful photographs and things
which will stun you. But that will be later
on, you can see. But even this is such an
advantage that I can talk to so many people.
And aeroplane is such an advantage that I
can travel all over the world. Everything
is such an advantage today. The communication
have improved so much that I could come to
Canada. Can you imagine Christ coming to Canada?
[Laughter]
So, I mean, see the whole advantage is there
and in Russia I have given realization to
people on television, on television. But they
are extremely sensitive people, extremely
sensitive. I mean, in the program when we
had the scientists, one of the scientist got
up and said, "But Mother, please tell us how
You cure people when they only attend Your
program when they are so many."
I said, "I don't know if I've cure people."
But they are so sensitive. Their spirituality
is just there. It touches so fast. We can
say that they are very, very ultra-modern
sensitive instruments. Just touch them and
it works. It's rather surprising. Their attention
is so good. Their attention is so good. So,
that's what it is, it works. But if they can
get it, you can get it. You can do it. But
also, another problem in the West is that
we are very guilty people. For nothing at
all, we are extremely - one side we are destroying
ourselves, that's one way and another is all
the time we feel, 'I've done this wrong. I've
done that wrong. Sorry, Sorry!' English language
is full of it.
So, we all the time start feeling sorry. There's
no need to feel all that guilt and sin and
all this nonsensical ideas. That really spoils
the game for Me also. I have seen Americans
are the worst. They are guilty for this and
guilty for that. What is there to be guilty?
After all, you are human beings and if you
have done any mistakes, doesn't matter. After
all you're not Gods. So what? If you have
done mistakes, all right forget it. Forget
the past.
But this is also another problem of the West
is: now their forefathers say came here and
killed some Red Indians. Now, the forefathers
are finished, they might have become Red Indians
in this lifetime. They are not there. You
are their children's children's children's
children. Now why are you carrying on the
jokes so far? But for everything they feel
guilty - is another such a mental nonsense
that please, before I start this program,
I have to request you that don't feel guilty
for anything. You have done nothing wrong.
[Shri Mataji speaks aside] Also, there is
another two-three people.
Question: Is Gorbachev is a walk-in, which
means that is he from some other place which
is advanced soul?
Shri Mataji: He is a realized soul, no doubt,
he is. That's why it's working out. He knows
Me very well. He is a realized soul. That
you recognized him, I'm very happy to know
that. He is and look at them, how lucky they
are to have him there. And, he is a very sensible
man, no doubt. Even Lenin was. Lenin was a
realized soul, you will be surprised, but
he was forced by all his party members. He
was alone, you see. And, all of them forced
him to take a course of line which was really
proved later on. But whatever was his state,
talked about stateless state and all that
was his dream and that's coming true. He was
also a realized soul. But he went onto a wrong
line and it took so much time for them to
come back and they had horrible despotic people,
no doubt but the way the Gorbachev is doing
is great and I have a rapport with him and
he is a very great man, I must say. And he
has tremendous respect for Me. Because we
are of the same style, you can say, the same
line, that's why.
You, too, had in America. You had, say, Abraham
Lincoln was a realized soul, no doubt. And,
we had Mahatma Gandhi. We had many people,
but they were singled out. They couldn't give
realizations to others. They were singled
out and they had to fight, but now you all
can become realized souls. We have to have
many more to get peace, to get joy, to get
what we deserve.
[Question: A lady seems to have some illness
that doctors can't diagnose and is asking
if Shri Mataji can help.]
Shri Mataji: Yes, that's true. I am Myself
a doctor. I've done medicine, Myself. I know
that. It's difficult for them because they
cannot raise the Kundalini. You see that's
the problem is. Please sit down, I'll tell
you.
The medical science is, of course has reached
a quite a lot of height and have understood
anything, but the problem with the medical
line is this: that when a tree is sick, you
see, we treat the leaves but we cannot get
to the roots, you see. But Sahaja Yoga is
a thing that gets to the roots, and I'm not
telling you off-hand, you see, there are three
doctors who got their Ph.D. in India in Sahaja
Yoga that they have cured people. There are
seven doctors in London who are now writing
down about how many people have been cured
with Sahaja Yoga.
But the problem is like this: like for in
America, I cannot cure people because I will
be arrested. If and if Christ goes there,
He will be arrested. The medical science doesn't
allow there, I mean, that anybody should cure
anyone. Now, the problem is if you come to
India nobody is allowed to come to India who
suffers with AIDS and all such diseases. Big
problem for the patient also. Even in England,
you see, if we cannot say that we can cure
them, lots of problems with the law. And,
we cannot. But only thing those who get cured
automatically, like we have the people who
are Sahaja Yogis who had diseases, they have
got their papers, everything, and then they
are cured, then we note it down. India is
the only place where I can start this curing
business. But to be very frank, we are not
in this business. We are not in the business
of curing. What we are doing is to raise your
Kundalini by which you get cured as a by-product.
We are not doing curing. That's not our job.
That's not what we do.
And, also I must tell you the Divinity has
common sense. A common sense in the sense
that: now these lights are here, we know that
particular bulb is not going to work. So nobody
wants to cure. The Divine doesn't want to
cure people who are not going to give lights,
who are not going to get to Sahaja Yoga, means
that their Kundalini doesn't rise. If their
Kundalini doesn't rise, then how can we cure?
That's the only way we can cure people.
So there are limitations also that your Kundalini
has to rise and then you can get cured. But
there are many miracles which have happened.
I don't know how people got cured. And there
have been many cures, no doubt. And, it sounds
very, very much fantastic that it can be cured
through Kundalini awakening but it has happened.
We have to accept the truth. As long as it
helps, what does it matter?
Yes, please?
Question: What would be the effect of increasing
number of Sahaja Yogis on the economic system
and the lifestyle of the country where the
increase of Sahaja Yogis takes place?
Shri Mataji: Oh, it just triggers everything.
For example, now what are our problems? We
see the economic problems of this country
is. I have understood it so well that we have
so much of a, say, ores and all other things
like silver we have here, and gold and all
kinds of things we have, and the ones who
are exploiting us are Americans and nobody
sees the point. Nobody sees the point. While
those who will get Sahaja Yogis, they will
become so dynamic. They will put in their
own industries here. Why send it? Why make
cars in America? Why not make them here? So
many things can happen because you become
so dynamic and there's so many people to help
you all over that this is what should happen.
After all, you have all kinds of things available
here. Why should you send your aluminum to
America, to be drawn into wires and beaten
into sheets? There's no need. We can do it
ourselves.
So this, you see, self-confidence that we
can do it together and the collective feeling
can give you such good ideas. And another
point is that the way we are working out machines
now. Now we have to understand that machines
are for us. We have created machines and machines
are to be used according to our need and we
are not for machines. They are not to dominate
us. So as much as we need we'll use machines
otherwise we'll not use machines. And as a
result, already it is happening that people
don't like machine-made things and machine-made
this thing. So they will go to the balancing
state where they will take to more handmade
things and handmade material. Now for a handmade
things you don't have to have so many. Like,
now we say in India, thank God, we are quite
poor country, we can't afford to have so many
machines. Thank God for that because now in
a household they will have about, say, ten
plates of brass or twelve plates of brass.
Finished. We don't have to have so many crockery,
cutlery, this, that, that breaks. Then, after
that you have plastic. Because it breaks so
you have plastics. So, you go on. The plastic
is now mounting up, mountains after mountains
we have created.
So, you take more to practical side, very
much practical and more to the natural. And
in natural, it's nice to have one natural
thing than to have ten plastics. Now people
are realizing, I'm not saying they are not
realizing it. But still there are machines
sitting on top of us. And then the entrepreneurs,
the entrepreneurs are very clever. Today they
start one fashions, tomorrow another fashion,
third day third fashion. England is another
one who suffers a lot. For example, in a place
like London, which is such a cold place, people
have pants which have holes in it. They call
it holy pants, you see. And now imagine, they
developed varicose veins with that. Or they'll
have tight pants. They have to do something
about it. They have to feed their machines.
So they will start this fashion or that fashion.
Now, there's another fashion which is also
very dangerous that people don't put any oil
in their hair. Before taking a head bath,
one can put easily some oil or before night
they can put it. They are all getting bald.
Once they get bald, them they'll sell their
wigs. The same hair which are fallen off,
they make wigs and sell it. They are befooling
you. If you see little bit, you stand out
and see how they are befooling you must, these
entrepreneurs are. This is the fashion today,
that is the fashion.
I was seeing the children, we are now producing
clothes for children, for example. The clothes
are such horrible clothes. I mean, they call
them...
[Shri Mataji asks someone in Hindi, "What
do they call such clothes now-a-days?"]
... trendy, trendy clothes. Children wear
trendy clothes. They have no respect, respect
for themselves. They don't respect themselves.
If you give them trendy clothes, you see,
they become like brats, and then you say they
are brats. You make them brats from very childhood.
You want them to be brats, you see. So,the
whole system changes. Children become so beautiful,
so dignified.
Dress makes a person understand what is his
personality is, isn't it? If you are just
sort of careless about everything, you are
not bothered and the way - I have seen also
children and even the grown-ups walk as if
you see the, it doesn't matter how you walk,
you throw your legs this side, hands like
that. That shows the personality, that this
personality has no sense of dignity - how
it has to walk, how they have to talk or things.
So the whole thing has come down.
Now, for example, English language now. I
never studied English language but when I
went to England, I was surprised the kind
of English they are speaking. I mean, you
don't know what sort of English they are speaking.
And, really is impossible. At least, in Canada
people speak better English, I tell you.
You'll have a language problem, really. Because
they, even people from Cambridge, they have
developed such funny, funny intonations and
funny pronunciation that it's impossible to
cope with them.
So this is what I'm trying to tell you: that
once you get this balance, once you get this
knowledge, you develop a balanced economy,
you develop a balanced ecology, you develop
everything in balance because all these imbalances
has come through human beings. What is the
source is a human being. You see, in the jungle
if you go there's no imbalance. Only where
human beings live there's imbalance. So once
you get into balance, when you have more Sahaja
Yogis, there will be more balance and you'll
be surprised how things will work out. And,
above all there is this Divine Power which
is going to help you.
Now, what do you want again?
Question: Can we meditate now?
Now, I hope you are finished with your questions,
because if you finish with questions it's
better because this mind, you know, is a funny
thing. Suddenly, you're meditating, suddenly
a thing will come, "Oh, I should have asked
this question to Mother!" But as she says
it's true that even if I answer all your questions,
it's a mental acrobat. I can answer all your
questions very well. I am good at it, but
it is not going to raise your Kundalini. So
no question, is better that you just see that
what happens because it's a happening within
yourself. It takes you without thinking about
it. It takes you beyond the state where you
become thoughtlessly aware. You are aware
but the thoughts absolutely subside. And then
ultimately you feel a cool breeze coming out
of your head and you feel cool breeze all
around you. This is what has to happen. And
I'm very happy that she has pointed out that
they are all waiting for it. And, there's
no end to these talks and things.
So, if you have any questions you may write
to Me or you may give Me in writing, if you
feel that it is such an important question.
Then, of course, these people will definitely
try to give you an answer for that.
Now, I have I think in thousands My lectures
are there and the tapes are available. But
we do not give people the lectures and the
books and things because once it starts the
mental activity they just run into that. So,
first of all develop yourself internally into
that abstract stage and then if you read,
it has some meaning. Otherwise, there are
people who know everything about Sahaja Yoga
but they can't do anything about it.
Still there are two persons. Now these are
the last two persons, all right? Now, what's
it madam?
Question: When do you feel the throbbing feeling
when the Kundalini rises, when pulsation is
there?
You see, actually, Kundalini is in this jet
age has become like a jet Kundalini. She just
rises, She doesn't give you much throbbing
or anything - normally, normally I'm saying.
But if you have some troubles, some diseases,
something, some obstructions, then it does
throb a little. But you can feel it nicely
on your head the cool breeze coming out of
your fontanel bone area, very nicely, you
see it, you feel it. So it is the throbbing
of the Kundalini and all that are just like
some sort of an obstructions or say, short
circuiting but that can be corrected very
easily. So, it's like a very nicely built,
very efficiently built aeroplane, has a very
smooth landing, like that Kundalini rises
very beautifully. And, this is the blessing
of the modern times, I think, that the Kundalini
works out that way.
There's one more, there was one gentleman.
Question: The question is that once the Kundalini
is awaken he's read that Kundalini can be
if uncontrolled, if you don't know how to
control it, can it harm you?
You see, these books are written by people
who have no idea of Kundalini. It's not like
that. You see, this is just to sell something.
It's marketing. Sell anything, any nonsense,
there's nothing. She is your Mother. She is
your individual Mother who's waiting to give
you your second birth. Why will She trouble
you? When you got your birth, your mother
looked after everything, she, poor thing,
went through all the labor pains and everything,
she didn't allow you to suffer anything, she
never wanted you to suffer. Did she? Then
this is a pure Mother, your own individual
Mother; She knows each and everything about
you. It's all recorded in Her and She is not
going to trouble you, and you are going to
be controlled by Her in such a manner that
She becomes your energy. She helps you. So,
all these false ideas people have given, written
books after books so that they can sell it.
I haven't written any books so far. You'll
be surprised, I've not written any books so
far. Twenty years have past, I've written
no books whatsoever. People have written about
Me, people have written about Sahaja Yoga,
they have written all this, but I have not
yet written. I'll be writing. I hope so I
get some time to write. But you see, what
is important is that whatever written can
be all nonsense. They can write anything about
anything. First of all, you should know what
it is. And now I have been going to various
places, I have not seen it misbehaving anywhere
or doing any harm to anybody. Of course, sometimes
you do feel little heat in the body, that's
all. That's the thing you feel little heat
on your hands, that's all. But it's so little
that it's negligible. So, be confident.
First of all, before starting I have to tell
you few things and one of them is that have
faith in yourself. Have faith that you all
are capable of getting your Self-realization.
Please have that faith in yourself. You have
faith in everything else but in yourself,
that's wrong. Please have faith in yourself.
That is first point.
Now there are two conditions we have to fulfill
before we get our realization. First condition
is I have already told you, that not to feel
guilty, forget the past. Not to feel guilty
is very important because when you feel guilty,
then the center here on the left side catches,
Vishuddhi as they call it, and it's the worst
thing that can happen because this is the
center when it catches you get spondylitis,
you get angina, all kinds of trouble with
this center. But the worst thing is that the
Kundalini cannot rise above this center. So,
not to feel guilty. I assure you that you
have done nothing wrong.
You see, there are so many norms a society
has created. Even if you put the fork on the
other side you start thinking, "Oh God, what
did I do?" You feel you are not sophisticated
or you have done something like a murder.
It's not that. It is just all these norms
are artificially created, all these are artificial
things. Somebody is very thin, he thinks,
"Why should I be thin?" Somebody's fat, he
says, "Why should I be fat?" But this is life's,
whatever is there we have to accept our life
as it is and there's nothing wrong in it.
Nothing guilt. Whatever is there, whatever
we have been doing, we have been doing as
human beings.
So, first and foremost condition is - absolutely
you cannot compromise on that - is that you
are not to feel guilty at all. Immediately,
you'll feel better.
All right, the second one is that you have
to forgive everyone, forgive everyone because
whether you forgive or you don't forgive,
you don't do anything. You are living with
a myth, all the time thinking, "Oh, I have
to forgive this person, I have to forgive
that person." There's no need to think like
that. You don't also have to think about any
individual, just in general you have to say,
"I forgive everyone of them." And, that clears
out this center, very clearly, this is the
center of Christ, this clears out, and it's
very easy for Me because this is a very constricted,
it's the gate to the limbic area so that gate
has to be widened and it has to be opened
out. And so, just forgive everyone. And, you
know it is a myth. You are playing into the
wrong hands. So, this is another condition,
you have to just accept. Then it's easier
for Me to work it out and easier for you to
get it.
So, first is just don't feel guilty. If you
don't forgive, you won't feel it. Then, you
will come and say, "Mother, I didn't feel
it." And then I'll have to say, "All right,
forgive, forgive, forgive." And then you'll
feel it. So, what's the use? Just better do
what I've told you, is very simple thing,
just forgive everyone in general.
Then there are certain simple things: that
we have to take help of the Mother Earth.
Now those who are sitting in the ground are
the best placed, that's all right, they can
just take out their shoes, so they're not,
it's better that their feet are a little open
out. And, all of you should have to take your
feet out, it helps a lot.
Those who are sitting, should sit more cross-legged
it's better, better to sit cross legged. It's
hardly will take any time and is ... you don't
have to fight with your thoughts, you don't
have to stop your thoughts, nothing, it just
works automatically. I would say, like your
attention is like this saree. Now, the Kundalini
rises like this, goes up and She pushes all
your attention inside automatically and then
when it pierces through here, then the grace
starts falling on your attention, on your
sympathetic nervous system and it soothes
down. Then, your centers open more and more
threads of Kundalini rise. So, this is what
is today's modern Sahaja Yoga, which somehow
or other I've managed to discover, that let
few threads of Kundalini rise to begin with
so that you open your chakras gradually, and
then more and more. And then one day I find
you all have become great gurus, great personalities.
So, may God bless you all!
So, let us now with all respect to ourselves,
with all love for ourselves, we have to have
complete faith in ourselves, complete faith.
Have complete self confidence. Now please
put both your hands like this. It's important
to understand that these five, six and seven
are the sympathetic nervous system endings
and this side also are, these are sympathetic
nervous system endings and they are the ones
who are expressing the centers within ourselves.
Like this, left and right meet and make one
center. So, is very important that you, we
have to put both the hands like this to begin
with.
You can, now somebody will show you how we
are going to nourish our centers. The left
side represents our desire, not the pure desire,
but our desire. And the right side represents
our action, power of action. So, we will be
using our power of action to nourish our centers,
while the left hand will be all the time towards
Myself. Before closing your eyes, you can
also take out your spectacles because this
helps eyesight also. So before, not now, just
now when I tell to, because just now I'll
show you how to do it and then we'll close
our eyes. So somebody will show you.
First of all, you put your left hand toward
Me like this. Of course, those who don't want
to do it, should go because it is proper not
to disturb others. You see, nobody should,
those who do not want to do should try to
do it because it's not proper and should not
disturb others in between to get up and walk
out.
So, now please put your left hand towards
Me like this. And, with the right hand we
nourish our centers. So, first we put it on
our heart. In the heart, resides the Spirit,
is reflected in the Spirit. Spirit is the
reflection of God Almighty and Kundalini is
the reflection of the primordial power, His
desire which we call as Adi Shakti or we call
it as Holy Ghost. These two have to meet,
and the seat of the Spirit is on the fontanel
bone area here, seat of the Spirit is here,
but it resides in our heart.
Now, so first we put our right hand on our
heart and then we put our right hand in the
upper portion of our abdomen where is the
center of our mastery. This is created by
all the great masters like Abraham, Moses,
Lao Tse, so many of them who were real masters.
They have created this. Like Guru Nanaka,
Janaka, all these people have created this
great center within us.
Then we take down our hand in the lower portion
of our abdomen on the left hand side. This
is the center of pure knowledge, pure knowledge
that is the one which gives us the awareness
on our central nervous system. It manifests
a new dimension in our awareness on our central
nervous system which is called in Sanskrit
as bodh, bodh from where the word Buddha has
come, or we can say it manifests in the word,
vidh. Vidh is from where Vedas have come.
That you feel the divine power on your central
nervous system, you feel the truth on your
central nervous system because whatever we
have gained in our evolution, you feel it
on our central nervous system. That is what
is "to know." Knowledge is not mental. It
is in our evolutionary process to know on
your central nervous system like hot and cold.
So now, this is the center which manifests
that pure knowledge.
So, now we take our hand again upward and
put it on the center of mastery which is on
the left hand side in the upper part of our
abdomen. Then we take our hand onto our heart,
and here we know that Spirit resides here.
Then we take our hand in the corner of our
neck and our shoulder here and put it back
as far as possible and turn our head to our
right, we turn our head to our right. This
is the center which as I have told you is
always in trouble when we feel guilty and
today also I feel it's quite a lot among the
people who are here.
So, now please remember not to feel guilty
at all. Turn your head to your right and just
not to feel guilty, is very important. Now
then we put our hand across like this on our
forehead and pressing on both the temples
with our small finger and our thumb on another
side we put all the other fingers on the head
and put down our head like this. This is the
center, this is the center for forgiving others.
Forgive everyone. Now, we take back this hand
on the back side of our head on the optic
lobe here, on the back side of our head and
push back our head as far back as possible
resting on our hand, and here is the center
without feeling guilty, without counting any
mistakes, just for your satisfaction to ask
for forgiveness from the divine power.
Now, then we stretch our hand, stretch our
hand and the center of our palm, we put it
on the fontanel bone area which was the soft
bone in our childhood. Now we put down your
head, put down our head and press this area
nicely by pushing our fingers outward. This
is very important thing to do is to push back
your fingers outward so there's nice pressure
on your fontanel bone area. Now here is the
limbic area, the opening of the limbic area
is the fontanel bone area. So now what we
do is to now slowly move our hand clockwise
pressing the scalp, move the scalp, clockwise,
seven times. Push down your head, it's better,
then you can do it better, move it seven times
clockwise.
Now, I think everything was done all right
but we didn't push back the fingers nicely
and the pressure was less but doesn't matter.
Now, so, you have been already told what is
to be done. Now please, again see that you
put both your feet away from each other because
they are two different powers. Put your left
hand towards Me, put your right hand on your
head. No, not like that, you can sit, I mean
you can sit cross legged, cross legged is
better, it's all right, for sitting down this
cross legged is better. I am just telling
for people who are sitting on the chairs.
Just imagine people getting realization sitting
on the chairs. Is something great, isn't it?
Otherwise, we had to go to Himalayas and starve
for so many days, work so hard, stand on your
heads and still come back empty handed. You
are specially blessed to be born in this era.
All right, so now we put our left hand towards
Me, and right hand on the heart and now we
close our eyes. We don't open our eyes till
I tell you. Please keep your eyes shut till
I tell you. Now, the whole thing works like
a divine computer, so you have to ask a question.
You can call Me Mother or you can call Me
Shri Mataji, whatever you like. Now, put your
right hand on your heart and left hand towards
Me all the time. And, now sit comfortably,
not bending too much nor in a stretched manner
but in a comfortable, straight way. Here now
you ask a question three times, "Mother, am
I the Spirit?" This is the truth about you
that you are the Spirit. So now ask the question
three times in your heart, "Mother, am I the
Spirit?"
Now, if you are the Spirit, then you are your
master. So, now take your right hand in the
upper portion of your abdomen and ask a question,
"Mother, am I my own master?" Ask this question
three times.
Now I have to tell you that I cannot force
pure knowledge on you. You have to ask for
it. So, now please take your hand in the lower
portion of your abdomen on the left hand side.
Here you have to say six times, because this
center has got six petals. So, please say,
"Mother, please give me pure knowledge." Say
this six times because I cannot force on you.
You have to ask in your freedom. I respect
it.
As soon as you ask for pure knowledge, the
Kundalini starts rising, so we have to nourish
the upper centers so that it's easy for Her
to rise. So, now take your right hand in the
upper portion of your abdomen on the left
hand side, press it hard. Here, you have to
say with full confidence ten times, "Mother,
I am my own master." Say it with full confidence
in yourself, ten times, "Mother, I am my own
master."
Now, raise your right hand on your heart.
I have already told you that Spirit resides
in your heart, so now here you say with full
confidence, twelve times, "Mother, I am the
Spirit."
We have to know this all-pervading power which
has created us, which is nourishing us, which
is looking after us, which organizes us and
which loves us, is the ocean of knowledge
and compassion. But above all, it is the ocean
of forgiveness, and we cannot commit any mistakes
that cannot be dissolved by the power of this
ocean of forgiveness. So, now please raise
your hand in the corner of your neck and your
shoulder and push it back as far as possible
on the spinal cord and turn your head to right.
And here, with full confidence, please say
sixteen times, "Mother, I am not guilty at
all." Please say it sixteen times from your
heart, please say it.
I have already told you that whether you forgive
or don't forgive, you do not do anything,
it's a myth. But, if you don't forgive then
you play into wrong hands and torture yourself
for nothing at all. So, now please raise your
right hand on your forehead across pressing
both the temples with your small finger and
your thumb and putting all the three fingers
on top of your head. And now, put it down
your head properly, press it hard on both
the sides. And here you have to say from your
heart, not how many times, "Mother, I forgive
everyone." From your heart, please say, "Mother,
I forgive everyone." Please do not say that
it is difficult. It's the easiest thing to
say. Put down your head properly, press it
hard and say it from your heart.
Now, without feeling guilty, without counting
your mistakes, just for your satisfaction,
you have to ask forgiveness from the Divine
Power. So, now take your right hand on the
back side of your head and push back your
head as far as possible, on the hand balancing.
Now here, you have to say again from your
heart, now how many times, "Oh Divine Power,
if I have done anything wrong knowingly or
unknowingly, please forgive me." This is to
be said for your own satisfaction. Push back
your head as much as possible.
Now, the last center which is most important:
stretch your palm as far as possible, put
it on, put the center of your palm on top
of the fontanel bone area which was the soft
bone in your childhood. Now put down your
head as much as you can, please put it down.
Now, stretch your fingers. Please stretch
them properly and put a nice pressure on your
fontanel bone area. Here, again I respect
your freedom and I cannot force Self-realization
on you. You have to ask for it. So, now please
move your scalp, slowly, seven times, clockwise,
saying, "Mother, please give me my Self-realization."
[Mother blows in the microphone seven times.]
Now, please take down your hands, both the
hands, and please place them towards Me and
gradually open your eyes. Now, watch Me without
thinking. Now, please put your left hand towards
Me. Bend your head and see for yourself if
there's a cool breeze coming out of your head.
Please see with your right hand. Some people
get it very close and some far away but don't
put your hand on top of your head. Just see
for yourself if there's a cool breeze coming
out of your head.
Now, please put your right hand towards Me
and bend your head again and see for yourself
if there's a cool breeze coming out of your
head. Some people get it quite far away. Please
put again your left hand towards Me and see
for yourself again if there's a cool breeze
coming out of your head. Now raise both your
hands towards the sky like this, push back
your head and ask a question, "Mother, is
this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?" or
"Mother, is this the all-pervading power of
God's love?" or "Mother, is this the Paramachaitanya?"
Any one of these question you ask three times.
Now, put your hands down. You feel very relaxed
and there's won't be any thoughts. You can
watch Me without thinking. All those who have
felt cool or hot breeze on their hands, on
their fingertips or out of their head, please
raise both your hands. That's it. May God
bless you. [Applause]
I am here only for tonight and I would like
to meet you all if you want to meet Me, I
would like to shake hands with you. Thank
you. [Applause]
[While walking towards the car] Now you have
to look after the new people, all of you have
to look after the new people with care, with
understanding. And, best of luck to all of
you. It's a very delicate work. Whatever impression
they get from you, that is going to work out.
They must feel that "these people are very
loving and kind" and you don't disappoint
them too much. You must show your own discipline.
[Shri Mataji talks to individual yogis]
It's with very difficulty that we are building
up Sahaja Yoga and Sahaja Yogis should not
break it at least but they can build it up
themselves such a lot. So, we have to be like
them, compete with people who have done something
for Sahaja Yoga, compete with them and not
with them who are trying to destroy Sahaja
Yoga. It's so important. One has to play one's
own role.
[Shri Mataji talks to individual yogis]