Talk to Sahaja Yogis
Eve of Birthday Puja
Sydney, Australia
March 20th, 1990
So My tour of Australia has come to an end.
Today is a day I can say it’s all very well
done.
We have had very good response; I didn’t
expect that much everywhere.
It was tremendous and very great things have
happened, some miracles also, during this
visit.
And one has to know that Sahaja yogis have
to be with great potential manifesting.
If they are, then it triggers very well; otherwise
I cannot work out.
For that we have to understand that in Sahaja
Yoga there’s no sacrifice of any kind.
Don’t have to sacrifice anything, it’s
all the time blessings throughout.
You don’t have to sacrifice anything, and
you don’t have to suffer also anything – nothing
of the kind.
I have told you about how My father was in
jail, My mother was in jail and how many times,
and how we suffered during the war of independence.
We lost everything, all our properties, everything,
for the war of independence only.
But this is the independence, the freedom
of an absolute nature: not only for you but
for the whole world, for your children, for
everyone.
It’s a tremendous work.
It’s a very great achievement.
In the history of spirituality, in the history
of the world this is the greatest thing that
has happened, is that people are transformed
into a new awareness.
Perhaps you are not aware of it.
And we take it for granted, we don’t understand
the importance of it; and we get lost into
smaller, smaller things and very wasteful
things which are of no value.
How are these things will be going into the
history, you must understand that.
And where do you stand in that history?
What will you be called?
So now first of all there were problems with
the leaders.
All right.
But there were some who stuck on to it.
They didn’t give it up.
They did not give it up because the leaders
were bad.
Nobody wrote to Me, all right, but they stuck
on.
But those who went away, why didn’t they
write to Me why they went away?
This is an escape from reality.
This is an escape, to say that there was something
wrong with the the ashram people, there was
something wrong with the leaders – of course,
it was.
But you should have written to Me – why
didn’t you write to Me?
Why did you take such decisions on your own,
and just left the Sahaja Yoga into lurch?
We have to be people of quality, otherwise
Sahaja Yoga won’t work out.
It’s not meant for people who are mediocres.
If there are few, doesn’t matter; but there
have to be people of quality, that is one
thing for sure.
Now I have seen that everywhere people have
taken here a view that it’s better to have
separate houses.
I mean, this is another absurd view: from
where it has come into your heads, I don’t
know.
Absolutely absurd, against Sahaj, it’s most
asahaj view.
Today only I was reading, five old ladies
were killed by one man, because they were
living alone in every house.
Such violence, such horrible atmosphere everywhere.
Even for security it’s better that you live
together, at least eight people, ten people
together.
There’s no sacrifice in it, there’s no
sacrifice.
On the contrary if you live together as I’ve
told you, you save money, your children are
looked after; if somebody’s pregnant she’s
looked after, there’s somebody to look after
you.
But what is the gain of having another house,
I don’t understand.
You have to work much harder, pay much more,
but a kind of a ego satisfaction is there.
And then they develop problems, I have seen:
we’ve got cancer, we’ve got heart attacks,
we’ve got this, “my son has run away”,
that has happened, that has happened.
All this arbitrary behavior, and I am supposed
to be sort of responsible for everything.
It’s a complete liability, once somebody
comes to Sahaja Yoga, then he is a liability
on us.
But he has no responsibilities and he has
no duties – only I have.
That’s not proper.
So now I have to tell you today very frankly
that you all have to live together, at least
eight to ten people in a place.
And don’t fight, and don’t create groups.
Group-making is a very wrong thing.
Before making any group you write to Me.
You are all welcome to write to Me, and I’ll
attend to that letter if it is worth attending,
because I know everything through vibrations.
Don’t talk against each other.
It’s a murmuring souls, and Christ has said
such people will go to hell.
It’s not hell outside, I tell you, it will
be the hell here.
It’s hell here.
I have seen people suffering.
I have been so frightened, you have no idea.
Don’t play about with Sahaja Yoga at all.
I’m just warning you, it’s a very serious
thing.
People have got heart attacks, have got accidents,
have got cancers, all kinds of things, and
really I am quite frightened that you people
don’t realize that there is another force
working it out.
Don’t take arbitrary decisions.
You are very safe in Sahaja Yoga.
Stay in Sahaja Yoga, grow in Sahaja Yog, enjoy
in Sahaja Yog.
Everything is there available for you.
And you don’t have to do anything else except
that keep together: it’s a collective happening.
It’s a collective.
If you are not in the collective, the Divine
is not interested in you at all – you are
out of it.
Only the collective gets the power, only the
collective is magnetic.
Single person who lives away from collective
all the time, is something wrong with that
person.
If you cannot be collective, there’s something
wrong.
Such a person should sit down and find out
what’s wrong with that person, must get
it corrected, absolutely corrected.
And see to it that you are all right; because
this is for your benevolence.
You want to lead a happy, healthy, good life,
then be sensible, have some wisdom about it.
And so some people who have been negative
are still negative, and just thinking on the
same lines.
So it’s high time all of you have to work
it out sensibly, and understanding.
There are leaders because I have to have communication,
that’s all.
And they will communicate to Me about you
people.
If there are problems, they will try to solve
you.
If they cannot solve it, they’ll write to
Me and I’ll have to see to it.
There’s not going to be any regimentation
in Sahaja Yoga at all; it is a thing of love.
But you must have love for yourself.
I mean, you should be self-disciplined.
Now imagine how I must have felt: I have come
here, I’ve worked so hard for so many times
I have been here, and when I come here what
I find, everything is broken down.
It’s so sad – I’ve worked so hard.
But next time I am going to see you all settled
down in proper ashrams, in different place.
Not for your own comfort you should think,
but if you have an ashram you put a center
there.
Every place you can have a center.
In Bombay, I don’t know, we have eighteen
or twenty-one centers, in Bombay.
That’s how it increases, and improves it.
You have centers everywhere, so it’s available
to people all the time.
You would talk about it, meet every day, evening
time you all can meet, talk to each other;
and you have one day in a week somewhere,
in a school or something, big place where
you all meet.
The more you meet, the more there is rapport,
the more there is collectivity, the more there
are blessings for each one of you, and for
all of you.
It absolutely simultaneously works out; whilst
when there is no collectivity – no.
When there is collectivity, everything works
out.
Everything is available to you.
So don’t try to break the collectivity by
forming any groups or anything – nothing
of the kind.
If you find anything wrong you have to write
to Me.
But it’s everybody’s responsibility is
to sustain the collectivity, to support it,
to help it.
If you find that somebody is talking about
somebody else, then you say, “No, no, he
was talking very good about you.
Why are you talking ill about that person?”
This is what, this is what Christ has said,
that these are peacemakers.
But somebody says something about someone
– oh, then you go into, “Ho, ho, ho, that
one is like this,” then another one.
We are not like common people, we are not
ordinary people, we are saints.
We are to respect each other, to love each
other, to understand and enjoy each other.
What will the children say tomorrow?
So nobody should get away with this idea that
we can have separate houses, live separately
and we are all right.
Better take out all My photographs from them;
they have no business.
At least eight persons should be there in
one household, at least, minimum.
Eight to ten people is a good idea.
There’s no safety, there’s no progress,
there’s nothing in such houses where they
live alone very nicely.
Morning till evening they are cooking, cleaning,
sweeping, swabbing, looking after the car,
locking the house – what else are they doing?
It’s so boring to be alone, it’s extremely
boring.
Now I have already told you very clearly that
we have to live together.
And let the children know each other, know
everyone, they should know about their friendship.
And you know, it is so nice the way they love
each other and the way they talk to each other,
and about their aunties and uncles they talk
so sweetly.
So many aunties and uncles to have is something
so remarkable; to have so many nephews and
nieces all over.
And unless and until you have that kind of
a feeling, it won’t work out.
Then if somebody finds something wrong with
your child and tells you, don’t get angry
for that – thank him.
Try to improve your child.
The improvement of your child is for the benevolence
of the child.
Not to feel bad: “this is my child.”
This “my” business has to go a little
bit; then I will come.
If there is “my house”, “my children”,
“my car”, “my” this, this has to go
away.
Let us see how we start diverting our energies
to a collective beauty, collective love, collective
understanding.
And if it is not, there’s something wrong
with you, take it from Me, something wrong.
So either you are right-sided or left-sided:
find out and just get yourself cleared out.
Treat it out yourself, and you will understand
that there was something wrong with you, nothing
wrong with Sahaja Yoga.
All such ideas are going to completely blast
Sahaja Yoga and finish it off.
They are selfish, self-oriented, absolutely
out-of-date ideas for Sahaja Yoga.
You can have one room each other, for each
one of them and you can stay together, and
you can have somebody as a leader, whomsoever
you want.
If you want we can do rotation of leaders
later on if you like that, can be done also.
But still I would say that unless and until
there is something wrong with the leader,
it’s not proper to remove such a leader.
But whatever you suggest, I don’t mind,
but we have to have someone who is looking
after you, and informing Me about it.
But the wife of the leader is never a leader,
understand that, it’s only the leader is
the leader.
Whether it’s the husband or a wife of a
leader is not a leader, and she should never
behave like that.
She has to be very motherly, kindly, and all
the time looking after all the people in a
more gentler way than the husband himself.
That’s the sign of a good wife of a leader.
We have some, we have such women, and wherever
there have been good ashrams, Sahaja Yoga
has prospered.
It has gone up to the governments, it has
gone up to the intellectuals, it has gone
up to such areas where we would never expect
it, anywhere there has been.
And most of the people now are in the ashrams,
in the whole world.
I hope you all understand the importance of
it.
Anything goes wrong with anyone here, immediately
the telephone comes, that something has gone
wrong with such and such person is sick.
Then I can tell you what is to be done, how
to get that person cured.
But supposing you are in some other house
…. It happened like this, one fellow was
like that and he met with an accident.
Met with an accident, nobody knew.
He was lying in the hospital – when he came
to his consciousness he called for somebody,
then they told Me.
It’s like one family, it’s like one body.
If something hurts here, every – the whole
body knows.
You must know how many there are with us.
You feel so strong and happy.
But first of all you must develop that rapport,
you must develop that love, must develop that
personality.
Now those who are left-sided, I’ve already
told them what treatment they have to take,
and take it seriously.
Left-sidedness should not be allowed to grow
at all – I tell you, it’s very dangerous.
All these horrible diseases that you have
heard of, all of them, one and all – say
epilepsy, mental derangements, you can say
cancer, all psychosomatic, this myelitis,
then there are other diseases like AIDS, all
that – attack only left-sided people.
Anybody who has left side, immediately try
to get rid of that left side.
The right side shows so everybody knows, and
you can throw away such a person, or you can
correct it.
But the left side be very careful, don’t
play about with the left side.
Left side is very dangerous.
To avoid that, don’t mix up with people
who are mentally deranged, don’t go to the
hospitals where such people live, don’t
try to cure people who are left-sided – they
can be all cured on My photograph.
And if somebody starts telling too much about
their woes and all that, just shut your ears.
All this left side comes from a kind of a
self-indulgence, in the sense that you start
thinking you are so miserable, you are so
unhappy, you are no good, and all that.
So the right-sided are over-confident, the
left-sided are diffident.
But they’re, because they’re diffident,
you see, all kinds of viruses can attack.
And these viruses are the thing which bring
forth diseases which cannot be cured.
So be careful on that point.
The right-sided people trouble others.
The left-sided trouble themselves, and the
right-sided trouble others.
They try to show off, they want to – just
think they’re too much.
First sign of a right-sided is that he starts
suddenly shouting, or giving lectures also,
that’s another one.
Thirdly, he tries to show off that he’s
a very big, great Sahaja yogi.
There’s nobody great in Sahaja Yoga, everybody
is just the same.
Just like all fingers are the same, every
cell is the same, everybody is the same.
So nobody higher and lower, there’s no hierarchy
in Sahaja Yoga.
Everybody must understand that we are all
one, part and parcel of one body, and we don’t
have to consider ourself higher or lower.
So there are so many ways of expression of
these boastful, right-sided people.
And we can pull their legs – all right,
allowed!
If somebody boasts too much you just pull
their legs, that’s allowed.
That’s how in India nobody can have ego,
because from very childhood if somebody tries
to show off, pull their legs.
If somebody talks loudly, pull their legs.
If somebody laughs loudly, pull their legs.
I mean, anything somebody tries to do, overdo,
just pull their legs.
So it doesn’t behoove for a Sahaja yogi
to be like that.
Sahaja yogi has to be very dignified; otherwise
why will people come to Sahaja Yoga, if we
are just like them?
We have to be exceptional, isn’t it?
And that’s what is what I call dignified,
loving, affectionate, kind, sweet – that’s
what is the beauty.
So anybody who shouts, screams, gets angry,
full of anger, this thing, bring one pin and
just prick it – allowed!
And if he says anything, it’s to prick your
ego.
Show the pins, you see, like this.
He’ll understand, “All right, this is
what I have.”
So when you make a fun of a person who is
egoist he may not like it; but you show him
a pin, he’ll understand, “Oh God, I have
got it!”
They are quite aware of their ego, they don’t
want to have it.
There was a gentleman from Delhi, his son
wrote to Me saying that “My father says
that he’s not allowed to speak at all, and
he’s feeling very sad about it.”
So in the lecture I said that nobody is allowed
to speak.
After My tape, meditate, stay in that meditative
mood, and go home.
Not that just after meditation, “Oh, what
cake I am going to have?” – all rush to
the kitchen.
So it’s surprising, even Indians are surprised
at it.
India, people don’t get so much to eat,
but they are not hankering so much after food.
Here the first attention is in the kitchen,
all the time they are in the kitchen.
How many times you take your tea is important.
You should count how many times you are in
the kitchen.
I mean, you are still little babies, I tell
you, in that respect.
I don’t think I have ever opened a fridge
to take out even water for Myself – I mean,
since I remember My life, never.
So this hankering after food is also another
funny thing that is.
After meditation people just get up and go
to eat.
You must sit down, meditate.
Now after meditation if people start giving
speeches, then the people are anxious to go
to the kitchen, here’s somebody giving lectures,
so big problem starts between the two.
They don’t like it, because they think,
“Oh, there’s a cake there, there’s something
biryani kept, and here it is this gentleman
is trying to give us a lecture.”
No one likes it.
But it should be something very different,
that we are in meditative mood, how can we
come out of it?
So I’d better tell you a story of Janaka,
which is very important.
He was the one, in the beginning at the time
of Shri Rama, He was the father-in-law of
Shri Rama, His name was Raja Janaka.
And He was a king.
So all the saints used to come and bow to
Him.
And He was a king, He used to live like a
king.
So one fellow, Nachiketa asked his guru, he
said, “What is this, you bow to this Raja?
He has got all the wealth, He has got everything,
wears all the ornaments, He has all pomp and
show.
Why should you, a saint like you, go and bow
to Him?”
He said “He’s videhi.
He’s so detached, He’s videhi.
He doesn’t exist in His body.”
He couldn’t understand.
He said, “All right, I’ll go and see Him.”
So he went and told Him that “I want to
become self-realized, as You are.”
He said, “You ask Me everything; I can give
you, but no self-realization.”
“All right, we’ll see about it,” he
said.
So one day they were having a bath.
He said, “Let’s go to the river, we’ll
have our bath.”
So He took this boy, they were sitting and
having the bath, when some people came and
told that “Your palace is burning, and everybody
is running away.”
So He was still in meditative mood, He wouldn’t
listen.
Then they came back again, shouted, “See
now, Your wife and children all are, have
come out of it and they are all running away,
because the whole thing is getting burned.”
Still He was in meditative mood, least bothered.
Then they said, “Now the fire is coming
this side, and what are You doing?”
So Nachiketa got up and he caught hold of
his clothes.
He thought, “I should wear my clothes at
least, they’ll be burnt.”
He was still meditating.
Then Nachiketa realized that He is videhi.
That’s why Sitaji is called as Vaidehi,
because She is the daughter of a videhi.
And that’s what we have to be.
“Where is our attention?” we should say.
You are meditating, take it deep down into
yourself.
That’s a meditative mood.
Keep yourself there.
And after meditation you just get up silently,
sit for a while.
I think best thing will be to have your food
first and then meditate, if that is so, if
you think that is proper.
But I think if you have to get now into that
new triggering, as I told you, into that new
jumping that we have to do in Sahaja Yoga:
if you have to catch that train, then you
hurry up.
You have to change all these ideas.
You have had many houses, you have had many
wives and many children in your previous life.
You never had your realization – now you
have got it.
So now just every individual, every one of
you should not think of others, think of yourself,
“I have to do it, I have to get it, I have
to work it out.”
This is what you have to do.
“Why should I miss it?”
This is a chance of many lives, the chance
of many lives.
And that’s how you can jump over, and work
it out.
We had lots of people in Australia, and if
they had worried about themselves as to “what
I have done for Sahaja Yoga.”
So in the morning you just decide, what I
am going to do for Sahaja Yog and myself;
in the evening, what have I done for myself,
and what have I done for Sahaja Yoga?
“Myself” doesn’t mean selfishness, but
“for my ascent.”
Every day.
You start a diary to write it down.
You face yourself.
No excuses, nothing.
If you are left behind, what we can do?
We can’t help it.
And that is how you’ll find all kinds of
blessings will come to you.
You’ll be able to save money, you’ll be
able to save time, you’ll get good jobs.
All your problems can be solved if you really
surrender yourself to that Paramachaitanya.
Everything can be done.
But as long as you have this narrow-mindedness
and these narrow ideas about yourself, till
then it won’t work out.
This drop has to become one with the ocean,
then ocean takes over.
And I am sure that can work out.
And you are basically a very good point here,
because you are born on the land of Shri Ganesha.
Basically it’s such an advantage for you,
much more than Russians have.
But Russians, I don’t know how, they have
shot up so well.
It’s an Agnya, it’s a right Agnya where
they have denied Christ, they have denied
all religions, everything, and still they’re
prospering.
So you are very well placed.
And innocence can never be lost, can never
be lost, whatever you may try.
Of course, there could be clouds, but they
get just into nothing, they just disappear.
If you just try to clean off your innocence
and simplicity.
And don’t think too much, “We should do
like this, we should organize like this, we
should have this thing” – nothing of the
kind.
Wherever you are, why to think?
I never think, “Where I will sit?
What will be My chair?
How will I sleep?
How will I go there?”
Nothing.
Just exist.
Everything works out for good, you should
know.
Now, if you redden too much on your faces,
you should know you have left Vishuddhis.
So first of all know that you are forgiven
for everything.
Whatever you have done you are forgiven, just
remember.
You are forgiven completely, absolutely hundred
percent.
There’s nothing to feel guilty about, nothing
to feel guilty.
And you are loved, you’re looked after,
you’re cared for.
Paramchaitanya cares, it’s a caring, caring
government, I should say.
It cares for you, looks after you, it manages
so many things.
Unbelievable, it is.
It manages, it works out.
You must have heard about the story about
Cairns, what miracle has taken place, have
you heard?
No?
So … Kay.
Where is Kay?
I was – Kay, can you tell them?
Please come here.
Just come.
It’s too much!
[Kay: It was a great blessing for Shri Mataji
to come to Cairns for us, and we had the opportunity
of taking Shri Mataji out to the Great Barrier
Reef.]
Just we decided spontaneously.
[Kay: Very spontaneously!
We delayed Her flight and kept Her from the
Brisbane people for a few hours, just to keep
Her a little more time with us; but we thought
it was important that She put Her attention
on the reef, because there was a lot of problems
happening with this great natural phenomena
off the coast of Cairns.
And we took a fast boat out to the reef, and
Shri Mataji graciously agreed to go down into
a semi-submersible and had a look at the reef.
And just looking at it, all the fish came
around.
It was just a miracle to be in the reef with
Her, while She was looking at all this wonderful
natural phenomena.
But within the next day the attention of the
people who had been researching the reef and
been worried about the Crown-of-Thorns starfish
eating the reef, and all the pollution, suddenly
they started to realize the reef was regenerating.
And all the Crown-of-Thorns starfish were
dying and they didn’t know why, they didn’t
know where they’d come from, and now they
don’t know where they’ve gone!]
They have written, it’s a mystery!
[Kay: And they said it’s a mystery.
But just a glance from our Mother has just
made everything right.
Jai Shri Mataji!]
But you are not a coral reef, you see, you
are not that; because you see, I cannot, I
cannot transform you that way.
You have to use your will power.
They are all animals, you see, and animals
are under the control of God, that’s why
they are called as “pashu”.
This “pash” means all the bandhan.
Under the bandhan of God: is whatever God
wants can do with them, with the, all the
plants, of animals, everyone.
But with human beings you can’t do everything.
And also to understand human beings is another
problem.
I don’t know how suddenly they become so
funny.
They are all right, going straight, and suddenly
you don’t know what happens to them.
So it’s a thing that God has created, and
then adding to that, man has created himself
a little bit more – which is quite a difficult
thing to understand.
So you better understand yourself, why you
do like that; and you have to with your free
will accept that “I have to do it.”
It is self disciplining and you’ll work
it out, and I’m sure one day you will show
that in Australia we have really achieved
a great height.
Children are wonderful here, no doubt.
Then another thing is that we have started
a school in India, with the idea that the
amount you pay only for their food and clothes
per month, that much is about to be charged
for them.
And they’ll have the best education of a
private school, with all other facilities
like horse-riding, swimming and every sort
of thing.
Music, dancing, everything can be taught to
them.
And the amount will be the same, practically
as much as you’ll be spending on one child
per month here, only for keeping them in the
house.
So it would be like going to a general school.
Of course, the transport and everything we’ll
look after.
Now for this we have – as it is, you have
paid some money, and others have also paid
– and we have made a good arrangement now.
The school has started.
With this kind of a school, the parents can
go and see their children for a month, two
months, whichever way you like, and stay there
with them.
Or if you want you can take them out to Himalayas,
whichever way you want to do.
But till the age of sixteen years I am thinking
the children should not be exposed to this
funny type of a country where they are just
trying to destroy them, because we have tried
that also.
When the children go back to parents, they
come back with great problems, so it’s difficult.
So now to think “they are my children”
– if you really think they are your children,
for their benevolence you must sacrifice.
Maybe a little money you might have to sacrifice,
but more this feeling that “they are my
children.”
They’re actually Mine.
And this will really help you a lot.
You will be free here to do what you like,
you have more time for meditation, spreading
Sahaja Yoga – because we are now on sort
of a warpath.
And we have to make these children so good
that wherever they go they will not take to
drugs, they will not take to bad things.
On the contrary, they’ll be very great Sahaja
yogis.
Maybe we might start a university later.
But just up to sixteen years, it’s guaranteed.
So now we have started for only, I think,
seven-year-old children a school now near
Himalaya; and also now we are going to bring
it down.
But now after three years or so we’ll be
starting school for all classes.
For all classes we’ll be starting in a big
way, and we’ll be having best teachers and
best timings, and we’ll look after them.
Only thing is that if the Cambridge University
accepts then we’ll have the Cambridge University
affiliation, because Indian standards are
too high, very high.
They have to work really very hard for that.
I would prefer Cambridge better.
So they might agree to do that for us.
That’s how our children can achieve a better
understanding of things, and they have more
time for other things to do.
So, so many things we are going to combine
there.
Basic education of Gandhiji I am going to
introduce into that, where children know so
much about the trees, about the plants, about
animals, about fishes, about the surroundings
in which they live, about the Mother Earth,
about ecological problems and things like
that.
And we have to create really great leaders
out of them.
So it is for you to decide now the children
that you want to send there.
You can have children up to seven years here,
or six years here for your primary classes,
but not for your high schools.
But primary classes also we have.
If you want to send your children for primary
classes we have that also, that we can look
after those children who are for primary classes.
And there will be leave for the children for
two months or three months, I think, for which
you can come there, or you can take them anywhere
you feel like.
But I would not advise you to bring them back
here because it’s too much of an exposure,
and you know what’s happening to your children.
They’ll have to learn how to respect parents,
respect everything; and to get the intrinsic
value of everything properly evaluated in
their minds, so that they do not become stupid.
I’m sure this will work out very well.
I have seen some children in Rome: they have
become so sensible, so developed, so beautiful.
So money-wise also we might have to cut down
little expenses of yours, doesn’t matter;
for your children you have to do something.
That’s the minimum they have worked it out.
They said that per month it will be about
three hundred dollars for a child, inclusive
of clothes, food, transport, everything, books,
everything.
You don’t have to worry for their expenses
at all.
You could give them some other clothes, but
they’ll have all their uniforms done by
them, books, shoes, everything will be done
in that amount, and education of every kind.
All kinds of arts, crafts, depending on the
aptitude of the child.
And you’ll see, they will be something very
unique children.
So think it over.
And in that there is a lot of work entailed,
and some people are working it out.
I’ll be getting some people from here also.
And the whole process will be under My control,
so you don’t have to worry.
So now, I hope I’ll be coming next year
again.
But for next year – I mean of course, not
this year – but next year we have decided
that it would be better to come here in the
month of April or May; because May is a better
month here than March, and April is quite
hot.
So what do you say, April or May?
May.
May, all right.
But May, I can only come of fifth of May.
After, I said, fifth of May, because we’ll
have one Sahasrara Day there and one here.
And we can work it out that way to come by
May, so we can have one month of May spent
here.
I would like to spend more time.
But you must not have any more groups, quarrels,
fighting, problems with husband and wife.
I mean sometimes I feel, why did I marry them
to create these problems?
They were all right without marriages!
So all these petty things should not be there.
You should all be big, great people.
I would like to come and see you here in your
ashrams and things; I would like to know what
you have been doing, what creative work you
have been doing.
It’s beautiful things you can do.
All right?
So with that hope, tomorrow we’ll have this
Birthday Puja.
And everybody is quite jealous of you that
I’m having My birthday here!
I love you Australians very much, and you
have to also love yourself and have proper
value about yourself.
Don’t fritter away your lives, don’t waste
them on nonsensical things, that’s very
precious.
If you were not precious, you would not have
come to Sahaja Yoga, remember that.
You would have been by now in some pub!
All right.
Now, so few things we have here.
Now, can you read out the lists …? [Hindi]
Come along.
This ….
You see, they told Me not to bring anything,
and because there is Customs, I think that
the Customs torture My life for nothing at
all.
There are Customs, this thing, that thing.
So I’m thankful to Mr Gupta that he could
manage to bring some things for you.
And I could only buy something in the duty-free
shop for you.
[Hindi]
So first of all there’s a present for [Hindi]
… One for Stephen.
These fountain pens are given to the leaders
so that they should write a letter to Me!
Brian, Mr Brian.
Now, others .… Cairns …. It’s all right,
I don’t read it.
It’s all right … Melbourne … It’s
all right.
So this is Perth.
[Hindi] Brisbane.
Brisbane is not here.
We’ll keep it for Brisbane.What else?
Canberra is not here?
All right, keep it.
Who else?
Adelaide.
For Adelaide, we should try still.
I think it will work out now, things are better.
Things are much better.
It will work out.
[Yogi: We have given You fifty-four macadamia
nut trees, for Your house in Prathisthan … for
You to take back to India.]
With Me?
[Yogi: Yes, from the Adelaide collective,
for Your birthday.]
Ah, I don’t think I can.
But what you can do is to send them with these
people when they come.
They can be kept here waiting?
There’s somewhere here, and they can bring
it when they come for the Ganapatipule, all
right?
For the tour.
All right?
May God bless you.
Thank you.
All right.
[Hindi]
So we start giving saris to ladies who looked
after Me ... Canberra.
So she’s not come as yet?
All right.
Lyn, is she here?
Lyn from Brisbane … Cheryl?
… Sandya Sapate … Jo?
Jo from Perth … Kay.
Kay from Canberra.
Now we have shirts for the boys, of leaders
of all the – what do you call it? – ashrams;
so you read the name.
And now you all
should try it, whichever fits you, and I don’t
know!
First do it, first you people do it, all right.
Come along, Cairns, come along.
Select.
Whichever fits you.
These are all loose ones, so they’ll fit
anyone … Good … All right, take any one.
Looks nice – beautiful!
All right ….
With embroidery!
... May God bless you.
Take whichever you like.
That’s a good one!
… Of course, Burwood.
What about the New Zealand people?
Auckland ... All right.
That’s fine ... All right, take it up …
Oh, blue?
You like green … So Melbourne has no, because
– Melbourne has no ashram so far.
Yes.
So they have to have ashram.
This is a special gift for Mr Stephen from
the leader of Hariyana, Mr Gupta, who has
been so kind to bring all these things through
your Customs.
So now we should disperse, I think, and tomorrow
is there’s puja.
If we want to start it’s about eleven o’clock,
but try to be there, make preparations, I’ll
be ready here to come.
I’ll be ready, very ready to come there,
but the problem is sometimes it’s not ready.
So we have told everybody eleven o’clock
we are starting the puja.
But let’s see how you do it, because the
preparation takes so much time.
All right?
May God bless.
I gave it today because tomorrow is My birthday;
I’m not supposed to give any presents on
My birthday!
(So finish it off now?)
Good night, everybody.
Sleep early!
Hello, hello, how are you?
[Child: My father’s here.]
Which one?
… Deep, deep, deep sleep, eh?
What’s your name?
[Shridhara.]
Shridhara, eh?
And you are really Shridhara!
He’s very good at acting!
All these children can be really trained up
so well, as they are born-realized.
So you will come to India to study?
To ride horses?
…. Yes, yes.
You don’t have to wear in India, there is
no need, but we can get you some hats also
… They’ll fit you all right.
They make hats for every size of head!
All right.
May God bless you.