Tad Nishkala
by Shrī Ādi Shaṅkarāchārya
There’s a beautiful saying of Adi
Shankaracharya, Tad Nishkala,
about Brahma Tattwa. I’m that
Brahma.
On that. If you have? Let Me see.
That’s the best way to understand
what you are.
Just bring it. It’s very famous.
Have you got it?
Yogi: Dakshina Murti?
Shri Mataji: No, not that, another one.
Just bring it. Have you got the book?
Yogi: Can you bring the book to Shri Mataji?
This is the one.
Nirvana Shatakam. This one is the one.
You just read it in English language.
I don't need it.
When you have got your Nirvana,
what happens to you – it says that.
Tad Nishkala is also known
as the Atma or Nirvana Shatakam –
six verses on the theme of spiritual
liberation.
Mano’buddhi ahaṅkār
chittāni n’āham
Na cha shrotra jihve
na cha ghrāna netre
Na cha vyoma bhūmir
na tejo na vāyuhu
Chid’ānanda rūpah
Shiv’oham Shiv’oham (x 2)
Na cha prāna saoṅdñyao
na vai pancha-vāyur
Na vā sapta-dhātur
na vā pancha-koshah
Na vāk pāni-pādau
na ch’opasthapāyū
Chid’ānanda rūpah
Shiv’oham Shiv’oham (x 2)
Na me dvesha-rāgau
na me lobha-mohau
Mado n’aeva me n’aeva
mātsarya-bhāvah
Na dharmo na ch’ārtho
na kāmo na mokshah
Chid’ānanda rūpah
Shiv’oham Shiv’oham (x 2)
Na punyam na pāpam
na saukhyam na duhkham
Na mantro na tīrtham
na vedā na yadñyāhā
Aham bhojanam n’aeva
bhojyam na bhoktā
Chid’ānanda rūpah
Shiv’oham Shiv’oham (x 2)
Na me mṛutyu shaṅkā
na me jāti bhedah
Pitā n’aeva me n’aeva
mātā, na janma
Na bandhur na mitram
gurūr n’aeva shishyah
Chid’ānanda rūpah
Shiv’oham Shiv’oham (x 2)
Aham nirvikalpo
nirākāra rūpo
Vibhur-vyāpya sarvatra
sarv’endriyāni
Sadā me samatvam
na muktir na bandhah
Chid’ānanda rūpah
Shiv’oham Shiv’oham (x 2)
That’s what you are. You are eternal
bliss and awareness.
The consciousness, the pure consciousness.
I think, this must be – everybody must
remember by heart.
And must say in all the ashrams.
That’s a very good way of remembering
what you are.
May God bless you.