To see so many Sahaja Yogis assembled here, I’m
sure the devil must have run away long time
back. And the caravan must have left but I
hope we are aware of it and we forget about
our fears of our catches, of our past, of
all the nonsense we have done so far. Suddenly
in My presence, I think, people get into a
sense of guilt. I’m here to soothe you,
to cleanse you, to make you beautiful and
not to feel guilty.
Actually when we start
looking at ourselves the first thing you notice
is that there’s a block on the Agnya, but
this block in the Agnya is the worst thing
that can happen to us because it is the door
of the Kundalini. She reaches up to Vishuddhi
all right, and then She has to move forward,
this Agnya stops it. That’s why we have
left Vishuddhi, we have all
the Vishuddhi problems. The flow cannot take
place. Also this is one of the reasons we
feel guilty because of left Vishuddhi. It’s
a symptom of a disease.
Today we are going to worship Shri Krishna.
So we have to understand first of all that
we’re Sahaja Yogis. We’re not ordinary
people or we’re not people who have not
known the truth; we have known the truth.
We have to be completely aware of it. That’s
one truth if you establish, you have established
yourself quite a lot.
Now the ordinary people as you have seen on
Oxford St., you see, they wear Indian dresses
funnily tied, they don’t know how to tie
it up, dhotis and saris and they shake their
heads and buy some of these, what we call
them, shindis or bodhis or I don’t know
what you call, tails, pigtails, and attach
them with some glue and they start dancing.
When they dance, their pigtail falls off,
and the saris and the dhotis, everything start
opening out. That’s a very funny, ridiculous
scene. One side you see the punks and another
side you see this nonsense, in the name of
Shri Krishna, that’s even worse. Punks do
not do it in the name of, I don’t know if
they do it in the name of King Solomon. But
they do it in somebody’s name, these people
that is so great as Shri Krishna. On the contrary,
Shri Krishna’s hair are described in all
the books and in all the poetry that poets
could sing about. He was never shaven-headed.
It is impossible to understand how these people
got the idea that you must shave your head.
So the Shri Krishna’s aspect of Yogeshwara
has been so misunderstood. It’s absolutely
misunderstood because we cannot understand
that the truth is covered with maya, always.
And you should keep maya on one side and go
to the truth. Instead of that, we get lost
in the maya, like very simple example, as
it is, that He is a Yogeshwara; so these people
have idea of a yogi, that He should be shaven,
He should wear that dhoti, dirty one, and
must put on a pigtail. Another concept, maya
is a concept. And when you start living on
those concepts of your own, you may gather
it up with something else, you may think that
Christ was a person who was a sanyasi, who
used to wear another kind of a robe and He
had a beard and He had hair like this.
All those ideas, “So if we become like this,
we’d be very great yogis.” These are all
our concepts about someone whom we have never
seen, whom we have never known. And because
we live with those concepts, we get limited.
It’s very difficult for these people to
break through because maya can only be broken
through realization. That’s why first thing
in Sahaja Yoga is realization. Take your realization.
You are a drunkard, all right, get your realization.
You are a drug addict, get your realization.
You are a bad man, get your realization. Anyone,
get your realization first; put the light
first into a person. Let him see for himself.
So all this identification with different
concepts is responsible for giving us a very
mayami or illusive personality. We live in
an illusive personality, live with it, enjoy
it and we think we are perfectly all right.
Now if you are aware you are Sahaja Yogis
and you have come here for Shri Krishna Puja,
what is the preparation we have to do. We’re
Sahaja Yogis, we know about Kundalini, we
know about Vishuddhis, we know about Shri
Krishna. All right, how are we going to prepare
ourselves for the puja of Shri Krishna?
First of all, He tried to break all the concepts.
First the concept He broke was that you have
to be like a ascetic to look. He broke this
concept; He lived like the king. In His childhood
He used to go and play with the cows. And
there He would use a peacock’s feather to
decorate Himself, and He would listen to beautiful
music of the river Yamuna and reproduce it.
He was leelala, He was the one who created
all kinds of mirth. What is mirth in French?
They don’t have mirth, I believe. It’s
not fun, it’s more than… , it’s mirth.
Mirth is sweeter than fun, all right, sweet
fun. What a word! Sweet fun! This is mirth,
now what is happening to you is mirth. I’m
creating mirth in which you feel tickled,
you know. Mirth is something where you feel
tickled.
So He tried to create mirth, never seriousness
but He was not frivolous. He was Yogeshwara.
He was not frivolous, so this difference between
frivolity and mirth is to be understood only
through Him because He’s also discretion.
Mirth is joy-giving, frivolity is destructive.
Anything frivolous if you do…
So we have to be in a state of mirth, so no
question of feeling guilty comes in, you’re
not prisoners are we? We’re prisoners of
our own concepts and our own ideas and our
own degradation. We degrade ourselves, God
does not. So we should be in the state of
complete mirth and enjoyment. Now it has rained,
all right. That’s a very good thing to happen
today. Yesterday I was listening to the program,
I was just smiling, because I knew it would
not work out that way.
And in India, on this day, when they celebrate
in the morning, children of the village or
children of the particular areas gather together.
And for them the house-holders tie a little
pitcher, which we call as a matka, and in
that there is money, anything valuable they
want to give to the children, sweets, everything
put inside, and is tied up in the air. Normally
it rains, if it doesn’t rain then they pour
water on the children to make them feel it’s
raining. Rain is very much connected with
Shri Krishna. So the children come and they
go in a way that the taller boys are first,
then smaller, then smaller like a pyramid
they go up till at the end there’s one boy
who’s sort of representing Shri Krishna
and then he breaks that. And from there everything
falls down and flowers, everything on them,
they take the money, they take all those things
and start enjoying. Then they go to another
place, the whole day they are moving in the
city like that and every good house-holder
ties that matka for these children, for them
to come and enjoy themselves. That’s in
the real sense, is the Krishna Astami in Gokul
where He lived as a child.
Now why is He so much connected with rain?
Once all His friends and He were looking after
the cows and Indra felt that He is very powerful,
somehow, I don’t know, He gets into jealousies
sometimes. And He sent rain to test His patience,
His leela, His play, His mirth. It rained
and rained and rained and they did not know
what to do. So there was a mountain called
Govardhan. Shri Krishna lifted it with His
stick or His finger and just put it up on
top of His finger, like that. That’s why
He is called as Govardhan Dhari. And the whole
mountain was on top and all the children joined
Him and now the cows and He asked the children,
“You also put your sticks up to help.”
And they all put their sticks and standing
very sweetly holding the Govardhan. That is
one of His names, Govardhan Dhari.
So the rain had to come and the cows with
their bells have to remind us. Imagine the
lake has a name which is a black; Krishna
means black, Krishna word itself means black.
How Sahaj the whole thing has worked out.
Can you see the coincidences are so Sahaj
but are so . And here we are sitting, it’s
raining, nicely enjoying everything. But on
the contrary when we start not enjoying we
play into, either into our ego or superego.
Supposing we are starved people, tortured
people, then we start making others like ourselves.
We like to make them suffer and torture them.
That’s why I always say, “Poverty is leprosy.”
Anybody who is in poverty can develop horrible
things within themselves. It is never to be
sided with, not to be sympathized but to be
completely eradicated.
Another side is the ego where we try to dominate
others and enjoy that. There’s no joy, there’s
no joy in dominating others and saying things
to others. I was sorry to hear yesterday that
there are some girls who are married, some
Indian girls who are married and their husbands
are not respecting them and troubling them.
It hurt Me very much. That shows they’re
so low level people, very low level. Such
a mediocracy, such useless people. They should
have never come to Sahaja Yoga and deceived
us like this. They will go to hell direct,
I can tell you this.
Now there are some who are caught up with
their superego; they suffer from some sort
of a funny Sahaja Yoga schizophrenia. And
they don’t want to get rid or it. They just
don’t want to understand that they’re
not normal people, they have to be perfectly
all right. They make everyone miserable, jump
on to all the places where they should not
be. Like a person who has got, say, example,
tuberculosis, a disease which is contagious.
Must understand he has got tuberculosis, keep
out, don’t give it to others, at least.
But those who have got badhas will definitely
come, either they’ll give big lectures.
I start seeing them like big bhoots speaking,
or if not they have badhas then they will
come at a place where they should not be.
They’ll put their hands in the prasada,
they’ll be sitting in the puja in the front,
all kinds of things they’ll be doing, catching
people. And they enjoy it because they are
identified with the badhas. How will they
improve?
There’s one fellow who is a bhootish fellow,
we have had him for, I think, for at least
for a century I should say, and he’s giving
lectures to others, “You must clean the
shoes of all the Sahaja Yogis to get rid of
your ego.” So such a gross, depraved and
low level people are still in Sahaja Yoga.
So the enjoyment of Sahaja Yoga becomes less.
If you eat rice with stones in it, how will
you enjoy it? And that’s what it is.
We are here to enjoy the blessings of God,
to have the mirth but still we are living
with all joy-killing things that we have.
How are we going to get rid of those things.
So at least we do not become thorns in the
lives of others. So the so-called free will,
I’m happy Rustom has told you about it,
is nothing but your ego and superego because
you’re not in the center. In the center,
you have nothing but freedom, that’s all,
nothing but freedom; nothing like free will,
freedom, complete freedom. There’s nothing
like will or nothing like bhoots, nothing
like bondage, it’s entire avenue of freedom.
Then this freedom is the knowledge, this freedom
is the love, this freedom is the discretion.
Then you say God gives you freedom and others
freedom equally then you act which doesn’t
bound you nor anybody else because it is knowledge,
it is discretion.
Age does not matter, what age you are. I’ve
seen some also very old people singing beautifully
and enjoying Sahaja Yoga
and make Me enjoy also. Life is for us to
enjoy, nothing else. But because we’re not
free people, we cannot enjoy. There is no
bondage of
any evil thought
which keeps you down. It is so subtle but
penetrating into every that is gross, that
is Shri Krishna’s beautiful flute which
creates a picture of the nature. The description
, the whole thing becomes silent like a picture.
So this evening we’ll have the puja, we’ll
have
all the enjoyment of Shri Krishna’s blessings
upon us. There’s no end to
the stories of
Shri Krishna, all full of mirth and play and
innocence that kills rakshashas, devils. So
today I’ve talked to
you
about His childhood, and the puja I’ll tell
you about Gita.
May God bless you.