1984-0708 Public Program 2 at Ilford Town Hall. Ilford (England), To Know The Truth PP 2
Now, again today, I would like you to ask Me some questions.
There is going to be the fourth lecture, that they will announce.
I hope you will make it a point to come and complete the series of lectures we have been having.
Q1. [INAUDIBLE]
A1. It’s true. It has been told that you must have a Guru.
But it’s said that it has to be a Satguru. Anybody you see, mostly,
the gurus who are in the market today. You cannot be in the market,
and those who are in the market are actually, are nowhere near God.
They have to be Satguru, means he has to be a realized soul of a very high degree.
Now you better become your own Guru. And then you will know that you are a Satguru.
I am the Mother, I am not a Guru. And what is Mother’s desire is? You had a mother also.
Whatever I have, you better have it. That’s all.
So as you have come to Mother, now you don’t ask for any guru, you better become yourself a Guru. All right?
Q2. [INAUDIBLE]
A2. No. You see, you must know that the Kundalini awakening itself, breaking through and all that,
is a big happening. A key event of evolution, the epitome of it, as you know,
as an Indian you know how Sakshatkar is such a big thing. But to achieve that,
there must be a big machinery within us. Like you see the electrical bulb here, or a light here,
you know there is a history behind it, and it is a big mechanism and organization that has worked it out.
In the same way to achieve this there’s a big organization.
So, when you become realized, that will happen very soon to you.
Means you’ll feel the cool breeze coming out of the Brahmarandra, through your fontanel bone area.
But then to develop it, you have to understand, deeper, the mechanism.
Then the mantras are placed according to the deities of these seven chakras.
Now if the Kundalini is stopping, or is weak at a point, any one of these chakras,
then you have to say a particular mantra for that. Which will be told to you,
which you can learn very easily. And you will know also about all the mantras that are to be said.
Like, you see, many gurus I have seen give away one mantra. Like they say Ram.
How can that be? You see, there are seven chakras, and if you take Ram,
he’s on the right side of the heart chakra, means [UNKNOWN SANSKRIT WORD].
Now, if you are taking the name of Rama, why, why Rama’s name?
Ask a question to him, you must ask a question. Why Rama’s name, why not Krishna’s?
Why not Jesus? The reason is, if he’s a Satguru he’ll tell you,
that you have a problem with your right heart. But all of them here, those who are realization souls,
can tell you where is the problem. And you will also tell tomorrow.
Q3. [INAUDIBLE]
A3. No, it’s not. There are seven mantras actually. Basically you must know about seven mantras.
But gradually, you pick it up in no time, because immediately you know where the problem is,
and immediately you say the mantra. It’s not very difficult, it’s very simple.
It is woven in a pattern and it’s very simple to say those mantras.
But it works out so spontaneously, I mean, these are all people who are English
and Greeks and this and that, and they don’t know. Even, we can say mantras in English language now.
That’s an advancement I think. That all the deities can understand English language as well.
So you can say it in Sanskrit or in English, it’s all right, it works out.
And, once you know it, it’s so easy to say it, easy to understand. It’s not a problem at all.
But first of all you should get your realization, that’s first thing.
That is you should break through, you see, the seed must break. [INAUDIBLE], its primule must break.
Then the second thing is to see that it sustains itself above the ground.
Then it is to be maintained and developed until you become a tree.
But it’s very simple, it’s not difficult.
Q4. [INAUDIBLE]
A4. When you get your realization you start feeling the cool breeze coming out of your fontanel bone area
and you start feeling the cool breeze in your hands. Then you can ask a question,
is this the breeze of the Adi Shakti? Is this the Chaitanya Lahari of the Adi Shakti?
Is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost? The Holy Ghost is Adi Shakti actually.
Nobody has explained to them, they don’t know. I mean, they asked the Archbishop of Canterbury
about Holy Ghost, he said “I’m agnostic,” can you imagine?
Yes, he answered. I mean, if he’s agnostic this Robin Day asked him
“So what are you doing here?” So he said “I’m doing my job.” So Robin Day said
“Yes” because he also does the job. He understood it. [HINDI].
Now the problem is that when you start feeling the cool breeze in your hands,
you might find that after some time it goes away then comes. See, depends on.
Some people have a express train, as we call it.
But some of them have some bogeys, which go up and down. It doesn’t matter.
We should not frustrate on that point, it works out. One should not get unhappy about it.
Q5. [INAUDIBLE]
A5. Subconscious. Of course, I mean the same. I am the Self, I am the Spirit, yes.
Like, I’ll tell you, in the bible, Christ clearly said it, very clearly, we don’t read bible that way,
that’s why. That Nicodemus, you see, He told Nicodemus that you are to be born again.
So, Nicodemus said that does that mean that I should enter into the womb of my mother.
He said no, that is flesh, and the flesh is born out of, whatever is born out of flesh is flesh.
You are to be born of your Spirit. And whatever is born of the Spirit is the Spirit He said.
But how many people follow that? That’s the consciousness I’m talking of, the real Selfhood.
What we do, in the churches, or in our Indian, any one of the religions that we have.
We put the water on the head, now you are baptized, you are a Christian.
For a Hindu they put a string, now you are a Brahmin, without knowing a word about Brahma.
[INAUDIBLE]. So now, there is reality.
All these people didn’t tell us lies you see, never told us lies.
But the truth is always covered by the intellectuals, by the intelligent people on one side
and by the fanatics on the other side, and that’s why the problem comes in.
Q6. [INAUDIBLE]
A6. You see, because, what happens that intellectuals rationalize it.
They say whatever we see, we see the science, so we don’t want to believe.
Now recently there has been a controversy about Christ miracles, isn’t it.
There, lets take this thing very recently, there’s a controversy about Christ’s being born of a virgin.
He was born of a virgin, no doubt, but how can you convince an intellectual you see,
because He cannot be born of a virgin. But He was born.
All these miracles are absolute truth, no doubt.
So the problem is they want to see through science. Now science is analytical,
it is not does the synthesis. Science deals with the dead.
It deadens everything, it analyzes, and whatever you see you think it’s the truth, no,
but it’s just a part of the truth. Now why do they accept?
See now, big challenge, is intellectual. This was Mr Paul, who came in.
When I was a child I asked My father, who is this Paul?
My father, being a very great realized soul himself, he said, he was another mad man.
And this Paul had never seen Christ. What we call, he had a supraconscious,
a kind of a [CONDITION or POSITION?], he got blind and all that.
And then he became, he was a horrible man, he killed so many Jews,
he killed the young boys for [STEALING?] you know he did all sorts of things and then suddenly,
he becomes a big Christian. Because he saw some sort of a political thing in that.
So what does he say, he doesn’t talk of Christ as He was, he talks of a Christ
which was the church Christ, the Christ of the church.
Now, Christ of the church has nothing to do with real Christ, has nothing to do.
So now, because they have to accept, the churches have to accept Paul,
they cannot accept Christ. It’s a good idea. Either accept Christ, or accept,
this is what happens with intellectuals. Even in India it has happened.
I’ll tell you when, when Adi Shankaracharya, he wrote a book called Viviketurya.
It’s a great treatise. About Athvaida [BEST GUESS] he said that God is everything,
Brahma is everything. A beautiful treatise he wrote. So there was a fellow called Vishra,
Mandan Vishra [BEST GUESS], is a great learned man, another intellectual,
he came to argue with him. And he argued and argued and argued,
you see with argument where do you reach? You cannot by arguing give realization to somebody.
And he said, “Why don’t you take your realization?” But he argued,
he said “You defeat me.” He said “I don’t want to defeat you I want to give you realization,
why don’t you take your realization?” He would not take the realization.
So, the intellectual, you see, tortured his life. He was so fed up, Adi Shankaracharya.
The book he wrote was Saundarya Lahiri, if you ever happen to read it,
it’s nothing but the praise of the Mother, throughout. He said this is how [SANSKRIT]
not by yoga by Sankara [BEST GUESS] by discussion, it’s only through Mother’s grace
you are going to get realization [INAUDIBLE].
So the intellectuals, you see, want to derive a pleasure of an intellectual feat out of most if it.
It’s not the real that they are seeking. They read, a lot, achieve nothing.
I have known people who are very learned, who have written many books
and they are so horribly immoral within their private life you can’t believe it that they could be philosophers.
And you don’t understand, how can you be, why are you so hypocritical? But they are.
Because they are not realized souls. And an ordinary person, you find a realized soul.
Just uneducated. That’s why Kabira has said Pari Pari Pundita Mura Kabai,
by reading too much you learned have become stupid. But I don’t say all learned are stupid.
No. But learning should reach that supreme power of intelligence, which is pure intelligence.
Then obviously you see the thing and you accept if you are honest as I said in the beginning.
You must have that pure intelligence to see, God is there.
He’s above everything, he’s above your intelligence, above your thoughts.
You have to feel him first, you have to rise. That is the transformation, if you cannot achieve,
then how can I talk to you? If a person is blind,
what’s the use of talking about colors to a blind person, what does he understand?
He can’t even see whether I’m smiling or laughing or if I’m crying. What can you talk?
So the eyes must be open, and these eyes which I’m talking of are above your thought.
You cannot by your projection get it.
It has to come to you. It’s a grace. Ashedvard [BEST GUESS].
Q7. [INAUDIBLE]
A7. No You see what I would suggest that what happens that once you get your realisation
then I have seen a person who has developed the intellect,
understands it in an intellectual way what realization is
and a person who is not supposed to be so intelligent starts talking like saints.
I had gone to a village in India and there was a person who was, I was going on a bullock cart,
he was driving Me and I asked him when he did you get your realization
and then he started talking to Me. I said “Kabira is driving Me or what?”
How is he talking like this?” The truth, tremendous, what intelligence.
How much Christ studied in what university?
So we should not misunderstand intelligence I mean the divine intelligence,
that’s a very different thing.
Q8. [INAUDIBLE]
A8. You are, all the time, if you, Shaktipad [BEST GUESS] is the word they use it,
Shaktipad you see, but it is very much misused. Shaktipad means people start dancing like mad,
they start shouting screaming how can that be Shaktipad? That’s madness, that’s possession,
you get possessed. Shaktipad means if somebody is a Shakti,
you see the Shakti of that person enters into your being and invites your Kundalini
so the Kundalini rises. That’s what actually it is
and then the Kundalini rises and makes you a beautiful person
it doesn’t make you a mad person no how can it be?
Just imagine now after evolving yourself from amoeba and all the donkeys
and all the monkeys and what else, oh, cockroaches are you going to become a mad person?
Or a frog, jumping like that.
So this is very much, that’s why I don’t use very much Shaktipad power because these days
every Dick, Tom and Harry is using you see. Shaktipad that’s not what I mean.
Shaktipad means if somebody has Shakti it just works.
You don’t go and put it in the head of that person, it just flows, all right?
But it was used in Patanjali’s day in that way but who reads Patanjali? Nobody reads I think
nobody reads and talks about it. What they talk is some sort of a head standing
some sort of a [SOUNDS LIKE SHEERSH] asana that’s all. I mean that’s we, we, we, part of it.
Nobody reads him I mean if you read it, I mean, [INAUDIBLE] you see what he has written is
that’s what I am doing. I am quite surprised how people talk about this thing.
What he says you achieve [SANSKRIT] means you become effortless
first [SANSKRIT] you become without thoughtless,
then the third thing he says you become complete negation of thought, [SANSKRIT].
But here it is they are all jumping, talking big, this, that, how can that be?
Meditation means jumping in the air, how can it be? [HINDI]
Indians understand thank God, Indians are that way you see, safe.
But there should be seeking in India. You see these people are seeking
and striving and they are the ones who want it, I must tell you very frankly
they are the people who really are nicely seeking, in England I am saying not in India.
But Indians are not seeking that, but they have one great thing in them is that they know what is reality.
They understand. You see like some of the people who went to a Guru,
I must tell you, and he gave them a mantra for which he charged £300 in secret, in the ears,
nobody to be told. And the mantra was “Tinga”. “Tinga” and they told Me in the ear
and I couldn’t help laughing, “Tinga” means showing like this to someone.
And he used to giggle at people because they were all so stupid, poor things,
but they were seekers, real seekers, you know,
of such high quality and this fellow who told Me was a barrister can you imagine?
Q9. [INAUDIBLE]
A9. Yes, you are part, you are part of the whole. You are part and parcel of the whole.
The microcosm becomes one with the macrocosm,
as we say in Sanskrit is Virata, you become part and parcel of that Virata.
Q10. [INAUDIBLE]
A10. No, no, no. [INAUDIBLE] Correct.
See it may look like that because the myth of responsibility drops out.
Supposing, this wire thinks that it is responsible for what I am speaking,
does it become more efficient? Say, what responsibility we have is like this.
When we are going by a plane, question is very good, I have seen it. I mean actually,
it must be understood in its full context it’s correct that when you think it is the responsibility of God
you see, then you become irresponsible.
On the contrary, you become an instrument into his hands you see.
But you don’t think that you are doing it yourself, like you are sitting in the play.
I give this example many a times because I have seen this happen.
Some villagers never knew how to go by plane so they were told not to take too much luggage.
They sat in the plane and put all their luggage on their heads.
Carrying the responsibility of the plane, saying that we have to carry the load
because we don’t want the plane to carry all our loads you see.
So that myth drops out, that myth drops out.
But you become a very efficient person
because the energy that’s divine starts dynamically working, manifesting.
You become a dynamic person, you can do a thousand and one things
which you have never done before, because you have become a perfect instrument.
You are not perfect as long as you think you are doing it, you see My point?
All of them, those who are realised souls, and you will be too.
What work are they doing, is spiritually they are doing a lot of work, now,
that’s another side when you’ll come to Sahaja Yoga we’ll tell you what work they are doing.
You see what work you want us to do may not be the work that we are doing
but we are transforming people. We are saving people from cancers and so many diseases,
we are transforming them, we are changing them so much that they have given up drugs.
So many people have given up alcohol, all these bad habits have dropped out.
So many people are cured of so many diseases, so many diseases we have cured already,
when you come to us we will let you know as to what substantial work it is. all right?
Starvation of course, our starvation. Why people are starving also
because I think people who drink are starving because they waste their money in drink.
If they haven’t, if they have money why should they drink?
If they don’t have money why should they drink? But most of the people starve themselves
because they spend all their money, in UK I am saying, not in India, India is a different thing.
But in India people who have got realization are blessed they don’t starve anymore.
[INAUDIBLE]
They don’t need anything, it is said that Yoga Kshema Wiam Miam,
first you get your yoga, your union with God and then I will bless you. Kshema.
[INAUDIBLE]
Yes, yes, of course, of course you can pay your rates, everything,
but you just come and see before. This is the intellectual side, come inside and see,
whether it works out or not. Why not see? Don’t argue for arguments sake, it works out.
There’s somebody sitting behind you who has, in his life it has worked out, just behind.
In many lives it has worked out but you come and see for yourself what miracles it has, all right?
You come and see all previous things just drop off.
Come and see how God is blissful after all the blessings come from God.
But we don’t want to do anything for God and why not God look after us,
what have you done for God so far. Can I ask a question?
Everyone has right to ask a question to Me, I better ask you all. What have you done for God?
Just surrender it. [INAUDIBLE] You are afraid? [INAUDIBLE] Afraid of God? [INAUDIBLE] Pray?
But what we pray to God is “Give me my food. Give me a job.
God get me this. Let me win this war. Let’s kill my enemies” I know all those prayers.
Q11. [INAUDIBLE]
A11. First you get connected all right. First let us get connected then you will know.
Then you will know what He wants and what He does.
Then you will know He is very kind man, very kind,
extremely forgiving that the way He has forgiven us for whatever we have done.
But don’t feel guilty for it, that’s one thing I didn’t want to start,
because you see that’s one trouble you all have is to feel guilty and I don’t want you to feel guilty
because realization doesn’t work out.
Don’t feel guilty it’s all right. We’ll have it next time madam, is it something important?
Q12. [INAUDIBLE]
A12. Talk. Talking is not the thing,
you see what I would say you should see the way they talk has nothing to do,
what you have to see, what have you achieved yourself.
Whatever people may talk is they might be talking because they are possessed, that’s all.
If somebody talks big be careful, be careful, the one who does, isn’t.
You have to feel the cool breeze coming out of your head is the point I said that nobody can do,
can anybody do that?
Those who talk can be good actors at the most, at the worst they are possessed. [INAUDIBLE]
Q13. [INAUDIBLE]
A13. Your married life improves immensely.
Because you will learn later on there is a centre for it and you understand your married life as a bliss,
it’s absolutely pure blessings to married people. Actually you will be surprised
we can’t give realization to people who are not married, in the sense
who are going to marry is all right. But those who are against marriage we can’t give realization
because they are a little imbalanced.
I think the one we had you see, we couldn’t give realization, I hope he’s not here.
But he is going to get married so we will give him realization,
we just couldn’t give him, but married life improves like this.
Q14. [INAUDIBLE]
A 14. What is it about Bhagwan? [HINDI]
This kind of a Bhagwan, who cannot even smell a flower. Can you think of a Bhagwan like that?
You know in the Devi Mahatmayam or into the Vishnu Shastranama,
or anyone of them where there is a described God at least twenty five names of God is he’s fond of flower, fragrance, flower.
I can’t live without flowers and the fellow who cannot smell a flower [HINDI]
I mean what do you give him? Phenyl or something?
This is one of the tests. How can you be a Bhagwan? [SANSKRIT] These are the names of God.
Q15. [INAUDIBLE]
A15. You see, say now if I give you Indian money say 100 rupees how do you know it is 100 rupees?
You have to go to India and spend it and see if it works out or not.
In the same way when you get the vibrations and you feel the cool breeze you spend it
and see for yourself and judge it.
You can do the whole process yourself, you can give realization to others all right?
You see now I would say please get your realization, if you get it, I don’t promise, if you get it.
That’s a very big if, sometimes. I know it happens if you get it
then you have to go and see for yourself whether it works or not.
But to get it is not easy in certain cases,
so be cheerful about it and be patient with yourself.
More patience is needed with yourself, not with Me because I am extremely patient.
You have to be patient with yourself because your mind will be coming up and always saying something,
you didn’t ask this question, you should have asked this question, tell your mind to be quiet.
Take your realization, lets see if it works out.
We cannot assure, it may, it may not, it’s your luck, that’s it.
Q16. [INAUDIBLE]
A16. This conscious mind that you have just now is the human awareness, all right,
at this point the human awareness is at such a stage, that you are not connected with your spirit.
First your human awareness has to be raised it has to be brought to that point
where you get connected. Like this instrument is here now,
consciously whatever you do with this it is not connected, it has no meaning.
In the same way first you should be connected.
After connecting only we can see where is the problem is, what is missing, what is it
and is to be done. So we have to take a very reasonable attitude towards it,
about ourselves, to understand that maybe there is something missing,
something is happening, it’s not working out.
Because at this awareness, at this consciousness that you have, this human consciousness is not sufficient.
So you have to jump, there’s a breakthrough, and you have to achieve that breakthrough.
Which I will not promise, as I told that gentleman there you, it cannot be promised,
it has to be achieved. If you get it then you have to have patience with yourself work it out and see for yourself.
Q17. [INAUDIBLE]
A17. Yes They did because that was the time you see.
Now Jesus came at a time when our Agnya chakra was opened,
see it’s like a Tree of Life has to grow you see and They come at a proper time what has to grow.
Now if it’s the root time and somebody else came in, when the shoot started
somebody else came in gradually it has come up to this point. Now Mohammed,
what Mohamed has said, nobody says that today.
All the Muslims must know that He said “At the time of the resurrection your hands must speak”,
where is that? He said it I mean nobody else but Mohammed had said so clearly about it.
And what does He say is not known nobody knows why He said [INAUDIBLE-namas] like this.
Nobody asked questions, why do you follow?
But after Sahaja yoga will know what [INAUDIBLE] what Mohammed means,
who He was and why He said so what is so important about it.
You can’t understand even Mohammed or anyone, Jesus or anyone, without realization
because you have not entered into that rank, you see My point.
Because the time that time was not to say whatever They had to do They did very important work very, very important.
Every one of Them have worked very hard.
Only I must say that today I am at an advantage than They are
because so many are getting self-realization. They had a very bad time.
They had a very bad time nobody accepted Them. All acceptance came later on when
They were not there and people liked to have such acceptance
because they can do what they like. They don’t want to,
nobody asked Them for realization at that time, nobody, everybody tried just to kill Them.
I mean everybody was anxious how to get rid of Them, isn’t it a fact?
Like today as there are so many who want their realization that time was not there.
Today is the time, all right?
Q18. [INAUDIBLE]
A18. You see that you don’t even need one minute for that, to say, “I’m born again”
it is all self-opinionated thing, just to say. But you have to have powers you see
that’s what I told you the whole lecture was like that.
That once you get self realised you get the powers you have collective consciousness you become conscious.
You see it is very easy to say, just to put the, I don’t know how much they pay
but you just put the name membership “I’m born again”. You don’t know this born again people,
horribly hot tempered, useless people absolutely. You see some of them brought some bibles
and one lady bearing all artificial jewellery here and there and she came to give Me the bible
and I just ignored her. I just started laughing and she was quite surprised to hear this sound.
So this is what born again how can they be born again if they can’t make out a saint.
How can they be born again? [INAUDIBLE]
Only the truth will survive. All these are fads and things [INAUDIBLE] it has no meaning.
END