It is so joy giving to be back in Australia.
When I wanted to come here in this month,
Stephen told me that Perth would be scorchingly
hot (Laughter) and, “I don’t think you
should go to Perth first, you can go later."
So I said, “That part you leave it to me!
The rest is alright!”
Now you have seen how it rained and rained
and rained, because you wanted rain.
That was needed very much.
And also you wanted a cooler atmosphere.
Both things have worked out.
But then the worry was that, because of the
rain, the seekers won’t come.
Also that was solved because it was a testing
ground.
I told them, “If they are real seekers they’ll
come."
Otherwise what’s the use of having a big
quantity with no seeking?
And see yesterday what beautiful people came!
They came all the way in the rain, because
they were seekers and very deep seekers.
They never even asked a question!
Can you imagine, in this Australia, I am always
bombarded with questions.
And they had told me not to allow them to
ask questions But I could feel their seeking
so much, that I said, “Better ask me questions."
And not a single question was asked.
So in one shot how many things are done?
You got the rain that you needed very much
for your trees, for your crops, for your fruits,
for everything.
And it was most unexpected.
And then you got it cooled down so that our
programmes could go on well.
Then you got the real seekers and the real
seeking.
But the electricity went off.
Now see the good point of electricity, also:
because electricity went off,
we had those candles and all the bhoots I
saw were just burnt with these candles on!
And I came in the room [and] they all went,
“Buk! buk!
Buk!” like that, and I could see why candles
had to be put!
So, also, that was a good thing that we should
rely sometimes on natural things.
We are so much dependant on electricity, is
not a very good thing.
So we should have always provision for something
natural.
We should keep some lanterns and things and
should try to live more with the nature than
with this electricity.
I tell you this electricity is responsible
for spoiling our eyes very much.
Supposing we had used those lights which [the]
older generation had used, we would never
have strained so much our eyes as we are with
this electricity.
Because not [only] that it gives us light
but also it takes away light from our eyes.
So too much use of electricity has made us
like slaves to it.
As you know that, in America, once the electricity
failed and so many people died.
So it’s more to depend on natural things.
And this is a good trend that you have, that
you try to have more natural surroundings,
more natural places to live in.
So the main thing we have to realise, is that
equilibrium that is being worked out by Paramachaitanya.
If Paramchaitanya is the power of love of
God, then it works out equilibrium.
So the Sahaja Yogis who are going to work
out Paramchaitanya have to have equilibrium
in their life.
This is a place where I say resides Mahaganesha.
So we have to understand how Shri Ganesh brings
balance in us.
It’s very important to see that his swastika
represents nothing else but balance.
Balance when it is steady.
When it starts moving in the right direction,
then constructive work starts.
And also it works out all that is important
for life.
But when it starts the other way round it
works out the destructive part.
These both are in balance.
If they are not life cannot go on.
The constructive and destructive both have
to be in balance.
If you see in the nature: for example, a bud
has to come, and when the bud dies then the
fruit comes out.
The tree has to evaporate its water to the
sky.
If it does not then it won’t rain.
It won’t trigger the rain.
But during winter season it has to drop out
its leaves, because these leaves have to die
and fall on to the ground to nourish the mother
nature with nitrogen.
Then, during summer time, again they come
back.
So the life goes on like this, that, whatever
is created is destroyed; something new comes
up; again that new thing also comes up in
a way that it becomes constructive.
And then whatever it has constructed, part
of it is destroyed.
So actually, if you see – in the death resides
the life.
If there is no death – imagine if all the
people who were born since long, would have
been living today – we would not have been
here.
It would have been so difficult to manage
ourselves with all these people.
But so many animals have died and those animals
also have become human beings.
So many human beings have to die to get other
people to come on this Earth.
And that you have to take some rest and come
back again.
So the death is just a change of life.
Without death, life cannot exist.
It’s a balance between the two.
So a Sahaja Yogi should never be afraid of
death.
He should never be afraid of death.
Because if he is going to die it is only going
to be another life where he rests for a while
and comes back with greater enthusiasm, with
greater energy.
So there is a complete balance in nature,
if you see.
If there was no balance we could not have
existed.
Supposing the Earth was moving with a greater
speed, you would not have existed.
If the Pacific Ocean was deeper, even by certain
feet, you would not have existed.
So many things are completely in balance:
the distance with the sun, the distance with
the moon.
Everything is so much in balance.
If this balance breaks then we would be nowhere.
So we have to understand that all this is
done by Shri Ganesha.
He is the one who looks after all the material
things and all the things that are created.
For example, the first chakra is created by
this Mother Earth and all this universe then,
is created by the second chakra.
But the first chakra is the one which emits
the holiness, the auspiciousness, which gives
balance.
Auspiciousness comes only through balance.
So I find people when they have lost their
balances, they go to the Right or to the Left.
People are very righteous, extremely righteous,
very good Sahaja Yogis, nice, but there is
no love.
Without love, righteousness has no meaning.
Love doesn’t mean that you indulge into
anything, but you must have detached love
and responsibility.
So in our life we should see if we have that
balance or not.
It’s very important if we have to see to
Shri Ganesh.
Shri Ganesha, as you know, is on Mooladhara,
he controls all our senses as far as the Mooladhara
is concerned, especially all the excretion.
So we are not people who believe in the indulgence
of it, neither we believe in the detachment
of it; but in the balance.
That’s why you all have to be married, you
have to have a proper physical life and that
you should have proper children and lead a
very sensible, dignified married life.
That is very important.
But love should be there.
There should be love between husband and wife,
between children and parents and everyone.
If one person goes into imbalance the whole
family goes into imbalance.
To establish a family, sweetly and nicely,
is also an art.
And if both of them agree and say that, “We
will do this way!”
I am sure it’s not difficult.
Because you are Sahaja Yogis [so] you already
know the quality of balancing.
What I find in the West, now, is the balance
has gone really on the rocks.
Because, see now, there are all kinds of problems
of homosexuality and this and that and all
that.
This is just because of imbalances [that]
people have gone to that limit.
Another is asceticism, where your people are
ascetic, made ascetic like in TM and all that.
They have taken to these things.
Because these are unnatural things.
Natural is to be in balance.
If you are not in balance then things go off
and you become either too much of something
and nothing of the other.
That’s how people suffer.
So from Ganesha’s chakra we have to learn
what are we doing.
So sometimes we have to accumulate things,
we have to consume things, and then we have
to throw them away also.
It is not that what ever we consume is just
stored up within us or in the house.
So we must also learn how to throw away things
and how to take inside.
This is in our household [and] in our thought
also.
In our thought also, when we receive some
thoughts from anywhere, we should only digest
that [which] is good for us.
And it’s digested because of Paramachaitanya.
The rest should be thrown away, you shouldn’t
bother [with it].
Like yesterday somebody met me.
She said, “Mother I am a Catholic and I
cannot get out of Catholicism."
She is supposed to be, she wants to do, Sahaja
Yoga.
Then I said, “You stay inside Catholicism."
Because there is no question of balance.
But in Sahaja Yoga whatever good of Catholicism,
means that you have to worship Christ – that
part is alright.
The rest, whatever is nonsensical has to be
thrown away.
So the whole atmosphere that you face, of
thoughts, of ideas, of books, whatever you
read, you must develop a capacity to consume
that [which] is good for you, and whatever
is bad you should throw away.
I must say in Austria people are really doing
that very well.
Somebody is now doing research on Koran.
He is taking out all the essences of Koran
which are in balance.
Koran talks of balance: talks of that you
must have balance – equilibrium.
It talks of it, and so he has taken that point.
And now he is taking out all that creates
imbalances in the Islamic book called ‘Koran’,
which people have used for imbalances.
On one point you can show how they have gone,
deviated, from their path.
‘Deviated’ means – they have gone into
imbalances.
For example Christianity now: you can take
it very clearly that they didn’t use Ganesha’s
principle there at all.
But all throughout it’s written that you
have to look after yourself in a moral way.
Now in the Old Testament it is written: ‘Thou
shalt not commit adultery’.
But Christ has made it even subtler – very
subtle – because He’s at Agnya controlling
the eyes.
So he said, “Thou shalt not have adulterous
eyes."
But the Christians have crossed all the limits
of adultery, all the limits.
I mean, I don’t know to what limit they
are going to go now, I mean really they have
gone amuck, the way they are going into this
kind of experimentation.
And then what will happen to your children?
What will happen to your society?
That’s what is happening now, in complete
imbalance.
Completely in imbalance, all these societies,
where they are using adultery as a style of
life.
What Christ has said, just the opposite they
are doing.
Same as Shri Krishna has said that in everybody
resides the Spirit.
Then everybody is just the same.
So how can you have caste system?
You can have at the most caste system according
to the work that you are doing.
But you can’t have caste system according
to the birth.
You cannot have.
I mean it’s so plain, clean.
You can see it so clearly, He has said it,
that everybody has got the Spirit.
So everybody can ascend.
Christ has said the same thing.
He has not said that women don’t have the
Spirit or men have the Spirit.
And look at the way that these people are
talking that they cannot have ordination.
Of course ordination itself is humbug, but
still.
But to deprive someone of certain rights because
they are women or men is something absolutely,
I should say, nonsense.
It has no relevance to dharma, because ‘dharma’
means balance.
‘Dharma’ means balance.
The one who has balance is the man who is
dharmic, who is in the centre.
If you are in the centre, say you take, say
a balance, this called as balancing.
But in Hindi it’s called as taraju (तराजू).
Now you hold it in the hand.
It’s called as balance, can you imagine?
You hold it in the centre.
The centre of gravity of that balance is in
the centre.
Now if you go more on this side this will
go down, or you go on this side it will go
down.
But if you are at the gravity point you cannot
move this side or that side.
Can you imagine the gravity is coming from
Mother Earth!
And Mother Earth has made Shri Ganesha.
So this gravity point within us is to be maintained
and this gravity comes very natural to human
beings.
It’s not to be adopted or anything.
If [in] childhood, if children are told about
their gravity, about their dignity, about
their greatness, they will immediately develop
it with a great pride that, “We are something
special and that we have to have this gravity
within us."
Now this gravity gives you a kind of an attraction.
Anybody who is grave, doesn’t mean that
you pull a big face, it never means that.
But gravity means that you are not disturbed
easily by any turmoil or anything.
Gravity means so many things as you can see,
from Shri Ganesha’s character.
Gravity means you are the one who is standing
in the centre.
A person who sees everything and doesn’t
get disturbed, doesn’t get tempted, is self-contented,
doesn’t ask for anything, doesn’t need
anything, doesn’t take revenge, forgives.
Because he has no way to get out of his gravity.
He is just bound there.
Now somebody takes a revenge and runs away:
“Alright, go away!”
If somebody tries to trouble him: “Alright,
go away!”
Because he can’t run out of that gravity
point.
That other person has lost his balance but
he can’t run after that person who is in
imbalance.
So he doesn’t run after that person who
has done wrong.
He says, “Alright, he has done wrong?
Have pity on him let him do that."
He doesn’t run after that person.
He is standing there.
And his standing there itself is sufficient
to frighten others, and to destroy others.
Because he’s standing at a point where he
cannot be destroyed.
But the others are running towards destruction.
So what’s the use of running after him,
getting yourself also destroyed?
Such a person who has achieved that balance
sees others as something to be pitied, because
he sees they are on the verge of falling down.
I am here nicely settled down, but they are
on the verge of falling down.
They may try to tell him, they may try to
help him.
They may try to do everything for that person,
because they can see that person is going
to fall down.
But if that person doesn’t want to take
to balance you cannot force it.
So the Ganesha’s greatest quality is that
he has gravity.
With that gravity he sits down on this Mother
Earth.
Now, because this is a country of Ganesha,
the Australians must have balance, should,
naturally have.
But they don’t.
I must tell you, they don’t.
And my experience of Australians before I
started Sahaja Yoga has been terrific, I must
tell you that (laughing)!
If an Australian starts drinking, only person
who can compete with him is a Russian!
And then they talk so irrelevantly, you don’t
know how to deal with them.
If they shake your hand, then you will feel,
after some time, you have lost it.
Everything they do in such a big way that
I couldn’t understand why is it [that] they
shake your hand so badly.
So C.P. said, “You see they have lots of
jungles."
He tried to console me, “and there are lots
of animals and things and that’s why you
see they shake hands like that."
I said, “No animal shakes hands you see!”
How have they learned from the animals?
I can’t get this explanation alright!
On the contrary they are extremely gentle.
Animals are extremely gentle with each other.
So how this kind of shaking hands has started?
And only people who can beat them are Greeks
who shake hands in a very funny way that really
you get a big jerk!
So I felt that the country of Ganesha, should
be absolutely in balance and in one tune with
this Paramachaitanya.
You see the animals who live in the jungles.
You have so much of nature.
See these trees – they grow up to a point
and they do not aggress others, they do not
fight, they do not have groups.
Nothing of the kind.
Just they grow, accept whatever is given to
them, live with it happily, and if they have
to be destroyed they accept the destruction.
But they are absolutely in contact with God,
or under the complete control of God almighty.
That’s why animals are called as ‘pashu’,
means pash, means ‘under the control of
God’.
While we have got freedom.
Even we have got freedom.
Still this is the country of Shri Ganesha.
[What] the nature should really imbibe within
you, is the balance.
And the balance should come in such a manner
that your whole character, your own temperament
should show that balance within you.
But what I find is the most difficult thing
in Australia that there are groups and people
fight and lots of problems with that.
It surprises me – how can [it be], in the
country of Ganesha, where there are ganas?
All Ganas are here.
If ganas start fighting with each other what
will happen?
Supposing the anti-bodies in our body start
fighting with each other then what will happen
to our body?
So you are like ganas!
You are specially blessed people to be born
in this special country.
And, after all these achievements that you
have made, if you are going to take these
absolutely nonsensical things of the countries
which are over developed, have lost their
balance, then what’s the use of being born
in this Ganesha’s land?
In this Ganesha’s land you have to have
a complete balance within yourself.
That’s what I expect from the Sahaja Yogis
of Australia: that they have to give to the
whole world the sense of balance of Shri Ganesha.
On the contrary it is being reported to me
that, every time we have our programme in
Ganapatipule, people have noticed that there
are groups in Australia, that people are not
clean hearted; they talk ill of others.
And they told me, warned me, “Mother be
on the look out, why it is happening.
They speak something behind their backs and
try to convince the people of other countries
about it."
Of course they being so clean that they don’t
like it.
They don’t want to hear it from Sahaja Yogis.
They don’t want to hear against anyone who
are Sahaja Yogis.
So they informed me, “Mother this is a very
serious thing!”
And certain things [that] they have told me
are really very serious.
So now we have to first decide that we should
bear no grudge to anyone.
How can you bear a grudge to anyone?
We have to be forgiving.
All the time forgiving.
Something, somebody has said it, alright,
doesn’t matter.
As it is, English language, you know, is not
a very soft language, it’s not a very soft
language, and in that if you say something
one should not mind.
It’s a very humorous language but the humour
sometimes cuts you out.
But it doesn’t matter.
That’s the defect of the language.
But that doesn’t mean that you should say
harsh words to anyone, or you should be indifferent
to anyone.
Do your duties to your children, to your wife,
to your husband.
Indifference to anyone, itself, is tremendous
harshness.
For the small thing if a woman gets angry
and doesn’t talk to her husband, or if the
husband neglects the wife, and doesn’t bother
about her, looking after her, caring for her,
then it’s a crime.
According to Sahaja Yoga it’s a wrong thing
to do.
Because you must have balance you must have
softness of nature.
You should talk very softly to others and
be kind and nice.
Just find out if you are doing that or not.
Then between the group [also].
It’s a question of using the power of love.
We have no other power: we have no money power,
we have no this political power, economic
power, nothing.
What power we have got is the power of love.
For that, when you talk to each other, one
has to talk in a soft manner; extremely soft
and kind manner.
You’ll be surprised: I must say, in my experience,
I have found Germans like that!
Extremely soft to each other, extremely gentle!
I mean I can’t believe these Germans who
killed the whole world once upon a time!
Now in Sahaja Yoga suddenly they have realise,
“What a horrible thing we have done!”
And Sahaja Yogis, they are extremely gentle.
You scratch anyone and you will be surprised
that the, all of them, all the Sahaja Yogis
are extremely, extremely gentle.
While the Italians I used to think would be
very gentle, because they have art, culture,
everything and they produce such nice things.
But on the contrary I find that Germans can
beat them.
It’s beautiful German Sahaja Yogis there
have.
They hate neo-fascism.
They said, “We have had enough of it!
We had such a bad name all over the world!
If they know we are Germans nobody wants to
look at us!”
And what are these people doing?
So they have become extremely gentle, from
one end to another end.
And this gentleness really brings them out,
because everybody is so surprised that Germans
could be that gentle, so sweet.
Now look at Shri Ganesh – how gentle he
is, how sweet he is and how innocent he is.
His ways are so gentle: how he works on you,
how he makes things for you, how gently he
does all these things.
Like see now you cannot see this flower opening.
In my room you put some flowers and they started
growing.
You can’t see the growth.
If you put a camera of a special nature which
can record, you can see it growing there,
but you can’t see [normally].
You can’t see a tree growing.
You can’t see a flower opening out.
You just can’t see anything that is growing
by nature, by Shri Ganesh.
He does it so gently.
Now also he will not grow trees one on top
of another!
But in such a way that they all get the suns
rays.
Just like a great mother, I must say, the
way, gently, he does everything.
Every leaf is made differently – what an
art!
Every leaf!
In the whole world you cannot find exactly
the same leaf whether it is from Australia
or from America.
The leaf, if you see it under a microscope,
will differ.
Every leaf!
Can you imagine?
Look at his work, how gently he puts everything,
how gently he works.
And while we are living on the grounds of
Shri Ganesha how gentle we should be.
And in dealing with people we should be extremely,
extremely gentle.
We should show that we are Ganesha’s special
ganas.
That’s what I feel about Australians.
We have had some mishaps, I know, doesn’t
matter.
But that’s alright.
A few of them were like that.
But all of you should really learn to be very
loving, gentle, kind and concerned.
Small, small things can make people happy,
very happy.
And I try all these tricks myself and you
should also try these tricks.
It’s very simple.
One day I gave a sari to a lady, so she said,
“Mother how do you know I love this colour?”
“Because I have seen you mostly wearing
this colour.
So I know you love this colour."
“But did you see me?”
“Yes, of course, I saw you."
So these small things: she was so heartened;
she felt that, “Mother notices me,” Because
I have seen you.
I mean I see all of you.
But I know about all of you because I am concerned
and bothered about you.
And everyone I know where you stand, what’s
wrong with you, what should be done, what
you like, what you don’t like.
There’s no harm in doing that.
It’s much better to have a better rapport
when you understand what’s the problem is.
I immediately know what’s the problem.
I know a person who is dominating, I know
a person who is mistrusting.
Everything I know.
And gradually I try to tell them in a very
gentle way that, “This should be corrected."
But you need not tell them.
For you there’s a very simple method of
giving bandhans and improving people.
You don’t have to worry about doing something
very drastic about it or to tell them on the
face.
Only thing if you give bandhan to them you
can do it.
Now, about this, how to develop this balance,
is the big problem and I was thinking that
I will talk about this later on to people
in details: how to develop the balance in
our character, in our nature.
Of course meditation does help you to be in
the centre.
But, still, sometimes we just slip off.
And there is a way by which you can really
make your character in such a way that you’ll
remain in balance all the time.
On the contrary when there will be a crisis
you will just jump on to your gravity point.
That should happen.
If that happens no problem.
It happens with me.
If I see any crisis anywhere, in Sahaja Yoga,
in my family life, or anywhere, immediately
I know that I am deep down on to my gravity.
And from there I can see everything so clearly
and then I solve the problem.
That is what one has to understand, that you
have to jump on your gravity.
And then it’s not a relative position.
To be on the gravity is not a relative position.
It is not that you have to compare yourself
with others.
No you don’t have to.
You don’t have to think that I’ll be losing
this or I’ll be gaining this.
Nothing of the kind.
You are there on your own position.
You are there.
You are in charge of yourself.
So you don’t worry.
There is no jealousy, there’s no fear, there’s
no kind of a temptation, just you are there.
You are not bothered.
Sometimes I have seen the leaders are worried
about their leadership sometimes.
Now leadership is just hocus-pocus, I must
tell you.
If somebody says Mother you become the leader
I’ll say, “No.
I know.
I know that joke!”
So it’s a joke.
Leadership is a joke you see.
And if you know it’s a joke, then only you
will work it out better.
Because, there’s nothing like hierarchy
in Sahaja Yoga.
As you know, we are all one, the same.
We cannot say that hands are better than feet
and the feet is better than this – nothing
of the kind.
In the same way everything is very important,
and everything circulates like the blood cells.
So we do not say that this blood cell is good
and that blood cell is bad.
Or this blood cell is higher, that blood cell
is higher.
In the same way everybody is circulating.
So one should not have any fear.
Also fear of the leader should not be there.
There’s no need to fear the leader.
If you are on your gravity you keep to it.
He will understand you.
As long as leader is on the gravity he’ll
be there, as soon as he goes away from the
gravity he’ll go away himself.
So you stand on your own gravity point and
nobody can disturb you.
You should have no fear, nothing.
Nothing to bother in Sahaja Yoga.
As it is you are all saints.
What is there to bother?
The whole ganas, all the angels, all this
All-pervading Power is looking after you.
Yesterday we saw a kind of a light, miraculous
light, following us on both the sides of the
car.
Especially on my side there was such a lot
of light following.
Just giving [an] indication that it’s alright,
this is Ganesha’s place and here things
are going to work out.
So you are placed so well, you have so many
powers within yourself and which you can express
very well.
Fearlessly you can have it within yourself.
Anybody who tries to trouble you will be looked
after by this All-pervading Power, you don’t
have to do anything about it.
So try to see: are you in balance in any way.
Some people are too much attached to their
family and some people are detached.
Too much attachment to family is also wrong.
What is the need to be attached so much?
You’ll spoil your children.
When they grow up they hit you back.
So best is to keep them in balance, have a
detached attitude towards life.
And this detached attitude, as I had told
you, is like the sap in the tree which goes
to all the places.
If it is surplus it can evaporate or it can
go down, but it doesn’t stick to anything,
because if it sticks to anything, that involvement
will kill that tree and also kill that part,
that flower, where it is sticking on to.
So we see that attached love is the death
of the love.
So we have to have a proper understanding
of this detached love, where you stand on
your gravity and you have concern about everyone,
you think about everyone.
In case you find that somebody is not alright,
you don’t lose your balance, but get that
person in the balance.
If you start losing your balance then how
can you get back that person.
And in that way you will lose all your hatred,
all your anger, all your lust, or what you
can call, all your competition, all that.
Because you stand in your own dignity.
You don’t want [a] certificate from anyone.
You don’t want any praising from anyone.
You just know that you are there.
And you are self-contented.
Then it’s not also necessary that, “Mother
must give me a special audience!”
It’s all ego.
“I must see Mother!
I have to see her privately!”
What is the need to see me privately?
I am never private I am available every time
to you, all the time.
So all these things are coming out of the
ignorance and out of the fact that you are
not on your gravity point.
So today, to begin with, we have this Ganesh
puja where we all should, in our heart, think
what is our gravity point and [on] that we
have to stand very firm.
May God bless you.