here you are
in such a great position that you have
got realization
that only thing you have to accept
the beauty of this
great yoga that
you just enlighten
your own powers which are
on these seven chakras now let us see
the first chakra belongs to the power
of gauri the power of the
mother of shri ganesha
gauri's power tremendous there aren't
they
because of her power you have got your
realization
now what have we done
to enshrine that power within ourselves
today's if it is the first day of
navratri
let us see what have we done
have we been able to develop our
innocence
within ourselves
when people talk they are so sharp
how can you be sharp if you are innocent
they are so bumptious
how can you be that if you are innocent
people play games how can you do that
if you are innocent harm each other
how can it be if you are innocent
so first of all you have to see yourself
that the power of innocence if it has to
live
all the rest of the nonsense has to go
away
if you want to have the innocence all
that is anti-innocence has to be dropped
off
i can understand about people who are
ignorant
who have ignorance then in ignorance of
course
how will they talk of innocence but you
are not ignorant people
you are knowledgeable you've got your
enlightenment
and the power of innocence is so great
it makes you absolutely fearless not
bombshell but fearless
and the greatest thing of innocence is
that you are respectful
the sense of respect
if it is not developed within you if you
cannot
develop the sense of respect for other
sahaja yogis
for other people for the ashrams for the
discipline
and your own self-respect
then it is of no use
even talking of sahaja yoga because
that's the very
beginning of it
first you do not respect all right you
are bumped us all right
you are in a big
fool's paradise as they call it riding a
fast horse
all that is there is all right is
forgiven
but once you have seen the light you
must try to
get rid of all the snakes that you have
been holding on
is a simple thing
in your childlike nature only
you can receive the blessings of gauri
otherwise you cannot
you have to be really childlike
otherwise
it is absolutely useless no use telling
you
anything because you think you are too
clever
to such a person who thinks he's too
clever was this of talking to such a
person because he already knows
everything
so the first power when you develop you
must learn to sit on the
mother earth first of all
you must respect the mother earth
because the first chakra is made out of
the mother earth
try to be more settle down with yourself
on mother earth
under respect see the trees
when they get their flowers
they are not so respectful but when they
are leading by
the fruits they bow down
to mother earth
in the same way when you have got the
fruits
of sahaja yoga you all must bow down
and innocence has a special capacity
to make a person extremely peaceful
extremely peaceful all the
anger temper violence
if a person doesn't have innocence
it cannot
come in you because the person who is
not innocent
is either sly or
aggressive
he cannot have peace within his heart
but an innocent person is not bothered
innocently he lives
enjoys everything in complete
peace and harmony
but this violence comes
when a person becomes clever
he thinks i am so clever the another one
is so stupid
i have a right to shout at that person
and the one who is not innocent is
never wise he may be to look at look
sharp but he's not wise
wisdom comes only with innocence and how
much
wisdom have you gathered
that is what one has to say when
your power
of innocence increases wisdom
is apparent people say that fellow is
very wise
for example if somebody is crying about
his wife
a wise person we could say obama just
look at this
still busy with his wife another one is
crying about his house or something he
say oh
look at this one still busy with the
house
there is no end to it
i have known people who get
so swollen up
that they think they must give a big
lecture for one hour
on sahaja yoga unless and until they
have given one hour lecture
they do not think their ego has
manifested itself fully
but a wise person he doesn't have to
talk
or speak or do anything
he impresses his silence
his wisdom on others much more easily
and that is what we have to see have we
been able
to discipline ourselves because our
growth is very
much in the beginning of it you have to
grow
quite a lot
and people don't understand this point
in an atmosphere of egoistical
temperament that you have to grow
you have not yet grown
you have to grow a lot
and when you grow you find this wisdom
really fragrant with compassion
your wisdom is fragrant with compassion
such beautiful compassion
can emit through your being
that anybody who comes in contact with
you
will feel your auspiciousness
but again
you must give due respect to your
self-realization
and to yourself that is the first thing
you have to do is to meditate
we are not drinking we do not have
hangovers
we don't sleep late
so why shouldn't we decide today that
every morning i'll get up and do my
meditation
and while meditating i must concentrate
on myself and not on others
and see for myself what is catching
where am i catching what chakra i am
coaching
whatever to do so on this day of
navratri
today as the first day
the gauri's power
must be enlightened within us and they
must express and they are
tremendous i cannot describe them in one
lecture
think of the primordial kundalini
she acts in the mother earth she acts in
the
universe she acts in the
animals she acts in the matter
she acts in the human beings and now she
acts in you
she is the one who decides
the face and the figure that you are
going to have
she is the one who decides what child
you should have
she is the one who gives you a
particular type of a child that you need
she is the one who has got you all these
beautiful children
she is the one who has given you these
sparkling faces and sparkling eyes
all this she has done for you but what
about the power that you have
within yourself how much have you
manifested that
so try to understand that
it is you who has to grow it is you
who has to manifest these powers
manifestation of the power
i don't know how far you have understood
when a person who has gauri's power
as soon as he enters a hall or any place
everybody's kundalini
rises just to salute
when you have gauri's power then you
stand out because you have that
innocent lustless greedless
beautiful sparkling eyes and wherever
you turn your eyes
even one glance would raise the
kundalini immediately
people who suffer from cancer suffer
from this disease that is it
all can be cured in no time if you have
developed only
one power of gauri
all your problems can be solved
negativity will go away and you'll
become
like a lotus
beautiful fragrant
overpowering all kinds of negativity
here it is
that fellow just touched me
and now i have become egoistical
if there is one fellow who is egoistical
he just talks to another person the
person goes egoistical
i mean this is not the way to be
sensitive you have to be sensitive to
god
and not to bad things but we
are more akin more
vulnerable to bad than to good
so the power the power of assimilation
of good
the power of emission of good
all these powers are just in
your complete reach
but all this should not become a praise
but should become a kind of a challenge
a kind
of a beautiful curiosity
and an advancement for you
that is why my humble request is
that you must learn
to worship discipline
i don't say do this do that you know
what is to be done
and then on top of that you should not
tell me i know i should
i know when you know why don't you do it
you have you are empowered
today let us with full confidence in
ourselves
and in our ascent let us with full
intensity
attend his puja and in our hearts decide
that i am going to discipline myself
may god bless you