Now, as you know that United States
or America,
the whole of it, is the Vishuddhi chakra.
Out of which, we have three sides
to the Vishuddhi chakra.
So, the central part of the Vishuddhi
chakra is United States.
The central part of the Vishuddhi chakra
is governed by Shri Krishna.
And His power is Radha.
“RA – DHA”. “RA” means energy, “DHA” is
the one who has sustained the energy.
“RA – DHA”. “dha-re-ti-saa”.
So, she’s the one who has sustained
the energy,
and so, she’s called as Radha. She’s
the power of Shri Krishna.
The word Krishna comes from the word –
Krishi, means –
the ploughing, or you can say, agriculture
is called as “Krishi”.
The one who ploughs and puts the seed
in the soil, is doing the krishi.
And, that’s why he’s called as Krishna.
Now, the seed that he has sown, is the seed
of spirituality.
It is Shri Krishna who said, in Sanskrit –
“Nainam chindanti shastrani
nainam dahati pavakah
na chainam kledayanty apo
na shoshayati marutah”
meaning – it cannot be, means,
the spiritual life
or you can say, the eternal life, or
the Spirit,
cannot be killed by anything, by any
weapon,
neither can be blown away by air,
nor can it be sucked in, nor can it be
destroyed.
So, to prove that, Christ came on this
earth,
and through His resurrection he proved,
what Shri Krishna has said.
And most of you sahaj yogis know
the relationship
of Christ and Shri Krishna – why he was
called Christ.
Christ word comes from the same – Krishna.
And, his first name comes from the word
Yashoda.
Yashoda is also called as Jesu or Yesu.
And that’s why (Krish) Christ was called
as Je-su or Ye-su.
Some people call him Yesu, and some people
call him as Jesu,
because of Yashoda (the mother), the foster
mother of Shri Krishna.
Also, you know that Radha was the same
as Mahalakshmi,
so she was the same as the mother
of Christ, Mary.
These, all these things we can prove it
in Sahaj Yoga.
Because, when the Kundalini moves up
to the Vishuddhi chakra,
and if it stops there, you can ask
the question –
Was Jesus the son of mother Mary?
Who was the son of Ra, was the same
as Radha?”
And then the Kundalini moves.
So, Sahaja Yoga today is the thing which
proves what has been said so far.
It proves. It’s not just a cock and bull
story.
Because people do not believe into all
these things.
They think that it’s all cock and bull
story. Who was Christ?
Who was Krishna? Who was Radha? After all,
there was no God.
But only in Sahaja Yoga, today, we can
prove it, that what we say is the truth.
Because, as through realisation, you get
connected to the mains,
your vibrations start flowing,
like the computer, you start working.
And whatever question you ask,
answer comes to you as tremendous
vibrations,
or it stops or you might get heat or you
may get blisters.
So, the whole message is communicated
to you through your fingertips.
(...) Now Vishuddhi chakra was created
on the Saturday.
So, it is the Saturn – that’s the important
star of the Vishuddhi chakra.
So, whenever the Saturn is at the highest,
America will be in a better place to do
things.
But I don’t think they know much about
themselves.
They don’t know what they are, why they
are on this earth,
what is their work, what they are supposed
to do,
or what is the purpose of God of creating
America.
The first job of the Vishuddhi chakra
within us was that,
when we became human beings, we raised
our heads up like that.
When you raised your head up like that,
you have become a human being, in the sense
that now,
there is a new movement in your
consciousness.
Now the new movement in your consciousness
started about 6000 years back
when Shri Krishna came on this earth.
That the new movement was, that it is
the Father.
The advent of the Father was celebrated,
and that’s how
people developed a kind of a new instrument
within themselves, called ego.
When the brain was lifted like this
you see,
it expanded in a pyramidical – it’s
a pyramid – it became a pyramid.
In an animal, the brain is flat. And,
gradually it rises.
When the head was raised, when
the responsibility was taken
of raising the head, the brain started
growing
in such a way that it became a pyramid.
And when it became a pyramid,
he attention became a different attention
from that of animal.
Because, when the waves of your
consciousness
fell on the sides of the pyramid, they went
into the parallelogram of forces,
by which the resultant force –
the resultant force…
Now, it falls like this, goes like that,
the resultant force is like that –
had two sides – one was this, another
was this.
So, the consciousness, or we can say,
the attention –
instead of going inside, started going
outward.
So, one part of the resultant was going
outside
and that’s how, when you became a human
being, your attention went outside.
Are the human beings only, who have their
attention outside.
Not that the animals don’t have,
but the attention of human beings are such
that they create reactions.
Like, you see something.
Now, I see Doctor’s house say for example,
then a reaction starts in my mind – what is
this, what does this mean,
how much it must have cost, from where
did he buy it!
Anything you see, it starts giving you
a reaction.
Not to the animals. Animals, at the most
they will say –
this I must eat, that I must eat, that
I must get.
But, they do not think about it.
It’s only the human beings who reflect.
And this reflection comes because of the
pyramid-like structure of the brain.
And this has a special reaction in
the brain itself,
that we start developing our own ego,
our own myths, our own mental projections.
And when we develop our own mental
projections,
this ego starts developing, “I know”
“what’s wrong”,
all these nonsensical things come.
And once that starts working out,
the balloon of the ego starts rising.
It starts pushing the other balloon which
was within us,
is of the superego – as an animal.
And then, comes up in the centre.
That’s how we now become normal human
beings.
But then we start increasing our ego.
It starts overlapping the superego,
and a calcification takes place, by which
we develop our I-ness.
So, it is all the happening that takes
place after we have lifted our head,
raised our head, and we are no more
like animals.
So, Vishuddhi chakra has a very big part
to play
in the human evolution, that by developing
your Vishuddhi chakra,
you have become human beings, first of all.
Secondly, because it is the chakra
of the Father,
who becomes again, the primordial – as you
call it in…,
macrocosm. You become the macrocosm.
You are the microcosm, and the Father
is the macrocosm.
So, you become that because of
the Vishuddhi chakra,
which is governed by Shri Krishna,
who becomes that macrocosm, called
as Virat.
In the brain it is expressed in this part.
In this part of the head.
It is here that you start manifesting
your macrocosm qualities – at this point.
Now, this Vishuddhi chakra has
a speciality – is that,
we always say that the responsibility
on my shoulders.
Always we say that – the responsibilities
are on my shoulders.
The reason is, the Vishuddhi chakra gives
you the sense of responsibility.
And that’s why you know, the Americans
feel responsible for the whole world.
Naturally!
It’s perfectly understood, that they feel
responsible for the whole world.
But how much they are aware of their role
as the responsible people, that’s
a different point.
But they feel they are responsible,
but their role, as responsible people,
if they understand,
then they have to be ideals. Ideals.
Because a person who is a responsible
person in a family,
has to be the ideal for others.
It started very well, I should say,
at the time of Abraham Lincoln. It started
very well.
When you started talking about democracy,
is also –
democracy is nothing but collectivity.
He started talking about collectivity
of the people, by the people.
All that shows that the sense
of collectivity
started coming right in this Vishuddhi
chakra.
(...) Specially for America, I’m wearing
this stone
which is called as the black sapphire.
Because, this is the stone of Shri Krishna.
It’s the stone of Vishuddhi chakra.
Every chakra has a stone.
And this is the stone of the Vishuddhi
chakra,
so I’m wearing this, just for coming
to America.
And, I hope that today’s worship will bring
out the potential of this country
by exciting the deities, Shri Krishna
himself, who is in charge.
By pleasing him. By making him active.