So
the New Year is coming and CP. It's expected
to be a very dynamic year for Sahaja Yoga
and Sahaja yogis. Everything new becomes stale
and never becomes new again. So whatever has
gone has gone. Let bygones be bygones. There
have been very sweet memories sometimes, sometimes
rather unhappy also, but on the whole we are
growing, realising, coming up. You've done
a good job of building up ourselves, into
a new way. New Sahaja yogis have come up now
have got rid of their lethargy and their jealousies,
their slyness, their slumber and narrow-mindedness
. All these things have to be buried in the
past. They are of no use to us. It's a load
we carry for nothing at all.
Today it happens that I read a very nice letter
which was lying with me which I didn't read.
It was sent by Gregoire to Warren. It really
touched my heart.
He was concerned about the jealousies that
people suffer and the way he said that, that
this jealousy is the most petty stuff, a most
ugly thing, and it comes up as something as
a challenge to your love, challenge to your
understanding or something like that, and
then he started explaining it. This explanation
is all rational. In Sahaja Yoga there is nothing
like jealousy . It doesn't exist. It doesn't
exist in the Kingdom of God, something called
jealousy, because all are part and parcel
of one God. So, one person becomes important,
another less important. Is only for the time
being. For example, when you are smelling
a flower, naturally the nose is more active
than the eyes.
When you are seeing the flower the eyes are
more active. So, it is not necessary that
at this moment, when somebody is more active,
doesn't mean that he is closer to God and
another person who is inactive. Everybody
is, but some people are active at a point,
some people are active at another. Or some
people are closer, some people are taken away
but they are all part and parcel. So this
is one of the things one has to understand
that there should be no jealousy. On the contrary,
if you find somebody who is spiritually higher
you must try to understand and appreciate,
especially a person who is wiser than somebody
who says wise things. If you hear somebody
saying something wise, try to notice, appreciate,
enjoy, be nice. Sometimes even the children
say something nice. Young people can say something
nice.
So the first thing is of jealousy which I
don't understand. Some of you think that I
like someone more than the other. To be very
frank I have no idea of liking or disliking.
I don't understand. There is no question.
It's a very different mechanism you are dealing
with. That person who doesn't get involved
into any, doesn't get entangled into any.
Only thing what I am trying to do is to disentangle
you. If I was an entangling type, how can
I disentangle? You see, if I was the person
who has to purify you and if I am the person
who cannot purify you, then what's the use
of My being there? So if the person who tries
to purify has to be pure himself. Supposing
there's a soap and the soap is the one that
gets dirty. Then what's the use of such a
soap? In the same way I never get entangled
with anyone. That's my name, Nirmama. To Me,
Nirmala, nobody is mine. Everybody. So this
should get out of your mind as
to Nirmala.
All right, so we have to bury this useless
thing called jealousy and it can be very serious.
It can happen very serious with people. I
have seen people, they got jealous. Then they've
got after another person. Then they've got
after Sahaja Yoga, then after. And this jealousy,
one should not allow to crawl in. You see,
some people are more congenial, sometimes
are more nearer Sahaja yoga, sometimes. They
are more helpful. Sometimes they are more
useful. Sometimes they have to be there. Sometimes
they need Me the most of all. Some of them
are lost people. Some of them are really possessed
and badly off. So sometimes that's why I look
after them. It's My own whim. I cannot say.
I cannot justify. Maybe that person is very
good. I look after. Maybe that person is very
bad. I look after. So one should never have
any jealousy with people. Only you must have
understanding that your Mother has to work
for all of you and has to improve you, cure
you, do something about. One thing we have
to bury is the jealousy that lives within
us. We bury something and something comes
out very bad, and what is that comes out of
this jealousy, is that we have to better ourselves.
So the outgoing jealousy should leave within
us. "Oh, am I jealous of a person!" Then what's
good in that person?
Now, this is not outward. Sahaja is not outward.
If that person is outwardly like this, outwardly,
it goes inward. If I correct somebody, I correct
that person because the vibrations of that
person are not all right. You see that person
can be extremely sweet also, a very sweet
type, could be anything, could be harsh, could
be anything, but the vibrations of that person
have to be all right. I have to gain nothing
out of you except that your vibrations should
be correct.
So, you should not have any misidentification
that some people are very dynamic, so they
think they can do what they like. Some people
think they are very sort of deceiving type
so they think they can do what they like.
All of this. First of all you should speak
collective.
For a mother if some children are left behind,
her heart, all the time she thinks they are
left behind. They should. That's the main
thing. This is not for one person. Like just
thinking about your own son or thinking about
your own wife, thinking about your own husband.
It's not the point. All of you are dearer
to Me, dearest to Me, but I belong to no one.
I'm a hopeless case. Just hear me up. I belong
to no one. No one can possess me. I cannot
possess myself. How can you possess? I am
beyond possession. Then if it is so, there
should be no jealousy. There's no question
of jealousy or in any way feeling jealous
of each other. Only the beauty of enjoying
others. Somebody has some great points - very
good qualities in that person - you'll imbibe
it. In Sahaja Yoga, whatever you enjoy you
imbibe. You know that. Whatever you enjoy
you will imbibe, just like that. You should
be able to enjoy.
Now supposing you enjoy creating rifts in
people, creating problems with people, you'll
have them yourself. Supposing you enjoy saying
harsh things to others, you'll imbibe that
in the sense that you will have more of it.
Whatever you want, you will have. Christ has
said if you want gold, you'll have gold. Many
people who came to Sahaja Yoga went away in
the search of money, promotions and they got
it. You'll have gold.
But those who are dearer to Me, will have,
will sit with Me on My throne. This is what
you should ask for. This is what you ask for.
Not for having more gold, more money, more
this, more that, but that you are part and
parcel of his company. Now somehow, I know
everyone of you. Somehow, I don't know how,
I know everyone of you. How far you are with
me, I know. There is no need to justify. No
need to say, "This is not so. That is not
so". I know everything. I should know. Otherwise,
how would I give you something substantial?
I have to give you something very special
and for that I have to know what you need,
when I know I love you. Unless until you love
someone, you cannot know so much about the
person. I know your beauties. I also know
your ugliness. I know your tenderness. I know
your harshness. I know all the things that
you have, that you have been, that you are,
and you will be. It is many-dimensional knowledge.
Some of you I expect it is too much because
I think you are capable and I know your past.
I work very hard on you. You know that and
I'll work and I'll continue to work, every
year, but '82 is a very remarkable year, where
you people should now work hard for Sahaja
Yoga. I have already given some idea as to
how to work it with Raveen. I have talked
to him. Raveen knows how we are going to work
it out in a systematic way, how to attack
a particular village, or a particular district,
or wherever you have to go, how to go there,
how to propagate, how to establish.
Wherever there is soft ground you should settle
down, not in the hard ground. The hard ground
will never yield any produce. So don't go
on working on a hard ground. Put your attention
to these factors. What can I do for Sahaja
Yoga? Take out your attention from yourself.
For example, supposing a person, now there
are presents all being tied up. Supposing
a person wanted a particular present, take
it like that. Sahaja Yogis are not that low
type but still, supposing take the lowest
of lowest, behave like children. So, you don't
get that particular one.
Now, to do all this with all the work I've
been doing here, select that and to arrange
all that, isn't it tremendous? So, whatever
Mother could do in that hurry and scurry,
with everybody's name and all that, it is
quite a lot to be done, and if She has done
that, one should appreciate the love that
Mother wants to bestow upon you. It is all
symbolic. But somebody can sit down and start
saying, "Oh, I should have had this. Why didn't
you give me this? Why didn't you give me that.
I should have."
You see, it is not anything that one has made
or anything, just to give somebody something,
in a small way, I am saying, but even in this
small way, you are worried about yourself.
You have to worry about Sahaja Yoga. What's
going to happen to Sahaja Yoga? How is it
going to come up? What have you to work it
out? What do you have to do? How many pujas
do we have to arrange? How do we have to do
anything? Not about yourself. How should I
improve myself? That point is also. Forget
it. What are we going to do to propagate Sahaja
Yoga, we have to say. Not go to personal life,
my husband and wife quarrelling, with them.
I mean, I've had enough of it. I mean, I'm
not here to settle your marriages. All these
nonsensical things, you forget now. Of course,
if you have a good marriage, it helps Sahaja
Yoga, no doubt. It helps because you get children.
It helps. If the husband and wife are not
all right, you might get very horrible children
which may be possessed from the very childhood
and be very difficult. They will be realised
souls but will be very difficult children.
So this is important that we should dedicate
ourselves to Sahaja Yoga today, to bring out
the old and bring out the new which is dedicated
to Sahaja Yoga - not to your personal life,
not your personal likes and dislikes, what
will happen to Sahaja Yoga - and to be sincere
about it. Many people who organise go off
their heads. I've seen it. Somehow, you give
them something to organise, they are about
to land up in a lunatic asylum. You give them
something to organise, make them the leader,
finished. It happens like that. It goes off
their head somehow or other. You see, there
is a crack in the head, and these, so the
cracked head then starts behaving in such
a funny manner, that you can't imagine how
far one can go. You have to organise, you
have to become right-sided, you have to work
hard, no doubt, but you need not be right-sided.
If you work with right hand you don't become
right-sided, do you? You don't double up your
ears, nose or (mantra?). Do we? Or you don't.
I mean, really, the nature, it keeps the body
all right, I must say, because there is some
right-handed people should have a right side,
emotions. Or the left hand should have a left-hand
development. Should be there, but it is not.
It keeps nature all right. Nature keeps the
faith all right, everything all right. It
keeps it.
So one has to know that when you are trying
to bring in something new, you must talk of
the new. Then whatever is old and outward
should be sent away, should be thrown out.
Otherwise you will never grow. It will shift
from here to here, here to here, the bhoot
particles.
So today's message of not feeling guilty and
not thinking of what all old things, old rags
you have had on, throw it away, same day.
You see, obstinacy should not be there. People
are very obstinate. They don't want to see.
They don't want to forget. They don't want
to forgive. Give up that obstinacy. Obstinacy
is not the nature of your spirit. If you are
the spirit you will never be obstinate. Have
you ever seen Me being obstinate? Ever? You
said, "Mother, sit here." "All right". You
say, "Sit there." "All right". No, not that
I am going to sit here alone. Never, never.
You say, "Mother, will you eat this?" "All
right," even if I am very, very full myself.
Sometimes I should put down My foot but I
don't. So you should also not be at all obstinate.
There should be not obstinacy. There should
be no fanatics. It's all a play going on,
this way, that way, that way. Just enjoy yourself.
So this is one thing, if you are obstinate,
you cannot become a new person. To become
a new person you have to give up your obstinacy
completely. Once you give up your obstinacy
you will be very happy and peaceful, and you
must come as a new person every minute, every
second you are. So I just.
Now, as far as Sahaja Yoga is concerned in
England, I think it has taken a good road.
Propagation has to be established. It has
to be publicised. It has to be talked about.
People are to be told you have found it. Go
and see people who are seekers. Whatever level
you are, supposing you are dealing with a
particular type, of say a lawyer, should meet
all the lawyers. If there's a psychologist
is there, should go and see the psychologist.
At your level, whatever level it is, you should
go and talk about it to others that this is
what you have found out. Why don't you get
hold of it, and you will all get good quality
people who are really seekers? You must talk
now and that is what is. Get out of your shyness.
That is very important to get out of your
shyness. Talk to people. But I've seen people
when they talk about Sahaja Yoga, instead
of giving a good name to Sahaja Yoga, they
bring bad name, because when they talk, they
talk in such a way as if they are being clever.
That's not good. We have to say we are just
the same. We are just the old egg and we are
just trying to talk because we have found
something, so others are not hurt.
So for that you have to remember the past
that we were like this, and if somebody had
talked to us, like this, they would have been
hurt. We have to remember our past, remembering
the past, just for your own manoeuvring, that's
all. Not that as a part and parcel but just
for your manoeuvring, how to deal with others.
Unless until you remember your past, you will
not know how to deal with others and you won't
have compassion. So that is what we have to
see, the importance of the past.
The future at this present moment is that
'82 is a great year, that's all, not more
than that. You don't have to think about '83
because even if you start doing it in '83,'82
will be silent. "You do it in '83, Mother.
What does it mean? I think I believe it would
be a better idea to do this in '83. What do
you think, Mother?" Suggestions. I have a
suggestion today. Supposing we do it in '83,
why not today? Why not now? Ask the question,
"Why not?" When such a thing is done, why
not now? And then whatever you do, you do
it fully, completely to the finishing point.
Like (Pais ?) has been very good with you
when we were working in that house. You were
chiselling the house and I was chiselling
you. You were building the house and I was
building you. It was very good, interesting,
very nice. Some of you have really gained
a lot, really gained a lot. You have really
become very dynamic, very beautiful, very
Sahaja. Quite a lot of you done that. I know
that and it is really very appreciative, work
that you have done. Anybody can see that very
clearly.
You are being described by Blake that you
will be the golden builders. Clearly, this
is done by the golden bridges, but in that
you have to learn first. Like now they are
painting, all right. The painter goes up to
paint. He takes a place to sit down on top.
When he comes out everything is there, all
the mismanagement that was done is still there.
The painter has finished the painting. Still
the scaffolding is there, the seat is there,
the things on which he was sitting, the cushion
is there, all these piers that were removed
that are there, all the carpets are there,
are just the same. It takes hardly ten minutes
to put it right.
So this is the future. The future is that
when you do something, feel, be that futuristic
seed of that person. See that the state in
the seed again. You give realisation to somebody.
See that it is fixed. So remember the past
for your manoeuvring and remember the future
for feeling so it is not lost in the future.
This is importance of making the spirit. Experience
of the back or the past should give you manoeuvring,
in the sense that at that moment you must
do something in the present. You must compensate,
do something by which the future is not giving.
This is how New Year's celebration should
be. '82 is important. In '82 whatever we have
learned from the past, we remember. We'll
not do the same mistake. Not only but also,
remember whatever past has taught us. We'll
have compassion for the people who have been
like that. We'll have love for them. We'll
have understanding. We'll do whatever is possible
to bring them round. We'll have concern, need
not just Sahaja Yogis, you see, sweet-talking
Sahaja Yogis, but we'll do something about
it.
So many are lost in intellectual pursuits.
So many are lost in financial pursuits. So
many are lost in political pursuits and so
many are lost in so-called service pursuits.
All of them belong to some category and you
have to belong to one of these categories.
So you have to think of them, try to bring
them out, do something about it, have a wider
standing.
When you have a small personalty, think of
your wife, yourself, nothing more than that
or your children at the most. But when you
are a wider personality you just think what
will happen to the people who belong to this
clan, who belong to Catholicism, those who
belong to Judaism, those who belong to Methodist
and to Jainism. Saint Michael, like that,
have a wider personality. Don't worry about
yourself. I've known people who'll come and
ask, "Mother, where should I find my keys?
Mother, where should I put my basket? Mother,
where should I put my nose? What should I
do about my luggage? What should I do about
my travelling?" All nonsensical things, they'll
come and ask. I'm not here to give you all
that. Every small thing they will ask. Now
if you tell them, "Why are you doing it?"
you said it. I didn't say it that you ask
Me every time you have to raise a finger.
"Mother, may I rise my finger. May I close
my eyes? May I smile?" Not that. You are people,
in My eyes are saints. So decide for yourself,
of course. You are saints. You have to assume.
You don't know you are saints. Assume you
are saints. This assumption must come to you,
on this great auspicious day that you are
saints, and saints have to be wise people
and do it by themselves, because they are
saints. If they fight, quarrel among themselves,
then this is stupidity, absolute stupidity,
against the whole. Sahaja Yoga is here to
solve the problems of others. What am I to
tell you anything? You are saints, that's
all I say, care. If you ask Me any questions,
answer is you are saints. Do what you like.
Whatever you want you will have. Whatever
you say it will happen. Whatever you ask for
it will happen. Whatever you imagine it will
work out, but if you imagine something good
and say something good and do something that
is divine, you are so great. You are made
like that. You are that. Assume. Assume that
power that you are a saint. How can you say
something nonsensical? Nirmala Vidya is at
your disposal, at your complete, I would say,
in fact, Nirmala Vidya, nobody had it except
for you Sahaja Yogis have. Nobody had even
the, Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesh, never even had
it. Can you believe? They had their own powers
but you have Nirmala Vidya and now what do
you want more and then you ask me, "Mother,
should I ring?" or whether, "Should I smile?"
This is (?).
First of all you believe in yourself and then
it will work out. Behave in a confident manner,
in a proper way, and if I say anything, do
not start going into confusion, something
like that. Just understand that what your
Mother is saying is not for Me, for others,
maybe, and if it is for Me I should correct
Myself. Simple thing. If it is for others,
why should I worry? If it is for Me, thank
them very much and I must correct Myself.
It's as simple as that.
A day should come when I don't have to talk.
You have to talk. I hope that I could listen
to all your wise talk as I listen to children
when they tell me something. As I listen to
children when they tell me something. They
are so wise. In the same way I would like
to listen to you, talking all wise things,
nice things, about each other, loving, not
frightened of anyone, very happy, with each
other behaving like great gentlemen and great
gentle ladies, and be very much in love with
each other, looking after each other, not
to be sullen and sulking and stupid faces,
but charming. Charm! I won't use the word
because charming can be horrible. I've heard
that because I would say, but faces that are
lit up with joy, happiness and of dignity.
Such people should be like (?). Loving, affectionate,
smiling, that should be that is what is Sahaja
Yoga. Those who do not want to join are absolutely
(unclear: (to God?). Actually, they are thrown
out. So, to stick onto Sahaja Yoga is difficult.
It is better to understand that to be a Sahaja
Yoga is difficult thing. To be a non Sahaja
yogi is to exist.
So this is what you have been seeking, which
you've got, which you assume, and be happy
and joyous and do not upset others. Do not
disturb others. Don't say harsh things because
Nirmala will get upset ( ?). Be kind to others
and understand. If you need any correction
I am there to tell you. Up to a point I will
tell you. After some time, I'll not. Once
the children are grown up Mother doesn't say
anything. She just sits down and watches the
beauty of her children who are so grown up,
so mature, so beautiful. I hope that time
will come in my lifetime and I will be able
to see such beautiful people around, that
they have grown up, they understand how to
behave, and how to be nice and good.
So for today's New Year let us vow within
ourselves that the selfishness or the self-centeredness
of the smallest in you is finished. Now the
drop has to become the ocean. Live like an
ocean and like a lion. Don't roar at others
and be generous and don't be afraid of others.
Everything is taken care of, but believe that
everything is taken care of. Sometimes you
might feel that you are let down, or you might
feel that this should have happened. Do not
desire for it. Whatever you desire is not
correct, that's all. If the desire is correct
and it's deserving it will happen - one hundred
per cent. So all the best. Have the greatest
year, and happiness and joy. Do your responsibilities.
Understand each other.
And now I'm going. Tomorrow I will be gone,
so-called. Don't worry about anything else
but worry about Sahaja Yoga. That has to be
established all over the world. Very great
work one has done, of course. I mean, you
can't say, one has done as much one can do,
but you can do much more. You can become really
dynamic
and
you can
do it. Try to
think of ways and methods of doing it. May
God bless you. So now with all these dreams
and blues, should we start giving presents
now.