So, the time has come to say farewell to all
of you. I must say this time our Tour has
been really very successful. There have been
no obstructions no problems nothing, except
for one stupid article, we had no problem
and which they are going to look after. On
the whole, we have learnt a lot this time
and I think everybody has been feeling very
much better because of Shivratri Puja. I’ve
got reports from other countries that they
said Mother: ‘What did You do this time
on Shivratri that we all felt so much higher
and better’.
Now the, few things I have to tell you that,
luckily you have a very good National leader
here, who has brought you all round very wise
person, and he is a very gentle as well as
very sensible person, and who has done, such
a good work that really I must say it’s
very remarkable, and now I have decided to
separate his work with National. See we Indians
feel very hot anywhere. We have too much of
sun within us I think. So, there, one has
to be thankful for that, that you have such
a nice leader here. Now I have to tell all
the people specially from Melbourne, that
you should not take things into your hands,
and start another sort of an organization,
arbitrarily doing something under some lady
like that Trish. If you have any problems
you can always write to Me I’ve told so
many times, but Australians don’t write
to Me is My main complaint about them. And
they should not start anything. I’m surprised
that there are so many Indian girls in Melbourne
and they also did not understand that they
have to write to Me.
So, once you are caught up you get lost, you
get vibrations in a very funny way so much
so that I can’t even really treat them in
this short time. So there is a list of people.
Can you bring the list? I’ve made the list
now, please write it down. Is there anybody
from Melbourne here? Yes. Go and tell them,
that you have to get all these people every
day, to sit down, Sunday morning maybe, and
see what sort of vibrations you have. You
can see it on the candle, there’s not to
go anywhere, just on the candle you can understand,
what’s wrong with you, and, you are getting
caught up. I’m surprised that you are supposed
to be Sahaja Yogi how could you not feel the
vibrations of this woman Trish. It took Me
not even a second to know that she is a bhoot.
But there’s a fraternity I think, that’s
why such nice Sahaj Yogis beautiful Sahaj
Yogis, got involved into it. So this is a
very serious thing and I hope this doesn’t
happen next time. Now the list is like this.
I made the list. Can somebody read it for
Me. Please, take it. It’s a serious thing,
otherwise you’ll be lost, I’m telling
you.
Leader: Michael Davies, Jackie Hodge, Peter
Hodge,
Shri Mataji: Go slowly.
Leader: Mother shall we give them a photocopy
of this?
Shri Mataji: Still you read it.
Leader: John Poulianakis, Fred Millar, Ian
Lowry, Greg Bradshaw, Lyndon DeValle, Philip
Noone, Martin Purcell, Colin Berry, Jeff Platford,
Bruno Archello, Glen Pulolovich, Ben Flora,
Savita Noone, Cheryl Bradshaw and Helen Platford.
Shri Mataji: They are all first class Sahaj
Yogis I tell you, all of them. And it’s
really beyond Me, even when he’s reading
the thing I’m getting on the left, you just
see, you’ll feel it, terrible. Getting the
pain here. Now how are they going to be all
right? I’m worried about them.
Now also in Melbourne, I thought I’m sending
a very very good sensible leader. But I don’t
know why people, got after him, and formed
a group outside. If I am sending somebody,
I should know that I know what I am doing.
So you become anti Me or what? So please all
those people, who have got, these problems,
work it out every night, every morning on
the three candle treatment, and you can go
in the garden, sit down there, also say Ganesha’s
mantras. It will take some time for you to
be all right, I can tell you. Even taking
their names you get left swadisthana, aren’t
you getting left swadisthana, the whole left.
This can happen to anyone, because somebody
like that comes up and starts her own. Anything
without the leader should not be done. They
went to such a limit, that they have taken
out the name out of the list of telephone
of these people, can you imagine. This is
too arbitrary, it’s very dangerous. It should
not happen anymore. People are very good at
combining together when it is some sort of
a, negativity. You see if you want to hate
someone, immediately, fundamentalists will
join together to hate someone.
Now for Adelaide I would say, Adelaide has
one problem also people are very arbitrary,
they have given Me lots of trouble before,
and if they want Me to come back, now I have
asked Michael Sweet, because he’s quite
good at organizing, to organize all the people
in Adelaide. And please support him. Now don’t
get after his life now. That shows that the
leaders who are unscrupulous, who are dishonest,
are more appreciated and, can dominate people,
while those who are good nice people, are
to be dominated. So please in Adelaide, unless
and until you have an Ashram I’m not going
to come there. Get an Ashram, all of you shift
to the Ashram and work it out. If twenty-five
people Sahaj Yogis cannot live together, how
do I expect the whole world to be there? Just
think of our vision.
Then Wollongong, another thing, the other
day we had very nice people, I don’t know
how Sahaj Yogis are working out Wollongong.
They have to have, a proper Ashram, no individual
houses. Same in Newcastle. You all can have
a big house. Now these are the best days when
you can take a house on rent. It’s such
a God sent thing now for us, that you can
really get a house for a such a cheap price.
Take a big house outside, outside the city
somewhere, not in the city, and sit down with
your meditation. I hope you must have realized,
that a very great work, we are doing in Sahaj
Yoga, the greatest of greatest, and you are
all part and parcel, of that work. So please
try, to find out methods by which you all
could be closer, and understanding each other,
loving each other. Also beware of Indian girls,
in this respect, they have a tendency, that’s
what everybody’s informing, that they always
want to separate out and Indian boys also.
Otherwise they are all right.
But one of the reasons I know now why it is,
that you see the girls, or the boys, from
the west have led a different type of a life
a very different culture, and we can say it’s
not Sahaj, and they try to tell them, what
kind of a life they have led, and that makes,
them very miserable and they develop a nausea
with that. Then they are frightened. We don’t
have to discuss these things with anyone,
past is past is finished why do you want to
talk of that, filth now? So, nobody has to
discuss about the filth through which they
have come out. Do you mean to say that when
the lotuses come out, do they talk, or do
they smell of the filth out of which they
have come out. No. They spread fragrance.
In the same way now you are lotuses, try to
assume your powers. Even if you put somebody
on the throne and make him king, still he
is in a beggarish way. Everybody comes, he
says; ‘Give me one dollar.’ Then what
to say? It’s the same situation. Now you
are out of it, finished now, so don’t discuss
these dirty things and filthy things, that’s
why these Indians are frightened. Because
there is a cultural difference, and they want
to run away. So if you don’t talk about
it, they’ll be all right. Don’t discuss.
It’s filthy it’s dirty why to discuss
it?
I’ve told hundred times when you are getting
married, not to talk about your past. There’s
no confession and all that in Sahaja Yoga,
you know very well, and people write to Me
and you’ll be surprised twelve pages fourteen
pages, of their confessions. ‘I’m trying
I’m trying’. I don’t read even one word
out of it because immediately I know the filth
is there. Burn it off. So no use writing to
Me also, I don’t want to know. Finished.
I don’t know what is the need for you to
write all these things. There’s no need
to write. All right? After all you are My
children, how you are born, is important than
from where you came is not important. You
are all beautiful people. I’ve already told
you what you are. Believe Me, you can check
out whatever I’ve said is true or not. Also
I’ve told you as I work without taking any
money, you too work without taking any money
don’t you? So please don’t discuss these
things. It’s not worth discussing talking,
filth. If some outsider starts tell them now
we don’t want to talk about. It’s finished
now, it’s gone.
That’s how things are working out now properly.
You see I depend on you very much for one
reason that you are from Ganesha’s country.
If you just know how to forget it, it can
be worked out. You are Shri Ganeshas in the
sense, that you are now innocent. Innocence
is born within you, there’s a fragrance
of innocence. Why do you want to remember
those dirty things. Now I’m telling you
again, if I hear from anyone, that anyone
is discussing this, then we’ll ask them
to get out of Sahaja Yoga. Because why do
they want to remember the filth? Again go
back to the same filth then. All right? This
is not to be done again, please.
So now we’ll come to another point of schooling
the children. I find that, still people are
very money oriented, as far as the school
is concerned. Very money oriented. Very. Now
for Indian schools we have calculated, how
much money will be needed and we have to also,
spend some money for equipping that to equip,
that school. Nobody is eating money there,
for heaven’s sake. As soon as it comes to
Indians immediately we’ll say, he eats money.
And when so many have eaten money in schools
here, Australians, nobody even thought they
will eat money. So, try to understand, is
much less the price that you are paying here,
even for preschool. While, not only it’s
education, but also food, also other amenities
they have to travel and this. There is some
little profit if they get will be good idea
so that we can equip them.
Now we have to build a high school. Who is
going to pay for the building? Is school for
your children, not for Indian children. Who
is going to pay? So that is it. We have to
have for, even for middle school that is after
the sixth of seventh that, what you call this
sixth class you call it or fifth class, we
have to have computer. They have to learn
about computer. Indian schools are not like
this. They have to have a science laboratory.
If you see the subjects they have to learn
you’ll be amazed. English they have to know
grammar very well, they must have proper spellings,
proper handwritings. This is the minimum,
I’m saying the minimum of minimum. My grandson
was studying in a school, it’s a very well
know school [INDIAN NAME] School and they
were paying much more there it’s a very
famous… We have private schools which we
call them as public schools and they’re
all, somewhere away from the cities. He was
paying much more. But when he joined another
school in Delhi, which is a day scholar, he
had to pay seventy-five thousand rupees only
to enrol himself, and every month he is paying
ten thousand rupees when he is just a day
scholar, in Delhi.
And this school is going to be much better,
much more equipped, various things we’ll
be doing. But every time I find such a money
orientation about schools. Same about preschool
I’ve seen it. See we must understand that
children are to be educated by us. The first
thing is you should never doubt the teachers,
no way. You must respect. This is what is
lacking in your education here. That’s why
children have no respect for anyone.
I told you the story, again I’ll tell you
the same story. That my father, had a, generous
habits of educating boys from poor classes.
That all we do, if we have money we just don’t
put it for ourselves and indulge into it but,
we always try to help our poor relations or
poor people. So he always had four five boys
studying. They stayed in our house and they
looked after them. One of them, did his matriculation
then he was doing his intermediate. He felt
little obliged and he said: ‘Sir if you
allow me I would like to teach your children’.
He said: ‘All right go ahead’. We had
two, gates to enter the house one, which went
through the, courtyard another through his
office. One day I don’t know why he came
through his office and immediately my father
stood up for him. Know he was extremely embarrassed
you see, he didn’t know, just thought, everybody
got up. Who is this gentleman has come? Then
he went inside, and he told My mother that:
‘I touch your feet but tell Sahib not to
get up for me it is too much I can’t just
bear it’. My father came in and he said:
‘Why should you be embarrassed? If I don’t
respect you, then my children won’t respect
you.’ You must try to be nobler people,
it’s ignoble habits, should be given up
otherwise your children will be ignoble.
Now whatever has to be paid to the teachers
has to be paid. Apart from that sometimes,
you must in the presence of children you must
try to give them some presents or some flowers,
respect them. That’s what they do in India,
and why most of the rich people donate money.
Absolutely if they have more money they donate,
money to the schools, that’s a sign of a
noble person. For a Sahaja Yogi it is important.
Supposing now we have somebody who doesn’t
have money or maybe not a job, and he cannot
educate. Now this is a good Sahaja Yogi who
has been in Sahaja Yoga for two three years,
has been giving realizations to people but
he doesn’t have a job. It’s our duty in
a way, to support his children to be educated.
See when this hand is self-supporting is all
right. I mean this is self-supporting is all
right, but in case it needs the support of
this, this has to give the support.
As we call scholarships or sometimes we call,
now we have got at least five or six children
in our school there, who are absolutely free,
absolutely. Food, some of them I am supporting,
some of them Yogi’s supporting and some
of them are absolutely free, absolutely hundred
percent. Will not tell you the names. Their
food their clothes everything and nobody knows.
We don’t want them to develop a feeling
[INAUDIBLE around?]. So all the time, to be
very calculating about things is bad. I’ve
seen a complete, manifesto typed [INAUDIBLE]
I don’t know what, about having a committee
on top of this little preschool. That is not
proper. It’s conditioning, everything, even
if you have to put these, balloons you’ll
have a committee. This committee on top of
that another committee another. Trust, trust
and trust. We have now one committee I had
to do it, is called as the finance committee
all right. They are all audits, experts and
accountants and they will be here in Sydney.
That doesn’t mean Sydney is dominating as
someone. Some subjects have to be central,
as in any government. That you should understand,
and that these can go and see your accounts
if they’re all right or not. But nobody
has to dominate in Sahaja Yoga, we have to
help support and trust.
Now in this preschool I find there are only
seven children of that age group who are studying.
There are smaller children also. I have suggested
to him that why not use this area for the
school there’s a school there. And I would
like children to be in My Room than anybody
else. So use this. You save money like that
and children will feel comforted. Everybody
should see if they have time what can I do
for children, can I come and help you. Instead
of that, how much money you spend this that.
You see there’s no income tax in Sahaja
Yoga, is there? We want to get rid of these
kind of things. Everybody feels frightened
and insecure, all the time. Forget about these
things. Trust. You don’t know how many thousands
of dollars I’ve lost, by trusting people.
Thousands. But we have to trust. What can
you do? We have to pay for our principles.
The main principle is trusting and not to
ask about money where is what what is right.
The second is a very bad situation here is,
because every parent can go and interfere
with the teacher. Because they think they
are paying for it. You’ll spoil your children
completely. Should never never interfere with
the teachers, never. With the school. I mean
if you don’t have money all right. Again
you can have a committee, to find out if they
really don’t have money or not. But if somebody
says I have no money I have no job all right.
Somebody should help them But it should not
be a kind of a police force behind these teachers,
or behind the school or behind the leader.
Where is the money gone where is that gone
this that? Those who worry too much of money
will never have money I tell you. Though I
lose money quite a lot, but I get double I
tell you, never a problem. I never have a
problem of money, never never never. One must
trust.
I’ll tell you one example, very nice example,
which shows how Sahaja Yoga works out things.
I went down to Rome, and we wanted to start
a school in Rome. We saw the land everything
is very nice, but we had to deposit the money
immediately. And Guido said: ‘Mother we
need about sixteen thousand pounds worth of
liras to deposit this’. I said: ‘I don’t
know if I have that money with Me in the bank
or not. I’ll have to see, but doesn’t
matter’. I reached the airport and I was
leaving. Suddenly, Sandra came with a packet
and she said: ‘Mother this I have saved
for You’. I said: ‘What is this?’ ‘This
is money, liras’. I said: ‘But why I don’t
need I don’t take any money why why do you
give Me?’. Suddenly it struck Me. ‘How
much it is? What is the value?’ She said:
‘Sixteen thousand pounds’. I said: ‘That’s
it’. So I got that money from her. I said:
‘All right give Me give Me I’ll take it,
and give it to Guido’. I said: ‘Guido
go and book your… He booked that. Then it
so happened that, the whole thing fizzled
out, and he got back his money again, like
a bad penny.
So we were starting this Shudy Camps. I went
there. Guido said: ‘Mother don’t change
your money. I have got all these liras with
me. All the things that I had to buy were
bathroom fittings and all the, what you call
the wc’s and all that, plus the, all the
marble and all the curtains and what not,
every sort of thing. And do you know, in one
day I did all that, for such a big place like
Shudy, in one day, really. It was a fast movement.
And after that, I told them that you pay them
and send Me the bill what ever it is. I also
gave them hundred pounds more I said: ‘These
curtains are very nice also get some more
for Me maybe, because they’re dark shade’.
And can you imagine when the bill came it
was sixteen thousand one hundred pounds. Exactly.
So I had forgotten about hundred. I said:
‘How is it sixteen thousand, what have you
done? Must be some manipulation’. They said:
‘Mother no it’s, grace of God it has worked
out’. I said: ‘Then this one hundred from
where?’ ‘It’s Yours. You gave us. You
forgot, this is Yours’. Then we bought the
land and sold it for double the price and
now they have an Ashram.
But where people are stingy about money, think
about money, things do not work out. And also
worth knowing, when we bought these two very
big Ashrams in Rome, I don’t know if anybody
has seen them, here, very big, two Ashrams
we’ve got them. That too, I told him just
be on the lookout. So he said: ‘Mother there
is one advertisement for a house, nearer the
main road or something’. I said: ‘Main
road won’t be good’. ‘No no it’s quite
in the inside but it’s away from the main
city. I said: ‘Have you seen it?’ ‘No’.
I said: ‘I have no time now, you’re telling
Me now, and I have to catch the plane’.
He said: ‘Mother I had no time to tell You’.
Luckily that day we heard that the plane was
cancelled because there was some trouble.
I said: ‘Very good, now we have got one
day’. I said: ‘Can you talk to the owner
and ask him if he would like to show Me the
place’. The owner accepted, and We went
there about, three o’clock, reached there
about three. My plane was about eight, to
India. So immediately I saw this, and that
amount which we had spent, I mean, for the
buying of the land had doubled and we could
buy both the houses. And it’s such a big
land. Immediately I said: ‘Buy it now.’
We bought it and I caught My plane and went
to India.
Nobody will believe that in such a short time
we got that beautiful, it’s a very very
beautiful school, and also very beautiful
area. Just see it worked out. So I have a
feeling that, when you start worrying about
money it slips out somehow, nothing works
out. To feel the grace is to leave everything
to God, now you do it I don’t know. You’ll
be amazed how things work out. It’s beautifully,
it works out and you’re amazed because that’s
how you know that you have the blessings,
how God has blessed you. Money is what, is
the dust of His Feet. So, I told you when
I came these people Customs troubled Me I
said: ‘I don’t know what they are going
to have now here in recession’. But doesn’t
matter. It’s not going to affect you at
all, if you are in a witness state you can
see all that, and things will work out, everybody
will have sufficient money, but don’t worry.
And the more money people have, the more they
are worried about money I have seen that.
Those who have less in any case they know
that they have less so what is there to worry,
like Me.
But about school now, we have three classes
and I’ve already talked to Stephan, let
him solve the problem. If you find anything
wrong, you can tell them, but no parents should
go and disturb the teachers, absolutely. You
have no right to do that. Even I would say,
Indian school. Nicely all the people go, stay
there this, in which school is it allowed
like this? After this, all those who have
to see their children have to stay in a hotel
and see them only on a particular date which
is being told that you have to see. You’ll
be disturbing your children all the time.
It’s not that anybody can go anytime live
there nicely, and interfere with the working
of the school. We have to bring some system
into it, otherwise your children will suffer.
Even the Dharamshala school was really absolutely
there were a visitation, of all these bhootish
people, they tortured the lives of these teachers
there. This is never done.
So now next time, nobody is going to go there
like this. I have told him, that if they’re
going to Dharamshala then they should stay
in a hostel, and the children can also stay
with you, not hostel we can call it a kind
of a, inn or it is a, can call it, what is
it a, it’s not a big hotel but a kind of
a inn sort of thing. You can take your children
there with you, but you should not go to the
school all the time, and sit with them, because
even there they have to study. The trouble
is, Indian standards are very high. All the
children, though they have holidays, only
take holidays for one month and the rest of
the time they are all studying. You’ll see
how your children will improve, they don’t
know even how to spell c-a-t cat. Because
of the interference of the parents children
are so bad. So now if you have real love for
your children allow them to grow properly,
and you’ll see how they’ll come up.
Another thing they have no immunity for anything.
Like if there’s any jaundice, they are the
first to get it, if there’s malaria they
are the first to get it, if there’s typhoid
they are first to get it. While Indian children
have that immunity, because I have seen here
also, everybody is carrying the child. Don’t
touch the child all the time. Keep the child
away from your body, has that, warmth which
goes to the child also. Yes sometimes you
have to look after the child, the child must
know you love the child, but all the time
carrying the child like this, I have seen
many ladies who are in my lecture also, doing
like this. Why what is the need? You make
the child so much conditioned, and the child
cannot remain quiet unless you do like this.
Massage the child nicely. Massaging is very
good. You should massage yourselves also,
but at least the child. Let them learn how
to take bath everyday. Everyday they must
be cleansed, so that they develop the habit
of cleanliness. They never wash their hands,
they don’t want to wash their hands, and
their hands smell, they just use paper. Whatever
you tell them they’ll use paper never wash
their hands. The hands smell, mouth smells.
With all your development, children have no
sense of personal cleanliness.
We have to know that they’re born-realized
children, and that they have to have, a very
different type of attitude towards life, as
the same way as the parents have to have,
a very different attitude towards the school.
It’s a very patronizing, and you should
be proud that you have such a school here.
Thank God, they are not in the same mess as
you have been. It’s so much protection to
them. So change your attitude entirely about
the schools, about the children, and look
after them as if you are their trustees. They
are in your trust and also, they should know
that you love them very much, as anybody else
also loves them. They must learn how to respect.
They must have good manners.
This can be done when the children are here,
because they don’t know how to say namaste,
they don’t want to say thank you, they don’t
want to say sorry, nothing of the kind. All
the time they’ll go on asking why, why,
and the Indian teachers start looking, Indian
children would not. Here they have no right
to ask. They will all be brats here, I tell
you all the children who are going to all
these schools whether private or to the municipal
schools. But the other schools that are where
there’s, horrible schools are there here
I know. Because anybody who comes from those
schools, we don’t want to admit them. We
have had three of them, we sent them back.
It’s cheaper all right, but we can’t admit.
Three children have been sent away. If you
feel that you must share your money with your
children, then see that they get proper education,
proper grounding. Of course I am going to
make a proper complete sketch of how with
the teachers, how to deal with the children,
how to make them understand, how to put them
into proper way.
But this is a very important age from three
to five years I think. Till one year they
should be with the mother and father. But
mother should not too much also all the time,
handle the child, and should look after the
child, in a way as if it is in her trust,
massage the child, look after the child. I’ve
seen some children just go on crying. I don’t
know maybe the mothers must have been very
unhappy, when they were bearing the child
maybe they had a bad time, with the mother-in-law
maybe with the husband whatever it is. All
the time crying. All right that can be corrected,
but they are our property and we have to look
after them. But again I say that doesn’t
mean, that a mother should expect others to
give bath or look after them all the time
it’s not so. So I hope you’ll use your
discretion now as far as your children are
concerned. I am very much concerned about
them.
Now the story goes about, people start talking
like that. About the Indian school there’s
lot of criticism. I would like to know how
much you have paid for the school, to build.
It’s only your children studying there,
nobody else’s. How much money did you pay
to buy the land? Nobody enquired. How much
it has cost to build this school? Nobody enquired.
But if you are sending about, ten dollars
for their food and everything. Hundred and
fifty dollars for four weeks, where they eat
their food, live there, they have all facilities,
everything, plus their education. But that
will be very much discussed. You have to know
that it’s a very big headache to teach the
western children in India because every money
has to be accounted for our FERanies Foreign
Exchange Regulations, and every six months
we have to give the report, to the Reserve
Bank of India, how we are spending this foreign
exchange. And they are experts. Despite all
that, the people loose-tonguers are saying:
‘Somebody is eating the money there’.
It’s very difficult, you don’t know, to
manage the western children in India, first
of all as they are, and then secondly, that
the government is on top of our head, they’re
sitting.
Then third is about food. Your children are
used to tinned foods. Like they’ll say we
want baked beans in the morning. We want this,
we want that, every child wants something
else. Now the people will go crazy cooking
for all of them separately. You have agreed
to such a thing, all right you want this habit.
You should not compromise: ‘No, better eat
this’. He won’t eat today, he’ll eat
tomorrow. Whatever is cooked for everybody
in the family please have it. And these tinned
fruits I am absolutely against it and I am
sure you also don’t want them to have tinned
fruits. They want to have, fried fish and
baked beans and potato chips. That’s all
they know about food nothing more, or less.
So don’t send them any tinned fruits, foods,
tinned fruits. I think you better not send
them any food, is a better idea. Because if
you send them chocolates, their liver will
be spoiled. They are getting everything there,
so please if you have to give you can give
them clothes or anything, but not something
to eat. Somebody brought lots of chocolates.
That’s how they got this, problem. Chocolates
should be avoided for children up to some
age, and also ice cream, but ice cream still
is not so much fat, but chocolate specially.
You can have lollipops and all those things
they are perfectly all right, lollies are
all right.
Be careful as to what habits you give to them.
And tinned food should never be given to children.
It’s very bad. There’s some preservation,
and for that preservation they put some chemicals
and that’s why the children are very susceptible.
They have no immunity. It’s easy to get
fresh things here. Not difficult specially
in Australia, you have no problem. Get them
fresh things, fresh fruits, fresh food. You
should give them. If you form that habit and
not from restaurants and thing. See everything
you get it in the market bring it home, and
just shove it into thing and give them. No.
For children be careful. Once you spoil their
stomachs it’s difficult to make them all
right. So be very very careful as to what
kind of food you are giving, even if you have
to give something, then you should read what
is in it you see. If there are anything artificial
things please try to avoid. These are very
precious children we have, and we have to
look after them.
Again and again I would request you, to be
very kind, to Me by looking after them in
a proper sensible manner, till they are with
you. Also you have to give them some discipline.
It’s very important. By giving them self-esteem:
‘You are Sahaja Yogis you are this’. If
you give them, they have no self-esteem at
all. If you give them the self-esteem you’ll
be surprised they’ll start behaving very
well. By saying that see: ‘You are special
children, you are Sahaj Yogis, you can’t
behave like that,’ how they have to be.
There has to be some discipline, otherwise
at the age of six years you cannot start,
and even if you start it, it takes some time.
It’s exhausting, absolutely exhausting.
Some children are very exhausting.
So I hope you’ll remember this. We have
to be kind and nice, discreet, sweet to them,
but first we should know what is going to
be helpful to them, what is benevolent for
them. And just some book comes about children,
you read it, done. In Sahaja Yoga you don’t
have to read all such books. I’m already
going to write and I’ve already told you
these things. Just in a wider way, you use
your discretion. After all you are all realized
souls and the spirit within you, can see in
the light of that, what is good for your child.
But avoid tinned food as far as possible.
Anything tinned is horrible and please don’t
take that for your children. I think you people
all need not also have tinned food what is
the need?. This cancer and all that so rampant,
in the west. In India, thank God at least
what ever poor they may be they don’t eat
tin food. We can’t afford. In tin food is
more expensive in India than fresh food, because
tin is expensive, luckily.
All right, so now this is we have done, I
have a little present for your, leader. You’re
an inch short of one pen, so I borrowed his,
and he said that: ‘Mother You have already
given me a pen’. I forget. I hope I have
never given you a watch. I never gave you
a watch so you can’t say anything. All right
this is one and today is his wife’s birthday.
So let us sing something for her, and a little
present for her. May God bless. What a nice
day to be here when it’s your birthday.
May God bless.
Now last but not the least, very important
thing is that the senior people in Sahaja
Yoga should not be called by their names.
We can say Uncle or something Uncle Tom, is
to be done. It’s very important, and even
I’ve heard some Indian girls calling somebody:
‘John’. I said: ‘What? He’s like your
father. How can you call like that?’ ‘Our
husbands insist.’ No, please, call them
with some sort of a uncle and aunty. Shouldn’t
say like that, it’s not proper, doesn’t
look nice. Or address to elders always: ‘Sir’
is a better idea. Shows you have some culture.
We are not brats, first of all. And also we
are not people who are hippies, you see. We
have to respect the elders. Very important,
it is that we have to respect all the elders,
that are within you. That’s how you will
be respected also. See to it that those ladies
or gentlemen who are senior people always
call them by, either ‘Mr’ or ‘Uncle’
or ‘Aunt’.
He was all the time with Me but I somehow
or other sneaked out tying. Ah beautiful.
Suits your hand very well. It’s really very
[INAUDIBLE] Very very [INAUDIBLE] All right,
so on a very happy note we should end up now.
Feel very sorry that I have to leave you all
here, and there are people waiting, as you
know in the eastern Asian countries for Me,
counting every minute, so I have to go.
Leader: Shri Mother before you go. It’s
not quite over. We have a little presentation
for You.
Shri Mataji: Ah no. You see you can’t…
Leader: Although it is Your…
Shri Mataji: It’s not My Birthday.
Leader: No Shri Mataji. But as it is the month
of March Shri Mother we feel that we can celebrate
Your Birthday in a small way but…
Shri Mataji: You have already given Me. Oh
chandan.
Leader: First we would like to..
Shri Mataji: Oh maa. It’s the, beautiful.
How can I blow so many candles. I think you’d
better do it for Me.
Leader: It’s a map of Australia Shri Mother.
Shri Mataji: Is it? Ah.
Leader: Including Tasmania.
Shri Mataji: May God bless you all. Thank
you very much. So beautiful it is. So beautiful.
Now come along, all the children, come along,
do for Me. This side also. I’ll be entering
now My seventy years of age. This is beautiful.
He will have to read it out. What’s that
supposed to be?
Leader: This is the card. To Our Beloved Mother,
it is You Who is our Shield. It is You Who
is the Focus of our devotion. It is You who
as Head of Your world wide Sahaja Family,
draws us together envelops us with love and
concern for one another. Beloved Shri Mataji
we your children of the great south land,
wish you a happy, gracious and triumphant
beginning to your seventieth year. On behalf
of all your children I bow to Your Lotus Feet.
Shri Mataji: And the second part also. Very
nice.
Leader: A little piece on the side. We vow
to You to spread Your work, to live the precepts
of Sahaj. We vow to You to live as one, a
great society of saints at large.
Shri Mataji: Thank you very much. Beautiful,
beautiful. Children, you must see what Austrians
have sent Me is beautiful things, and they
wanted Me to be there for My Birthday but
I don’t know how I’ll do it. In any case
you can have a look at the way they have wished
Me. Oh, this is very beautiful. Children have
done it? Oh My. What’s that?
Leader: I’m not sure Shri Mother. I’m
trying to find my way into it.
Shri Mataji: Prohibited. So beautiful it is.
It’s too much, much too much. I don’t
know what to say because, pearls are, the
Adoration of the Sahasrara you know that.
There are stones on different chakras of which,
every chakra is made and the pearls are for
the Sahasrara. So beautiful of you to think
of that. It’s very kind. Thank you. Thank
you very much. Now you’ve bought it but
I’m now going to cancel also pearls from
My list.
Leader: And one final thing Shri Mother You
travel so much You have so many things to
remember we noticed You looked at one of these
and You thought it might be useful.
Shri Mataji: Ah. I’ll need somebody to operate
it. Just imagine. Budget planning period.
What a joke. Now then this, morning meetings.
As soon as You come out of Your bed it starts.
Then lunch engagements. Plan next meetings.
Then interviews. Finished.
Leaders: Not for those Shri Mother but for
telephone numbers and, all those sort of things
that You have to keep somewhere.
Shri Mataji: It’s quite a lot of things
I must say. I am very bad at, but somebody
has to look after it, because I don’t understand,
how will I work it out. [HINDI] Two thousand
five hundred ninety names and numbers, and
one thousand eight hundred and twenty scheduled
appointments. Large forty character by eight
line display. What are these characters are?
Leader: We have one appointment to put in
there straight away Shri Mother and that is
for the early part of next year in Australia.
Shri Mataji: Oh My. And the best part is,
that built in help, screens available, for
major functions at the touch of a button but
how do you find the button. You see these
buttons are so soft You just touch anywhere,
they work. All right so thank you very much
I hope I’ll learn something. Thank you very
much thank you. What these are doughnuts?
Yogi: Profiteroles. Profiteroles.
Shri Mataji: Oh. Oh My. Nobody has eaten so
far I’m the only One. [INAUDIBLE] Thank
you very much. I must thank you all for really
making everyday new things for Me, taking
so much trouble looking after Me so well.
I feel very comfortable, all the time with
My children and, I was driven around in a
very comfortable car. I’ve really enjoyed.
And I don’t look as if I’ve done the tour
already, I’m quite fresh.
Leader: Disappeared strangely Shri Mother
none of us know quite how it came about
but it’s all bits of Australia. We thought
You might like it. It’s a calendar. Of the
Snowy Mountains. Doesn’t look real does
it.
Shri Mataji: It’s very nice. What colors,
very colorful country. Just imagine. Unbelievable.
Thank you very much, thank you. It’s beautiful.
Thank you very much, beautiful photographs.
I will take your leave now.