Very happy to be back here in Melbourne, after
such a long gap, and everybody's grown up
so much; nice to see you all so healthy, beautiful
and joyous. Of course I feel sad about the
ashram that
we have lost, that we should not have lost
the ashram. But whatever has happened you
can't help it; but it's important for Sahaja
Yoga that we have to live together. I also
told the same thing in Perth, that try to
get a big place, because you know your children
are there, and you all are there, and if you
are together, negativity runs away. It has
such a tremendous force, an ashram has a tremendous
force. When you live together, you help each
other, you understand each other, you know
so many things, you learn so many things from
each other and, it could be done very easily,
once you start enjoying the collectivity.
Human being is a social being. He is not a
person who wants to live in a -- single way.
That's why if you jail someone, if somebody's
in jail, it becomes a punishment. Though in
the jail you have all the conveniences, everything
is there, on the contrary you don't have to
work so hard, you get your food all right,
everything is fine, somebody cooks for you.
But it's a punishment.
And for our ascent is very important to be
collective. It's said that wherever you are
together I reside there[with you?]. But human
nature is funny. In some places collectivity
has acted very well, like in Austria and we
have the best ashram in Austria. Now they
have about five, six ashrams there, one better
than the other. In itself in Vienna we have
I think four ashrams, and it's growing so
well. Nobody wants to live alone, so anxious
to join, come back to ashrams; and so many
problems are solved otherwise also on very
material level. Everything gets shared, you
don't have to pay too much money. Now if you
are living alone, then sometimes you feel
like spending your money here, there and at
the end of the day no money is left out. But
in the ashram you know how much to pay.
Then there are some people who want to buy
-- I mean on a material level -- something
very exorbitant, something great and this
and that, and nobody to control that, that
desire that need. As a result, we become extravagant,
so much so that you are left with nothing.
Exactly this happened in Perth. I know of
people who had money, and when they took their
houses and they're living there, they have
no money at all. I said, 'Why?' He said, 'For
food we spend so much and then need to go
and get this and do this,' and the whole day
they are busy working it out -- on individual
basis. There's no time for meditation. There's
no time for listening to My tapes, no time
for anything. And everybody has gone down
so much in vibrations there that I was really
shocked. Perth was one of the places I felt
was a very good place. It's so open and so
clean and so nice; and what are you doing
-- going out shopping, buying this cloth,
that cloth, this dress, that dress and piles
in the house, because that fashion was the
other day.
In Sahaja Yoga there's a Sahaja fashion. We
don't change our dresses every day in Sahaja
Yoga. Every year we buy whatever is needed.
That's all. And Australia specially, being
such an expensive place, I mean, I think this
is one of the most expensive nations I've
seen -- the most expensive. First I used to
think Helsinki, Finland is the most expensive
but now I've gone just to buy these shoes,
I've walked for hours together to get the
pair of shoes here. In India you can get it
in no time and I've paid at least three times
more that I would pay, even in London and
at least four times more that I would pay
in Italy. In India I need not tell, you know
that very well.
So if you -see it's a kind of a time that
you have that if you start doing this, doing
that. And the essence of all that is what?
Is to please others. We buy good clothes to
please others; want to have nice curios to
please others; want to decorate our house
to please others; we don't do it for ourselves,
do we? So then there is not the other -- like
we were staying in London and there were seven
houses, and everybody was busy you see, cleaning,
sweeping, swabbing, doing all the lawns, everything
and polishing all the brass and everything
in those houses. But not even a rat would
enter that house. I said, 'For whom are they
doing it? I don't know'. Poor things, they
are working so hard, nobody to see it. And
that's how they become extremely depressed
and unhappy.
This depression you don't find among Indians
at all because their houses are open, anybody
can walk in, have food, walk out. You will
not know whose house, to whom it belongs.
Then this depression walks in. Is a psychological
thing, because human beings are social beings.
You must understand the essence of [INAUDIBLE].
You can never be happy living alone. And this
aloofness and this individualism has brought
this kind of a new thing which we call as
tensions and as depressions and then go to
schizophrenia. There's not a single case of
schizophrenia I have seen in India -- not
a single case. Ah some people become lunatics
but lunatics are there and they are put in
the jail. There are very few lunatics.
Now, in England the lunatics are so many,
and so many schizophrenics that they have
said: "Now we'll not have any more, let them
be with the society. If they live with the
society they'll be all right". So now they
are starting a society of people who would
like to stay with lunatics and the lunatics
have improved, living with society. Even here
they will start after some time, that allow
the lunatics to live with the people. Talk
to them nicely. Because, how do we live? With
love, with rapport. We can't live alone. That's
a little bit of a, idea we have that, 'This
is my house, this is my this thing, this is
my...' But you rise above a little bit and
then you'll say, 'It's so nice to decorate
the ashram, it's for everyone.' Do good to
others, so everybody says, 'What a nice thing
it is'. Now see such a nice house [man's name?]
has got. If he had not come you would not
have seen it. She would have worked so hard,
poor thing, nobody would have appreciated
it.
And this idea of 'my-ness' and 'I-ness' has
to be given up in Sahaja Yoga, then you will
know what is joy is; and then you will write
to Me, 'Mother, we are all swimming in the
Ocean of Joy'. Matter is just -- you know
you'll be surprised -- matter is only for
expression of love and for nothing else. They
all call Me very generous but you don't know
I am very selfish because I enjoy Myself by
giving it to others, that's the greatest enjoyment
for Me. But this time I had gathered so many
things for you, and they told Me, 'Don't bring
anything to Australia'. Look at this country
-- funny one -- they don't allow any presents
to be brought here for people whom I want
to give and enjoy My generosity.
So that is what it is that when we understand
the essence, now we are on the essence because
we are on the Kundalini. Then we must know
the essence of joy. And the joy is in sharing.
But here people share which should not be
shared, their privacy. Where they have to
be private they are not. Just the other way
round. I shouldn't say that but is a fact
you know it for definite. You see even Mrs.
Thatcher said that, 'It's our culture that
women must expose their body.' Can you imagine
Mrs. Thatcher saying that? But I heard with
My Own ears. So whatever is to be shared is
not shared, whatever is not to be shared is
shared, and if you say, 'Why are you sharing?'
'You are jealous, you are very small-minded,
you are very narrow-minded, you are very selfish'.
As Sahaja Yogis you can see it because you
have the witness power, you can see it clearly.
You have that Divine eyesight, you can see
that clearly, that this is this thing, just
the opposite. Of course you don't have to
take sannyasa. You don't have to do all these
stupid things, but you have to enjoy the collectivity.
This is the culture of Sahaja Yoga. And now
if you people cannot live together, how do
I expect the whole world to live together?
Of course there are problems, because of our
ideas, not because there's something wrong
with collectivity. I told them this morning
the same thing I would like to tell you: that
the first thing is when we start looking at
others we try to gather the thorns, 'What's
wrong with that another person,' instead of
gathering the flowers. If you want to gather
the thorns, all right, go ahead. I mean how
can you get flowers then? As simple as that.
It's a very simple mathematics. But if you
want to have flowers you should see to the
beauty of another person, glory of another
person, the better side of it. And those who
cannot see it, can never enjoy another person.
And the Sahaja Yogis can enjoy each other
very well. It's so sweet it is and so beautiful
that you all can live together like that.
I wish I could, all the time, with you all.
But it's not in My Fate I have to travel from
one place to another. I left them there. I
was so much wrenched in My Heart really and
I was so heavy that I just closed My eyes
trying to get over it; and there I find all
the flowers smiling at Me at the airport and
whole thing finished. Neutralized. I said,
'Now these were also waiting. After all I
have to come for them, here.'
So you see this love, this affection, this
deeper understanding that we have, within
ourselves, that we are in love with each other,
where can we express? In a house which is
separate, the housewife is busy with the household,
man is busy with another thing. But doing
it together is such a beauty, and that's what
has happened to Australia today. As it is
Australia is such a cut-off place, from the
whole world, is more necessary that you should
ask for collectivity here. Even to come, even
from Perth to here took three hours for us;
such a vast country so separated from each
other. When you are separated you come closer
to each other, very much more. Try to understand
your essence and I think now your attitudes
will change and next time I should come to
an ashram here. That's what I want. All of
you if you work it out you can do it. After
all there is paramachaitanya working on it.
But is a common case with people that they
don't want to live collectively. It's very
common case. But those who enjoy, you see,
their Spirit cannot enjoy life without living
together. Because Spirit is the collective
being. It is a collective being. It's nature
it is a collective being. That's the trouble.
So you can't be in the water as well as in
the boat. And either you have to be spiritually
inclined, or you should be in the Spirit or
in the body. And for your ascent is very important.
We have to establish very good ashrams, where
you can also have a center down below or something.
All of you put together can manage that, I
know that very well. If it is decided you
can do it. If you need any help I am willing
to help you. This Kew thing, I don't know
why it fizzled out. The man became very greedy
or whatever it is. But this was a very beautiful
place, I enjoyed it very much thoroughly there.
Also sometimes it happens that somebody becomes
despotic, somebody becomes dictatorial, some
things happen like that, but it will pass
out. But once you break away, it will be difficult
for you to come together. You'll find excuses,
'I have got this work', the another will say,
'I have that job', 'I have to do this'. Everything
can be done collectively much better. Just
now see I was talking to him, one minute,
before, but I didn't know what he was doing.
I said, 'What do you do?' He said, 'Government
service,' 'What kind?' He said, 'Immigration.'
I said, 'That's it. I wanted you.' Not for
My immigration, but for John Watkinson, and
he's worrying Me too much because poor fellow,
John Watkinson, you know; you know John Watkinson
very well -- how beautifully he works out
everything, you know that very well. And he's
in trouble. He can't get his wife in England.
So I want him to immigrate here. I was talking
to him and he gave Me very good idea. Supposing
we were not together, I would not have done
anything. Immediately you see, as soon as
a problem comes up, they say, 'All right,
so this place, there is someone like that,
Mother can we take her?'
All over the world we have people. It's like
one big body. And as soon as there's problem
with the eyes, some hand is there to help
us. That's how we are going to work it out.
Do you understand the importance of Sahaja
Yoga, at this juncture? It's not 'by the way',
it's very important, extremely important thing.
I don't know if you really know about it.
Such work was never done in the history of
Spirituality, in the history of this world,
or universe whatsoever. And this kind of a
masse transformation that is taking place,
which is going to transform the whole world.
But just the opposite of us are Russians.
Russians are tremendous people.
Now we have a house, big, huge house, in Russia.
I've been there only twice, once for eight
days, another time for two days, and they
are so dynamic and so spiritually evolved,
I cannot describe to you, when I went there
in Leningrad, there were two thousand people
inside the hall, and two thousand sitting
outside, and I didn't know what to do with
them. After all lecture, program -- it lasted
for two hours or so, two and a half hours,
when I came out all two thousand were still
outside waiting. It touched My Heart really.
Said: 'But Mother what about us?' I said:
'All right, tomorrow you come along here outside
I'll see you, all of you, I must meet you
tomorrow.' So the two thousand who were inside
and the two thousand who were outside -- all
were there on the grounds and all of them
are there now in Sahaja Yoga. The follow-up
we had to take in the same hall.
Now they've found a house for us, anything
you want. Even their ministers. They gave
us an independent chart. There's no organization
from outside Russia has got an independent
chart. We can do what we like. They are willing
to pay for My ticket, for the ticket who comes
with Me and they are going to pay for My hotels
and they are going to do everything. Tremendous
personality and they might one day become
the greatest Spiritual people -- the way they
are. But they had to learn collectivity through
their training of communism, that has come
handy. Though there are many defects of communism
no doubt, but the greatest advantage they
had is the collectivity; to know to share.
And that's why it has worked. I've been thinking
"Why is it so much?" Of course they have no
conditioning of religions and things, they
all divide us, religions this that. But there
is one thing that is so great about them is
that they are very collectively conscious.
I mean we all went there, forty-five of them
just jumped in, from all over the world to
come to Russia because very interesting now.
You won't believe they looked after us like
lords, gave them food, this, make all arrangements.
Where My program was there was a big dinner
they threw; not a single pie we had to pay
them. I mean there was no organization there,
nothing; no Sahaja Yoga, nothing. Only Oleg
was there; nothing in Leningrad- and Oleg
was actually in Moscow, and even to touch
the platform on which I was sitting there
was a big cue and when I went away also they
were touching the platform, can you imagine.
They said: "We have never heard of such a
thing, it's such a great thing. I cannot believe
it there such a thing exists." And they're
all very well-educated people.
They are scientists, lots of scientists, doctors,
architects, businessmen, all kinds of things.
And the ministers of the Supreme Council.
What do you say? They came to my program.
They all touched My Feet. I said: "What world
is this?" And they haven't got this sense
that you are a minister or anything; everybody
just the same. Of course that's the thanks
to communism. But communism has given them
something very very great and that is collectivity;
they know how to share. I just really didn't
know to really measure out their potential,
really, I couldn't make out. They're all waiting
for Me there.
They made a film out of Me already, and they
showed it and all the film had nothing but
vibrations and some light tuck tuck on people
and all that. So that film became very popular,
they made a lot of money out of that. All
that they have given to Sahaja Yoga now. And
first only they brought lot of money I said:
"Why? For what?"
They said: "For Sahaja Yoga."
I said: "I don't need any money just now."
Lot of money.
"No but we've saved this for You, we saved
for You.
I said: "But you never knew".
When I was going for this another seminar,
this Yoga seminar My husband said: "What's
the use of going there now? You've been there
eight days now. Again for the seminar? Anybody
can look after".
I said: "I have to go."
He said: "Why?"
"To break the Eastern Block."
He said: "How will You break?"
I said: "There will be all of them there in
the seminar."
Really it happened. They gave Me only forty-five
minutes. I spoke for thirty minutes and for
fifteen minutes I gave them Realization. See,
and in that fifteen minutes all of these were
from all East Germany, from Czechoslovakia,
Poland; everybody was there. All of them walked
with Me out; there was nobody left in the
hall for any other lectures, and they gave
Me their addresses. "You must come to Poland,
You must come to this, You must come to East
Germany." And just after that this triggering
took place and they all started. But they
must be very powerful means, that's the point
you must remember. From every country there
could be ten or fifteen people who could have
attended this. All together there were only
three hundred delegates. And in Romania also
[spacing] I found people were very spiritual,
and I said: "Romania will be all right. Don't
you worry." It has happened there also. They
have broken the whole shackles. Then came-
before that was the Hungary, you see; they
said: "What about Hungary, Mother?"
I said: "Let there be one Sahaja Yogi from
Hungary." And there was one; he was quite
sick though. Hungary became free.
So you are the channels, you are the ones
who are going to work it out. If it was not
so you think I would have asked you to do
all these things? I would have done it Myself.
I can't. It is you have to do and you must
understand your responsibilities. You should
not go into the same mundane nonsensical ideas
but come forward with it and work it out.
You can break all these shackles completely,
if you have that power within you. But if
you, who are the one who are the one who are
going to transmit this, are not equipped and
are not strong enough what will I do? How
can I emit? Still we are going in that small
circle of: "Me, my family, my children, my,
my, my, my". So it's very important.
I'm sorry I didn't come earlier; I should
have come. There's nothing wrong with you
that I didn't come. But I wanted to see how
you grow, and I think this is not the way
we are going to grow at all; we are not going
to get separated. We are going to live together.
If you have any problems let Me know. But
you should immediately try to find out some
place- big one, immediately. We all can contribute.
From all over the world people will contribute;
I know that. Same thing in England, you know;
England is another mess.
We got so much money for Shudy Camps, and
in the Shudy Camps who lives are people who
have no money, paying nothing. Like Hounslow
house nobody paid anything, living free. English
are the worst in this, the worst of all, I
should say; and I don't know how they are
going to come up now; everybody has given
up. The leaders say: "Mother no use making
any house, anything for them; they'll all
come with their bag and baggage and we'll
have to pay for even their food". But now
we are getting some better-educated people,
some professionals and things, but still I
would say that England this Shudy Camps has
failed completely. We wanted about seven doctors
to see to this. We had made everything arrangements
beautifully done, worked very hard for it.
I put in such a lot of money in there; effort,
planning ; everything has all failed. Is just
haunted by some people who have no place to
go to. This is another kind. What's the use
of their collectivity there? Except that it's
a pressure on us in every way. Now you have
to show them. You were running very good ashrams,
no doubt. There were no such problems, no
such things happening, and then something
went wrong here; I know that also. Because
of that we should not give up our unity. Has
happened something; doesn't matter; we should
reunite. Unless and until we are united we
cannot fight. And the negativity is at your
door that can enter through even Sahaja Yogis.
As it had through your leaders also; I know
that. But nobody told Me about it, surprisingly.
I've already said that you don't tell Me against
the leaders but you tell Me if they are doing
something wrong; is absolutely allowed. Nobody
wrote to Me a word till I Myself discovered
it. Otherwise from Australia I get at least
sometimes minimum of ten to twenty pages letters.
But not a word about what was happening here
or how people were dominating you and how
things were going worse. I had to discover
it. We are all one family, after all I'm your
Mother. If you don't tell Me, who is going
to tell Me about it? You have every right
to tell Me. Leaders is just a myth as such.
That's the way I can communicate. But if you
find anything wrong with any leader, or anything,
you should tell Me. I'm always available,
you can always telephone to Me, I can always
talk to you. How many people have talked to?
I never say: "no" if I'm there. Any Sahaja
Yogi is trying to telephone to Me, if I am
in England or if I'm available, I'll talk
to that person. Or if there is David Spiro
he can convey to Me, he'll communicate to
Me exactly what you tell.
So nobody told Me. I never knew what was happening.
You'll be amazed I even did not know that
the school was removed
to Sydney. I did not know; nobody asked Me,
nobody told Me; I had no idea. I never knew.
Suddenly the photographs of
the children came and their eyes, you see:
"What's the matter? Where are they?" Then
they told us the school has been removed and
all that, and the children were not normal
at all. I was so shocked. Then I found out
that the school was removed without My knowledge,
without telling Me. So arbitrary and everything.
Nobody told Me. You have to tell Me, you have
to inform Me. Now, in My lifetime, if this
is the situation, I don't know what's going
to happen later. Will it be
like other Christianity of Paul or another
Hinduism or another thing like that; after
all
you
are Sahaja Yogis. And then you forget your
responsibilities because if you are together
you remember your responsibilities that
you are carrying a big load, a cross you can
call it,a big load. Suddenly you remove your
hand: "Get out. I have nothing to do. I'm
alone, I'm separate". Who is going
to carry this
big load?