happy Easter to y'all so we celebrate Easter to
show how Christ resurrected resurrected himself
the spirit that is Christ has to resurrect out of
the material manifestation of the divine itself
the matter is manifested because we ourselves
have created it not that we are born out of
matter our body but we are attached to it we
want to want to have it whatever you want that
sustains itself by your desire because
now you are on the stage if you want to
sustain the matter if you want to keep the
matter as the first priority it will remain
it cannot disappear it has to go out of your
mind that matter cannot hold you any further
Christ rose out of the matter came out of the
tomb which symbolizes the matter which has in
enclosed us within which has to be open
out with our spiritual power throw away
throw with a stone that is covering this
grave get out of that and stand outside
this is the message of Christ's resurrection
the tomb that we have created we have created
ourselves because we have allowed people
to dominate us we have allowed them to make
these graves for us we have allowed them to bury
Christ within ourselves because we were afraid
but Christ has to rise so we create our
own matter through our conditionings
through our fears through our absolute
wrong ideas about goodness and kindness
and compassion in the light of the
Spirit you can see what we think as
compassion is nothing but a kind of
a sympathy which leads you nowhere
but one should learn to see everything in the
light of the Spirit but do we use all the time
the light of the Spirit we do not for Christ it
was not difficult, because he was the Spirit but he
has shown you the way he crucified himself to show
you the way all the ideas about sophistication
about our standing in the society how we relate
ourselves to other dignitaries or to our country
to our politics to our economics and the world I
draw large all of them can tied us down to that
tomb you belong to another category I have told
you hundred times I'm in a category which is a
spirit which can rise about all the tools and
throw everything this way you are conditioned
all absurd ideas have been accepted which you
cannot explain why you were conditioned like this
why I talk more of conditioning because of
England English are very much conditioned
people the others are Americans were abundant
I mean you can't talk to them about anything
because they cannot be rooted in toilet but
English had too much conditioned people and
when they are too much conditioned they build
their own tools all these ideas are to be seen
with a new dimension of awareness that you have
you are the spirit why should you worry about
anything else but your vibrations because you're
saying I should just worry about the comfort of
your spirit whatever congenial to your spirit just
worn doing that observing that accumulating that
and settling within yourself all conditionings
will run away because these conditionings you
accept because they look comfortable
they look comfortable but they are not
Christ is a great example and he fee is the
one whom you follow if he is the one who may
have understood and recognized in the light of
your spirit then you must know why why did he
go into the grave first of all the man was so
powerful who when he'll come he'll reduce all
of them into ashes such a great personality
like him of a kadesha rudra why did Christ
allowed himself to be crucified and to
be married into that because he wanted
to stoop down to the level of other people to
come down to that level so that people should
see that through his life is shown that you
can be resurrected now the resurrection has
taken place Sergio keys are resurrected no
doubt but still in one foot is in the green
and the second one I don't know whether it will
be outdoor if it is just half way through one
foot is of course outside no doubt but still is
not yet touching the ground and the other one
cannot be lifted and listen to push the
ground this matter again to push it out
if you live with your spirit you should have
no fears should have no worry see now I'll
tell you how God is showing his ways here like
in Dharam the fellow is now under complete fire
he's our know what to do and himself is so
stupid and senseless saying is that Vanaja
Kali predictably when your destruction
time comes you think of all perverted
things before it Aboudi so he's done if
you I mean see to the way he speaks I
mean blasphemous and he is under fire he
himself lit the fire and now sitting on
top of it and now when he gets the heat the
heated words come out of his mouth we don't
have to do anything it's all done already
they are baked and cooked in their own
so why should we have fear but we should
know what is right and what is wrong
that's only possible because you are with the
absolute that is the spirit and related to the
absolute if you do everything related to they
are doing the right thing if you are related
to Christ how can he do wrong that's one of the
proofs that they are not Christians of anything
because none of the Christian organizations
have done anything good whatsoever except
for creating fire for themselves so you can see
clearly how this conditioning has worked within
us because we have been so-called Christians
we have been going to churches we have been
worshipping Christ as they told us the way they
told us we worshipped him everything regimented
the one who came to resurrect us from the
bondage of the grave we used him to build
our graves now you are out of it thank God
but take out the other foot fast this is one
advantage you have because you have Christ
before you but also there's a disadvantage
because Christ has been used to shut you down
in the grave so change your concept about Christ
know him through your vibrations what he was
I mean as a child I knew what was going wrong
with Christians and left and right little girl
like me about seven years to give big lectures
even when I was baptized I was horrified
the way I was baptized by some stupid fellow
I didn't know what was he up to and then he
put a booth on my head I think or something
which hovered round and we met with and very
big accident I fell down this booth must have
put it in the horse ID but rather booth this
priest the super stupid fellow he belonged to
the Lutheran Church I don't know what you call
through of that Lutheran imagine Martin Luther's
Church and that's how they baptized me I D I
knew all about it but I didn't know what to do
I must have kicked him quite a lot but whatever
it is so far he baptized me I had to accept all
foolish stupid things in this life because I had
to show I was quite normal me not being accepting
stupid is normal these days and to tolerate an
idiot is even more normal so I had to show that
I knew very well what sort of a thing it was this
fellow was up to and I accepted the nonsense he
did and many other things I accepted just to show
that I am nothing special but I knew all about it
and when I saw the way Christ
was described I was aghast I
said what are they doing to Christ for
me nicely second crucifixion going on
we also know about it thank God there are so
many to whom I can talk and they understand
my language but the resurrection will not
be complete unless and until you pull out
many out of their grace I don't know how
you'll go about it look at this fellow
Dharam who get such a publicity when he's
doing all blasphemous thing he's getting
all the credit and kudos from people what
about us what are we doing why not we write
to the newspapers why not we talk to them
Observer has given us a clue I think there's
one gentleman mr. Wilson he wrote it quite
nicely why not try to him some letters get we
because you see what I am little
concerned about this matter is as
it is they're half-hearted Christians now
if this Durham fellow speaks like that who
is now the big a 30 on Christianity Christ
his mother and everybody else mr. Dharam
and now this fellow if he goes on like this
those who are half-baked will already fall
off to communism and the rest of them
who may remain also they may accept him
so the Anglicans anglo-saxon brain
i am saying is going to accept mr.
Dharam very well I can see that
or else they will just leave and
become communists I have nothing to do
with this God who has so many problems
so in the seminar of yours in Birmingham when
you have I would like you to think over this
new thing that has come up in the heart of the
universe everyone knows about Durham fellow they
know his plight everything but what about us
we are so many let us try to find out how we
can talk to these people sensibly talk to these
Anglicans find out about them and communicate
to them what you have found out you need not say
in the beginning only that I am the ADI Shakti or
I am the Redeemer and the comforter that Christ
has said but we can start talking about find out
these people these Anglicans church people church
goers would believe in God who believe in Christ
I mean they are voting can you imagine they are
voting here whether Christ was true or not can
you vote like that you feel you are in a lunatic
asylum or what it's terrible they're taking words
can you imagine such a thing like that at this
moment we have an advantage because they are
so much confused to give them concrete idea as
to what is God what is Christ what is religion
one side I feel very hurt unhappy I think
these three days I have gone through real
resurrection myself the way things have been about
Christ just I can't bear it and it is too much
you all should be stirred also should be
concerned and you must go through it and
see what you can do and tell them are you all
mad or what why don't you listen to sanity as
you know when I went to Australia it's a
different country altogether they're much
more sensible people than you are I think the
way they were exiled they learnt a lesson and
they are better so I feel the English have to go
into exile or jail for a while to understand it
there are very sensible extremely sensible
people you can talk to them sense everyone
the media is sensible the people are sensible
thousands of them came they repeated no first
program we had once it was 1,600 2000 can you
imagine such people and out of them repeats for
600 now for the last how many years we are
having the same 600 people again and again
what seminars are we going to do all of us
eating and cooking some chicken that's what
or making some cake for mother which
she doesn't eat let us take out our
satisfactions from these little lazy theme
into something bigger let us talk about it
without fear we have to go and talk and
tell people about it take it a big way
there should be no hindrance on this point we are
a very big group we can assert
and we can talk and meet people
the situation has improved a lot because now
I have to go to India as you know and in India
for me the situation is much better it's not
at all difficult as you know I went to the
hills at the foothills of Himalayas but three
thousand people came from all over the little
dirty villages that they had they didn't take
even a second to recognize me they were singing
the praise of the goddess of the hills goddess
of the Tigers goddess of the Lions this started
singing my place without any lecture or anything
we were all joyous that I've been there and they
knew Anna they accepted me and finished I have
to just put my foot down there and I've done
Jaipur they said mother you just put your foot
here oh really so for me the situation is very
good in India now let's see what you people
are going to do with these big big seminars and
lectures why not get some outsiders to listen
to you invite them invite these intellectuals
try to talk to them tell them what is it
what do you call them those who know about
Bible what how theologians see or what
najin's without logics theologians call
these theologians challenge them why not put
a challenge we are not alone you are so many
and don't tell them you wear saris when you come
for my puja they won't understand it they
are not that deep you can wear your jeans
or to convince them more you can be punks that
would have bring them better you go with your
funky conditions their jolly well have to listen
to the otherwise they are in for trouble if they
had that stupid why not handle them it's very
easy to handle a stupid person than to handle
a person who is not who is not stupid nor who
is clever stupid can be stupefied very easy
so I think we have to change our course
we have to take it in a big way the whole
thing what we are going to do all of you
should give some concrete ideas as to what
you would like to do and that would be
really the way it will work out so now
in the seminar you must discuss more how to
talk to these people how to create a platform
for sahaja yoga find out how do they create
a platform out of nothing like this bunks
and once you do all these things you will be
surprised that they will have to listen they'll
have to listen now go full ahead I'm giving you
all freedom do what you want except for telling
them that I am Adi Shakti that they won't be able
to digest that an Indian has become now the ADI
Shakti they think now additionally has to be an
English lady at least French so don't patient
me if you want you can but don't mention me as
guru or anything but you should succeed that lady
who showed us the way and or something like that
not referring much to me but to them I think you
should go ahead with it and work it out because
now we have had lot of patience and all nonsense
going round us better tell them or are you going
to allow all of them to go to hell direct message
of Easter East comes from East I don't know why
they call it Easter and we were thought of it
why do they call it a Worcester sauce I don't know
I don't know why they call
anything anything but Easter
you can't explain you know like
her screen you don't know so I
don't know but Eastern it is coming from the east
the wisdom has to come from the east the
resurrection has to come from the east
whether they like it or not and that is the
message of Easter today that let us give them
the chance of resurrection by talking to them
all of you should make it a pun go and talk to
people who are in charge of theology churches
Bibles go and talk to them tell them what are
you doing I remind why I want to die why do you
want to be sleep people do not know anything
another thing I would suggest that we should have
regular classes to understand sahaja yoga properly
I have seen some people who are sahaja Yogi's
for years don't know anything about sahaja yoga
even in Bombay people told that some of the late
these are absolutely zero as far as sahaja Yoga
is concerned they don't understand what is sahaja
Yogi's they don't understand what is what are what
are the chakras are they listen to your lecture
everything and then like a bubble the whole thing
disappears from their minds I don't know who gave
them these ideas but they were quite shocked so
let us have a class like thing for sahaja Yogi's
two different topics and subjects let us work it
out recently you must be knowing there's a book
going to be published by Yogi Bhajan called Neeta
enlightened which is a very good book of course
I mean most of it I have had three Mary's being
with me and all that but doesn't matter but
he's understood the subject the other day they
published a very beautiful book in Marathi once
soraka such a lovely book he wrote that in the
light of gana shuara what is sahaja yoga and it's
written it so well that anybody was a theologian
or anything like in India will be impressed by
I wish I could translate that book for you but
it's all the stands us from Ganesha para which
is in Marathi language wrote such a nice book
on sahaja yoga and that is what he gave me on
my birthday is that something so substantial I
felt and once it reaches into the hands of any
one of these people I mean it will in any case
and he published himself he brought some copies
gave it to me and all the copies were sold out
in that program every copy was sold out for two
rupees each so this is what we have to do now is
to write write two different magazines meet people
tell them we want to come and talk to you first of
all you must know about sahaja yoga you should
be well equipped it's not that you can show my
photograph with a light here that's not sufficient
what is the light here also you have to show only
few people know what is sahaja yoga the rest of
you don't know anything let us see what questions
we have in our mind let us sit down and find
out what are the questions what questions are we
lacking in what we have to understand in sahaja
yoga what part we don't know let's find out all
those things all the details let us write it down
every one of you whether it's a woman man child
everyone can do it find out what are the questions
which are not yet answered in sahaja yoga how can
we answer particular questions all right all these
things can be found out if you put your attention
to it you can easily find out what you need
everyone has to do it you must be all equipped
if anybody asks you a question about sahaja
yoga and if you cannot answer I mean how can you
convince people you take one ordinary so-called
lay man for Christianity so-called Christianity
again the man is lemon and the Christianity is
also lame he will give a big lecture on Christ
every verse the Bible is telling chapter Matthew's
2 verse 2 this is what Christ I said that you'll
be calling me Christ Christ and I will not
recognize you telling about himself only so
you have to be absolutely equipped for it now
you have to also know what will confront in a
particular country for example when I come
to England I know I have to confront these
theologians and the Christ and everything if I go
to India what I have to confront I know I have to
face it on different lines and different fronts
you don't have to do that just think about your
own country for French have to think about France
you people have to think about this country and
then go ahead with it you can chalk out a good
program and work it out properly I'm sure by
God's grace everything you work out because when
are we going to do it now I am going away as I
told you to India and I don't know when will
I be back you wanted to arrange my program
to England in England but I think I cannot do it
because I have to go around to all the places you
know pan all that finished that you better do that
during when I was not here what Turing did you do
nothing you could have taught now at least these
three months when we are having a nice summer
time I'll be traveling all over Europe everywhere
you please see that you go around England visit
different places arrange programs talk to people
find out who are the big Johnny said the mayor
stays that go and talk to them tell them about
this that is how new programming should be done
and a new dimension should be given to our sahaja
yoga propaganda you have done no propaganda in the
right sense in the sense that we were not so much
sure about it that will work out but now we weigh
because people are writing there's an atmosphere
against rice so we have to fight and that's how we
should become the people who are fighting for
Christ now there could be areas where you can
talk of integration of talking about how we do
not know much about Christ that we have to go to
other books to find out who he was why did he come
on this earth we have to go much deeper we have
to prove that there is divine power and you have
seen how divine power works what wonders there are
you take my photographs show them these are the
photographs can you explain these things that in
the hand you see the Sun show us in mrs. Thatcher
science even a star won't drink all these things
are to be seen in the right perspective and at
the right time we must do whatever is right at
that point that is the way sahaja Yoga is hit
the point when it is to be hit if you cannot
do that way you cannot achieve so this is the
right time for you these are now three months
ahead of you I would like you to see what you
can do because now the Sun will be coming out
we'll have a nice summer go ahead but now just
do not fix all your holiday during these three
three months going to some beach somewhere so
Yogi's have no time they are busy people they
have no time to waste we are on about a warpath
we have no time to quarrel among ourselves fight
we have to fight very great enemies we have no
time to waste on our families and our children
and our relations and father mother sister
brother we are on a warpath very important
so let us now prepare ourselves as Christ stood
out of that grave let us get out of this grave
of lethargy of compromising of comfort of our
past ideas about life's pleasures this is the
new era that has to show its manifestation in
this country it's very important and you all can
do it you have to be very brave you have to be
self similar wise kind and also forthright but
you have to say what you have to say because it
has to be said and this is the only thing to be
said nothing else is important whatever these
people talk about has no meaning they are not
mantras some of them are anti-god some may not be
but they are useless wasteful garbage s I should
say why they are given so much importance and
not the real thing that is there you understand
that this is the reality that is come into you
people actually you are Felda reality actually
you know the reality you are in the reality
why not talk about it why should we not is
it not the most important thing that we have
to do if you realize it I'm sure it will work
out with all my blessings with all my love
I really command you to do that now may God
today on this day you all should Wow Wow
that we are on the warpath and we are
going to find out ways and methods of doing
this thing for these three months we are
going to work it out just bow just ask for
wisdoms and the spiritual power that's all
and promise it to Christ that
as you did we are going to do
may God bless
so many steaks
this is too much coming up in
less than three there are two
each of them their one year wonder
should be less than his burns better
when are you having your seminar weeks
I mean I would like to plan out my visit to
Southside London after this Birmingham mistake
and please ask the sahaja Yogi's abroad I mean
in the European countries how they would like me
to do it so that say Birmingham will be over by
the end of April middle of April then we can do
the other places as well because I am going to
Austria in any case I will be able to come for
different food as I said but we can have a few
there so just find out I know they're all here
it's such a joyous meeting meeting all of you down
here but if you see in India foreign I will tell
you how I mean really I mean you do feel that why
should you deprive them isn't it sometimes you do
feel that there is no question of favoring anyone
but you feel that after all that the deserving
people what are quality water quality no question
no nothing is just surrendered I mean they may not
be smart looking or they may be something I mean
they are poor villagers you see living in the
hillside and all that but all properly dressed
putting on the north and everything and all the
best dresses that they could lay hand so on and
they all came all the way it's really surprising
and the gentleman told me only thing
mother if you can look after the weather
that's all we want the weather to
be clear the weather is just like
Indian I said that you don't worry and
there was not a single cloud in the sky
all right so now you bring it
nervous
he's honest a little digital
- inca baths convoluted solid
animal apoptosis karma kagyu injured soccer no
hmm so all of you have got it with you is
better that all of you try to read it when
he's washing my feet now you see for Easter
that best thing is to get some children little
boys and girls but not very little those
who are sitting here in the program down
I've come to wash my feet that's great
now who else come along that's great
now Olympia where is she come along the
girls can come come down come down come
along come along how are you hello very
good come along all the children come
along all of them those who can now say
the mantra little bit one each one and
two of them three of them can come now
come along wash my feet now now first
these three then then again now now
wash my feet come now put the water
say
dad no let them come it's alright
now let them come come now
give them some trouble to
wipe their answer come on
good night good night good night your feet yeah
so habitat both diets I was both that yeah yeah
that right good let other three
children come now wipe your hands
may God richly wipe your hands they
call it now who are the three other
William I know who she Sarah
Athena so big she's Vika Sarah come now no
washer wash rabbit hell yeah hard both that
Athena's become very very sensitive good
girl alright let's thank you now wipe your
hands go wipe your hands around now come now
that's some bigger who else tell their names
now what's your name
Francois all right now Kamla both of you
come closer come closer to children as better
rabbit rabbit are transpose every time
well done thank you ready now burn wipe your hands
regardless just take a transpose you take this
come on what's your name Pat then
are there no vice rub it rub rub
rub my heart sorry what's your
name since you're sick bad knee
can a girl be taking Joseph Rabbit are
non-arab it adhere to default gravity
that not all right come on call this child
also just that girl rabbit rabbit now here
come look come in come see all the children
are doing it no no not to be afraid see how
they are we see now rub it hard ramita
you keep this boy ah he's not frightened
all right daddy can come daddy can come
in it then come along come along let it
see now let's see how you do it aha look at
this Sarah you've done you've done already
you wiped your hands you sweet girl now come
along you try you try my child come up let's
see what happens see now this put you just
do it loud let's see just do it just right
she said ice that's also try to dance
now cleaned up
you
yogurt money keep it down to Joseph
justice just don't see the 108
that different names you have to save
return you know honey that differently
my whole vibrations going now remember
these are all different shopkins you
have to say no no matter which at theme
just my whole I don't know what was that
take every name namo namah they are
different Shakti you are awakening
your shops is the whole just
imagine the vibrations aren't
you feeling the cow well now come on
start it properly what is the hurry
the
dump it nice
some chapter from the about price that you have
company is not completed
we see more water is needed
now in the fullness of time within the
word strong the waters this boy came to
be denominated afterwards by the name of
Mahavira homogeneously as there is nothing finer
than iranian so there is nothing grosser than a
marketer this powerup is Mohammed Iran was 1/16
of that of Shri Krishna the highest self about
this boy all of the truck we need rousted is
the sole stay of all this universe denominated
by the name muhammad it is every for countless
universes are existing so much so that even Shri
Krishna could not count them if it were possible
to count the number of the dust particles it is
impossible to count the universities so there are
endless promise business and lifestyles energy
from another a Brahma Vishnu and managers
each brahmanda extends from Tata Tata the
brahmana they burn a fight under is higher than
that it is situated outside of brahmana again
the albergue Nicole okay fifty katyayana 5510
like all cartoons in Milan - this guru Kodama
is eternal and real educational eternal this
is the so you are in the Brahman alone that's
why you are feeling the Brahma sure you follow
these seven loka's you know these seven loka's
ah boo boo is this between that's the when the
Kundalini at the mooladhara chakra mooladhara
let's move then move up while this whole cosmos
interaction is swadishtana then swaha is a lobby
what is it called as what Lu Shuang then
here it is mana at the heart is mana then
this is Jana because Shri Krishna stands
for collectors the Jenna means people
Jenna this is tapa here Christ had to go
through the great penance that's why this
is tapa and he's the light tapa also
means life then such at this place is
the subtle Oh such thing is where you come
to know about the truth through your brain
through your central nervous system then the
brahmaloka you are here one beyond all right
the splendor of Brahma doctor is like that as
long and go not see this destroy substances
inside these brahmaloka a transient what
transience what does that ring of transient
is all drum sol Maya hmm when this brahmanda
the cosmos dissolves everything dissolves and
is destroyed all the temporary light bubbles
of water what do you what to speak of others
even Krishna cannot count the number of
these pronouncements in every tremendous
Brahma Vishnu and Mahesh the child Narada in
every prom under the number of the God is 330
the universe began to look after the
sky again and again anything within that
possess knowledge like that's
your hunger and thirst vanish
that give me the holder of the innumerable
dissolution without any selfishness we fear
that the best aeroplanes to manage death disease
sorrow nor any other 1850 the same repeated
thrice on the day of the six legged mantra
worshiped by the beta's without unmask the giver
of desires of the destroyer all troubles and
calamities thus giving the mantra shri krishna
arranged for feeding us in every universe
whatever offerings will be given three Trishna one
sixteenth of that will go to Narayana and fifteen
sixteen is to go to this boy who threw up Shri
Krishna did not have any share in himself himself
son sending all the controls over satisfiability
so what necessity is there any further agreements
whatever the people offer with diversions are
over Lakshmi the morality eats all these bunchy
krishna giving us to the Veera the burden of
the mattresses which I say what more you do now
I will give you that in stamping the deer a boy
hearing the words of our omnipresent I saw snow
for a long time in this going to sacred places
of pilgrimage ability attacks if he be without
any party to Shri Krishna rain is his life
is devoid of any evolution to Shri Krishna
under this grace he has obtained his life and
whom he does not have a home a tradition or
myself or anything his body this all the
chakras come here it's like to be little
trying to manage that primeval person the
furniture of the highest life child I see
you know I'm a designer Shri Krishna then
spoken sweet words your child that you remain
as president like me you will not have any fall
even if the numerable drama brought the way that
you do that I get a selfie parts I'm turning
into smaller units in every universe Brahma
will spring from your navel and will create
the cosmos from the forehead of that Brahma
was bringing in the drugs of the destruction
of the route from each of your subdivisions
the Vishnu will originate from that psych eval
mission will be the prisoner of this Vishnu world
I say that under my paper you will always be in
fact eating plain and absolutely you meditate on
some of the creative brother sing the Lord of
the universe remains Brahma Shiva the auspicious
to the Lord but you cannot learn at the form of
the great puzzles wearing yellow garments being
colored the Duke Lacrosse lay sleeping pervading
everybody rom after his birth and his name then
after his birth began to travel in that navel
Lucas and in the stem of the lotus for one that
divorces the 400 Vishnu the preserver of the
university he went to Schmidt happy humane
any of us engaged in creating this universe
movable a non-believable comparative free world
that's from the force of that great fear of the
universe's around and in every universe there is
one smooth on Brahma condition here on the best
of twice-born as I have described the glories of
Krishna became exceedingly nice a what Mori monty
here in the third chapter of the ninth book on the
origin of Brahma Vishnu realized what a tremendous
thing it is to have Christ on this earth
and the ladies
what about the ladies coming
it's Americans receive of unicorns Ocalan control
uncle Dominic on table each generation
alcohol take my sorry said on the fire
attorney sun Lepofsky
they're not dumb like on a date what's
the matter why the children whose child
is crying so much what's the matter
I hope they're all right now Dylan
Remy them all right the man it will become
shoot me are you married customer all right
Thank You Dennis
some modern solution
remember stick a little bit but don't eat
sadly one
- missing some songs he was the basement
did you get the song on were
Christian soldiers being that is
Atena sorry bro
double double double
whether it is you can return forever
like I just
oh my god anybody
like you've got
this violence you must evacuate
the London
beautiful very beautiful this is the kind
of songs you must really take them down and
that's what will be appreciated very much
I'm sure in the western world you can use
also table with it and sitar and everything
we have so many combinations which you can
use and make nice programs and you can
say that we can show you something great
dude
in a bit of a bundle
this one is better than Garland beautiful
No
yeah
Oh
thank you
yeah
my mother tonight
you
light it with this
valid charity the ocular trauma
cutie last one is not old
may God bless you they got this fever
you wonder take a bundle is good right
wrench are going today or tomorrow
I wanted to discuss the future plans
tomorrow evening I'll be free if anybody
can stay on and we plan out our future
plans for the European to Mora evening
Olivia
No
the decide what
austerity aru Garnica
pretty good idea
ah doctor sir up to this point is alright but
when you are putting on the next it should be
just the just the actually proper garland you
mean but even if you put it easy this portion
if you can just make it a string it would
be better because that all gets entangled
oh yeah you want to give it to that all right
MA first seven Sergio keys first is dummy
mati Marie
they're not here while the rest who is there
where is he video service holy he's the first
one was to Ste Marie the steam
is coming keep on focus to Mari
we can send her one where if
somebody can take it for Mari
now she's become Swiss you
tamale the series coming she
we are in time my video anniversary that's not
I'm very bad I don't despise I think better
start distributing these things
can you give one of that to be
how would you like it yes no
no giving chocolates which is
generally the chocolate the like chocolate
when they are the children all the
children hello all the children all
my children do you know they're a little bit
responsible all these demons are also children
the can't see what children are wearing
you've always come up with changing back
Bob hey sniffing
should bless this company that it should
not be so expensive that's what she makes
things that everybody can have she's only for
somebody and we can't have anything from that
motapod aganetha mala
or flapjack duck
by the English surgery after their emergency money
you see spot
the price is there's no no it's not price this is
the Vino so you just say the name right
and right and sahaja Yoga Center please
sister so joke I Center Birmingham's Birmingham
AL I don't see La La's is still in Singapore
Debbie calculate M Ridge Cambridge Sheffield but
Exeter please our G better Exeter
yes Kancha buddy beautiful to
their first novel oh you're
reading it but character begins oh she's all right
knowledge let's make our knowledge
little sparrow good she's looking fine
dude all right now make up its Edinburgh Edinburgh
Lester Lester Lester
well Jake to me
no not tempted
you should not yet oh yeah you
didn't hear me not Hampton I said
come on would it sex he sex they'll
all use it for my channel I am sure
I hope I will be able to make
it sometime next year I'm shy
I'm shy kings cross
skinks cross how slow
lambda
Lambert
that's very kind of my house I read
that friend you are having that
they're sort of threatening them included a
thank you
little France
well-integrated no one knows
they take the
so now tomorrow evening I would
like to meet people who would like
to discuss about my program using these two verses
even
saying the third or fourth week
of April fourth week of April we
can do what is in science for fourth week of April
be part of be careful thank you
nn-no no fedora all right let's keep it at I'm
gonna put up but uh you think you can manage guru
puja because and there is next by the orphanage
where there is under than fifty paise and the
other people can be put in the as domes in this
big spot complex where you had the pugilist time
so the room where we were last time should be
used could be used as a dome and there is there
is you put that to be five to seven what will
be the number four group food acting so to be 29
we're 6th and 7th of July when is the cooldown
and I'm a tall one second whatever they wanted
let the children have they all like Indians
who is just imagine you don't like chocolate
what is it
and what about the program Saturday
and Sunday Saturday and Sunday can
have program which in Saturday's nature
sattva-guna in Paris he's alright but
the Sunday there is nobody I don't think
we'll have many people oh you can have a
following on Sunday morning something yeah
you tell me - big days are better weekdays
is better over there now I can arrive on
C's because there well Tuesday Tuesday is
the food Jana when I try one Mondays you
are on Monday Jack yes Wednesday Thursday
I should say that in July mother in
Paris they may not be a lot of people
because there are only days is July and
August so it may be it is sometimes quite
empty Paris is quite hard when I tell
people well they are the fish on the
beach and the sea is aside I see today
is there is a sentiment is looking nice
or in Paris where every sin is end of
every small so now you tell me about them
when you said troubles just rusted
and thirsty so I come on my Tuesday
because the or you you see because it is so
we can end up with up to the sea because it's
a weekend yes so we have a future after this
big program no no no that's guy is in yes guru
puja we can have it after the seven half turn
the program two days we can have people there
pooja guru - yeah we'll have lots of people
Yes Mother then what you can do is to have a
weekend for them yes so we have a few choice or
the weekend before the few or the weekend after
this before before so we have it on 29th of
June and 10:30 start of June that's what we do
now well maybe this is in April and the program
what is the date in there that will will be the
23rd 24th and 25th thank you for that's all right
we have a to be a bit hairy to Mecca 24 24 second
23rd 24th and 25th St eyes on the
it's Australia already and you go to Germany
Germany so that that peak is gone then we have
we have to go to another place Switzerland
Judah after guru Buddha we can do Sarah
but next week what is the puja I gave them
that will be in November that we can do it
all right how'd you do that good
now ratsy is when we do that so
then switch our next please people after
Germany next research didn't steal me
don't relish hippies are endemic
and a ship is not Navy day
Washington attending same
what is it it's deadly sending to your loved
one Getti sending to your love
and whenever somebody's magnets
you have my love lots of it alright this
oh you bought it you got it there relax when
you got I must say it's beautiful we got this
she can wear it from both the sides the green
and the red of the got it little baby boy oh uh
sure II believe yes when 15 does a good baby
good boy boy is course very loose and father
was worried very fast but he has the he has
the hand of this father a long long fingers
yeah we have a little problem Jesse's father
was very much worried she doesn't have you
know there was a little problem mother of
because Romick was not working properly so
it would not assume himself I mean materially
speaking so we have bit embarrassed because she
this wife is a bitter as a guest because he's
in the ashram and he could not pay for his rent
for a few month now so what why because he's
maybe it's too much involving his music and
it doesn't understand not sure it was a right
when he was a mean bachelor but now he has to
a fought for the second person is not so he
was earning not a bachelor so we were quite
I'm just one second
then we told him very frankly that he has
to find a work because you cannot stay like
that on the charge of the collection yes
to afford is living so he took a job just
now but we hope screen just put that in your
attention yes you can just put it put is mine
since I'm in Paris mocha good I have acute you
a great job mother yes I'm living three weeks
in Paris and one week in Lyon good and all the
families some days I'm very optimistic some day
we have started discourse mother you know
I spoke to you before about this all so we
have an initiation course to start your garden
the deepening course and actually we have few
people who are following it in this quite quite
serious about it and in sahaja Yogi's that as to
make any photo so because they have to give
the cost now - they have to know about such
oh god that's that's working out with what
do you think of starting the course here
and but we have we have been frankly a beginning
we are asking them to pay for participation and
spaying then that is only because we give them
some tapes and papers and all that so they can
read about sahaja yoga but we use it for that to
further the books the use and the tapes we give
them tapes of your tapes mother and as very cheap
action it's the gesture but I think like that they
did start and finish the course so that means
the course is three months mother so for Amelia
I believe to whatever this is for Austria
those who want to go are very welcome there
Austria now we have a new arsenal what
about Italy now whatever you have decide
only one thing you asked us to if you could
come in 15 days in Paris it could be done
but if we have little more time a bit you
know it may distill your mother April may
end of method for example I don't need of
after maybe sastra I'm just saying we can
do it in 15 days but if you really
want to make your coming successful
we do the better
I said we're supposed to take the plane tomorrow
morning mother me to have to put my attention a
little bit on my work because we can fix it
others will will definitely go in 15 days
time and we'll definitely go for the perusal
what 50 what is 15 days around the 21st and
thank you
Caroline
Thank You Mataji what about Spain
when you do Paris would it not be
such a good idea to do Spain as
well just before or just after
Spain yes you're going in July 2nd
of July and you're going on the 23rd
you can do Spain just before the
Guru puja if you wish but mother
they go on holidays also everybody wants
to say oh it's Spain but on the seaside
Austria's fixie France is fixed Italy is not
yet fixed they're not here mother Antonio
we can get
yeah
merica
have some shopping in Paris this time with
summer you have some shopping on
pair in Paris this time alright
so the I don't come to my house
all right when should I come to
your house look the sound alright alright
I'm sorry we did come two more because
we have we have a fixed booking mother
oh I'll have a look in here
that's dude definitely
sometimes go to New Zealand we have the
money to fly we can get there yes great
and of June is the German the weekend the weekend
is equal to puja on the 29th and 30th of June July
and there's nothing marked as marked on the
calendar Mother's nothing mom sure you like
in end of July that might be even
you party doing
guru screamin at you I brought it from India for
my children if there is a breaking sigh break them
what about America mother when did
you you're going to bring it I want
to tell you how well things are going in
New York nowadays how well things were
going in New York now that everybody's
come from the west coast and it's ready
I just get it it is a very we'll
bring something a little courage
there is another big one and
this and this is a big one
so many get several nice would it be alright to be
at the meeting in Birmingham
announcing in the papers is