and that's why that's why this water
which is the Trina fire water is the
purified water purifies us physically
and also our poisons are driven out of
our never also my water water is on a
very great element in removing all
problems you use water for so many
things you know how he went up so this
Lakshmi which is purification was born
out of what that's why she was called as
many as I to me and I am also called as
Mila may be born out of what
so one has to understand that today's
message is that we inculcate
we should not cheat it really easy to
keep what mission in forget you will
take within ourselves as a matter of our
own action as our own declaration and
our own deity and not just because it's
a it's a lugubrious thing or it is a
very hard thing not like it should be
achieved with great pleasure and happen
how do we like to have a bar in the same
way we should try to clean our thoughts
just by paying attention to them you can
clean so to keep it pure and simple is
take two water element as much as which
helps water it has zero etirsa
take to water element and that is what
Lakshmi is Lakshmi is the one that gives
you the Mahalakshmi not from the Lakshmi
only the Maharaj means this word Ronson
and we see after the purification
through the Lakshmi process see
Mahalakshmi is water so now you turn
depends that's a done now one rinsing it
down whatever whatever
satisfied now coming to the pot it
fetches the first the spiritual trust
you can trace the spiritual thirst of
people tremendous power because we
believe in the realization that the
seeking is over all right then another
one now communal what are the [ __ ]
dinkleberg water
nourishment
you know spiritual nourishment to people
through your power even if you are
standing there you're nourishing others
then it's a solvent you dissolve their
ego you dissolve their somebody all
these powers are your own route to
realization just think of it waters give
anything if anything divinity but that's
very way because divinity how to relate
it with water people won't understand so
let us carry others and carry others
very gently and also drown some of them
now into the lotion but you can also
push them with two running jumps all
right that also can be done it has a
very great quality that water permeates
and to the smallest parts when it goes
to the roots and it stuck to the rooms
so Mohammed will power you just see the
roots of the person we just know where
the problem comes from jump
actually it is it is the event tell me
the truth father whose get sunlight and
you understand that now where is the
problem and you just phony eternity and
you sucked
you can be easily sucked before need you
see when you are sitting near a person
and you tell me mother this is catching
at the back the person doesn't work not
permeated personality is permeated is
one person even though you have
permeated instantly and you are feeling
the roots when is the problem the water
is flowing into that mean the divine
water is flowing into that B and AB such
an expense so that divine water and you
can say that this is that exact strategy
so the Fermi is permeating and the
another one is the glistening what is so
you are still
still becomes very good and the last of
all is the reflection the person who
sees you sees his own reflection that's
right and I don't mean anything back to
anyone but people are unnecessarily
frightened of me because they see their
reflection so when they meet you they
see the reflection they can be very
aggressive so they see their reflection
they can be very hard on because they
see their touch
i if it is clear-cut
water then you see the depth of the
person if you are are clear-cut some
Yogi's they feel the depth 3 and they
can see through the spirit shine
these are the quality of water within us
the more of that I would say especially
in my body the water acts as a buffer to
protect with chakra if I don't have
water in the body and I may have broken
so it acts as a buffer also it suits
your epithelial cells you can say it
suits your lining see there's no
moisture you feel all these dinosaurs
you know it's so separate and there are
other types of powers of water which we
know that when it comes out of your eyes
it expresses your compassion
that's the only thing out of all the
elements which expresses emotions water
power
what are the other qualities also which
makes people know how to static
pressure because of pressure and a
person would exist like a sahaja yogi
will definitely put a pressure on others
you will not you will not address but
there will be a pressure and pressure
and another core CitiField
the cement and he gets the advantage of
it but if he does not receive me then he
feels pressurized and it is a little bit
dominating your neighbors your family
beacon and the beginning with geodesic
pressure because the body achieves a
kind of a weight and that's how the guru
tattwa is formed out of them I eat there
is salt that's a new principle then the
weight is even more so today for water
should really know that water is a very
holy thing and in our use especially
this thing signifies the Kundalini that
means the Kundalini is the water jar or
the Terrier Aquarius and this is the age
of the experience so how important is
water and the water is the carrier of
divine love is the best barrier
and this is the time of the acquiesce
mr. Kundalini
it's made of divine water so the whole
idea of celebrating today then that
means they is to understand that in us
she has become a Mahalakshmi and by that
we have so many powers of which we are
not aware I mean we do not know so that
we are realized Souls some of us do not
know and that we have those powers
within us that we can permeate Internet
you can project ever personality on us
you can find out what's wrong with that
we can find out about ourselves we can
go into our selves you can go to our
permeation is like water is very flowing
order and this it's a very important
that we should be aware of our powers
that knowledge then we start respecting
ourselves there is Raja Lakshmi come see
and then that Mahalakshmi comes in and
everything comes with it when we become
aware of what we have a challenge of our
self-esteem
of our technique so this gives us
dignity Maya gives us dignity and that's
how we start understanding the value of
human beings sense of dignity and we
live it our own dignity and that's how
it should be pure transparent on it
within ourselves we should be honest
absolutely honest water we sew on a
spirit self we put anything into the
water feature put any color equation put
an American show you have to be so
honest honest now the whole thing should
work out to be a personality very
congenial beautiful permeating no doubt
but rain unlikely because mihashi that
by itself is enlightenment in every way
so we have to dedicate ourselves to
about purification no notifications for
water purifiers there are only things so
nice and listening on your face and I
can see that on TV playing us all today
we said that yeah baby sorry booth H
Fantine you better listen I think we
like them and that is that when I see
New York but already found but it should
be inside us