Barbara: Thank you, Mother.
Shri Mataji: May God bless you.
Barbara: Before we begin, I would like to
introduce myself to those of
you in the room. My name is Barbara Schuler
and I do a radio program on a station from
Monterey called Discovery which is usually
on Wednesdays from 1 to 2:30. And, is going
to be now on Thursdays from 11 to - 11:30
to 1 o’clock. And, it’s my privilege to
be here to do a taped interview for my listeners.
So, for the listeners I would like to say
that we are at the Kennolyn Campgrounds in
Santa Cruz and this is an interview with Her
Holiness Mataji.
Mother, today there are many, many things
said about Sahaja Yoga, about Your philosophy,
and very little is said about who You are
as a person. [Shri Mataji laughs] And, I thought
it would be good to start out with some, some
questions about who You are; who were You
as a child; what people influenced You; what
brought You to the place You are today as
a Luminous Being sitting before me and before
us.
Shri Mataji: I am a very ancient being – that
problem is like this. [laughter] I had to…
what can I tell you about Myself? I just don’t
know what part will interest you, but only
thing I can say that I was born with this
understanding and awareness that I have to
find out a method by which I could give en
masse Realization to people. I was a Realized
Soul, of course. I knew all about it from
My very childhood. But the problem was that
how to make many people get it, because if
one person gets it or one person has it; if
one person is an incarnation, people don’t
understand it. Not only that but they may
even try to destroy such a person. That’s
what happened to all the saints who came on
this earth. Christ was crucified; Mohammed
Sahib was given poison - because they were
ignorant. They did not know what it was, what
was He saying.
So, it was important first of all to find
out a method how to give them en masse Realization,
and from that angle I just thought that “this
is why I am on this earth and I have to do
this job” for which I wanted to study about
human beings. I took My birth in a Christian
family and that too a family which was Protestant
family, because I felt that Protestants are
fanatics but very sophisticated. [laughter]
And, they rationalize everything to such an
extent that nobody can see beyond it. So,
I better take My birth in them and My father
and mother had already taken birth whom I
had chosen as My parents. They were great
people, realized souls and specially My father
was a person who knew why I was on this earth.
Even My mother knew about it.
So, a special rapport was between them and
Me and they could understand why I was busy
meditating or finding out about how to give
realization to others. Then, I would say My
father was a very learned man, who knew about
fourteen languages, who translated Quran-e-Sharif
into Hindi, who was a member of the Constituent
Assembly. He made our Constitution. Also,
he was the only Christian to be elected in
those days. And, then My mother was a honors
in Mathematics. All very well-educated and
nice people!
They dedicated their life to the cause of
freedom of India. And, I also felt that that
was very important, because if we are not
free we cannot do anything on religious basis.
There’s one thing is to be free from this
level. And, that’s how I also helped them
a lot and our whole family suffered a lot.
And, I went through terrible times, terrible
times since very young age.
I was with Mahatma Gandhi also because he
liked Me very much as a child. So, I stayed
on with him then I used to come back to study
again, go back to him. He used to call Me
“Nepali” because My face is a Nepali face.
And, he used to talk to Me as if he is talking
to his grandmother sometimes. [laughter] It
was very sweet and he was a very sweet man
– extremely sweet person to children. Very
strict with himself and strict with others
- elderly people - but with children he was
very, very sweet and kind and would try to
learn from children lot of things. It was
surprising how he understood that there’s
lot of wisdom with the children sometimes
than with the older people who are mixed up.
Now, we got our independence and we had a
very bad setback because of the partition
we had in our country. And, I was studying
in Lahore Medical College there because I
wanted to know about medicine – what these
people call such and such thing. Because I
knew all this but … I knew about the body,
I knew about everything, what you call the
complete nervous system, but I did not know
what was the vocabulary attached to it, so
I studied there for two years. Now after that,
this war broke out. So, I had to discontinue
with My studies and My parents wanted Me to
get married. And, then I found that My marriage
was important, I agreed to marry and I married
this gentleman, Mr. C.P. Srivastava.
Then during all that time, My only pastime
or the full-time work was to find out about
human beings – what’s the problem they
have. How they avoid reality? How they shun
it? How they run away from it? What are their
problems? How are they seeking? What do they
have to offer? What will they accept? How
to handle them? It was quite a intricate question.
Every person provided a new sample of problems
and I had to fight it out. In a way that it
was a system which I knew how to do it, because
to enter into somebody subtly, to understand
the problems of the Kundalini – you can
go into the journey and find out about a person.
And, then I found out the permutations and
combinations of their problems. So, like it
is like, you can say that like periodic tables.
You had to divide them into three, then into
seven, then into their permutations and combinations.
So, you can imagine – three into seven,
raised to power eternity – it was like that.
But doesn’t matter! It worked out and in
the year 1970 on the fifth of May. I was little
bit hesitant at that time. I thought I should
wait but certain circumstances made Me to
open the last center.
And, when I opened the last center, it started
working with others on en masse scale. But
still I gave Realization only to one lady
who came to My house. I tried if it works
out with her and she … I gave her Realization
by touching her centers one by one - six centers
and then bringing out the Kundalini on top
of the head.
Barbara: What does it mean to open the last
center?
Shri Mataji: The Sahasrara. Last center is
the center which is the limbic area where
is the seat of all the seven centers. It’s
all integration there. So far, everybody who
has come – like, Christ has come on this
center what you call the Agnya Chakra. Or,
Krishna has come on this center which is the
Vishuddhi Chakra. Like that, they have been
appearing on every center of ours – giving
us a new dimension to our awareness. And,
that’s how our awareness has improved to
this extent and now the time is for you to
get your Absolute; to get your Spirit – that
your Spirit must shine into your attention,
that you should have your Self-Realization,
that you should have your second birth. That’s
the time! And, that is only possible if baptism,
the real baptism works out - real. Not artificial
- somebody coming and putting the hand on
your head and saying, “Now, you are baptized.”
That’s not the way. But it is a real thing
that happens that you start feeling the Cool
Breeze of the Holy Ghost coming out.
So, then I started giving first of all Realization
without confronting any kind of a position
or anything. I started with one lady. Then
I went ahead with it. Then the first twelve
people got Realization. Then I was very happy
because en masse Realization has started.
Then gradually it started working out. I went
to Indian villages. I thought they are better
simple people. First work on the simpler people
and they got Realization. Now, we have thousands
of people in the villages who have got Realization.
They have dropped out all their bad habits.
They have become very creative. They are doing
very well. They are very happy. And, they
are experts. So many of them are experts,
I can say, in India now whom we call as Sahaja
Yogi, maybe in thousands. Some are working
in the villages; some are working in some
cities. So, we have lots of people now in
India who can do this job.
Barbara: This all happened since 1970?
Shri Mataji: I started it.
Barbara: You started?
Shri Mataji: Yeah.
Barbara: I have a question that’s important
to me and to many people who are searching
for something or seeking perhaps, what you
call, Self Realization or Sahaja Yoga or something.
Some of us don’t know exactly what it is.
But we find that there are many teachers.
How do we recognize those teachers that you
might call fraudulent from the real ones?
It’s so difficult because they all seem
to be able to inspire us in certain ways and
give us experiences. How do we know who is
teaching something that’s true or who is
being deceptive?
Shri Mataji: First and foremost thing is,
anybody who lives on your earnings is not
a guru. A guru will never live on the earnings
of his disciples. But here there are people
who have built palaces, bought aircrafts and
cars and this. I mean, this is something one
should understand. It’s so, so open to you
to understand. I mean, I cannot understand
more obvious thing that this one is that it’s
a parasitic living. And, you cannot have a
parasites as your gurus. They can be parasites
but not your gurus. That’s one of the things.
And if you… [laughter]
I mean, you can retain some people, you know.
If you want because you are rich people, you
can retain some. That’s a different point
but you cannot have them as gurus. Guru has
to be a higher personality, you see. Now,
you have seen Christ was such a great incarnation.
He didn’t take any money from anyone. He
was a carpenter’s son and He used to do
carpentry Himself and He lived like a modest
man. He never lived with big cars and big
houses. It’s not necessary because such
a person is Himself is a very big king, you
see, like a big emperor. He doesn’t need
anything. An emperor doesn’t need anything
because nothing can give him comfort except
that he himself is in complete comfort. So,
such a person doesn’t want anything. So,
you must see that such a person has no needs
of comfort at all. He can sleep on the grounds,
he can sleep anywhere.
Now, in this life, I should say I come from
a quite a wealthy family or married to another
wealthy man, you can say that way according
to your own relative ideas. But to Me, I can
sleep anywhere. I have no problem. I have
no problem of food, no problem of sleeping
anywhere, no comfort. And, I find it is beyond
My self-respect to live on the earnings of
others. It’s not proper. But you are My
children. Supposing now you bring a flower
to Me or something, it’s all right but I
can’t have a palace out of your money and
all those things. It’s absurd. Absolutely
absurd! So, this is one thing one should know
that it pampers our ego that we can purchase
our guru. We can purchase our Self-Realization.
You see, this is a very subtle pampering.
And, that’s how people accept, you see.
They don’t want to accept a person who says,
“You cannot offer anything.” It’s too
much for them.
Or maybe that, secondly, could be that people
think that if you pay something then you get
attached to it, you go through it whatever
it is. Say, you have paid for a ticket and
you find that the whole play is horrid, you
can’t bear it but you have to go through
it because you have paid for it. That’s
the human nature, you see.
Barbara: Yeah
Shri Mataji: That’s the human nature. I
have seen that. They do it. And that’s what
it works out. But this is very gross level,
I’m telling you. But another should be that
in these modern times, it is promised that
you will become prophets. You have to become
prophets. So, you must see have you become
prophets out of these? Easiest is to see the
disciples of this man.
Any XYZ who says he is a guru – now what
is happening to the disciple? Is he a free
person? Has he got any knowledge? Has he got
any mastery? What has he achieved by being
with that person?
Now, you have seen here there are Sahaja Yogis.
One better than the other! You talk to them,
they are knowledge. Some of them have met
Me only for a say, eight day or so. They have
become knowledge. So, what have they achieved
you should see. What is their style of life,
their pattern of life, how they behave? And,
there cannot be any privacy about it, you
see, like mafia – you don’t tell that
and you don’t say that and you shouldn’t
do that. Of course, in Sahaja Yoga, the truth
is exposed gradually, but it is not like this
that if you give some money, nobody knows.
Everybody knows everything in Sahaja Yoga,
you see. Now, supposing we have to build an
ashram, say for example. All right, you build
your ashram; you collect your money, do what
you like and know about it. I have nothing
to do with it. Also, among yourself you should
know how you got the money, how you spent
it, what is the expense and all that. Because
ashram you can pay for but not for your Realization.
This is one thing is very important that what
you get out of it is important that you should
become a prophet.
Have you become a prophet?
Then, thirdly, you must know that if you are
going from one to another, what we call guru
shopping business – that means you have
not found it. Otherwise, you would just settle
down. But some people are so weak that they
do settle down with one and are finished with
them. You must always see the people who go
to these gurus, what have they got. Have they
got their transformation? Because this is
the age of transformation.
Barbara: Mataji, what about teachers or gurus
who produce miracles. You go to a guru who
will materialize something out of the air
and say, “This is divine.” That’s a….
Shri Mataji: This is all jugglery. It’s
all jugglery. And also, you see, now supposing
somebody says, “I produce a diamond.”
Now, these people come from India, why don’t
they solve the financial problem of India?
[laughter and applause]
Secondly, you see, at every point they can
be challenged. You should say that … then
all right, one gentleman came to Me and said
that, “He gave me a diamond.”
I said, “Why you? How many diamonds you
have?”
He said, “Hundreds.”
Then I said, “Why did he give you? He should
give to your driver who hasn’t got a diamond.”
You see, that is what it is. So, it is all
jugglery. You should see those who materialize,
what have they given you? They have to give
you something eternal. If they talk about
God, God is not going to give you diamond.
Which God has given diamonds to people? Have
you heard of anyone giving diamonds? No! [laughter]
So, you should ask for something which is
the highest, which is the supreme most.
Now, the fourth thing which is very important
that whatever experiences you get, for example,
some people start just like jumping, some
start shouting, some start behaving like animals.
And, they say, “Oh, that’s what is coming
out. We are taking out, you see.”
They feel very bad, they get horrible diseases,
they get into troubles and they get into pains
and all sorts of things and contortions. They
say, “Now your subconscious is coming out.”
Nothing has to be brought out. That’s one
thing you must know. The subconscious, as
I told you, is on the left hand side and the
supraconscious on the right hand side. What
you have to do is to ascend in the center
and come up. Above your head is the superconsciousness
and when you become that, then you develop
collective consciousness. So, those who want
you to become like frogs again, you must know
that you are not going to become frogs anymore.
That’s not anyway evolution. The evolution
has to go higher, not becoming frogs or earthworms,
you see. And if you start crawling, it is
simple mesmerism. Anybody mesmerizes can do
these tricks, you see. It’s simple mesmerism.
And, then to believe that now you are surrendered
and all that is all nonsense, you see. It
has no meaning to Realization. In Realization,
you just become the master. You become the
master of it.
There are many people in this country who
came and lured you by their talks also. Talking
big about Brahma, Atmatatva, this that and
everything – that is not the way you can...
That is what is just the pendulum moving from
Christian sermon to Hindu sermon and from
Hindu sermon to Islamic sermon, from there
to the Rabbi sermon. It goes on like that,
you see. That’s not the way. You have to
rise higher within yourself. And, that’s
why those who lecture about these things are
really sometimes can be very, very dangerous.
And, so many have died of cancer, this, that.
I don’t know what to say that people who
go to these people get into very bad troubles
and suffer so much. And, then on top of that
when all this happens, they say that, “You
must suffer.” That’s a very good excuse.
[laughter] “You must suffer.” You must
pay to suffer. Pay money to suffer. [laughter]
And, then people go on suffering.
Now, one thing I have to tell you that Christ
has suffered for us. We don’t have to suffer
anymore. Those who deny His sufferings will
have to go for suffering. All right, have
it! But He suffered for us. There is no need
for us to suffer anymore. When He is awakened
within us, He takes away all that is our ego
means our karmas, our superego, that is our
conditioning completely removed and you become
one with the Divine. There is no need for
anybody to suffer and this idea of suffering
is all nonsensical. You should not suffer
at all.
Barbara: Good! [laughter] I’m glad it’s
over. Mataji, You are called “Mother.”
And, it seems in the Hindu tradition there’s
a special context or meaning of the word “Mother.”
What is this meaning?
Shri Mataji: You see, in the Indian philosophy,
even in the Christian philosophy it is so,
but it has been little bit changed. If you
read the books of Essene, you will find they
have described the “Mother.” You see,
the Holy Ghost is the Mother. When they say
about the Holy Ghost, She is the Mother. But
how can you have… You must reason it out.
How can you have a father and a son without
a mother? [laughter] It’s a, you see, simple
thing like that. You see, so it’s the Mother
only. Holy Ghost is very important. So, Holy
Ghost is the Mother, you see. It’s absurd
thing, I mean, to have such a thing. Even
homosexuals cannot have children. It’s funny
thing, isn’t it. Absolutely absurd! But
Christians accepted this. I don’t know why.
Why didn’t they go into find out what is
this Holy Ghost business is? They said, “It’s
a mystery.” How can you say it’s a mystery?
When you cannot explain then better not say
anything about it. So, Holy Ghost is something
hanging in the air. No one knows; it’s a
mystery, and the rest of it is the father
and the son. It’s absurd!
Now, the principle of Mother is in every,
every scripture - has to be there. Now, the
Mother’s character is that She is the One
Who is the Womb, She is the One Who is the
Mother Earth and She is the One Who nourishes
you. She nourishes us, you know that. And,
this feminine thing in every human being resides
as this Kundalini, as you have seen. And,
when She rises, She gives you this new awareness
which becomes compassion, which is flowing,
which becomes soothing, nourishing energy
of love. And, that’s what today people are
saying feminist this thing and all that. That’s
again a pendulum – a man becoming a woman,
woman becoming man – all this problem there
are because of this. But when you move spirally
upward, then where do you move? You become
a personality full of compassion, of love,
of universal understanding through collective
consciousness. And, then you rise up to a
position where you become universally conscious.
So, that is what should happen to you, and
if that happens then we should say that your
motherly qualities within you have risen and
that’s what we have so far neglected. You
do not become a woman but you become motherly.
First the father, then the son, and now the
mother! All right?
Barbara: What is the role of woman in this
world, the role of the feminine principle?
Shri Mataji: I would say … I don’t say
that women as women who are born as women
only have the role, even the men have, everyone
has because everyone has Kundalini within
them. But the women must know that if they
are women, they have a greater responsibility.
Not that they should sit at home and only
look after children and brood and then nag
the husbands when they come home. [laughter]
That’s not their role. The role is such
that they have to be forbearing. Any person
who is the mother has to be like the Mother
Earth - how much She is forbearing, how much
She suffers! We dig Her out, we torture Her
life. Still, She is giving all the time; She
is soothing, forgiving, bearing it out. We
are doing so many sinful things, I mean, She
should explode real with anger, the way it
is but She does not. She is very careful.
She slowly, slowly informs that “Now get
out of this place, it’s rumbling.” She
is so kind, you see - that all should come
to us.
So, it’s not that it is only the women who
should settle down with these qualities, but
the time has come that men have to have these
qualities. Otherwise, there will be always
an imbalance. So, now the men have to become
extremely kind, affectionate, compassionate.
Give up that competitive spirit, that fighting
spirit like Napoleon had - all those ideas
are outdated. Now, whom do you respect? People
like Mahatma Gandhi or Abraham Lincoln. Everyone,
an American should think of Abraham Lincoln.
Barbara: Yes, indeed. Mother, what are we
doing here? What is the purpose of life on
earth? What are human beings walking around
on this planet for?
Shri Mataji: You are specially made by God.
You are specially chosen by God to be human
beings and you are here with a very great
purpose. The first purpose of God is that
you should become the vehicle of God’s powers,completely.
So that He flows through you, He flows into
this atmosphere, into this universe, to make
it a divine place. When you get Realization,
what happens? These - all your abnormalities
drop out and you become very normal person
and these vibrations of Cool Breeze start
flowing. With this now you can give it to
Mother Earth, you can give it to the plants,
you can give it to the trees. The whole thing
becomes a “Garden of Allah” where you
reside in complete joy and happiness.
The second purpose is that God has prepared
you now to settle into His Kingdom. That’s
your throne. That’s your right to be there.
It could have been short circuited at a time
when Adam and Eve were called and told not
to go into this so-called “book of knowledge”
or the “fruit of knowledge.” But they
didn’t listen, you see. If you give freedom
to someone then, “What’s wrong?” So,
they started doing things which were brought
to them by a satanic force and they accepted
it. So, that was the original sin we have
committed. So, they had to take incarnations,
do all those things and now brought it to
this level where human beings have to be brought
again back to the position where they were
to go.
Barabara: Mother, what is the true nature
of death? Is it possible that you can choose
not to die? What’s the purpose of death?
Shri Mataji: See, death is just like changing
your clothes. So sometimes when you use too
much of your clothes you get tired. You want
to change it. Like that death is. Nobody dies,
there’s nothing that dies except that the
part that is the Mother Earth and the part
that is the water falls off, and you remain
as you are. But if you are a realized soul,
then you have a choice. If you want to be
born again, you would like to be born. If
you don’t want to be born, you will not
be born. But after Realization, it becomes
your choice. If you want to die, you can die.
If you don’t want to die, you need not die.
But you want because you think that “Let
us die and come back as new people again to
help Mother.”
Barbara: Many of us have heard discussions
or read in books about the evolution of matter,
the evolution of substance. What are Your
views on evolving matter and how does this
relate to our own physical matter in our bodies,
in our cells?
Shri Mataji: For the matter did go into evolution,
you know that, and when the carbon was established,
actually our first Chakra was established.
That’s carbon which is tetravalent and carbon
is the one which started producing amino acids,
you see. When amino acid started manifesting
itself this, then the other processes took
place by which the evolution of,say, from
amoeba to human stage took place. That also
we understand very well after getting Realization,
how we became from amoeba to human stage;
and after human stage we have to achieve our
Self Realization, means the Spirit which is
in our heart has to manifest in our attention,
or we have to feel it on central nervous system.
But what is the relationship between matter
and this? We should see that point. It’s
important.
Now, through the matter all our centers are
made. For example, the two centers that are
down below are made of the Mother Earth principle.
And, then another one and another one like
that. All these elements have contributed
to make the centers. And, these centers are
just like mirrors made and the reflection
of the Divine falls on them. Then, at a human
level the matter improves so much, goes into
such evolutionary processes, that the reflection
at the heart level improves so much that the
Spirit shines there,and the Kundalini is properly
set for your evolution which is the epitome
of evolution. Like this instrument that is
made one by one first collecting this part,
that part, that part then put together. Now
the time has come for you to be put to the
mains. Now, this has nothing to do with the
electricity if you see. It exists without
electricity but it can carry the electricity.
In the same way, we become the lamp and when
we become the lamp, the light can be brought
in and we become enlightened. So, there is
a big relationship between the lamp and the
light but light cannot exist without the lamp,
so lamp has to be there.
Barbara: Mother, can I ask you a question
about sex?
Shri Mataji: Yes please. [laughter]
Barbara: It was stated today that sex has
nothing to do with evolution the way it’s
been described in Sahaja Yoga. What does this
mean?
Shri Mataji: You see the thing is that we
think that by doing sex or by going into sex
we can evolve. It’s absolutely falsehood.
You have not become a human being from amoeba
to this stage by doing sex. Because animals
all do sex; everybody does sex. If they do
it or not, makes no difference! The thing
is the evolution takes place only through
your seeking. When you start seeking something
then only you evolve. And, the seeking first
was for food. If you see in the animals was
for food. You see, sex was spontaneous, they
don’t think about it, they don’t read
about it, they don’t have any education
about it – nothing. Sex comes out spontaneously,
just like your breathing you see. You don’t
have to have as you have in your schools now
teaching sex. What is there to teach I don’t
understand, I mean? It is such a spontaneous
thing. On the contrary, the more you talk
about it, the worst it becomes, you see. And,
the more it becomes the brain thing, you cannot
do sex with your brain, you see. [laughter]
So, it’s all a nonsensical thing. All these
things have added to your problems of impotency
and all sorts of things in this country. Too
much thinking about sex, at the time of sex
you are nowhere, you are lost. So, what’s
the use of such a life, you see? So, the people
who think about sex too much are really very
unnatural people, they are very unnatural.
To be natural is to keep it spontaneous, to
live very spontaneously. Of course, as an
Indian lady it is too much to speak on details
but I would say that… [laughter]. We are
not supposed to even say the word “sex”
in Indian life, you see, it’s like that,
you see, but I think we are very potent people.
The amount of children we are producing, you
can never produce even if you want to. [laughter]
So, now the thing is that as a Mother I give
all sort of grace to these people, grace marks
I should say, when they said that the sex
can take you to Kundalini. Because you know,
in the beginning they must have tried something
like that and they must have seen the expression
of the deity which has got a trunk, you see,
which is settled on this center. We call it
as Ganapati who actually incarnated as Christ
on this earth later on. But He is the Ganapati.
And, there you see just the trunk and they
must have misunderstood that this trunk is
the Kundalini because it has a shape like
that. And, that’s why they might have said
it, but it’s the most dangerous thing. If
you go through sex, then you are open yourself
absolutely to hell. If you go towards sex
and try to come to God, it’s absolutely
wrong, you see.
Christ has gone to such a limit because Christ
was born here and He looks after our all optic
lobes and all this part of the eyes. And,
what He said, “Thou shalt not have adulterous
eyes.”
Just see. What does that mean? That means
you have innocent eyes. He was innocence.
He was the embodiment of innocence. “Thou
shalt not have adulterous eyes.” No lust
and no greed in your eyes. Now, is only possible
is if Christ is awakened within you. Once
He is awakened within you, then you will have
your innocence and you will also lose the
lust from your eyes. Eyes will be absolutely
looking, but not getting involved. That sort
of a thing will happen to you.
So, the sex which is a normal thing to do
has to be sanctified by collective people.
Should be done in a proper way so that you
get good children. The marriage should be
sanctified collectively and should be done
in a proper way and should be looked after.
Because now of course people are on a different
line but when I had come ten years back, when
I told them that you have to have sanity about
sex, they were very angry and they said, “You
are Victorian.” They called Me Queen Victoria.
[laughter]
But now I think they have learnt a lesson
because I had told them, I had told them that
“You will get a disease which you will not
be able to work on. Don’t do all this nonsense
of perversion. It’s very nonsensical.”
But even now they are trying to evade the
issue. Don’t try to evade the issue. You
can be cured of that disease if you can awaken
your innocence within yourself. Through the
grace of Christ only we can do it.
Barbara: Mother, we have learned, heard that
when we learn love then we shall have will.
What is the relationship between love and
will?
Shri Mataji: When we’ll have love, then
we’ll have will. Good! Love is when you
become the Spirit, because Spirit is nothing
but God’s love. – is All Pervading Power,
is Spirit. So, when you know that love which
is not attachment - it’s not attachment,
you see, like a sap rises in the tree, it
goes even to the trunk, and then to the branches,
to the leaves, to the flowers, to everyone.
It doesn’t settle down into one flower.
If it does, then the flower dies and the tree
also dies. So, it is not attached, but it
is nourishing. It does what it has to do.
That kind of a love which is absolutely without
any conditions, unconditional, without any
lust, without any greed - that kind of a love
when you will know. That is only possible
when you will become the Spirit. Then you
will know the Will of God. The Will of God
- what is to be done, because you don’t
know.
When you get your Realization what happens
is this Cool Breeze is like a computer working.
You ask the computer, “Now, should I do
this work?”
If it is yes, you will have cool vibrations.
If not, no vibrations. So, you will know His
Will. Thy Will be done, you see. How do you
know His Will? Then you just know. You become
the knowledge. When you become the knowledge,
when you become the love, then you become
the knowledge also. Even in everyday life,
if you love somebody you know a lot about
that person.
Barbara: Mother, this afternoon You said something
very interesting in response to a question
by a woman. And, the response that You gave
was, “Service and sacrifice are a myth,
or is a myth.” Can you describe what You
meant by that?
Shri Mataji: Yah. You see, when I said that,
when you become a saint, in the sense when
you become a realized soul, you find that
you are collectively conscious. Then what
happens that if somebody has got a problem
you feel it on your fingertips. Now, you rub
your fingertips and the person feels all right.
Now, you have done no service, you have done
no sacrifice. It’s your finger that is in
trouble. Now, if you rub your finger, who
is the other? You see this comes out of ignorance
and those … in India actually, they knew
it so well that those people who talked of
sacrifice and service were called as Shudras,
means untouchables. That means they had no
knowledge about it. Those people who talked
that, “We’ll serve you; we’ll do this
dirty work of yours, that dirty work of yours”
– they were called as Shudras. They are
not the people who should be touched because
they have no awareness that the All Pervading
Power of God is there which does everything.
What you have to do is to just become one
with It.
And, once you are one with the whole Primordial
Being, say, on your body if there is a pain
somewhere, you just rub it. All right, you
rub it and it’s all right. There’s no
obligation on it. In anyway you have not served
anyone, you have not obliged anyone. So, the
concept that you are one with the Whole itself
is the noble’s concept. And, those people
who do not have that concept cannot understand.
They think, “We are serving others; we are
looking after others.”
“Who is the other?” I ask them. Who is
the other?”
That is why this is the concept with which
Indians have always lived. And, that’s something
good they have. But they also picked up - you
see, when your missionaries went there they
also started their missions, this, that, serving
and serving and all that.
Now, to the poor people, now how do we serve?
We serve in this way in Sahaja Yoga that once
they get their Realization they don’t remain
so poor at all. You see because first of all
the poor people have bad habits of drinking
- all those things drop out. So, all that
money doesn’t go into nonsensical thing.
Secondly, they get those vibrations. Now,
whatever work they are in they become dynamic.
They have no health problem. They don’t
have to go to the doctors. They become healthy
people. Mentally, they are so alert that they
do better than any other.
We have seen people who came to Me and said
that, “Our children are very bad at school.
Must do something about them.”
When they got their Realization, now they
stood first. They got all the scholarships,
everything. They are doing so well. So, such
people become also materially better off.
They don’t become extraordinarily rich but
they become materially well-off, satisfied
people. You see, also dissatisfaction is another
poverty because you are dissatisfied. I think
those are the greatest poor people because
they are never satisfied. But the people who
are realized souls are satisfied souls. They
know how to live well and they are helped.
Like Krishna has said it, “Yogakshema Vahamyaham”.
He said, “I’ll give you Kshema after Yoga.”
First He said “Yog.” “Kshema” means
your well-being. So, well-being acts after
Yoga, not before.
Barbara: Mother, in the West there is a great,
especially I would say in this part of the
West – in the West Coast, there is a great
interest in subjects such as kabala, tarot,
astrology, spiritual alchemy. How does Sahaja
Yoga relate to these? What are Your views?
Shri Mataji: I can’t understand. That means
they are not seekers those who have such interest,
you see, because these things relate to a
material life.
Barbara: How do they relate to material life?
Shri Mataji: You see, because kabala will
tell you when will you get married, or how
much money you’ll have, what race you’ll
win. All those things, you see. God has no
interest in these things, you see. All these
things are … spiritual alchemy – how will
you change this into gold. And, what does
it matter? Gold and all those things - what
are so important? Isn’t it? The most important
thing is to be your Spirit. And, those who
are seeking the Spirit are real seekers. All
others are seeking money in some other form,
you see, and then when they go to these people
- actually these are nothing but spirits and
they get possessed by spirits and they have
horrible time, you see. One should never indulge
into these things. Christ has warned the most
of all and we are doing it. So often, it’s
very wrong to ask for anything material like
that. Why should we have easy money like that?
It’s not good I think, through some spirit
helping you or something. I don’t know if
it really helps. It may little bit help but
give you later trouble.
Like, one lady had a problem with her husband,
you see. She said that, “He is a bad man;
he‘s a flirt and all that.”
She went to such a women and he became as
far as she is concerned, he gave up flirting
- but he started racing. And, he got lost
in racing. Then she went there and she said
that, “Now, he should be all right from
racing. He should get out.”
So, he started drinking. And, after sometime
he started doing all the three things, you
see. So, it was too much.
So, this kind of a nonsense you should not
indulge into if you are seekers. But there
are category of people who are seekers. That’s
what I feel, and those who are seekers are
getting into it should get out of it and get
to your Spirit.
Barbara: What’s the role of the artist in
this work, this Sahaja Yoga?
Shri Mataji: Who?
Barbara: An artist, artistic work like music…
Shri Mataji: Oh, great, great! Tremendous
it is! You see, those people who have been
realized souls have created eternal art. Like
we can say, Michelangelo was a realized soul.
So his work is eternal art. And, they produce
art which creates vibrations. You can feel
vibrations from him. In the whole church if
you go you feel horrid, but when you go to
Sistine Chapel and see his work, the whole
thing fills you up with vibrations. They are
creators of vibrations. Imagine! The musicians
like Mozart - Mozart creates vibrations but
Wagner… [laughter]
You see. So, they are the people who are realized
souls. You have some tennis players who are
realized souls also, perhaps you…
Barbara: Tennis players?
Shri Mataji: Yah! MacEnroe is a realized soul
and Borg is also. And, My grandchild told
Me, “You know, why Borg has retired? Because
another Sahaja Yogi has come now, the younger
one, so give chance to him and that’s why
he is very honorably retired.” [laughter]
Is because when MacEnroe speaks, you must
have seen, he tells himself “John, now behave
yourself.”
They are in the third person. And, that’s
why people don’t understand him and he doesn’t
like to be insulted. And, that’s very true.
Anybody who is a saint doesn’t like him
to be insulted. So, like that you have so
many people who are realized souls, we can
say. Even the Princess of Wales is a realized
soul and the new child is a realized soul.
So, there are so many people like that who
are realized souls.
Barbara: The listeners who will be tuning
in to this program on the radio won’t have
had the experience of being in Your presence.
Some of them may have who were in this room.
What can you say to them about how to become
a realized soul, how to achieve this Cool
Breeze that comes from…
Shri Mataji: At the beginning of My lecture,
if you tell them that they should put their
hands towards the radio. Just on the radio.
They might feel the Cool Breeze. If they don’t
feel it, then tell them to put the right hand
first till they feel the cool breeze, and
left hand up as if ventilating out. And, then
the left hand towards the radio and the right
hand up. It might work out because it has
worked in Hong Kong. [laughter]
Barbara: I’ll tell You something interesting.
I interviewed Danny and Doug before You came
so that listeners would have a chance to come
here. And, one of them called me and said
that he went into meditation in the afternoon
and felt the Cool Breeze just by hearing them
talk.
Shri Mataji: See, if Sahaja Yogis can do it
then when I’m talking it should happen.
[laughter]
Barbara: We are about at the end of the interview
and what I want to do now, Mother, is give
You a chance to say what’s in Your heart
to say. What is there that You wish to share
that has not been said this evening?
Shri Mataji: I have to say that America is
a great country in the universe. It has the
place of the Vishuddhi Chakra, which is the
center of responsibility and discretion. And,
they have been so responsible. So far they
have given such noble ideas of democracy and
of freedom and all those things which are
really all belonging to God’s ideas. And,
when they talk of all these things, we must
know that there is something much more that
they can give to the whole world. So many
saints are born in this country because they
realize that this is the country where they’ll
be able to prosper better into their spirituality.
So, it is a very great responsibility of Americans
to understand that we have had great leaders,
we have had great noble ideals, we have had
got great saints living here. So many are
anxious to come down here. Only thing what
we have to do is to establish within ourselves
our Spirit, and to be ready and prepared for
this great, tremendous work that is going
to come now. And, this is what the world has
to do. If emancipation of the humanity has
to take place, it has to take place only from
inside out and not outside in.
Another thing, I would like to tell that the
danger is not from outside for America, not
from anywhere else. It is from within themselves.
So be careful. We have to be careful about
ourselves - the way we are destroying. When
we say, “What’s wrong?” we go head long
into our destructions. Human beings should
not take freedom as abandonment, but freedom
to enjoy completely and fully. The freedom
that takes you to a destruction is not freedom.
The right idea of freedom must be taken. And,
people should know that freedom, ultimate
freedom, is when you become your own master,
when there are no habits, when you cannot
be dominated by anything. You are above everything.
That’s the freedom you have to achieve,
and that is why people talked long time back
in this country about freedom. They helped
all the countries to get their freedom, and
now it is their job to get them their own
freedom within themselves so that others will
also follow.
May God bless
you all.
Barbara: Thank you, Mother.