as you know our second chakra is very
important so what is the swadhishthana
is the general it's very important
because in this Kaliyuga
swadishtana box
we have so many agents to make it work
and work very hard you know what is the
second chakra interstate 8 Kappa what
happens that we have caught up by our
ambition and the ambition needs to run
up and down and I'll see it marry sir
you breeze also getting lost so it's a
very important a for all of them
so second chakra is important because in
modern times it is very very costly as
well exactly we become radiant
overactive and we start thinking about
everyone we are not concerned and
bothering our heads
so today's chakra is important because
it bothers your head it troubles you a
lot and you start thinking about them
you start thinking what have you said
what has happened who is angry all sorts
of nonsense you are all sahaja Yogi's so
you shouldn't worry as through all these
people what they say what they are doing
you should just enjoy yourself
second chakra you must enjoy that's the
best way to enjoy sahaja yoga where your
swadishtana is satisfied nothing can be
stony point disturb and swadishtana you
can really do conquer so this landscape
is so much good for you because now you
are sahaja Yogi's and you can master it
that is one chakra which offsets
pressure in the West people think too
much all the time thinking
that's wrong swadhishthana you get that
problem from Soares ha
to satisfy sauna Stan you have to take
to silence you have to take the boy to
and look at yourself
what is bothering you what is troubling
you what gives you ideas and thoughts is
Feliciana
and some people think so much there may
not be any problem but they create their
own problem with the solution and just
go on bothering about stuff so
understand it's very happy when you are
just laughing and enjoying and not
bother about consul's how much time we
waste on nonsense we don't need it
so Yogi's no need it it's only those who
are not yet realized must be suffering a
to suffer and they might even trouble
you but just laugh at you but you must
pardon them or give them is what they
are doing this because they can take it
you see the Spanish and your eyes
bothering them so they parted so now
don't allow your mind to bother about
whatever nonsensical thoughts are some
all kinds of all kinds of bouncing
you have nothing to do with them but
that thoughts are coming now this is the
work of mr. swirly time you must get
into silence
once you get into silence then he will
move and don't bother so what you have
two things now not to have anything to
do with swadhishthana but what you have
to become is your surgeries I had no
swadishtana to bother Australia is
really great to have beautiful children
like this I had people scared question
that is first thing you must do is to
care for direction that is fighting your
father's done anything father shoe you
worry about your own children finish you
want to bother about them and everything
will work out you are definitely blessed
because you are not falling to the whims
of time so it makes you run up and down
and thinks and think anything specially
all the sahaja Yogi's have this problem
so you should just think
that you are sitting and you have to
become silent and beneficial and how I
see you all and I'm very happy because
that's gone now all that nonsense is
finished and there is nothing bothers
the root of all religion is Felicia it
comes from there so you should know not
to play into the hands of Cilicia and
going to thinking thinking thinking they
want thinking having something that
doesn't exist they go on TV so initial
spot comes in you Henri de Monte
relations are there too simple you don't
think if you have any problem you get me
but you don't think what do they do you
can write it down and send the problems
to be I have to see all right