Today we are here to worship Shri Krishna within us.
As you know, that you all have been seeking
before coming to Sahaja Yoga.
You went to different places, read lots of
books, and also some of you were lost.
And in that seeking, perhaps you did not know
what you were seeking.
What you were seeking was to know yourself.
In all religions it is said “Know thyself.”
It’s a common thing all of them have said.
This is one point which is absolutely there
in every religion, “Know thyself” –
because without knowing yourself you will not know God.
You will not know spirituality.
So the first step was to know yourself,
and that one people did all kinds of tricks with you,
they taught you in a different ways
and tried to actually loot you and cheat you.
All those things have happened, is finished.
So then you come to Sahaja Yoga and you get
your Self-realization.
Well, what is the purpose of Self-realization
is to know God, or the Goddess;
that is the purpose of Self-realization.
But after getting Self-realization, what should
happen to you?
Many of you have lost interest in nonsensical
things like drugs and all those things;
you have lost interest in reading also useless
books; you have lost interest
in other habits like drinking and all that.
But that’s not enough, that’s not enough.
That would happen in anyway.
What has to happen by knowing God, is that
why does God wants you to know Him?
Because He wants to see His reflection in you.
He wants to see His reflection, that’s why
He has created you, and He wants to see His
reflection in you.
Same with the Goddess.
She has given you Self-realization because
She wants to see Her reflection in you.
So you have to prepare yourself for that reflection,
which is so much purer, beautiful, loving,
compassionate and above all, full of wisdom.
So this is the point one has to reach, where
you understand you have to have wisdom.
If you are lacking in wisdom then you are
not a self-realized person.
At the level of Shri Krishna, you see, He
wants you to become one part and parcel of
the Virata – or the Viratangana, also wants
the same thing, that you should become part
and parcel of the Virata.
Not because you are realized souls now, so
you go about thinking you are perfectly all
right, you don’t have to do anything about
it.
What do you do beyond this is the point, that
after Self-realization you have to see the
reflection that should be within you from
the lives of these people like Shri Krishna.
Shri Krishna was first born in a very difficult
situation, as you know, and He was carried
from there to Gokul, where He was brought
up by Yeshoda.
Now there He started His playfulness.
So you have to be playful in life, you have
to create fun and joy.
He didn’t say that you sit down like a old
sage somewhere in the Himalayas, but you mix
up with children, you talk to them, you play
with them, have fun.
At the same time He was destroying negative
forces which acted upon Him.
In His playfulness only He has done it, as
a child only He has done it.
How matured He was as a child you can see,
that He killed the Putana, and there are two
horrible rakshasas also, He killed them.
At the same time He was playing with the gopis
and teasing them, troubling them, making fun of them.
Why?
Because He wanted them to be playful; and
all kinds of celebrations He arranged.
He had once a big rain came, and He lifted
the complete mountain on His fingertips.
That time these people should have understood,
it’s not possible, it’s a miracle.
But He was just standing there with the one
finger at the mountain in a very simple, unassuming
manner; He was doing all that to protect all
the boys who were playing with Him.
Then He went and killed Kaaliya, the one who
was a big snake in the water.
In the water this horrible fellow was creating
venom, and by which many people were killed.
It took Him no time and He jumped inside that
horrible water of Yamuna, from where He rescued
in a way all the people by killing or hitting,
or you can say that by winning over this Kaaliya.
But the wives of the big serpent, they asked Him
that “Please forgive him,” and He forgave.
All these things show a child of six, seven
years doing all these great things without
feeling what He was doing, we can say that
without even thinking about it.
But He achieved it, because He was aware that
He was Shri Krishna.
So first thing, you have to be aware that
you are self-realized people.
You are not ordinary people to behave in an
ordinary way, you are special people made
specially to reflect the qualities of God
Almighty.
It’s not expected that you go and kill Kaaliya.
But the situation is such today that you are
all the time protected.
You are all the time protected.
No one can harm you, no one can kill you,
and you can be looked after
because you are Sahaja yogis.
Now what should be the attitude of a Sahaja yogi
towards taking decisions, one should understand.
It should be a spontaneous decision.
You don’t have to tally it with this, go
there and find out – immediately, spontaneous,
like Shri Krishna who jumped inside the river.
So in the same way you should have a very
spontaneous decision for anything.
Now you want to buy, say, a carpet.
All right.
You go in the shop and immediately you should
know which is the one.
In every walk of life you should have a very
spontaneous decision, instant decision.
But what I find, the style is very different.
They’ll go from shop to shop, then make
a list of it, then make all the measurements,
then go home and say that “We’ll decide
it tomorrow.”
That’s not the way a Sahaja yogi behaves.
Sahaja yogi has to decide everything absolutely
spontaneously, at that moment.
You should be like this: now somebody is getting drowned,
so the first impulse should be that you have to save.
And how do you save?
You jump in the water – because you are
protected, nothing can happen to you,
so just jump in the water and you’ll save the person.
Minimum of minimum this should be your attitude,
this should be your temperament, that you
take a very spontaneous decision.
All this thinking and all kinds of decision-making,
and having a big conference for decisions
and all that – not needed.
In day-to-day life also you have to be like
that.
Also in every political life, economic life
or any other life you have to lead, you have
to be very spontaneous.
How do you become spontaneous?
What quality you have got?
What is the weapon you have got, to know what
decision to take?
Do you know?
You have got vibrations, you have the feel of the vibrations,
and you know what vibrations are.
You know what vibrations tell you, and convey
and communicate to you.
They speak to you.
So through your vibrations you should know
in a second what should you do.
For example now, somebody told Me that “Mother,
when I came to Cabella I felt tremendous vibrations.”
It’s a fact.
But how many of you feel that way?
Because your sensitivity is not yet developed.
You have to be sensitive about your vibrations.
You should know looking at anyone, sitting
next to anyone, even shaking hands with anyone,
you should know what sort of vibrations that
person has.
This kind of sensitivity if you develop,
then you will definitely take a very spontaneous decision.
You know I am very good at it.
I bought this Cabella in five minutes, really
five minutes.
When I came here they said, “You can’t
go up, because You have big car.”
So the Mayor said, “All right, come along,
I’ll take You in my car.”
So I went with him on the car, on that car,
and I saw it.
It was all dilapidated, no doubt.
It was all absolutely in a shambles, all right,
and looked like a ghostly place, no doubt.
And everybody who was with Me, they said,
“Ah, what a place, Mother!
You can’t buy that.”
So I told the Mayor, “I am buying it.”
“When?”
“Today.
Now!”
He was amazed.
I said, “You tell Me, how do I buy?”
He said, “Very easy.
In this Italy You have to buy like this, that
You pay one-third of the price, all right?
And then You can occupy.
If You find something wrong with the place
You can give up, but then You’ll not get
Your money.
But if the other fellow who is selling You
says no, then he has to pay double.”
I said, “Very good bargain.
I am buying.
I have told you I am buying.
I’ll buy.”
And everybody was surprised what Mother was
doing.
So what decided was the vibrations.
Vibrations of the place just decided.
I said, “Buy it.”
That way they took Me to seven, I think, castles;
I said no.
Outside only I could say no, and they were
surprised I didn’t even go inside.
I said, “Ask them what was here.”
They said, “Nunnery.”
I said, “See?”
Now you should develop that kind of a spontaneous
decision.
Then you will be amazed how in such a short
time you can really achieve such great things.
But that doesn’t mean that you all should do that way;
first you should have that sensitivity of vibrations.
If you have that sensitivity of vibrations,
then I would say you are now matured in Sahaja Yoga.
So the maturity has to be brought in.
You cannot just say, “Now it’s all right,
I have got Self-realization, I can do this.”
First you tally your sense of sensitivity.
So now, how do you know?
For example, you take a spontaneous decision,
you find that you have got nothing, it’s
all nonsense – possible.
But you can see for yourself that your decisions,
if they are spontaneous: if they fail, if
they are wrong, if there are some mistakes
or that will make you suffer, whether economically,
politically, in every way, then your whole
value system will be judged very well how
far you have gone into Sahaja Yoga, how far
you have achieved your Self-realization, and
where are you.
This is what is the way to test yourself.
You should not be afraid of failures, and
not get enamored by success, because you are
self-realized souls.
Of course, if you are sensitive, immediately
you will know what is it.
Now of course, I wouldn’t say that
you could have the same as I have, but you should try it.
Now, I have seen some people will praise some
man, “Oh Mother, he’s so good.
You must meet him.
He’s such a nice person and he’s of such
a help, and this will happen and that will
happen.”
I said, “All right, you show Me a photograph.”
I said, “I am sorry, I don’t want to meet
him.”
They can’t understand.
“Such a great man, he’ll be a minister
tomorrow.”
“I don’t want to meet him.”
And you find immediately, just next day, a
big report about him in the newspaper that
he’s a very bad man.
So you must tally your experience and your
understanding of what you have decided spontaneously.
But still I would say, keep to spontaneous
decisions.
Don’t think about it how it should work
out, what should we do.
It has a very far-fetched influence on your
mind also that you see, that you know what
is right and what is wrong.
I don’t know how many of you have seen the
house I have built.
The another side of Shri Krishna was that
He was extremely creative.
In His childhood He did all these things,
these pranks, and when He became a grown-up
person He became the king of Dwarika, of that
area.
And He used to dress up like a king only – after
all, He was a king.
When He was a child He used to wear a small
little piece of a feather from the peacock,
but when He became the king He was wearing
all the things, and He used to sit on the
throne and talk to people in that manner.
All that greatness was there, and He was extremely
creative.
He built a beautiful, very, very beautiful
castle or you can say, palace in Dwarika,
out of gold – can you believe it?
Shri Krishna did it.
And it was all then covered with water.
Now the intellectuals in India, all trained
by Western people I think, said that it’s
not possible, there’s nothing in the water
and He never built His palace there; it’s
all a story just, just like a myth.
But some people believed in it, and they dug
up.
They went down and they found there was a
very big palace.
There was gold little bit left, but not all
of it was there.
And they were amazed, such a huge, big palace
He had made.
Under the water it had gone, but it was there.
Like this, all these incarnations who came
were extremely creative.
If you are not creative, what’s the use
of Self-realization?
Now, what is the greatest creative thing you
can do very easily is
to make others Sahaja yogis.
That is the easiest and most joy-giving thing,
is to make others Sahaja yogis and give them
the blessings of the Divine, which they have
been seeking for ages.
By giving them, you don’t know what a solace,
what a blessing you give.
So now when you have got your Self-realization
– you got it very easily, I must say; they
all say that it is a instant nirvana, Sahaja
Yoga is instant nirvana, it’s true – but
whatever you get so easily and instantly,
you don’t understand the value of that.
They always say for India that they got their
freedom so easily; they didn’t get it that
easily, that’s why they do not value it.
But it is true, if you get anything free firstly
and without any special effort, then you don’t
value it, you don’t understand.
You think it’s a matter of right.
But do you know how much people have suffered
for getting Self-realization?
They used to go on the Himalayas, stand on
one leg, sometimes on their heads for months
together, and they didn’t get realization.
I have heard of some people who lived in a
room for twenty-eight years to get Self-realization.
And why they lived like that?
Because they thought by keeping away from
other people, other bad atmosphere, everything,
they might get realization.
They never got it.
So one must understand, though you have got
it very easily,
it’s something so precious, so great.
It’s not very easy to get Self-realization.
You read about the people who are self-realized.
Perhaps they did not even know how they got
it, they did not know even about the kundalini,
but they got it, through their guru maybe,
maybe their efforts.
Buddha, how much He had to suffer till He
gets His realization – think of Him, how
He got His realization.
I mean, you shudder to see of His life: ultimately
dies of hunger and poverty.
But nothing happened to you.
You have got it without any difficulties,
in a very sweet manner, all of you.
Nothing – you don’t have to pay, you don’t
have to do anything about it.
But that doesn’t mean you should not value
it.
Like a seed which is put in the Mother Earth
spontaneously sprouts and gives life to the
primule which grows, can grow into a shrub
and then into a tree.
But you have to put water in, and you have
to have the care of a gardener or someone.
In your case, you are the one who has to do
all that.
First of all you have to put the nourishment
of compassion and love.
Have you got that compassion and love?
Do you love people?
Like somebody told Me today – I was shocked
– “I don’t like children.”
I said, “You don’t like children?”
“No, I like others’ children, not mine.”
Just imagine, how can you be doing that?
How can you say such a thing, you don’t
like your own children, anything?
First of all, for all of you I would say that
you should never say “I like” and “I
don’t like.”
These are anti-mantras.
“I like this” – it’s very common.
Who are you?
“I don’t like this carpet.
I don’t like that silver thing.”
Who are you?
Can you make one like that?
To take a decision of that kind is also shows
they think it’s very spontaneous – it’s not.
It has come from your conditioning, that you
think you have a right to say “I don’t
like, I don’t want.”
But who are you?
If you are the spirit you’ll never use these
words, because it might hurt somebody.
You’ll never say something that will hurt
others, you’ll never do anything that will
be dangerous for others; but always you’ll
say something that would be extremely loving
and compassionate, and peace-giving.
You will emit joy for others.
There is the power of spirit, that it gives
joy to others.
If you are a glum person, grumpy person, then
you are not self-realized.
You should be able to give joy and love and compassion,
and it should happen absolutely spontaneously.
There’s a story about a saint in India,
in Maharashtra.
So they all used to take water in a container
called as kanwar, and would take it all the
way to Gujarat, to a temple of Shri Krishna.
That was regarded as a great, you can say,
surrendering to Shri Krishna.
So that saint also carried water in that container,
this kanwar.
All the way he carried it from his village
in Maharashtra, and when he reached the temple,
at the foot of that temple he saw a donkey
very thirsty, dying out of thirst.
So he gave that water to that donkey.
Everybody said, “Imagine, you brought this
water for miles together, for days together
to be put on the deity here, and now you have
given it to this donkey.”
He said, “You don’t know, God has come
all the way down here to take the water.”
See the attitude that he took.
So for a self-realized person the compassion
should be like that, of very generous nature.
If you are not generous, if you are miserly,
always worried about your money and saving
of it, then firstly you are not a matured
Sahaja yogi – you are not.
Apart from that, this kind of money will never
give you any happiness.
Miserliness is against spirit.
Spirit is extremely generous, extremely generous.
It never strives to save something, or cheat
people or steal something – is out of question;
because there is no greed left in it, there
is no greed at all.
And that is why such a person who is a realized
soul cannot be greedy,
has to be extremely generous.
I have seen many people like that who have
been extremely generous, and who have been
very understanding about the problems of others.
While a Sahaja yogi will have his own problems,
he is not a Sahaja yogi at all.
He is there to solve the problems of others,
and not to solve his own problems and go about
talking about it, “This is the problem I
have.”
Now this is a new word that has developed
in modern times.
They never used to use the word “problem”
before, I tell you; only for geometry we used
this word “problem.”
But now it has started with a … “There’s
no problem.”
They are all in a problem, actually they are
problems, I think.
So what you have to do is to understand that
you should not give your problems to others.
You should not ask for anything, “Please
do this for me, please do that for me.”
It’s very surprising that people try to
sort of take advantage of others.
Now some people like to visit some countries,
so they will ask you, “Please call me.
I would love to come to your country,”
and a generous Sahaja yogi will say, “All right, come along.”
Now, who is failing here is the person who
asked.
You shouldn’t ask for anything whatsoever,
because you are complete.
Not that only you are satisfied, but are complete.
What can anybody give you?
All desires just disappear when you are in
complete shape.
Like today I was coming, I saw lots of stars
had come out.
I said, “As soon as the moon will come,
they’ll all disappear.”
In the same way, when you are complete, you
do not expect anybody to do anything for you.
On the contrary, you want to find out what
you can do for others.
You become the others, in a way that whatever
is the problem of others you take upon yourhead.
You jump into it.
It’s a very, very interesting growth that
should come in you.
It should happen to all of you, because you
have got your Self-realization.
You develop a kind of a personality which
only lives for others, not for oneself.
You will be amazed: you can live anywhere,
you can sleep anywhere.
You can have food, you need not have food,
whatever type of food you get it’s all right,
because you are so satisfied.
On the contrary, you’d like to cook for
others, give them food, do whatever you like
possible, you try to do.
As long as you can work it out, you do it.
But there are people who have only their own
problems.
They are not Sahaja yogis.
How can the spirit have problems?
How can that happen?
So just understand that you are now the spirit,
and beyond everything.
So your creativity also goes to other dimensions.
Of course you start giving realization to
people.
You create art.
You know Baba Mama, he was very bad at literature and he was – well,
he didn’t know any language.
He was very good for mathematics, because
My mother was a mathematician, but language
he did not know.
I used to write his essays, he was so bad!
But after realization he wrote such beautiful
poems.
Unbelievable!
Nobody can believe this Baba could do that,
because he didn’t know any language well.
I used to write his essays, as I told you.
So, amazingly, from where he started writing
Urdu poetry, Marathi poetry, Hindi poetry?
And one of My brothers asked him, “How do
you get this Urdu poetry?”
He said, “Shri Mataji has, She tells me.”
Everything he used to say, “Mataji tells
me.”
So the creativity within you is just flowers,
and you are amazed at yourself
how this creativity has come in.
Now imagine, for a person who is a mathematician
becoming suddenly a poet – I mean, it’s
impossible situation.
And you have these capacities.
You have all these capacities that you can
become very creative,
and you have to be creative in every way.
I am very creative, I must say, I am all the
time working out something
which comes out very well.
And also I don’t have that interest as normally
people have, that it should be praised by
everyone or it should be, sort of, very much
in the newspapers and everything.
No, no interest.
You create for creation, for the sake of creation
you create, and you just enjoy that creation.
And you become very adaptable, or you become
so congenial with all the things people say,
talk – all right, let them do it.
They will be offensive, or they could be also
praising you … you don’t know that they
are praising you.
Even sometimes when you “Shri Mataji ki
Jai!”
– I also say, and then I forget they are
talking about Me.
Somehow you are above all that, and you are
there, and you just don’t understand why
human beings behave like that, why their behavior
is so funny.
Even when they come to Sahaja Yoga I see they
have a great desire to be leaders, or they
have a great desire to be a great organizer
of Sahaja Yoga,
to be very well-known in Sahaja Yoga.
They want to have an international fame as
a great Sahaja yogi.
But they do not think that “What creativity
I have shown?
What have I created?”
Just all these things are so common in human
beings that they always want others to praise
them, to have a very big sort of a exposure
– of what?
If you are a spirit, everybody knows.
What is there to expose, what is there to
show off, what is there to come forward?
Even if you are at the back there is light,
you know there is light.
So you have to get out of your darkness, because
you are the light and you spread light; instead
of if you are in the darkness, what light
can you spread?
So your spirit cannot have problems.
It has no fear.
But above all it has wisdom, tremendous wisdom,
and that wisdom is the one sign of you being
a very higher personality.
As I told you, this is evolution, and when
you are transformed you are evolved.
Of a very different nature you become, and
you are to stand out.
If Sahaja yogis are like other people, then
what’s the use of taking to Sahaja Yoga?
What was Christ?
He was a son of a carpenter.
He never got education.
But what did He do?
He was the Spirit.
He reflected God within Him, and that’s
why He got Himself crucified also.
Now in Sahaja Yoga you don’t have to get
crucified, there are all not such testing
things for you, but your value system is to
be checked.
You must find out how are you working out,
through introspection.
You should ask yourself, “So well now, Mr.
Sahaja yogi, how are you?
Are you indulging into all these things that
these people
who are not self-realized are doing?”
Just try to find out, because the growth of
Sahaja Yoga is shown in your behavior, in
your styles, on your face.
There is no wrinkles on a person like this,
he has no worry; you don’t worry, then how
will you get wrinkles?
Such a person doesn’t get upset with anything.
I mean, on the contrary he laughs at things.
Once in a church there was in Switzerland,
one lady came to hit Me with a Bible, and
I started laughing.
I said, “What a thing, and I have to be
hit by a Bible!” you see.
And she got such a fright that I was laughing,
and I was saying, “Look at this stupidity
of this lady, coming to hit Me with a Bible!”
I mean, I can understand stone or anything
else, but Bible will never hit Me.
All these things have happened in your presence,
and you know about it.
There are negative forces.
They try to harm you.
They will harm you bodily, they will harm
you mentally, they might harm you emotionally.
But when you are above this, then no one harms
you.
At least you never feel the harm, you are
not bothered about the harm.
But what have you created?
Today I had some ladies and some men, and
all for divorce.
After getting married in Sahaja Yoga, they
want to have divorces, can you imagine?
I was shocked.
And they had funny ideas that “my husband
is like my brother.”
I said, “Really?”
All kinds of stupid ideas coming into their
heads means there’s no light of the spirit
in them.
If you have light of the spirit, then your
understanding is very different.
You don’t worry about yourself, you only
worry about others, and you try to find out
solutions for them.
You try to help them.
It is very easy for you.
What is so easy for the light to burn?
Once it is enlightened, it is burning.
It’s difficult for it to go out of light.
But for human beings, I can’t understand,
even after realization, after growing for
years together they are still so stupid that
they don’t realize the value of their Self-realization.
It is something, the spirit, you cannot kill
it.
It cannot blow off.
This light will go off, but the light of the
spirit won’t go off.
But what is the oil that keeps it there is
your compassion, is love, care of others.
I know there are people who are very, say,
dominating, may be troublesome, what else
– but care for them.
Know that they are not like you, they are
not complete, they have problems; so you care
for them.
But instead of that, you start thinking that
“Why should I care for him?
How does he care for me?” or something.
Then you are finished.
So this kind of a reflection, or I would say
the reaction, is not that of a spirit.
A spiritual person’s reactions are very,
very different.
In the life of Shri Krishna you can see that
He had a friend who was very poor, and he
wanted to meet Shri Krishna.
And the wife of the friend gave him some rice
crispies, as you call them, “And that’s,
take for your friend.
You must take something for your friend.”
He was a little shy, you know.
And when he went to Shri Krishna, Shri Krishna
was in His palace, and the people at the door
said, “No, you can’t meet Him.”
He said, “All right.
You just go and tell Him that Sudama has come.”
He was sitting on the throne discussing something,
and He said, “Sudama has come!”
He rushed out and went to the door and hugged
him, hugged him again and again; and He said,
“Why are you standing here?”
He took him and put him on the throne that
He was supposed to, and He told His wives,
“Please come and wash his feet.”
And then they brought for him clothes and
all that.
He had a bath; He made him sleep on His bed
– see the love of Shri Krishna.
He had very dirty feet, all were cracked.
He tried to put on that some sort of a medicine
by which it would be all right.
He tried to do whatever was possible to him
to cure those cracks.
And He asked him to sleep on His bed, and
asked the ladies to fan him so that he doesn’t
feel hot.
See the compassion of Shri Krishna, it shows
so beautifully.
Are we that compassionate?
There was no need for Him to do that; it was
no drama, nothing – but His heart!
He took a spontaneous decision.
When He heard Sudama is there, He just rushed
there.
He just felt so happy that “My old friend
has come.”
Then, when He went to Hastinapur, there the
Duryodhan, the Kauravas’ eldest son, he
asked Him that “Why don’t You come and
stay in my palace?”
He said, “All right, I can come, but you
see, I will go and have food with Vidur.”
Vidur was a son of a maid.
He went and had His food with Vidur.
Now Vidur being a poor man, I don’t know
what food he must have given Him, while Duryodhan
would have given Him such sumptuous food.
So for such people, taste and the level of
food and all doesn’t matter; it’s the
love, the respect of Vidur, who was a realized
soul – respecting other Sahaja yogis.
If a Sahaja yogi respects somebody who is
a governor – I can’t understand; the spirit
is above everything else – and does not
respect a Sahaja yogi, there’s something
wrong with him.
He should understand that this spiritual person
is higher than all these people who have these,
all kinds of these big names behind them.
And that love is shown in everybody’s life:
all the saints, all the incarnations, everyone
had that love which was above everything else,
without expecting anything, not doing it just
to expect something from them.
It is a kind of a personality which really
reflects God’s love.
That reflection should come from you.
You are Sahaja yogis: that doesn’t mean
that you are something higher than others,
but you are different.
You are above them.
You have no superiority, that’s why you
are different.
You are so humble, that’s why you are different.
You are so joyous, you are so peaceful, that’s
why you are humble.
There are so many things I can tell you from
the life of Shri Krishna, showing He was,
they call Him Yogeshwara.
He was a Lord of Yoga.
It is because He was Virat.
But He showed it, His form, only to Arjuna,
to nobody else, because nobody was like Arjuna.
Arjuna also got a fright when he saw that.
So He lived like Shri Krishna, like a cowboy
He was living in Gokul, and He never showed
off His powers.
His powers were within Himself, which were
expressing spontaneously.
This power has wisdom and discretion, complete
discretion.
If it does not have then this is not divine
power, this is some satanic power: because
somebody is nice to you if you are nice to
that person, nothing doing.
Mostly we had in India people who were called
as avadhutas.
They were the realized souls who had gone
away from the society, from the multitudes,
and gone and lived in some small little place
or some cave or somewhere, hidden from others;
because they thought nobody is going to understand
them, so what’s the use of talking to them.
They were singled out, one person here and
one person there.
What could they do?
They were not like you, so many of Sahaja
yogis together.
You have so many friends and you have so many
others with you.
They were lonely people, and they hid themselves
from the society.
They would not meet people, because if they
tried anything they would be crucified.
But not you people, because you have a society.
You have a beautiful enlightened society of
very good friends, of very good spiritual
people.
With all this if you cannot create, then what
should I say?
You have to create something: may be art,
may be music, may be poetry, may be literature,
may be writing – whatever it is, you have
to create.
And above all, you have to create Sahaja yogis.
That’s the main creation you have to achieve.
That’s the main thing you have to have,
is creating Sahaja yogis all over.
And there I can go to places, can have programs,
do everything.
But you have to show with your own example
that this is something great, how they have
achieved this state; we should achieve also
that state.
So you will be the ones who will really inspire
them, who will really make them follow you
and take to a life of a Sahaja yogi.
Actually you are Mahayogis, if you become
complete – and you have to become.
Nothing is more important than becoming a
Mahayogi, by which your spirit gives joy,
peace and blessings to everyone.
May God bless you.