I am very, very happy to see so many of you
coming down here for the program.
Actually, I bought this land at least, at
least twenty-five years back.
I couldn’t do anything about it as they
had lots of objections, this and that, but
then somehow, I planned the whole thing and
it all worked out.
Happy to see you all here but with all those
difficulties ultimately now you find so many
Sahaja yogis attending this program, My puja.
I must remember My brother Baba who has worked
very hard for the propagation of Indian music,
classical music, all types of art, whatever
he could do.
It’s a very sad thing that he is not here
today to see you all.
He has done so much work religiously without
expecting any reward whatsoever and I wish
you could have him as your ideal and that
will work it out everything in that way.
There’s one thing about him I know, he never
tried to show off anything.
He was very intelligent, educated man but
he caught hold of all the people of ordinary
living and he looked after them and he promoted
their skill of music and art.
With the same idea, I decided to have this
place dedicated to his idea of propagating
music and art and I am happy to see that that
idea has materialized.
But I wish [UNCLEAR.
EITHER had or that] My brother was here to
make you feel very happy about it.
He was a very loving and a kind person.
Never used to get angry with anyone, I’ve
seen that.
But always he gave Me a very good picture
of every person.
You can’t help it.
[Speech in Marathi & Hindi begins]
Today I wanted to bless you all that
you become completely musical in temperament
– rhythmic and entertaining to others and
not quarrelsome.
Now as you have seen how the western music
is taking to wrong side, to the wrong progress
and I don’t want you to fall into that.
This will all disappear, I know because it
is [it is DEL] very destructive.
But
after
coming to Sahaja also, if you
have
the same destructive ideas, how
can anybody help you.
So
I hope you’ll fulfill My
ideal
about it.
May God bless
you all.