It is really gratifying
to come to Melbourne
I came here
because somebody who had come to Sydney
and said that "Mother, you must come to Melbourne.
We need you."
When I came here for some other purpose,
I felt vibrations of Melbourne
are really very good,
and here it is quite possible
that there maybe many seekers.
It is really gratifying as I said
to be here among you.
It's a fact that the time has come
for thousands and thousands and thousands
and millions of them
who are born as seekers on this earth,
have to get their Realisation.
They have to know their meaning.
They have to know why
why the nature has made them a human being from amoeba.
What is the purpose of their life?
Unless and until you find the purpose of your life
you are not going to be happy.
You are not going to be satisfied.
You may try anything else.
You may have one of those ego trips;
you may have other trips like seeking money.
You may have other things like going to drugs,
alcoholism,
livercation, all kinds of things.
But these things have not given any satisfaction,
to anyone.
You have to find out that Absolute,
without which we are in confusion.
That Absolute is within you.
That's why Sahaja Yoga
is as spontaneous thing, is a living thing.
"Saha" means with, "Ja" means born.
It is born with you,
as in a seed
all the maps of the seed that is going to manifest
are built-in.
In the same way within you,
your Spirit and your Kundalini
are all already existing there
and they are just waiting for a chance
to give you your Self-Realisation.
Before telling you about the benefits of Self-Realisation,
I have to tell you that you must keep your minds open
as you would for any science lecture or any other lecture.
There's no jugglery
or there is no shopping, guru shopping in Sahaja Yoga.
It is a happening, it’s an actualisation.
It is within you. It’s a living force,
like a flower becomes a fruit
or an egg becomes a chick,
you get your Realisation and you become a different personality,
a new dimension of awareness grows into you
and this new dimension of awareness
is an actualisation,
it's not just a mere words
or any kind of a brainwashing.
It is an actualisation within you,
which happens by which
you start feeling
the collective consciousness.
You are a part and parcel of the whole,
so many have said it.
We also believe in it
that we are the part and parcel of the whole,
but so far in our awareness,
in our central nervous system, we have not felt that.
So this is actually should happen to you.
In this we have to accept,
whatever is nourishing for our growth, after Realisation.
Gradually you started accepting it
and I'll tell you why it happens
but the thing is in Sydney I found
that people are extremely honest about their seeking
and they really appreciated my honesty.
This is a process
which was built in since long within us.
Here that you see different chakras.
Are placed.
Can you see? All right.
These centres are placed within
the human beings
and they exist as subtle centers
in the spinal cord and in the brain.
These are called in Sanskrit language as chakras.
These centres exist within us
as milestones of our evolution.
For example, the lowest chakra
called as the Mooladdhara chakra,
is the center,
at that point we were carbon atoms. We were matter.
At that point we were innocent. Matter is innocent.
So the first thing that was created within us was innocence.
This whole universe was created
after innocence was created.
This chakra is placed
below the Kundalini, if you see it clearly.
Kundalini is the pure power of desire.
Pure power of desire.
Whatever is pure we call it Holy.
Is the Holy power of desire,
which remains
dormant.
This power is the desire
to be one with the Spirit.
Without knowing the Spirit, you cannot know God.
You are to be input to the mains.
You are not yet put to the mains.
For example, this instrument that we have made
if it is not put to the mains, it has no meaning.
So that has to happen.
It's like the primule in the seed,
a germinating power
in the seed,
that you have got this power, residual power
sleeping
waiting for a moment
when somebody
who is authorised by the Divine
and not
by any organization or certificates
that human beings give.
But somebody, who himself is a Realised soul,
as an enlightened person
and he knows
what is this power is,
it waits for such a personality
and then it awakens itself
and you get your Self-Realisation.
It has to be spontaneous
everything vital in life has to be spontaneous.
The breathing that we have
is so spontaneously going on
that we take it for granted till it stops, or till we feel
that we cannot breathe.
If you have to go and read books,
or putting some efforts to breathe,
then how many of us could
even exist for more than
say five minutes?
It is so vital
is the culmination of our evolution
and as the whole creation was created by the Divine,
as you are also created by the Divine,
this great happening is to be done by the Divine.
Now some people asked me
that can it not happen by itself to us.
We do not know that at every stage of our evolution
some aspect of God had to incarnate
or some guidance had to come from the Divine,
to give us a higher awareness.
But specially at this time
it is very important
that somebody has to do it
because you have reached a stage where,
you have to know it in words,
and Divine had to speak.
It's a very common question that in,
I think people are ego orientated,
they said, "Why you Mother?" I said you better be there!
I’ll be very happy if you could do it
because I am a happily married woman,
I don't need anything from anyone,
I have to just give
but if you can do my work, I will be very happy to retire.
It's very easy to say, "why you?" I mean you should ask
God why He gave me these powers?
But they are there,
but one need not feel hurt about it so much also.
After all you have some many powers which I don't have.
For example, I don't know how to drive,
really I don't know.
I don’t know many things,
even I don't know how to open ordinary cans
but if I know how to open the Kundalini
why should it hurt your ego?
And why should you feel bad
because I have to really work day in day out.
To do this work,
it’s something just a gift to you.
There is no shopping;
you can't pay for it.
It is beyond,
your control.
To conceive God, you have to see, as the reality is.
You have to give up your conceptions.
Supposing I had conceived a hall
before seeing this,
I would have had funny ideas
but after seeing it
only I really know what it is.
In the same way
people have written books,
thousands of books they have written
or even millions of books they have written, so what to do?
If they have written the books,
have they given you any Self-Realisation?
Have they given you that experience
of the absolute by which you know yourself,
you know your centres and you know the centre of others
and you start manifesting your own powers.
You become the master of your powers.
This is what should be the criteria of your seeking.
Why should you be identified with anything else but yourself?
Because I get people
belonging to this cult or this group
or this religion or this and that.
But you must understand
that you are not here
to be pleader for any one of them.
I mean you pay them to be their pleader
or to be their lawyers or solicitors, whatever you may call it.
But you should really try to honestly seek the truth
and ask for this truth
and then only you will get the truth.
So first thing one should understand
that you cannot purchase Divine.
You cannot pay for it, it is an insult,
it is an insult.
And secondly you cannot put in effort for that.
When you have to sprout a seed
what do you do? You put it in the Mother Earth,
and she sprouts by itself spontaneously.
It has got that force in it,
only you have to put it to the Mother Earth.
And the Mother Earth by her warmth
germinates the seed.
Do you get angry with the Mother Earth for that,
that, why must you do that?
If she has to do it, she has to do it.
Whatever the sun has to do has to do,
and whatever you have to do, you can do
and whatever the animals have to do, they do.
If we understand that
we have not yet achieved what we wanted to,
then you will realise
that there is a very little gap.
The Kundalini awakening takes
split of a second,
but its rising may take more time in certain people
because of blockages in the centre
or maybe some imbalances within us.
In short I will try to tell you
what is the Kundalini and what is this picture about.
I hope you have got some books with you,
you can also open and see for yourself.
Those who haven't got books can also get from them,
it will be easier to understand it.
At the back of the book you will find a nice chart.
Firstly you have to be honest about your seeking,
absolutely honest about it then everything will work out.
Now here you see this chart
is the first center
called as the Mooladhara chakra, as I said,
and the sacrum.
See the meaning of the word sacrum means sacred.
Sacrum is the bone in which the Kundalini is there.
I would like you to see from the top
this blue color balloon like structure
comes down up to the first chakra.
Now this,
represents a subtle force within us,
which is the power of desire.
It manifests outside
the left sympathetic nervous system.
This is the emotional side of a human being.
It is not only emotional.
This is the one that
takes conditionings
within itself
when we say "Don't do that, don't do that, don't do that"
and creates by its activity
a balloon like structure called as superego
which is in Sanskrit called as mana.
So this is the power of mana, of manashakti.
English language is a little
confused, when you say mental cases
you do not mean, the mental cases
that has something to do with the
mind which thinks.
But when you say mental cases,
you mean to say that they are the people who suffer
from emotional problems.
It's a little confused thing
but in psychology
it is very nicely described by Jung,
who was a realised soul himself,
the superego
and the ID part is this
power by which we
get all our conditionings within us
and we pass it to our past.
Beyond this area on the left-hand side
lies beyond the subconscious,
the collective sub-conscious, all that is dead,
since creation lies this side on the left-hand side.
This manifests as I told you,
the left sympathetic nervous system.
Now in the medical science,
there is no difference between the left and right.
But you will find out
they have entirely two different functions.
The left sympathetic nervous caters
to our emotional side which can be proved in Sahaja Yoga practice.
Now on the right hand side,
there is another power
which is the power of action.
When we desire, the desire has to be put into action.
And this power of desire
is called the prana Shakti,
or the power of action
the kriya Shakti, some people call it
and it looks after
our intellectual side,
our intelligence
and the mind with which we think about the mental side
and our physical side,
through which we go into action.
This as a result of it’s activity creates
another balloon you can see there,
a yellow color balloon
which we call as ego.
EGO, ego.
And this two powers meet at a point,
when a child is about say
12 years of age, he is completely
calcified here.
But in childhood only you see at
the age of say one year or one and the half year,
you start feeling the calcification,
of this soft bone called as fontanel bone.
In the center is the third power,
called as the power of evolution.
The power of sustenance.
The power of religion
which is innate within us.
Now "religo" means a
capacity, you can say a quality
like
gold is untarnishable,
that is the quality of gold.
Carbon has four valencies
that is the quality of carbon.
In the same way,
human beings also have got ten sustenance
and these ten sustenance are
the dharma
or the religions of a human being.
It has nothing to do with outside religions, whatever you believe into
or whatever you have fallen into or you are born into.
But there are ten sustanances within us,
which are in this area,
call as, we call it as Void, but it's not the same void as Zen says,
but is the visceral cavity
in this area,
we develop our sustenance.
By developing our sustanance only we evolve.
For example, first a fish
came out of the water
and developed a sustenance by it started crawling
and it became a reptile.
Firstly only one fish came
and then
shoals and shoals of fishes started
coming out of the water.
So
the evolution went on like this till we became human beings.
In this process,
as you know very well
the left sided and the right sided animals,
the right sided are the more ambitious, the dominating type.
The left sided are the sly.
As you have many nocturnal animals
they are all left sided,
they're frightened and live in the left
and those who are aggressive are on the right hand side.
They were discarded even some vegetables and what you
call the plants were discarded in the process of evolution.
And they were thrown on the right and left side.
And God created man in His own image.
That means
man has
everything that God has.
If He is the primordial being,
He is the macrocosm then you are the microcosm,
you are a cell in His body
but you are not aware of that.
There's a difference between awareness
and just consciousness.
Awareness is an actualization,
while just to be conscious
means mentally you believe, rationally you are a conscious, I know that,
we think we are brothers and sisters.
Now the centres that are
placed within. The first one, as I told you,
is the Mooladhara chakra.
You will be happy to know that
in the universe Australia is the Mooladhara chakra.
It's a fact you will know that
on vibrations if you ask a question you will know.
Basically you are innocent people.
You don't know also when you commit sins that this is sin,
you just do it very innocently.
You don't do it knowingly, innocently you do it.
And the center second center,
is the center called as Swadisthana chakra.
The first center manifests your pelvic plexus.
The right side, as I told you manifests the right sympathetic nervous system.
The centre one manifests your
parasympathetic which is broken, which is not yet complete.
Whatever you have achieved
in your awareness as a human being
is there and there is little gap,
where you have to just
break through into that, and become
united with that force.
Now this second chakra
is the chakra called as Swadisthana chakra,
you need not worry about the names,
but is the centre for action,
by which you think, think for the future.
And this center looks after
many other
visras or you can say organs within us.
It looks after your liver.
All attention is looked after by this centre.
Liver, then it looks after
your pancreas, your spleen,
your kidneys
and uterus in the women.
The most important function of
this centre is to manifest the aortic plexus,
in the gross and to convert
the fat cells of the stomach
to replace the fat cells of the brain
because after all the fat cells
of the brain are to be replaced because you think, think, think, think
and go mad with thinking.
You think so much
that as if two horns
are coming out of your thinking.
You may say the other day that "Mother,
mind is very important because
mind is the problem."
Don't you know that this mind is limited?
This rationality is limited.
You have to go to unlimited.
When I have to come to this hall,
we had to leave the car outside.
This mind can go up to a point and if you
try to go beyond that,
then you really go crazy.
We don't bring the cars inside,
in the same way this mind
cannot take you to the unlimited.
It’s a limited thing, you have to go beyond the mind.
This centre is doing this work
of supplying the fat cells and when you think too much,
all other visaras or all other organs are
not looked after, are neglected by which
the person who thinks too much
who lives in the future, who plans too much,
also then drinks, in addition to that, supposing,
and in addition to that
he does other things like
drug taking in the stomach and eats lots of fat food
and all that, so he really finishes that poor liver.
And that liver is the one that sorts out
all your poisons in the body, all kinds of poison.
But this liver gets out of order
and you don't feel it, only the heat starts accumulating,
you feel always nauseating
and you feel so unhappy, you don't want to face the present,
you want to run away.
You feel extremely horrid
you don't know what to do with yourself.
All that comes from a bad liver.
Also apart from liver
your
pancreas goes
out and you develop a disease called diabetes.
With that you also try some coffee and all those things,
which add up.
I mean coffee, the amount of coffee
people consumes, sometimes I can't understand.
And that coffee can really spoil the pancreas
to such an extent
that you can develop
even more serious diseases
than diabetes of the pancreas.
Beyond the pancreas lies the spleen.
Spleen is the real victim of modern people,
real victim is poor spleen.
Spleen is the one which is the speedometer within us,
it regulates your speed.
When you are eating your food,
you suddenly open the news
on the TV or something, horrible things happen.
You get so shocked and emergencies built-in,
the spleen is already the busy producing RBC’s,
red corpuscles for the digestion of the food,
and suddenly it has another emergency, and
a third emergency. The way we take our breakfast,
half sandwich in the mouth and half
outside
stepping into the car, telling your wife that do this, do that
and then rush through the rat race,
ending up yourself
into a very crazy spleen.
The spleen does not know
how to carry on with your telescopic behavior
and it go so very crazy
that it starts producing crazy cells
and these are the crazy cells
which create ultimately
a very serious disease called blood cancer.
The other day somebody asked me a question,
"Mother, how the children get blood cancer?"
I said if I tell you you shouldn’t be angry with me,
but when we are after the life of our children,
poor things, they are small children.
We are trying to make them good citizens.
So this crazy spleen, becomes
absolutely uncontrollable
it start producing blood cells
which become malignant. They go at random,
any time and the malignancy starts
where one cell becomes very big,
unique as we are also malignant people sometimes.
You want to be unique people in the society,
engulfing everybody, encroaching on other people,
in this competition we want to have everything to ourselves,
and by the time
you are old, you find your hands are shaking,
feet are shaking, you can't walk properly
or you develop diseases like say,
heart attack, or a stroke.
This rat race is
very competitive. Competition for what?
Everybody should be able to grow
in relation to others.
For example, if your nose only starts growing like that,
not in relation to your body or face,
what is going to happen to the rest of it?
To be on your own, I’m on my own,
and then you start growing
without any relationship or co-ordination with the other
parts of the society,
other parts of the world,
then you become malignant.
You lose all balance, you don't know what you are doing.
This is the tragedy
that when this happens to us
we are so ego-orientated
that the pangs are not felt
till you reach a stage, that suddenly you find
a person goes they you call it in English - "ga-ga",
American English.
You find them, they can't talk, I have seen it
in Paris. Some people,
not very old, younger to me in age,
walk into a bus
and they are talking loudly,
all sorts of French words
and I asked what are they doing?
They said, "Mother they are talking about last war. I said why?
They said they just go on talking like this, they're gone.
They are, what did you say, out of the deck.
Because you are having such a running jump towards the hell,
that the progress, so called,
will make our society into very funny people
who are jittery,
who are twitching their heads, necks and everything
and their children are so aggressive,
that it is impossible to understand why they're behaving like this.
We have to understand
that we are part and parcel of the whole.
And anything that is done
without the relationship of other
can create
tremendous problems for the whole world as it is and it is creating.
The second centre is very important
for modern people as I told you,
because when you start thinking too much also,
what you do is use your right side,
and the left side gets frozen.
By improving
on your thinking processes,
thinking too much of the future and
planning and of course most of the plans go waste.
Such a lost of energy we waste in thinking
that we find that if we had not thought so much,
we would not have been that much frustrated.
The planning also to such an extent
doesn't help in any way.
Supposing I have to come to this hall
and I do not know the way.
What planning can I have?
I have just to ask somebody how do you go there
and face as it is.
Supposing a seed has to grow into a root -
does it have any planning before hand?
It does not. What it does is that it faces.
It's a little cell, and so wise,
and it knows that there is an obstruction, no use
fighting with this rock,
so it goes around,
all soft places it pierces
and gets itself embedded sensibly and wisely
and uses that rock,
uses that rock for the strengthening of the tree.
So when we try to dominate others,
I mean the sophisticated, the more sophisticated you get,
the more sophisticated this ego gets
and with that sophistication you are very pleased, sorry,
yes and all those things are there,
but inside a big Mr. ego is developing,
like a balloon. And it presses down
your superego,
and it comes down.
Now the gap that is between the two
or the place where it should be is not there
and ego presses down the superego,
till superego starts seeing
the colossal ego.
And then such a person takes to escapes,
it takes to alcohol,
which gives rise to superego
or it takes to drugs
and all kinds of escapes in life
to run away from his own ego because he can't bear it.
Now the wobbling starts,
the ego and superego starts wobbling
and that's how you get people who are absolutely confused.
Moreover, to add up to the whole problem
the modern times are the ones
that in this confusion,
last judgment has already started.
Through your Kundalini awakening only
you will judge yourself
and correct yourself
and you will enter into the kingdom of God.
These confusions
actually have led human beings to such frantic
precarious ages
that Sahaja Yoga
had to come on this earth,
to solve the problems once for all.
After getting Realisation,
it's so remarkable when you find your absolute
through Kundalini awakening
I have seen people overnight they give up so many things.
Like I know of an old man,
very old man, in Singapore
who is very well known, very rich man
and a very well known personality,
and he got his Realisation
and he told me that overnight,
"I gave up my gambling,
I gave up my drinking
and I gave up my racing".
These are also escapes in life,
these are all escapes
because we are so bored of ourselves.
Imagine a person is imprisoned.
If he is just imprisoned in a nice place,
he should not feel upset. After all
it's a very good thing to face yourself,
that's the most beautiful thing we have.
But because we are so frightened of ourselves only,
that we don't want to be left alone, we think that we are lonely.
We want to run away from ourselves.
We want to have somebody else is
better to have somebody else, and even when somebody else comes in,
we do not want to face him squarely
but we want to have something in between,
like a bottle of beer or something.
After Realisation you first time start enjoying each other.
You first time start feeling the vibrations on another person
and you really enjoy the beauty of another person's
through this cool breeze that is coming
out of the being of that person.
And this should happen to all of you.
You all should achieve it,
it's very important because you are out and out seekers.
But first you must have your self-estimation.
You must know that you are not here to play
these games with yourself.
All kinds of games are available.
The industries have provided,
the Industrial Revolution has provided,
all modern thinkers and the books and all that have got it
and to add it gurus have come from India to supply
this demand market.
So the picture is complete.
This should not upset,
because behind all fakeness and falsehood there has to be the reality.
If you see thousands of
artificial flowers you must know there has to be one real rose.
And in the same way behind all this falsehood
and confusion there is reality
which is so beautiful within yourself
which you have to achieve through Kundalini awakening.
In short now I will tell you about the other centres
because if you go through this book
you will know
about the names and things but in short I can tell you.
That the third centre
is the centre of our seeking
is the center by which we are seeking,
is the navel centre is
by which amoeba, an amoeba felt hungry,
he was seeking food. In seeking food only
we went up to the stage of
say mammoth and all these big animals.
But they were such unwieldly big things
that they could not maintain themselves.
So then the intelligent animals came in.
In that also
some of them were very horrid ones
like foxes and all that.
Then very powerful animals came up
who had more physical power
than their big body.
Like that we develop
with this seeking up to a point when we became really human beings
and when we became human beings
we started seeking things like possessions;
if not possession, like power,
in politics, economics, social work, social things
and lastly, the Spirit.
Spirit is the solution for all of them.
Without the light you cannot see anything in this world.
I cannot see you without any light in there.
To me, in darkness you are nothing but darkness. I don't see it.
I cannot relate one to another.
I do not know who are sitting here and listening to me,
but once there is light you can see everything clearly,
and that's what it is, happens.
That when you get your enlightenment
you become the master of yourself.
This is the end of the seeking which starts.
In this seeking only, around the seeking
are our sustenance’s are developed gradually
and ultimately we become human beings.
And for human beings there are ten sustenance’s
described in the Ten Commandments.
When I talk about Ten Commandments,
a one gentleman got very angry and said "You are
a Christian, you are a Christian, you are a Christian!"
But Ten Commandments were written
when there were Jews, they were not written,
Moses was not a Christian, he was a Jew
and the Jew got angry with me
that I was a Christian.
Moses, Abraham,
Confucius, Socrates,
Mohammed, Nanak, Janak,
Lao Tse, these are the
Primordial masters.
The principle of primordial masters, the Adi-Gurus
who incarnated on this earth
to teach us how to keep our sustenance.
They taught against all strong alcohols and strong things.
Christ did not talk
but it does not mean that when He said
He converted into wine, means He
fermented the wine.
You cannot ferment the wine in a minute, you understand that.
Wine is a very common word, even today if you go
will find that wine means
grapes. I mean even
a creeper of the grape is called a wine,
even the juice of he thing is called wine.
Now to differentiate we are starting to call it
grape juice. But it is very, very
loose, but you will be surprised it is a very
... About fifty years back people must have started or something like that
in India, but may be abroad, I don't know.
Even today many people call it a wine "raksasia",
even in Indian language it is called as the wine.
Any grape juice is called as a wine.
So there are many other things
which these people told us
that you should not do, to keep yourself in the centre.
Now I divide our mistakes into categories.
The first mistake we have is not to believe
that God Almighty
is going to look after our well-being.
Krishna has said very clearly
that Yoga kshemam Vahaamyaham. Meaning
after Yoga, after union with God,
I will look after your well being.
That means you should get connected.
Supposing I am not an Australian citizen
why will Australian Government look after me?
In the same way if you are not the members
of God's community
or if you are not entered into the Kingdom of God
or if you are not a citizen of His Kingdom,
it is not His responsibility to look after your well being.
I mean of course He has created you, so He looks after you.
But otherwise it's not certain that He'll look after you.
People demand so much from God,
they think they are already connected.
They treat Him as if you can find Him somewhere under the stone.
They go on demanding please look after my son,
please do this, praying morning till evening,
I mean it's pestering.
When you are not connected with God,
if you go on
doing like this to any human being also,
you'll get arrested.
And that's what happens, that we live under myths:
"Oh I have been praying and God has given me this,
and I have been doing this."
But we don't see, do we deserve it?
Are we the Spirit? Have we tried to be the Spirit?
We have done all kinds of things but to be the Spirit.
When you are the Spirit then you are really blessed -
really blessed,
not only by His powers
but you become the master of your being,
and you start manifesting your own powers.
This seeking and the surrounding dharma
which is looked after by the Primordial masters
is another centre here, above that is the centre
of the Mother of the Universe,
who gives us the security.
This one when spoiled
the security, the sense of security spoiled
especially among women,
when they feel that their husband are negligent or they are
flirting with other women and all sorts of things.
Then this centre goes but of order.
When this centre goes out of order,
then they develop diseases like breast cancer.
Breast cancer
is more common in societies where they have divorces.
I have given a regular speech on this
which you should get from Sydney and you will know all about it.
Now the right side heart which you see here
is the centre of a Father,
the left one is the centre of the Mother.
The right side heart centre catches when as a father
you have not done your duties
or if your father has died very early,
you were shocked, then also it can happen.
Anorexia and all these diseases can also be
caused by this kind of happenings
or also asthma.
Asthma is invariably is caused
by this centre going out of order.
The left side is the centre of the Mother,
our father and mother we chose.
Before our birth we chose them.
It was foolish to choose horrible parents.
But you better pay for it.
In one lifetime
it is better to pay for the horrible ones
so that next time you won't have them again.
But we are not to judge them.
If they are not seekers
it's a very difficult thing to live with them, I know.
It's very difficult to live with parents
who are morning till evening
counting every penny, counting every tin which are emptied,
every tube that is emptied, they store up,
they are so materialistic
and you just can't bear such people, I can quite understand.
Even a wife could be like that, and a husband could be like that,
extremely materialistic, you will be fed up.
They write down everything, every lamp post they must know,
count everything.
Today a lady who interviewed me asked me,
"How many people, Mother, have you given Realisation
and how many people you have cured."
I said "You better ask the sun first of all
how many leaves it has made green, then talk to me."
I never write any accounts,
leave alone of human beings, even of money.
I never write, I have no time,
I have no understanding as how to write accounts.
Next life maybe I will be an accountant, for your information.
So this happens to us when we become
against our parents.
I don't say that you should carry on
with mad people, there's no use
asking the bull to come and hit you, is correct.
But you need not judge them,
you can leave them, stay away
and do not have them in your life, it's alright.
But if you are taking
interest in them as well as fighting with them morning till evening,
then you catch on this heart chakra.
I would say that in this respect Indians are sensible people.
They are very sensible that they keep their parents all right.
And the parents are also yet
very sensible people. They love their children, they give
everything that they have to the children,
and children start really loving their parents,
till they die they look after them.
The result of that is of course very bad,
because here in all the western countries the parents
are still in a bridal mood, I mean they are brides
and the bridegrooms you see
they never become old enough to be parents.
Seen even an eighty year old man you will find
marry an eighteen year old girl. I mean
it's a thing going on all the time. God knows
what sort of intelligence is that?
But with all that happening
poor children do not know
which parents to be chosen.
And the last judgement has started, now what to do?
Now you place yourself in their places
and think what would you do
when you know such crazy parents that today
they are together, tomorrow they are divorced.
On the streets they will be kissing,
hugging each other,
doing all kind of nonsensical thing. Very embarrassing also,
and if you ask them where are you
going they say they are going to the divorce case.
These kinds of absurdities are taking place and because of that
children don't want to get birth
in all these places; England,
Germany, Switzerland, everywhere.
The birth rate is towards the minus side.
In Germany especially, West Germany
and East Germany of all the things
people give so much money that a woman if she produces
three children she earns more money than their Prime Minister.
But still women don't want to produce.
They want to be free, independent, they don't want to be mothers.
As a result this poor India
has to accommodate for all the children born today
and we are blamed for over population,
now what to do? We have to bear the load.
So also it is your responsibility
to see if you do not produce children
at least those who are producing children
have some compassion for them
and have some understanding.
Do not blame them. Oh everybody tells me,
what about your problem of population.
I tell them now who is responsible for our population
because in that country even if you have fourteen children,
they love all their children that are there.
They are not so ego-orientated that their hearts are not closed,
they are not so unemotional,
anybody who has no child will go to
all the holy places
and ask for blessings that they should get children,
to get a child
is such a blessing in India and child is such an important thing.
But the mistake they are committing
is just the other than yours.
The mistake in those developing countries
is that they do not believe that God Almighty
is the One who is going to look after your well being.
They don't believe in the power of their Father,
so they do the crime against the Father or
you can say the sin against the Father.
When you don't believe in the capacity of your Father,
so there is bribery, corruption, all sorts of things going on, you know
cutting corners and money and all those things go on.
Still in India I would not say that
ordinary people are dishonest. I mean our bureaucrats may be, our
politicians may be and business people may be. But
ordinary people are very honest in India.
But this is what happens.
On the other side, you see supposing
an Indian comes to your house, be careful
he may run away with anything that you have in the house, anything,
see, but
if an American comes to your house, be careful about your wife.
He may run away with your wife or with your daughter.
Or say an Englishman comes he'll do it in a subtler way
because he's a scholar.
So he reads some poetry to your wife
and in the night you find she is missing.
This is fundamental, I mean the wife
who runs away like this creates problem
fundamentally for the household.
Just think in a house,
where there are children, there is husband, kitchen
and all the places, everybody sleeping nicely,
early in the morning they find
that the main pole of the house is missing and the whole thing is collapsed.
What will happen to the children, nobody thinks.
Nobody understands
or they think they are being in love
so they must go.
Men do the same. I mean there is no difference between men and women.
But this is the sin against the Mother
that the women have to be respectable and respected.
Housewives’ position is within us
here on the left hand side, nabhi
and if a housewife,
the deity of housewife, is not in our house,
not that the woman but the housewife,
then our spleen goes out.
We get, children get crazy,
why is there in-disciplined. Somebody asked me today
what happens to the people like who try to kill Reagan?
I said, ask his mother.
She must be after the life of the child, morning till evening
and that's why he's taking action,
or is a reaction of what has happened to him.
How do these complications arise
has a basis in the family
in the nest, that is your house.
You have to live in the nest
as a father and a mother
looking after your children.
Children are the most important things
in the whole world for human beings.
Let the politics go to hell,
and let the economics take its own course,
but children
are to be looked after, that's your primary duty.
But in India we go to the other end,
when we start look after our children we don't mind
selling our countries also in the name of children.
But we live with two extremes I feel,
the sin against the Mother
and the sin against the Father.
When we sin against the Mother
as Australians, as I am now an Australian,
let us face what happens to us.
Absolutely we are emotionally blackmailed by ourselves.
We torture ourselves, we live with artificial things.
Like if a wife
wants to run away with another man
we will even go to get a honeymoon ticket for her
because we are very considerate good husbands.
Same thing with the wives if she finds that the husband
is interested in another woman,
she should not be jealous.
In Sahaja Yoga this is not very much appreciated.
Husband has to behave, like a husband. He should make his wife
run the house.
And the woman has to be a woman.
She must see to it that
no danger is brought to the children.
We have no business to hurt anyone like this
and we do not know how much we hurt,
we give cancers to our wives and husbands.
We give all kinds of horrible diseases,
mental tortures we make them mad, by our
mad, capricious,
very shallow, understanding of our emotions.
A one man starts going to another woman,
then he goes to another woman,
then to ten women he goes
and then ten men go to ten women
and end up in a lunatic asylum or
in the orphanage. I have seen in England we had a neighbor
who had a very huge house, he died, he was an old man
and you'd be surprised
they did not discover his body for one month.
Because there's no family feeling, nothing,
even a rat doesn't enter that house. Can you imagine!
This is what has happened in thinking,
“I am separated, I am individualistic.
I am exclusive”. If you are really individualistic,
if you are really mature, individually,
then you know the unity much better.
Then you understand that you are the support
of the whole because you are so matured.
No wonder our children are not maturing.
They are behaving in such a manner.
We are responsible, we must accept that in our own
ideas about compatibility and all this nonsense,
we don’t have in India, we are quite comfortable,
we are producing children quite all right.
We have no problems. Why do you run after these capricious,
these shallow ideas?
You will be held responsible
for all these horrible diseases that men and women have got,
and the children that are going to suffer,
if you have charity, better start it at home.
Better be charitable
to your own wife and to your own husband.
Be charitable to your children.
Don't go by concept of falling in love,
you'll fall, really and make others fall too.
It's a concept, just a concept.
I think some of these horrible people must have given you this concept.
If you really fall in love
how do you get up to marry another person?
You fall, marry another person,
again ready to marry another person.
You are holding the hand of a person
who is suppose to be your beloved or whatever it is,
and looking at another one.
This concept is absolutely wrong. You have to grow in love.
As your own child is
in the same way is your companion. They are two parts
of one chariot.
One is the left and other is the right. They're not
unequal, they're equal
but they are not similar, they have their own role.
And women have to take their role courageously,
to be the mother, as I always say, look at me.
I am a Mother and in no way,
in any way, I cannot think
I could be anything better than this.
Now if I start thinking, Oh God,
I am a Mother all right, but
I must know how to drive,
then I'm finished. I must know how to drive a bus,
I must know how to drive a train!
What is the need?
I saw one photographer who came to see me.
He was supposed to take my photograph
and whole hands were fill with blisters.
I said first let me cure your blisters.
How you are going to take my photograph?
I said what have you been doing with your, photography?
No, he said, this, I went to a forest
and I cut some trees. I said, for what?
You are a photographer, your hands are soft and deft
why do you want to kill the deftness of your fingers?
He said, no we must do other things also. I said, why must you?
You see the nose doesn’t do the work of the eyes
and the eyes do not do the work of the ears.
Why must you do, your hands are all finished! And this is what it is.
To us we feel that men are great
so we start saying, "let's do the man's work."
The man thinks, why "should women be like this?"
You are companions -
you are eternal companions. You are two
beautiful wheels of a chariot.
This is to be grown
and to be matured within you.
And when this centre is out,
you get the problems of this centre
by which you get asthma, tuberculosis,
and the breast troubles.
Men get asthma, very serious asthma and
other problems of the lungs
and ultimately, also lung cancer can develop.
When you work too hard with the right hand side,
you are ego orientated, that is ego develops too much,
then your left side is neglected,
you become unemotional, that time
your heart gives a signal, you get a heart attack.
When you do too much sometimes
you may escape the heart attack, but you may get
a  brain paralysis.
We are bent upon destroying ourselves.
The destruction is going to come from within, not from without.
Those people who are try to shock you, this will happen,
that the sun is doing this, this is nothing.
It's all within you, the destruction has started.
You are facing it because
you cannot accept it.
You have to accept
that this is a challenge, I am not
going to allow myself to be destroyed by foolish and stupid
ideas that are around.
And then in your own estimation and glory
you will be surprised. After realisation
you will be enriched but
without Realisation, I don't know,
it becomes a lecture and a lecture, just a brainwash.
That beautiful thing should happen to you,
and once you find your beauty within yourself,
overnight I have seen people changed.
Overnight it happens
and I hope that will happen to you tonight.
Today I have talked to you about this centre
and later on I will be talking to you about
two other centres which are here and here.
And the Realisation that takes place,
out of the limbic area,
in the fontanel membrane,
which is called as the Brahmarandra in Sanskrit language.
Thank you very much. May God bless you.
If you have any questions you please ask me.
But questions should be something
which are helpful, not some sort of
quarrel. I am not here to quarrel with you.
If you don't want your Realisation I am not going to force you.
Please do not plead for any other organisation or any other guru,
because I am not interested. I am only interested in you,
I see that sparkle in you,
that's why I am only interested in you, I'm not bothered about others.
So you do not try to bring others ideas
that this guru has said this or this
one has said that and this is in the book.
The proof of the pudding is that you haven't got your Realisation.
If you have got it then you can go out.
If you are sure you have got it, I don't want to force it on you.
There's no quarrel about anything.
There's no election on, nothing.
You cannot give me anything.
There's no shopping. It's a temple, you have come for a blessing.
All right? Now you can ask the questions. Thank you very much.