in this
108 names if you have noticed
they have shown that
kartikeya is the innocence
that is acting on the right hand side
in the pingala and that is
also it is very much related to prana
it gives you prana prana is the vital
breath that we take
breathe in and breathe out so it is
related to the right side
then also it is related to eternity
anantari
ananta is the snake or the
which is the brother of vishnu
so it is he who is represented here
as kartikey he is called as ananta
so he is the fire
he is the one who ignites within you
the capacity to consume the force
also the capacity to command
the people and
also the capacity to be
a person full of brilliance
you see an innocent person could be very
brilliant
all these capacities are expressed in
karthikeya's
swarupa in his state
today by parship worshipping karthikeya
we have to know
that kartikeya is now awakened within us
and with that capacity
we have to fight ultimately he is the
nishkalanka
he's the one who's the final so
from ganesha to christ to nishkalanka
these are the three stages into which
the innocence has gone from ganesha
to karthikeya and now
to christ and from christ
to nishkalaka in the form of nishkalanka
he is innocent so he there's no kalanka
there's no
spot on him nothing he's absolutely
clean immaculate
plus he's fiery
plus he has all the qualities of
means the 11 qualities or the forces
of shiva which can kill
so he has a capacity to kill
and destroy that is evil
and to give blessings
and courage to his followers
this is the last incarnation which is
called as kalaki
in normal words you call it kalaki is
actually
in the white house so it is the
kartikeya
who sits on the white horse so how
innocence grows within you now is
up to the point of karthikeya
this has been today done on this land
jewish land as you call it where
karthikeya
is to be born within you to be awakened
within you
may god bless you