and also the idea is to give more
encouragement to handicrafts and to art
because so many times have told that a
little of clay you can take and make it
into a beautiful thing which is worth
such a lot so why should we exhaust this
mother earth why not we have few
artistic nice things instead of I am so
many things but you should go in the
shops I don't get anything don't get
silly you cannot get this you cannot get
that so difficult to get anything
natural because people have only making
unnatural things whatever it is in that
also you should create beauty if you
start creating beauty then we'll try to
preserve it and use it sparingly instead
of having thousands of nonsensical
things everything is possible after
sometime we will have to have human
beings who are disposable you'll have to
dispose them off how will they live on
this earth if you do not understand that
we have to live it on this earth with
its limitations seven telling you many a
times take two artistic things take two
handmade things more two handmade don't
go too much at least even if you have to
buy something which is say artificial at
least see really that it is artistic
so the once you have a great desire
today is the day they want the whole
world to pray for the preservation of
Mother Earth that's why I started this
topic that we should pray that we all
should develop art develop for ourselves
give as presents to others and also to
use artistic things made of artists we
can have few things but artistic which
expresses art not cheap things in the
whole of France
what I saw was that into everything
these plastics are scripted whether it
is God it can enter into everybody
everywhere except for the brains of
human beings it's horrible so whatever
it is in that also see that you my
artistic things not plain horrible cheap
things all right so this is what we have
to today also you have to pray to me
when you are doing puja that our mother
our mother please save our earth give
people wisdom that they should behave
themselves and they should be conscious
and every sahaja yogi should be
conscious about how much energy he is
using of electricity of telephones or of
water or of anything we have to be
frugal about it if you do not take the
responsibility of these things then it
will not penetrate anywhere else so it
is for you to do
you have potato in your everyday life as
a part and parcel of your life that you
try to save the energy of this Mother
Earth
it's very important