Seminar in Mill Farm – Sherborne, Dorset (UK), 2 August 1981.
In Mahalakshmi’ s temple, which is a real temple,
where all the three deities have come out in Bombay
where I used to live very close to that place,
just imagine, and this is very common.
So to understand how human beings reacted to that
is very well shown in Delphi.
It’s a beautiful thing is so done.
But I was amazed at the Temple of Athena when we went there.
It’s so much so near to the thing that
the Mooladhara is shown there where the Kundalini exists.
Now She is the one who has snakes around Her, see?
And She has little, little snakes as Her children. Can you imagine?
And She is one, and She has a daughter,
which is the Kundalini in you and a God who is a child God.
And when She stands She has a Kundalini in her hand,
the snake coming out of Her hand. With all the charkas, she is made.
It’s so beautifully shown.
The best was Her Sanctum Sanctorum
where nobody is allowed to go inside where She resides,
is the Adi Kundalini.
But they say that She came out of the head of Zeus,
the Primordial Kundalini. And Her place nobody can go inside,
nobody can reach except for Her son, the child son.
But Her,
Her steps are very large
also are roundish. She curved. Can you imagine?
They’re curved as if part of the Kundalas they are.
And they are 3 ½ in height,
you can see that, in height and in width also.
Like every place is made of big,
I mean the three are made of big stones and the last one
is made of the small, three and a half, and they go in a curve.
And that is Sanctum Sanctorum nobody can go inside.
Now what an expression it was. This was the early Expression
and Athens is after Her name Athena.
If you see the face also you will find your Mother very much there.
I’ve got the photographs and all that which I will show you later on.
But what I’m saying the Mother Earth has done Her job.
People have done their job. Christ or we can say Mohammed
or Buddha, Kabira, anyone of them;
they have done their jobs, alright. They have worked for you.
They have created places within you. They have done their job.
Now it is you who are on the stage, not Me.
Sahastrara has to work it out.
And Sahastrara always surrounds the heart.
You are enlightened by your Spirit, which resides in your heart.
And the whole Sahastrara’s mandalas are around the heart.
So as you are now the temple of that Spirit,
you are the heart.
You have to be very, very assiduous.
This is the fourth point, which is again against all Englishmen.
They are holidaying permanently.
The whole attention is in holidays.
At the slightest pretext, they are on a holiday.
The word holiday comes from the word holy day,
is to do something holy on that day.
God took his leave from the whole world for one day
to cleanse Himself and to be in a holy condition.
Because you see when you clear other people,
when you create something,
then you want to have some time to yourself and to enjoy yourself.
That’s why He got this holiday.
Here it is permanent holiday not holy day, holly means hollow.
It’s hollow day.
And this madness of holiday
is of course I am working out on my level to cut it down.
This is the time one has to really get into Sahaja Yoga,
to work hard, is the time to give up all your lethargies.
You have to get out of your sleep.
I have seen people – I’ve told, she asked Me that,
“Mother we would like to have your puja”. I said, “I know
why you want to have puja is good because puja means flooding.”
The floods come in, ah everybody feels fine.
Some feel fine for a month, some for a week,
some for a day, some for an hour.
Again, as it is.
Because with flooding
you feel the water has come inside.
But it should be needed; there should be some depth.
That is not done. Every Sahaja Yogi must do it every day,
is a part of his life.
Cleansing is a part of his life. Is just like brushing his teeth.
Even if he does not brush his teeth does not matter.
I do not brush My teeth every night. You might have noticed it.
I need not brush. My teeth are still solid and I was asking My husband,
“When do the human beings lose their teeth?”
He said, “You have already passed that age.”
I said, “That means I will never lose My teeth?”
He said, “May not.” But I never brush My teeth in the night
before sleeping as you people religiously do.
The most important thing is cleansing yourself every night.
Whether you cleanse it with water or rub it yourself with salt
or with butter or you do the tratrika, with the flame,
do what you like
but you have to pay attention to your cleansing every night.
And morning time you have to surrender
before doing anything else.
You have to get up early? All right get up early.
Do what you like but you have to work hard.
And you have to think every day what have I done for Sahaja Yoga today?
It’s not the same cycle we are going to start you see.
Once you have denied materialism you became hippies,
now after coming out of that we are not going to start
the same cycle of materialism.
This is a new way where we have to go,
where we understand our detachments from things.
It’s all right.
We are not going to run away from matter
but we are going to master it. If we get it well and good
if we don’t get it well and good, it’s just the same,
makes no difference.
And hard work is needed now, real hard work I tell you
because now I’m going to America.
When I am there, there is so much of lethargy;
when I don’t allow you to sleep after 6 o’clock even if you try.
I’ve done that if you notice,
rather difficult for people to sleep after six.
But, still,
when I go away you have to really work very hard
and keep yourself clean every day
and write it down on a piece of paper.
By the time I come back again I find all my horses.
That’s not going to be this time.
Today you have to promise Me that,
that all of you are going to work very hard,
cleanse yourself completely. Go all out.
After all, this country is not so big to travel.
It makes a big impressive. You have seen Australian Times.
I had only one Sahaja Yogi with me thank God, that was Mr. Regis.
I was only controlling him. Only one horse I had to control
and he was all right. He behaved very well,
otherwise he could have gone off you know.
Anything is possible under the sun.
But he behaved very well. He was quite under control
and they were impressed by his presence there
and they called him serene. Imagine Regis very serene.
And he was very sweet I must say
and he explained to them very well because he is well educated,
he is a doctor.
Today I played a trick on him though, I’m sorry for that.
It was too much, whatever it is,
but he, it worked out and he’s done it well.
In the same way it is you people I have seen it
and said it again and again,
that you are the people who are going to
bring Sahaja Yoga on this earth.
You are the people who are going to do it. I am nothing.
You see now when there is waterfall,
what energy do you see? Nothing, it’s just a waterfall.
But when you put it to turbines
and take out that electricity from the turbines
and then you see them here then you say, "yes there is electricity".
Whatever is potential has no meaning.
Whatever is kinetic, whatever is showing has a meaning.
And so it is for you
to be the showpieces of Sahaja Yoga, not Me.
Because some will say
that, “Oh you may be, so what,
you are a different clan altogether.”
Some may say that,
“Oh we can’t believe you.”
But they will believe you much more they will believe Me.
They will not believe Me at all. They’ll say I’m fantastic.
I, I cannot be understood, you see?
So they won’t believe Me, they will believe you.
They will not trust Me, but they will trust you.
They would not trust Christ but they will trust you
because you are one of them.
That is why it is important that you should improve
in all sincerity, in all truthfulness to yourself.
Become a perfect mechanism of God.
No reservations, should be no reservation.
You see thinking, “All right, if I do this much
then it’s all right, then I come back.”
This is not all out effort.
It seems to be very common you see, ‘cutting corners’ as they say.
“Oh this much, all right, should I do this much
or should I do this much?”
I’ve seen very much discretion is used for all these things.
It’s typical you see, “How many people so how many sandwiches?
They will eat at the most two or three
what’s the use of making more? So but everybody will not eat three
so make it say two is all right, somebody will eat one.”
These calculations, see?
Who will eat one? The one who is calculating should not eat at all,
then that’s the best way.
But it’s all this calculations starts in the mind, you see,
and these calculations ruin you.
It’s a very tricky path. I know it’s very tricky.
But you have beacons before you. Really I tell you, ‘lit’.
Nobody had that.
And you have got the torches in your hand.
And you have a balancing way automatically in built.
Just trust in all those things, and if you walk straight forward,
straight forward, forget all that is past,
all that is nonsensical. Forget it, you are a different person.
I’m sure you’ll rise very fast.
And you will be really a living, organized being.
All of you put together. Living, organized.
These two are not complimentary ever.
Because living is always disorganized,
according to human concept like
they will say that this flower comes out this way t
hat should come out that way. That human being’s thinking
but God thinks that this is the wayit is organized.
So, living organized means organized in the will of God.
That’s how Sahaja Yogi are going to form that nucleus,
that great nucleus, that powerful nucleus,
that tremendous source
which is going to overthrow all that is nonsensical.
It is tremendous, believe Me.
May God bless you