I asked some of the boys, “What is your
policy?”
They said, “We have no policy."
“Then what is your aim?”
“We have no aim."
“Then why are you doing this nonsense?”
They said, “Because whatever the elders
tell us, we do it."
I said, “Have you no personality?
Nothing?”
Is exactly what happened when this hippy movement
started.
Some so-called intellectuals started this
horrible hippy movement in the West.
And when they found they cannot do anything
about it, they found it’s going to fail,
so many children lost their education, so
many children I know became pregnant, girls
and boys [sadist scout/squat].
All that took them to the extreme that they
became violent.
But unless and until there is a change within
yourself, how can we change anything outside?
We cannot.
And the first seven people I fought were all
hippies.
Very difficult.
They called themselves hippies but they used
to hog like a pig.
They wanted all the comforts, everything free,
extremely dominating and quarrelsome people.
But the foundation was laid on them.
Very surprising.
But I had to work on them for at least four
years regularly.
So that is how Sahaja Yoga started, and today
you know how much it has spread, how far it
has gone.
Only in Maharashtra this problem is there
of so-called intellectuals, this is called
themselves, but they have no intelligence.
I talked to one man; I got fed up.
He didn’t know anything about spirituality,
he didn’t know anything about medicine,
he didn’t know anything about science.
I said, “Now, what do you know?”
So it was impossible.
So such people who are jobless ? we call them
[nikaam bekaar] ? they have no work, they
are starting all such things and we should
not be upset with them.
They are trying to create problems and they
are getting money from some sources.
They are afraid, I think the politicians are
afraid, perhaps, that Sahaja Yoga may turn
their tables down because we believe in honesty,
and maybe a day may come when these honest
people might harm them, perhaps.
I do not know why.
This may be one of the reasons these people
are frightened of us.
Or whatever it is we have to understand that
for doing any great work one has to sacrifice.
Of course, you are not going to be crucified
like Christ, no.
Nor you have to sacrifice as my parents sacrificed
for the independence of this country.
Nor you are going to be tortured.
But really, inconveniences you may have.
But I must thank you very much because of
you are coming here and singing Marathi songs.
They are quite impressed and they think it’s
only possible because you are all Sahaja yogis.
Otherwise you could not have done.
So if there are any inconveniences think that
it’s a joke; that’s all.
Today I was thinking we should do the Puja
of Shri chakra and Lalita chakra which we
have never done.
This is the right place to do these two chakras
today.
Lot has been written about Shri chakra and
about Lalita chakra, but to understand fundamentally
the left side when it reaches up to Vishuddhi,
then it uses on the right side the Shri chakra,
on the left side the Lalita chakra, to manifest
itself.
These two chakras are the ones who manifest
all that you see.
But these chakras are the ones who emit vibrations
of different kinds, and because of their angularities,
like if you have some sort of a cardboard
attached with small, small holes of different
colors and which rotates all the time, you
get different colors.
Also you can get different permutations and
combinations.
In the same way, different permutations and
combinations are created, and that is how
you get all the advantages of Sahaja Yoga.
So these two chakras are very important.
I do not know if you know of any mantras about
Shri chakra but I’ll give you a book, later
on I’ll translate it to you and you can
compose something for Shri chakra.
Shri chakra on the right side, Lalita chakra
on the left side, so what we are really worshipping
today is Mahasaraswati power and Mahakali
power, both put together.
So now we started combining things, not individual.
Now, these two energies are very important.
Without the energy, without the power, nothing
exists.
For example, if this light had no power to
give light or to burn, it is useless.
In the same way, without getting your realization
you are useless because your power is not
awakened, at least not complete.
But these two powers give us lots of benefits
even without realization.
Whatever you see in this world created is
done by these two chakras of the Adi Shakti.
But here the power doesn’t move.
It’s not moving.
But in the human being the power start moving.
And when it starts moving, then we can say
it is creating another world.
But movement is not the only thing.
This power acts, gives you intelligence, gives
you all kinds of things which you have as
human beings.
But later on this power itself becomes enlightened
within you when the left and right side both
become enlightened.
This enlightenment, you get it when you get
your Self-realization, but not immediately,
not immediately.
This, one should understand.
For example, if you have pain or if your chakra
is catching, you have to use your hands.
You cannot say that, “The energy is flowing
within me.
So it’s all right.
I can manage."
It’s not like that.
You have to use your hands to impart that
power to yourself or to others.
If you have pain in the stomach then you can
say that, “If there’s energy in my stomach
why should I have pain in the stomach?”
But the play of these chakras have to come.
And that is why you have to use your power
of your hands.
If you cannot use your hands then you cannot
impart this energy.
Many people have asked Me that, “Mother,
when will it move horizontal?”
It will move horizontal, no doubt.
It does.
But even that horizontal movement is to be
guided by these two very important chakras.
So you must understand the importance of these
two chakras within yourself.
That’s why I have told many a times, “Don’t
move your head too many times."
And this way many people talk, I mean, it’s
style of talking, “No, this, that,” very
common with French, specially.
That’s another way you are not respecting
your chakras.
Shouldn’t move your shoulders too much.
Mostly they talk like this.
It’s anti-chakras, anti-chakras.
Should keep your shoulders straight.
When you are singing you can move your whole
upper part ? it’s all right ? but not your
shoulders.
This is the thing one has to understand that
these two centers are to be looked after.
You can move your neck, your body, when you
are singing.
It’s important, that helps, but not your
shoulders.
Shoulders are to be kept intact.
But while saying just, “Yes,” you need
not go on, “Yes, yes, yes, yes."
It’s a very, very simple thing that it can
have a very bad effect.
And those who move their shoulders too much
do not feel vibrations much because the chakras
are not all right.
It’s a very simple thing to be understood
that they are the most important chakras we
have, and whatever is to be used out of this
Paramachaitanya they have to be used by these
two centers.
Even supposing your some chakra is catching
on your spinal chord, you have to use your
hands.
Somebody can say, “I can just put my attention."
Doesn’t work out that good.
Because yet your attention has not that reached
that stage where these chakras, like Lalita
chakra and Shri chakra, obey your attention.
They do not.
So you have to work out with your hands.
Be careful: don’t move your shoulders too
much.
And if you see now Indians when they sing
bhajans they’ll move their whole body, they’ll
do like this, but never their shoulders.
The shoulders will move in the same way as
the neck is moving.
They might move their neck also but they’ll
never move their shoulders like this, and
it’s regarded as inauspicious according
to Indian standards.
Because of this culture based on what the
saints have told and also about many seers
have told, it is more related to spiritual
life than to materialistic life.
Now the materialistic life, unless and until
there is the foundation of the spiritual life,
takes you to a very partial development, you
can say.
But to get a full development you must have
your foundation on spirituality.
That’s why spirituality being the foundation
has to be deep, has to be fully equipped,
has to be absolutely perfect.
Then the whole building can be built.
It’s gone wrong in the West; doesn’t matter.
Now you can build it up and then you’ll
be surprised how you become really solid people.
This is a very short talk about Shri chakra.
I think I should sit down and write all about
it and it would be nice handing it for you
to read.
But you must know that beyond thought, when
you go, these chakras become extremely efficient
because the thought puts a pressure on them,
and because of the pressure the movement of
these chakras is very slow and ineffective.
But once you can get out of your thoughts
and go into thoughtless awareness, then these
chakras start working it out and you start
moving much deeper into your own being.
[The lecture continues in Hindi but becomes
inaudible after some time]
I must say that this beautiful Earth has created
so many beautiful things.
But She Herself is nothing but detached, simple
Mother Earth.
Perhaps that’s My condition, too.
When it comes to creation I can create beautiful
things.
You are so beautiful, too, creatures.
But as far as I am concerned I do not think
that I require any one of these things or
I’m bothered about them, or need them or
tempted by them.
So what Grégoire has said is because they
are insisting that they are going to give
Me presents every year and that’s why this
is a delude to them.
But I’ve been telling them that there’s
no need now.
Let’s say, you all consider it, is only
no need to give so many presents.
What you can do now to start reducing the
number of presents you give Me.
One country can give one present.
If you can do that I’ll be thankful, but
I’ll have to build another house.
And the grandeur and all these things are
created by Me but never enjoyed by Me.
I just enjoy Myself; that’s all.
And Myself is so big, it is such a big thing,
that I don’t know what it means; it means
grandeur, or nature, or anything, or you all
people.
I enjoy everything of it.
So for Me there’s no need for you to.
Now as he said that those people came, three
of them ? Brahma, Vishnu, Mahesha ? to give
presents to Christ.
Yes, they did.
And you have given Me, too.
But now I think it’s better that you people
reduce some quantity at least.
I’ll be very thankful that if something
could be done like that, and from next year
we should try to make it less and less and
less.
Because it’s very sweet of you to have given
Me all those things, because I enjoyed them,
they are beautiful things, and when I see
them I remember your good heart.
But you know that Mother is too simple and
though I can create all kinds of things, as
far as I am concerned I am too simple.
And also Mr.
Shrivastava so many times, says also, “You’ve
got so many saris but you’ll go on with
Your white sari all the time."
The reason is, you see, a simple personality
can only create beautiful things.
A simple heart can only create nice things,
because simplicity at the simple level is
so simple.
Like you are made of seven chakras, seven
chakras, then the permutations of these seven
chakras, that’s all.
But supposing you start from outside then
you’ll have to go to medical science or
you’ll have to go to another complicated
thing.
But basically, fundamentally, it’s too simple.
That’s why Sahaja Yoga is very simple, because
we are dealing with the fundamental things.
So fundamentally, if you are simple then everything
that you do is just a combination and permutation
of all these things, and all these things
when they are put together they make such
beautiful things.
For example, as I have told you once I was
travelling and we went to a place called Palitana
known to be a very beautiful, beautifully
carved place.
And we had to walk, I don’t know, for three
miles at least, climbing up or something like
that.
With Me was My daughter and My son-in-law.
Went up and there was a little temple.
They wanted to rest.
And also we laid down ourselves there.
And as soon as I saw all these beautiful elephants
were there, so I told My son-in-law, “Look
at these elephants.
All their tails are twisted differently."
He said, “Mummy, we are so fed up.
How do you have energy to see the tails?”
I said, “Because I see the tails I don’t
feel tired.
That’s the point.
Because I see the beauty of these tails, I
— ”.
So you see, even in simple things there is
so much of beauty.
In very, very ordinary persons you’ll find
that they have a very beautiful things and
very nice way of saying things, very simple
talks of children like that, it’s so simple,
so straightforward, and whatever they say
it’s so deep.
So whatever is deep is simple, but when it
is expressed outside it can have lots of permutations
and combinations and it can work out in a
beautiful way.
I must tell you, I had no strain in making
this house, nothing.
I was not bothered at all.
I found everything so easily; I brought it
here, put it down here, I never even thought
there’s strain or anything.
Everybody says, “What a concept."
But I never conceived anything.
I mean, I just don’t know.
What is a concept is there; I just told, “To
Me is nothing great."
The whole world is there for us to see and
to be fascinated.
But behind all that, all this world and everything
is created with the very little, simple idea
of God, that you all have to enter into the
Kingdom of God.
That’s all; such a simple idea.
So He’s created such a beautiful world,
then he created all kinds of things to bring
you to the human level, and now just simple
thing is to enter into the Kingdom of God.
You should not complicate yourself too much
and once you do that you will be surprised
how beautifully you will be able to produce.
Even some artists were extremely simple by
nature.
Like Ravi Shankar, you know, and his guru,
he has got Alla Raka and Ali Akbar; all these
were his disciples.
Such a great genius man, such a simple man,
I tell you.
And he knew Me very well.
He used to call Me “Ma”; he used to call
Me “Mother” from the very beginning.
And one day he brought one little deer, a
baby deer, brought it to Me.
I said, “What’s the matter?”
He said, “See, this deer was crying too
much.
So I brought it to You."
But I said, “For, why for Me?”
“So, You see, he will feel the love of his
Mother.
So You just caress him."
Imagine, such a great artist coming like a
little baby to Me, making that.
I was so surprised at him.
Look at him; such a simple man.
He’s doing that.
And you see, if you see the children when
they love, how genuine they are, how they
work it out.
The same place there was a child.
He was very fond of Me.
And one day he decided to bring some pumpkins
for Me.
So he brought one to Me.
I saw him bringing in the thing.
He said, “All right, just wait."
Then there was, he went back, and there was
another one kept little further.
He brought that.
He had put nine of them in different places.
One by one he was bringing them.
He brought nine pumpkins to give Me.
So sweet.
But I said, “Why did you bring nine?”
“Because I don’t know which one you like
so I brought all of them."
So simple and so touching; I mean, just [touch/touches/tears/turns]
your heart.
So we have to be simple people.
We have to talk to each other in a simple
way, not in a complicated way, in a very simple,
sweet manner.
That’s how we are going to create a beautiful
world.
So I would request all of you to be very kindly
and very gentle with each other, especially
for the newly marrying couples.
Try to be nice.
Nobody is going to dominate you if you are
nice.
It’s only you dominate yourself.
And don’t try to control your husbands or
your wives.
Let them be.
Let them enjoy their freedom.
They are not going to do anything wrong.
So some people try to control too much and
there are problems.
So please do not try to control like, “If
I am keeping it here, they’ll keep it there."
There’s no need.
Let it be.
Doesn’t matter; nothing so serious.
But on small, small things, I’ve seen, such
marriages fizzle out.
And it is absolutely wrong.
So for marriages today, it’s a very auspicious
day.
So many people have been engaged to be married.
But one thing you must remember, that you
should not lose your connection with joy.
It’s stupidity.
When two nice birds are together they should
chirp and laugh and enjoy.
Instead of that, if they start pricking each
other, what should we call them?
So today it’s a great joy for Me.
So many people are engaged and are going to
get married.
But now, understand your responsibility that
nothing is to be done.
You have to be just sahaj; don’t have to
do anything.
“We are working out."
You cannot work out marriage; you cannot work
out.
Just know about your husband or about your
wife and just try to enjoy whatever they are.
I mean, I do enjoy that way about My husband,
so many things which may sound little queer
to people, but I enjoy it.
Because I know that’s a nice thing about
our human beings that they have varieties
and they have little, different angles to
themselves.
And these angles are to be enjoyed and to
be appreciated.
If you can do that, then you will never fight.
Because two persons cannot be alike; even
two leaves are not alike.
So you should enjoy.
Everybody has some sort of a super quality
thing or whatever it is or maybe some angle.
Just enjoy that angle.
You don’t have that; so let him have at
least, or let her have that.
So today, special day is that so many marriages
have been fixed out.
I don’t know how many ? he has not told
Me yet the number ? but quite a lot have been
fixed.
Sahaja yogi: Fifty.
Shri Mataji: Fifty have been already fixed.
All right.
So now it’s a very big number and will be
more by the time we reach Ganapatipule.
So let us not create problems out of this.
You don’t have to sit down.
I have seen after marriage they start thinking,
“What, what do you think about him?”
It’s like after realization you start thinking.
Once you are married, you are not to think
then accept.
Before marriage you think.
What’s the use of thinking after marriage?
It’s a very common thing.
After marriage they start thinking.
Then, after marriage you enjoy.
After cooking the food you eat the food.
Or after the food has been served then you
start thinking about it.
It’s absurd.
So this is a very common failing we have had
so far.
I would like to tell you first of all, you
think before getting married and after getting
married you carry on.
And don’t try to control.
Don’t try to dictate.
Try to be nice and sweet.
You don’t have to go out of the way, but
be normal and it will all work out.
May God bless you all, specially all the girls
and boys who have been engaged.
I bless you from My heart, and enjoy each
other; that’s the main point.
So thank you very much.
Thank you.