Hindi
I am sorry I was delayed.
We were supposed to see the Collector and the
Tahsildar, as they call him.
They have done so much for us; so much they have organized,
all the way, and officially they have done so well,
that I had to wait for them to thank them very much.
I think
it's not very much hot for you, see the
wind is blowing, can you imagine.
And if you see, there's no, no leaves, leaves are not moving.
You always used to go and sit in the sun,
so now here it is, you'd better have some of it.
I hope you all enjoyed your stay in Jabalpur
and the visit to Jabalpur.
It was quite interesting. Some people have not yet arrived.
I am sorry to say they haven't been able to arrive
from Bombay.
I think they are more Bombayites, not from the foreign countries,
but otherwise I think all of you are here.
It's a very unusual thing to happen like this, you see,
this My father built this house about eighty years back.
He was very imaginative and fond of guests,
so he also put up guest bedrooms and guest bathrooms, such,
and it was a hill station.
Now of course, because of crowdedness very cold and a hill station
so people used to come, his friends used to come from Nagpur,
so he had made arrangements for them.
There were no hotels or anything so they used to have -
and the people of this place are extremely hospitable,
very hospitable.
So it was his idea that he should have a house here
where his guests could be.
His brother had a big house
but it was joint and he couldn't receive his guests,
so he thought it's better to build a house here,
and behind was a huge, big compound bigger than this,
which I have seen.
I was only four years of age when we went away from here,
but I remember each and everything
about this house, and everything about Chhindwara.
And you know My memory is unusually, very, very sharp.
I mean, I remember even My birth, it's to that extent.
But I never knew that there would be so many saints coming
to visit this place of My birth.
I never expected that there would be so many people
who will take to Sahaja Yoga in My lifetime,
because when I was born I found people were so blind.
I thought, "How will I talk about Sahaja Yog? What will I do?
How will it work out? It's very difficult."
My father knew about My mission,
and he told Me that "You'd better find out a way
by which You can give Realization en masse.
That was important, because
even if You give Realization one person, is of no use.
Also You should not write anything,
because You don't create another Bible, Gita, Koran,
because books also bind them.
So best thing is that You should take to...
search of human beings,
why they can't get it, their en masse Realization,
because now You have come for that purpose."
Somehow it worked it out,
and really it was surprising, I was really,
was not thinking to open Sahasrara,
but I was literally forced into it and it worked out.
It's working out. You can see, all of you are here.
It's very amazing thing that can happen to someone like this,
that in the lifetime only,
you have come here to see this birthplace of Mine.
It was such, such vibrations
that My Sahasrara became completely jammed with vibrations.
So cool inside, and outside was so hot that I didn't know
what was happening.
So I'm happy all of you could come and see this place,
and a very humble house it was,
but in those days it was the most,
I mean, well-planned house as such,
and was very much appreciated by people.
And after that four years I was here,
and then we went to Nagpur because we had a,
My father had a big practice in Nagpur,
he had to go many times down,
so they thought it's better to go.
There also he had many houses,
and Babamama is going to take you round to see those houses.
He says he'll find out time to see wherever I have lived.
But Nagpur also is very vibrated place, you can feel it.
People are very quiet, it's a very quiet place.
So this is a very novel thing,
I don't think it has happened in the lifetime of
any one of the incarnations who came on this earth.
Even for Rama Janma Bhoomi we are fighting even today.
So you can imagine.
Thank God, we have got this place - in a way. It's not yet ours,
but in a way we are there,
and maybe with your good wishes we'll own it very soon.
Today's puja I thought was best to have
Shri Ganesha Puja in a short way,
because the first Puja here, and I was born here,
so it's better that we should have a Ganesha Puja.
It would be a nice thing to start with,
and I, we have a doctor here.
They are all Sahaja Yogis and they are going to help us
to do the curing. Actually I always thought,
"Which is the place where people will get cured?"
So now we'll send all of them here to get cured.
It's a, it was a jungle here.
All around was jungles, hills,
but I think all that's finished and broken now.
And we used to get tigers and things;
little far away from here is a place called Tamiya
where they could go see tigers,
but now they are there no doubt,
but they are saying that nobody is now going that side,
they all go to some preserve places
which you have seen yourself, also Kanha Kisli.
I hope you enjoyed. How did you enjoy Kanha Kisli?
And the River Narmada also I was told you enjoyed very much.
I am happy this has happened.
It was a little circuitous and quite
different from all the tours we have had so far,
but I am happy you all have enjoyed it.
I have said so many things about Shri Ganesh,
I don't know what to say now, anymore,
but all of you have seen that, a place, now see the -
this breeze is coming from where? I don't know.
You are sending breeze to Me, instead of I doing it.
All right.
[Shri Mataji is starting to talk in Hindi for about 5 minutes}