Face yourself for becoming.
Then the preparation is done
to become something and on the whole, when
you know that it is your ego and superego
which are loading you up, you have to scan
them out with vibratory awareness.
Now there are two types of attention we have
to pay.
First is a constant attention that is a routine
of a Sahaja Yogi, and the second one is the
emergency attention.
I have been saying that all the Sahaja Yogis
must start writing their diaries: one with
every day’s experiences, if you know that
you have to write a diary, you’ll keep your
mind alert, and another one whenever you get
any special idea of the past or of the future,
also to jot it down.
So, like that, you should have two diaries.
For your constant attention, you have to fix
up your mind on certain facts.
The first one, as I said, that if you keep
a diary then you will know that you have to
remember what important things have happened.
So your attention will be alert and you will
be looking out for such points, where, what
is the thing you see.
And you’ll be amazed, if you make your attention
alert, what new things come to you – very
brilliant ideas.
And the miracles of life and the miracles
of God’s beauty and His auspiciousness,
His greatness, His kindness, His blessings
– how they work out if you start writing
every day even two lines about it.
It will make your mind constantly involved
with it.
That’s a human style of doing things.
Also you can mention in the diary what happened:
did you, could you do your meditation?
Did you get your time for meditation or not?
A little bit as if you are appearing for some
sort of a examination or something, you prepare
a little note like that: “Did I get up in
the morning?
Did I?”
Then any special path or any special movement
in the centre or left or right also should
be mentioned so that you keep a watch on your
mind.
It’s a very good thing to maintain a diary.
Also, you will see progressively how your
ideas are changing, how new priorities are
settling down, how you give more importance
to real things and very little to unreal things.
I think this is a very, very practical side
of human beings that one should have a diary.
[The] same diaries, after some times, will
become historical things and people would
like to see what you all have written.
Not to be hypocritical about it or deceptive
about it, but quite truthful and understanding.
You should jot down few lines just before
sleeping.
Now we have to see that we have problems for
superego and ego.
Now superego is the left side, is darkness,
tamo guna and our past.
Those who have left side problems should think
of the future, it gives them balancing if
they think of the future.
For example, a person who is lethargic should
take to working.
Put your mind into working for the future
planning: what to do, where to go, how to
do.
That will keep you away from [the] drag of
the left side and gradually then you can balance
yourself also.
Now the right side of a person, when it is
activated very much, he has to balance it
not with the left side but with the centre.
That is, a person who is very hard-working
must develop a witness state.
You try to do a work, any work, indulge into
work in thoughtless awareness, as a witness.
Whatever work you are doing you just say that:
“I am not doing it."
This you can do it after Realisation.
You become thoughtlessly aware and start doing
your work.
So the compensation of the left side is done
by movement to the right, and of the right
side [by] movement in the centre.
Left side is the tamo guna, right side is
the rajo guna, the centre is the sattwo guna.
But still these are three gunas.
That’s not the state which we have to achieve.
About this I’ll tell you tomorrow more,
how to go further then.
After scanning out which side is weak, you
should plan out your style of life.
For example, if you are extremely lethargic,
you cannot get up in the morning, you feel
very sleepy in the night, you do not feel
alerted then start planning as to what will
you do.
How will you get up?
Even puja is a good idea, homa (havan) is
a good idea.
Do something like that, so that you have to
do something, what you call the kriya, is
the action, get into the action.
Some sort of a action you go into in Sahaja
Yoga as well as in your daily life [then]
you’ll be able to change that mood and come
to the right side and then you’ll go to
the, your movement should be towards the sattwa
guna, is to watch everything.
Now at the sattwa guna point where you are
in the centre you have to see how much you
are misidentified.
Say, supposing you are at the first stage
of left side, then you will just do daydreaming,
“‘Oh!
This person is so much identified, that one
is so much identified,” as if you are the
best.
It’s just human nature, you see.
“Oh, that person is like that, he is like
that, this is very bad in the society, that
is going bad in the society.
It’s better…”
Then we can also go to this limit is to, “That
guru is very bad and that one is another madcap."
Like that, you see, all daydreaming going
on.
How far it is affecting you, how far are you
improving by that is not….It’s just, you
see, thinking, analysing.
It is, it’s a lazy stuff, sitting down and
just analysing, it’s a lazy stuff.
The second thing could be when you come to
the second side of it, is the kriya.
Then what happens when you start doing it,
then at least your attention is on what you
are doing.
It’s not allowed to drift into something
and which goes into any nonsense and can,
I mean, then you don’t know from where the
funny thoughts are coming.
So, you start doing something.
You can go and plant some trees or you can
go and plant some flowers or if you want you
can do some cooking, you can do some work.
Take to work!
That will help you.
Any work.
But while doing the work the problem will
be, you’ll develop ego.
That’s why when you are developing the ego
you have to tell yourself, “You are not
doing, mister!
This you are not doing, this is not doing,
you are not doing."
If you go on suggesting to yourself [like
this] Mr.
Ego will not come up.
And then many things, you see, which normally
trouble you and trouble others – like you
have cleaned the room, alright.
Then [if] somebody comes and spoils it you
get angry with that person.
Naturally!
Because you think ‘you’ have done.
First of all you don’t clean the room.
If you clean the room then you be prepared,
it will be dirtied, otherwise why should you
clean?
Now, if it is dirty, well and good; if it
is not dirtied, well and good.
This type of a attitude you should take to
jump on to sattwa guna.
On sattwa guna you start accepting it.
You become extremely mild.
You become a mild personality.
Then at that time you do not discuss as to,
“Oh, I don’t like it; this was wrong;
this should not have been."
All these things do not come to you in sattwa
guna.
You start seeing it.
That time you see it that, “Alright, doesn’t
matter.
It’s done, it’s done."
On the contrary, you feel hurt if you are
a sattwa guni, that by any suggestion you
have suggested your ego.
Can you get that point?
You feel ashamed of your ego, I mean to say,
if you are a sattwa guni.
For example, even to say that “This is my
car,” you will feel shy.
That’s a sattwa guni type.
Or even to say, “Why did you spoil my carpet?”
I mean in India nobody will say, I can tell
you this!
Is regarded [as] bad manners, absolute bad
manners.
If anybody comes to your house and the carpet
is spoiled they say, “Let it be, doesn’t
matter."
Even it is burnt, “I don’t know.
Let it be.
Are you burnt?”
They’ll never say that, “You have burnt
my carpet, or done anything to my…”
Is regarded [as] bad manners.
Like here, you see, if somebody’s sleeping
[and] somebody makes the noise.
The person who is sleeping will never say
that “You are making noise,” He’ll just
get up and ask, “Do you need anything?”
That’s difficult for people here to understand
because ego is just sitting on the head.
But is bad manners there.
You will find when you’ll go to India you’ll
find this.
These are bad manners to say that.
Or to say, “Oh, I, I feel very comfortable."
I mean, to say “I feel comfortable” is
bad manners.
I mean, they never say.
“I like it."
So what?
All these words are not to be said.
If you are a sattwa guni then you just don’t
say, you will say, “Do you like it?
Is it comfortable?
Would you like to have this?”
The whole attention goes from your side.
Do you understand that?
That is the style one has to develop.
Then you are a sattwa guni.
Otherwise, you are still on ego trip.
You see, whatever you may think, “I don’t
like that, I don’t…”
“I”- who are you?
First of all ask the question, “Who are
you?”
If God says, “I don’t like you,” I can
understand, with good reasons, but for you
to say, “I don’t like it” …After all,
how did you come on this earth?
How did you get a human birth?
How did you get all these things?
Now think like that.
“Who am I?
I am nothing."
Anybody who thinks, “I am something,”
he should know that he’s nothing; makes
no difference to God whether he exists or
does not exist, you see, he’s nothing, he’s
just a drop.
So, this point if you understand, that even
if you do something, any work you do or anything
you are doing: you are just doing it because
you want to do it.
That is how you come on to sattwa guna.
But normally it doesn’t happen.
It happens the other way round.
For example a person is, say, doing something
[if] by any chance he feels hurt or he thinks
that whatever he has done is no good.
People don’t appreciate, or maybe he might
think that, “Oh, it’s not up to the point,”
or whatever it is, then the reaction for him
is not that he does not try to rise to sattwa
guna, but he goes back to tamo guna.
“Alright, I’ll not do it.
I’ll sleep over it.
Let them do it, why should I do it?”
So the training that you have to have through
your rajo guna goes a waste.
It’s just a training period that you are
with rajo guna.
You are doing something.
Now in that training period you have to learn
only how to come in the centre.
For example now, water is required for you
to swim.
If there is no water you cannot swim.
All right?
In the same way, rajo guna is required for
you to come to sattwa guni.
If you do not do any work you cannot come
to sattwa guna.
So you are just working just to train yourself
to be a witness.
Now do you follow that point?
You are not doing it because you like particular
thing, you are used to particular thing, because
you want to be this.
This is not the way it is.
You are just doing it to learn how to be patient.
To practice your patience.
To see how much patient you are.
Once you start doing it, you’ll be amazed
that you will never feel the burden of the
work.
But it never happens.
Most of the people, if they find their work
is not effective, they’ll go back to tamo
guna.
There are many attitudes.
Say, somebody’s working, then he thinks,
“Why should I do all the work?
Others are not doing!”
He’ll go back to their stage.
But those who are not working will not think
that, “This person is working, let me also
work."
It’s other way round, you see.
This can be an attitude of some people that
“if this person is working, let him work."
This is even a meaner stuff, [to] avoid, just.
You go to a restaurant and somebody takes
out the purse, others start looking this side
– is very mean, it’s a very mean thing
to do.
Everybody should come forward and once you
have paid, you have paid it, finished.
Then you just don’t start counting, “Why
did I pay?”
Once you try [to do this].
Or any work has to be done, go forward with
it, do it with your heart.
Don’t worry if others have not done it.
Just do it for its pleasure and the pleasure
only you will get when you will do it with
the understanding that it’s a training period,
you are better trained than the other one
is.
You are at a higher class than the other one
So we have to be at a higher class.
For that this is just a training on.
And that’s how we can really put our preparation
into practice, into all details to see how
we work out our ego and superego.
Today, in the morning, I have told you that
your intellect must imbibe this within itself,
all right?
And now I’m telling you that your action,
action that you do, must be every time branded
by you as just your training – any action
you do.
Supposing you have to drive for miles together,
you are trying your patience.
You see they’ll do in everything.
Say they have to go for say helicopter, or
say if they have to drop from the…what you
call them, they drop down?
Sahaja Yogis: Parachutes.
Shri Mataji: Parachuters!
Or helicopter you take away or whatever it
is.
You go on doing it again and again, isn’t
it?
You practice it again and again.
You drop many-a-times, you break your legs,
you break your hands, you do this and do that
till you become a master.
You understand My point?
Driving – same way, till you become a master,
you go on.
In the same way, you are doing this work just
to master your patience.
And then your love, is your love – how much
you love really.
If you really love someone, you are never
tired of working.
You are never upset with work.
But if you don’t love, you start counting,
“How much money, how much work, how many
hours, how much to be paid?”
All artificiality comes because there is no
love involved in your work.
Whatever you don’t want to do, you don’t
do it, to begin with.
To begin with you just don’t do what you
don’t like – to begin with.
But once you have mastered that, then you
have to master it that you do something that
you don’t like.
Like meeting some bhooties, for example.
You don’t want to meet, you want to run
away, but you go little nearer it, you see.
Then develop a immunity for these bhooties.
After some time you’ll not catch them.
We have to develop the immunity, isn’t it?
Otherwise one person comes here and everybody’s
head goes out.
Instead of the fellow improving, you all go
out.
So all these things are, all these events
are for your training, your immunity.
Your immunity is to be trained and when it
is so, when we are training ourselves we should
take it as a job.
But the attitude should be extremely positive,
extremely positive and all that should be
expressed in your notebook: whether you got
dejected or you got upset and disgusted, you
want to run away from it – all sorts of
things.
It’s just a training to your mind.
Whatever is the situation, wherever one has
to live, whatever one has to do, we should
do.
Whatever may be the circumstances, conditions,
you’ll be amazed, you will not even know
what you have eaten in the morning, what you
have eaten in the evening, whether you have
eaten or not you will not know.
You’ll not fuss about it, you’ll not worry
about it, you’ll not think about it.
But this being, the aim, is to reach to sattwa
guna, every other thing becomes zero.
It’s the greatest hurdle comes to Sahaja
Yogis I’ve seen, when they start organising.
They start organising something.
Now somebody wants something, so they’ll
run up to get the thing for that person.
Now just now I’ve said that you must look
after the needs of others, but if I am sitting
here and there’s a lecture on then you’d
better be just listening to Me.
You see, this also is there that: how to have
your priorities, at this time when something
[is] working on you.
This is the first thing you have to do.
Not that at this time you go and cook.
You have known the story of two sisters attending
on Christ.
Alright?
So at this time, what is your first job is
to try to be more exposed to Me so that automatically
you’ll go into your sattwa guna.
This is the best!
But if I am not there and when you are alone
or when you are with other Sahaja Yogis you
must now compete in rising higher and higher:
from tamo guna to rajo guna and from rajo
guna to sattwo guna.
But actually by Realisation you have gone
beyond these three gunas.
You have gone beyond it.
Actually that is what has happened to you.
But, like clouds, they cover you again and
again.
And when the sky is covered with those clouds,
you cannot see the sun, you cannot see the
moon, you cannot see the stars.
So we have to know how these clouds are coming
into us and that’s how we go into our complete
analysis.
How these clouds are coming to us, you find
out about our different chakras.
What are the chakras we are catching?
Here comes the another constant attention
towards our chakras.
Are our vibrations alright or not?
Are we getting our vibrations?
If not, what chakra am I catching, what must
be the catch?
I must raise my Kundalini, see for myself,
where is the catch.
Do I do my meditation or not?
If I do it, am I doing it just dozingly or
am I really in it?
Am I really feeling it or not?
Am I alert or not?
All this is to be assiduously, sincerely,
absolutely, truthfully should be worked out.
Because it is a process between your self
– ‘Atamanyeva Atmana tushta’ [The Spirit
is satisfied with Itself].
You see it’s a very funny, it is so funny
relationship that it is the Atma is satisfied
with Atma!
You have to be satisfied with your Self.
There’s nobody, Mataji is not concerned,
nobody is concerned.
It is you who is concerned with your Self.
For example, you ask somebody and he says,
“I am like this, Mother."
Now think that you are Mother, one personality,
another is, say, Mr.
Don or Kingsley or someone X.
You are two personalities.
So when you are telling your Self, means that
is Mataji, that, “I am not alright,” then
Mataji must come up and say, “What do you
mean by this?
Why should you say like that?
What’s wrong?”
When you say that to your self which is outside,
then the attention starts moving towards your
Self which is Mataji and you start becoming
that and you start seeing through your Atma.
So your Atma is to be satisfied by your Atma
only.
There is nothing in between.
It is you only in this dual personality has
to satisfy your Self.
One is in ignorance, one is in knowledge.
Now try to identify yourself with that Mataji,
call it, or any Xyz whatever you call it,
Atma.
And just for, just a drama, say.
You just think that you are the Self, Spirit.
So how will you address your Self?
Let’s see.
Supposing you have to sit in My seat, yes,
take it like that, a position.
And then you are sitting in front of Me also,
alright?
So you are sitting here and sitting there.
Take a position like that.
Now you put up your Self in a drama and you
start addressing your self, “So Bala, how
are you?”
so Bala says, “Better,”
So if you are identified now with Mataji,
gradually Bala will diminish, alright?
But if you are still identified with Bala,
he’ll grow and this [Mataji] will diminish.
You have to try to address your self as if
you are Mataji.
It’s a drama.
You sit before the mirror.
In the mirror you see this outside of yours
and here you are sitting, whatever you are,
Mr. Don for example.
Now Mr.
Don is addressing the other Don there, and
let him take up a role that, “I am the Spirit."
He’ll say, “I am the Spirit and I am eternal.
I am this.
Nobody can destroy me.
I am above everything."
That thing will go down.
“I am a realised soul.
I know what Spirit is.
What are you talking?”
It will go down.
This is how you start moving.
But is only possible that first you become
a sattwa guni.
If you are not a sattwa guni, with ego, “I
am this,” then you become a guru and you
start minting money!
First the ego is to be brought down.
If there is still ego, then without becoming
Atma you become an ego.
So first this journey should be brought in
to the centre of sattwa guna.
That is why I say that when you are talking
or doing anything, you must know that it is
your Spirit which is doing it.
That’s how you put your Spirit in charge
or say at the pedestal – first stage.
Then when the Spirit is there, then from this
stage to that stage, then you say that, “Now
I am the Spirit."
For example, if you have a prime minister
and a deputy minister and a minister – three
persons, alright?
Now, if the prime minister is your Self and
the minister has to become the prime minister,
so he has to first become deputy minister.
After becoming deputy minister he has to become
prime minister; but deputy prime minister
and then the prime minister.
But supposing this fellow starts to jump over
this, this will come up and hit him and he’ll
say, “I’m the one!” and this one is
E-G-O.
Do you understand My point?
So you cannot surpass it.
You have to merge this into this and then
this into this.
The movement has to be like that.
But if you try to just become this, actually
you will become this, not this, because you
cannot become this.
Do you understand My point?
So, even when doing this exercise of sitting
before a mirror and telling yourself that
you are the Spirit, you are the part of Viraat,
that you are the Ocean because your drop has
fallen into the Ocean.
Then you must know that your drop has fallen
into the Ocean.
That’s why you’ve become an Ocean.
If that stage is missing, then you’re saying
that you are an Ocean is absolutely bombastic.
And that is why one has to be very steady
and careful, absolutely steady as far as dealing
with oneself.
Because you know how this intelligence can
cheat you.
So be very, very careful and when you are
dealing with you, you must know that you have
to first overcome this ego.
The best thing to overcome ego is to change
your language style, is to speak in the third
person.
Is a very good way.
Like you must say, when you are talking about
yourself, “This Mataji won’t listen to
Me.
This Mataji won’t do this,” you see, so
what happens, this ‘Mataji’ means the
ego part of it, you see.
And once you start separating this Mataji
away from your self, then that ego Mataji
disappears.
You understand?
Like you can say, “This Bala is like that.
He won’t listen."
So whatever the real Bala is left in you is
alright.
That’s how you get rid of your ego and by
understanding your centres, what you are catching,
where you are catching, how you are catching;
it would be very easy for you to get rid of
your problems.
Now, see what Sahaja Yogis do.
Supposing there are five Sahaja Yogis sitting.
I mean you know that
I know about everyone, everything.
I don’t have to ask, “Where is catching?”
Now why do I ask?
I show complete ignorance.
Because perhaps I never catch also, to be
very frank.
But if I want to know where I’m catching
I can find out but I don’t want to.
So what I say, “Alright, Chaya, tell Me
where is he catching."
At this time one attitude could be that, “I
must tell, otherwise Mataji won’t know."
This is very funny.
(Laughter) The second one could be, and the
second one could be that, that, “I know
where she is catching and, and I must tell,
and Mataji also knows but She wants to test
me.
So I should be careful."
At this point people make mistakes.
If I ask them, “Where is it catching?”
“I am catching on left heart but very mildly!”
Finished then!
You, you’ll get less marks.
[Laughter]
You get less marks.
You tell Me whatever you think, because at
least you’re honest.
Whatever you think.
Supposing the fellow is not catching heart
but you are feeling the heart.
You say, “Heart” That’s being honest.
Then I will tell you who is catching the heart.
But if you are, “Perhaps yes, Mataji.
No, Mataji,” then you get less marks.
It’s not a very good answer.
“I am not alright, I don’t know,” that’s
not a good answer.
You have to tell Me who is catching where.
Then you pay more attention that you have
to pass this test.
This is just testing.
Why?
Because tomorrow you have to give Realisation.
You have to become the gurus.
You have to know all this.
So this is all training period.
I’m just training you by asking you to tell
Me, but I have seen people even getting ego
with this.
It’s surprisingly sometimes.
That also gives the ego to people that I say,
“Alright, you tell Me where is he catching?”
“I told correctly!”
Finished!
You see, it is just a very, very, I can say,
razor stage I tell you, where one has to see
clearly.
So be a simple person like children are.
They just come.
This one, that one, finished.
Then they’ll go and sit down, “Now I’m
tired , I’m sitting down!”
They are not bothered that they should … they
must say something or something show off,
nothing.
Whatever they see, they say.
But only grownups will say that, “Maybe
I’m catching, maybe it is his.
I don’t know."
All this is done by grownup people because
still the sensitivity is alright but they
are not sure of themselves.
Children are very sure.
They are cocksure of everything.
You ask them anything, they’ll tell you,
“Yes, this is this, this is this."
But you ask anyone, “What is the colour
of this thing?”
They’ll say, “Maybe green, maybe red."
[Laughter.]
Like we had one old gentleman, not very old,
as old as Myself – but he was to come to
My house and he telephoned to Me.
He said, “I want to come to Your house so
how should I come?”
I said, “This place is Oxted, you can come
there but if you don’t get a taxi then it’s
very difficult, better come to Hurst Green."
He said, “Where?”
I said, “Hurst Green."
So he said, “Hurst Blue?”
How he is saying blue to green, I don’t
know.
(note: ‘Hearse Blue’ is a famous colour)
I said, “No, it’s Hurst Green."
He said, “What did you say?”
I said, “Hurst Green."
So he couldn’t understand.
“What is the second one?”
I said, “What is the colour of the leaves?”
He said, “Blue."
(Laughter.)
I said it to Gregoire, I said, “Now listen
to him, what is he saying?
Colour of the leaves is blue?”
So, Gregoire lifted the phone he said, “Alright,
you come to Hurst Blue."
(Laughter)
So he said, “Now at least…”
I said, “What are you telling?”
Such a confused personality, mixing between
blue and green!
You are fighting.
That’s what it is.
The attention drifts.
So try to see that if you are confused, there
is confusion, clear it out by clearing out
your chakras.
Now every chakra, let’s have a little testing
of it alright, let’s see?
One by one.
So who are going to answer the questions?
Let’s see.
Simple questions.
Not ‘Mastermind’ (a British TV competition
of 1970s and 80s).
Very simple questions.
Now, say your Hamsa Chakra is catching, what
should we do?
Who will answer the question?
Hamsa Chakra is catching, what should we do?
Let’s see, one by one.
Sahaja Yogi: Hamsa, Hamsa.
Shri Mataji: That’s the name of the chakra.
Sahaja Yogi: Someone said to me that you say
Hamsa.
Shri Mataji: No…you see this is the Hamsa
Chakra so you have to say that, “Twameva
sakshat, Hamsa Chakra Swamini sakshat, Shri
Mataji Nirmala Devi namoh, namah."
See, opened now.
Now say it, all of you, because just now you
are catching.
Now put your finger like this and now say
it.
(Everyone says the mantra).
Say it again.
Say it thrice.
[Everyone repeats twice more] See?
Better.
Now, what happens in this centre that both
the Nadis, Ha and Tha, Ida and Pingala, they
come and meet and they cross over.
So, for the right Nadi, right side, this one,
the left Nadi flows and from the right side,
the one which comes from the right side flows
into left side.
These two centres meet here, I mean two Nadis
meet here actually, below the Agnya, it’s
below the Agnya at Hamsa, you see, and the
problems come to you either from the right
or from the left.
Most of you catch on Hamsa here, because of
cold or whatever it is.
Now, I have told you many things by which
you control your cold.
But if it is due to the left side, left side
catching is there, then for left side Hamsa
what should you do?
Tell Me.
Sahaja Yogi: Keep your eyes on the ground,
on the green.
Shri Mataji: That’s one of them, but another
thing, I mean as far as mantra is concerned
what mantra will you say…
Sahaja Yogi: Ekadasha Rudra.
Shri Mataji: No that’s much higher, that’s
even above the Agnya.
Sahaja Yogi: Mahakali.
Shri Mataji: Mahakali, correct.
But you can say Ida, Ida Nadi.
Now see just now I have told you that it is
the Ida Nadi which comes from the left and
goes to the right side.
So, you have to say Mahakali or Ida Nadi,
Ida Nadi Swamini.
Now say it.
Just now you are catching on the left.
[Sahaja Yogis take mantra of ‘Ida Nadi Swamini’.]
Shri Mataji: Again.
[Everyone says the mantra.]
Now, then another thing, that supposing your
right side is catching, or you have a liver
problem, then what should be used – light,
sun’s rays or water?
Sahaja Yogi: Water.
Shri Mataji: See, right side is heat, is Surya
Nadi.
So you have problem of Surya Nadi – right
side.
So to neutralize it you have to use something
else.
So then that time what you have to say, is
to – you can say, you can take the name
of Chandra, you’ll cool down.
If there is heat on the right hand side, you
should take the name of Chandra.
If it is the left side catching, then you
have to take the name of Surya.
For example you are possessed, then go and
sit in the Sun – all the bhoots will run
away.
They run away from Sun.
But supposing you are an egoistical person
then go and sit in the moonlight.
May be you’ll be little lunatic.
(Laughter) It comes from the word ‘luna’,
you see?
But if you are a crying type and all the time
over-romantic [it’s] better not look at
the moon and better see the sun.
See the compensations.
This is absolutely understanding that many
people, if they have liver they put in this
[fire].
What can the fire do now?
There’s already fire here.
Adding fire to the fire again, you see?
But, also, what one can do is to take out
this fire and give it to this one.
Now, how do you do that?
Sahaja Yogi: Lemon?
Shri Mataji: No, no.
to fire.
Supposing I want to treat My liver with fire.
How do I do it?
Sahaja Yogi: You put your finger actually
to the flame so that it burns off.
Shri Mataji: No.
Sahaja Yogi: It’ll take too much a week!
[Laughter]
Shri Mataji: Yes, that’s correct but something
takes some times about it.
Think it over then, think it over, take it
over.
You see, you have to take out your heat and
give it to these heights.
How do you do it?
Think it over.
I’ll tell you simple thing is: this left
hand is minus, this [right hand] is plus,
you can take like that, alright?
So whatever you do with left hand you suck
in.
Whatever you do with right hand, say, for
example, you give out.
Alright?
So now if you want to now give out, what you
do is to put left hand on you here and right
hand outside.
So this is cooling it here actually and the
heat is going there.
But if you do the other way round, you are
sucking heat.
Sahaja Yogi : Hum
Shri Mataji: But from the left hand side you
do it like that.
Just electronics, alright, then?
Now if you burn here is a good idea, very
good idea for Left Nabhi.
So the Left Nabhi gets heated up.
This side needs heat.
This side needs cooling.
This is the basics.
If something wrong with this side (right)
you have to give it the cool.
If something wrong this side, you have to
give it the heat.
Some people get too much cool vibrations.
They’ll perspire and cool, means left is
finished.
Now what should they do as far as fire is
concerned?
Let’s see.
Sahaj Yogini: [inaudible] right hand here
Shri Mataji: He perspires.
Right hand on the heart, left hand here.
If anyone perspires, it means his heart is
weak.
So put right hand here and left hand on the
heart.
The heat comes in.
Are you following the electronics, no, the
electrical?
Sahaja Yogi: Yes, Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji: So the basics if you know that
the left side is the cool side, the right
side is the hot side.
And above the hand, this is the minus side,
this is the plus side.
Even you can do like this and you are balancing
yourself.
That’s why in India we do, specially if
you see a great bhootish [person] then you’ll
do like this, fully.
You see?
So, these two sides are: one is the hot side,
one is a cold side, while the Sattwa Guna
is the meeting point, is lukewarm.
The Sattwa Guna gives you the temperature
that you have.
Alright?
And these two give you either very cold or
very hot.
So we come back to now sinus again.
It is which side problem?
Sahaja Yogis: Left hand side.
Shri Mataji: Correct!
Left side, because there are three things
now in our bodies.
One is…what do you say to that?
Bulgam.
Another is the bile and the third one is the
gas or Vayu.
Alright?
So the left side is the Kapha.
All these colds and things are due to left
side.
And the right side is the bile.
The fat is created from bulgam, which doctors
do not know.
Do you know that?
When fat is heated up by the right hand side,
then it dissolves and the gas movement is
in the centre.
When these five types of gases which are within
us, when they all combine together and get
enlightened by the Spirit, you get the Cool
Breeze coming out.
So the centre path is the prana.
When it gets absolutely heated up then diseases
like tuberculosis, all these things can come
in.
And when it gets heated up on the left hand
side you get tuberculosis and all these things
due to too much heat.
When it gets heated too much, then it comes
to the right hand side and you get diseases
like liver and all these heatening things
on the right hand side.
So though the left hand side is cold, if it
is heated up then also diseases are caused.
Now we have to go into details sometimes to
find out what, basically, are our diseases
within our body.
We should know what is our disease.
Sometimes even if you have ordinary cold,
it is a disease, according to Sahaja Yoga.
You should be a normal person.
Supposing you are suffering from, say, the
terrible disease, the greatest nuisance and
the blessing of London and England put together
– is cold.
Call it hay fever, day fever, or anything!
So it is due to what?
It is due to basically within us less resistance,
no immunity.
Less resistance come to us because of lack
of calcium within us.
Those people who have taken proper care in
childhood, taken vitamin A and D and good
massage, say with cod liver oil or olive oil
and things like that, and proper sunning of
the body is done, such people suffer less
from cold.
Specially the Vishuddhi Chakra problem it
is.
Now those people who have not been careful
about their Vishuddhi Chakra get the disease
settled within themselves, but when this disease
is settled, what happens actually?
What is the reason, as we said that it is
the left hand side problem.
Cold is a left hand side problem.
That means cold has something to do with your
emotional side.
That means there’s something also wrong
emotionally with you.
So it indicates that you have some emotional
problem.
According to Sahaj Yog, to overcome cold one
should see into this emotional life of oneself.
What are you doing about your emotions?
For example as soon as you’re affected by
emotions, you will start crying or sneezing.
(Laughter)
This is a fact.
If these are girls, they’ll start crying.
If they are men, they’ll start coughing
or sneezing.
They’ll cough for nothing at all.
You see [Shri Mataji coughs] they will go.
[Laughter]
Isn’t it a fact?
Unnecessarily they’ll be doing like this.
Is an emotional thing, to attract the attention
maybe or whatever it is.
To say that how pitiable they are, you see,
is a thing by which we show our pitiable condition.
You see, is a thing, we reduce ourselves to
a position by which we try to, you see, excite
the pity in other person.
So this cold is due to our emotional problem.
Now so we should see what is our emotional
problem.
We should find out how much ‘Romeos’ we
are [Shri burst into laughs].
And how much delight of life we miss by that.
Once you start understanding that you are
your own Romeo and you are your own Juliet
– most of you will get rid of your colds.
Take it from Me.
It is some sort of an emotional problem.
Could be with your father.
A person who is very attached to his father.
‘Attached’ is the word best is, gets also
attached to cold.
Attached to mother is even worse.
If somebody is very attached to her mother,
you see, then all reasoning fails and then
the mother misbehaves or does something and
the child feels very hurt, the child cries,
he gets the cold.
Any such attachment which makes you foolish
should be given up, to get rid of your cold,
I mean to say.
Whatever makes you stupid, foolish or hankering
after someone, creates troubles like colds.
‘Romeos’ specially.
Then very beloved children, beloved fathers,
beloved mothers, you see, the ones for them
their daughter is important, their son is
important.
Some people just don’t love their children
and if some love they’ll dump them onto
everybody else.
So these two types of it.
You must know that you are just a trustee
of your child and as far as your ‘Romeo-ness’
is concerned, you are just to see drama of
your Romeo, that’s all.
Then this detachment will take place and a
simple disease like cold which looks so horrible,
incurable, can be cured.
As long as you people have cold, without having
any romantic feelings Myself, I also get it.
So I request you to rise above these things
and become more sensible, and your attitude
should be of enhancing mutual understanding,
mutual love, and not romantic feelings.
But worse than that is dry feelings, on the
right hand side you know.
Then if you have a dry throat you cannot even
speak.
Suddenly you find -finished- [laughs] you
just can’t speak because you are dried.
So the other side is where some people try
some psychological tricks with their wives
or husbands – like “I will not speak”.
This I’m telling you just an emotional side
of life.
“I’ll not talk to her.
I’ll not speak.
I’ll behave like this."
Dryness.
That also kills the delight.
The one is overdoing of it and one is not
doing of it.
You see, either you’ll take sugar which
is one ton in one glass, or you will not take
sugar at all.
You will not take one spoon of sugar.
Not more, not less, you see, to have the optimum
delight of tea.
In the same way, in life also, you should
not take too much of something and too little
of another thing.
Now somebody who’s married now, for that
person, Indian women specially, husband becomes
last one, then everything else is zero.
Then such women are useless.
Or men that I’ve seen here, they are just
mad on their women.
For them also, life is useless.
So take a balanced attitude of the whole thing
in that.
It is in you is the person who is loving your
wife, who is also within you.
You are your wife, you are your husband.
Now the wife who is your wife outside, if
she just does not tally with the wife that
you have within your mind, that should not
upset you, because that wife is always with
you.
Once this understanding develops, you see
your partnership -[Shr Mataji aside: by the
way I found your letter]- the partnership
of husband and wife could be absolutely perfect.
Now with the children as I said –
Hello, by what train did you come?
Sahaja Yogi: The late one.
[Laughter]
Shri Mataji: Real late one this one was!
What about your food?
Sahaja Yogi: We both had some.
Shri Mataji: Really?
Where?
Sahaja Yogi: In Winchester.
Shri Mataji: You were telling something else.
Where?
I mean if you are telling the truth you’ll
tell the same thing.
Sahaja Yogi: We had some chicken from the
Fish & chip shop.
Shri Mataji: Alright.
There is some food if you want, please have.
Please let them have…..
We were just missing you all.
Yes, very good, very cool and nice (vibrations).
Good.
May God bless you.
So you go and have your food.
Now, why making it so light : for you to understand
that marriage is not a serious problem.
[laughter] As long as you have your ideal
with yourself and you don’t try to impose
that on your wife, or the wife does not try
to impose that on your husband.
Let the wife be a wife and husband be a husband.
But the wife should not become the husband
and the husband should not become wife.
If that happens, then I don’t know how to
correct it, because that’s something absurd
if that happens.
Now, on that the main thing one has to know
is that you are married to have children,
not to be Romeo and Juliet anymore.
You better have your children.
And then the children that will be born to
Sahaja Yogis are going to be realized souls,
tremendous source of energy.
That’s why you are married, that’s why
you are going to have children.
Then look after your children with respect,
regard.
Don’t spoil them!
And develop [them] in that love of Sahaja
Yoga.
Now this we started with our Hamsa Chakra.
Now see the Hamsa Chakra is the left and the
right.
The left is the woman, the right is the man.
They meet at Hamsa.
So this is the wedding place of your left
and right.
If there is no balance between the two, there
is a problem.
They have to be equal.
But they are not similar.
Left is left.
Right is right.
So the right must be on the right hand side,
left must be on the left hand side and here
when they come, they marry, and this is the
point one must know that, whatever is the
function of a wife is, she should do that
first whatever is the function of the husband
is, he should do that first.
And then the secondary functions of life can
be shared and understood.
But it’s not possible that the wife goes
to work and husband starts producing children.
You cannot do it!
[Laughter] And the other way round.
So whatever is the work is so important.
To be a mother, I think, is the most important.
Today if you didn’t have a mother, which
father would have done this work, you tell
Me.
Which one?
Can you think of anyone?
There may be ‘Father in Heaven’, but Father
on this Earth working with all Sahaja Yogis,
let Me see which one is there.
Anyone of these fathers, you call them.
Nicely to sit down on Heaven and watch the
whole stuff.
But who’s going to do the work?
Washing the dirty linen and washing all the
napkins and things is done by Mother.
She does this with love and attention and
with care, and She is the one who knows how
to grow Her children.
Is the job of a mother.
So Mother’s job Mother can do.
Father can sit in the Heaven very nicely.
All thanks goes to the Father.
While the Mother is doing a thankless job
here!
Alright, doesn’t matter.
It is so, so should be accepted, whatever
may be the situation, whatever may be the
position.
Now at Hamsa Chakra, this understanding must
come that you must balance both the nadis,
the left and the right.
Now to balance the left and the right, the
best way is to do some breathing, is to take
the air through one nostril and keep it waiting
here for a while and then allow it to go out
of the other.
Then you breathe in with this one, allow it
to stay here for a while and then allow it
to go down.
But it is to be done very slowly.
Not in a hurry, not too much.
Only thrice (3 times).
Best thing that I’ve told you is neti.
If not that, another thing I have seen that
those inhalers, you see that you get, are
very good.
The neti thing that I’ve given you.
If you fill the water below the spout and
fill it, put in some two, three drops of one
of those things that you get for inhaling
and put that neti thing in one nose only,
and with another nose it goes up.
Then you come, bring it here, it goes up and
clears it out.
It’s a very good thing.
If you do it every night before sleeping,
in three, four days you’ll be absolutely
cleared out.
But the main thing is: it comes because of
imbalances in our temperaments.
Like a man is a man, woman is a woman, alright,
so the woman starts dominating a man or a
man starts dominating the woman.
The balance is broken.
Once you understand the woman is very important
– without the woman you cannot, could not
have been here.
Alright?
Without a woman you cannot be here.
Man is very important that woman has no meaning
without a man.
You see, Shakti has no meaning without God.
For whom is She working?
For whom is She doing all this?
For God to be pleased.
If there’s nobody to see the job, why should
She do it?
So both have great meaning.
And if you understand that both beings within
us are balanced, understood, respected in
their proper ways and shared and coordinated,
the personalities in proper understanding,
respect and love, your Hamsa will be alright.
You’ll feel better.
So you have to correct your ideas about marriage,
about women, about men, about yourself.
That’s very important because it is a very
big emotional thing and, as the left side
is weak, all people who have left side weak
get cold.
And all the things that has to do with your
– they call it bulgam, is it?
What’s it called?
Sahaja Yogis: Plegm.
Shri Mataji: Phlegm.
Phlegm.
It has to do with your phlegm.
So emotional side is to be properly nourished
and looked after and one has to know that
your dignity is the most important.
Anything indignified is not love.
Love is very dignified.
And if you keep your dignity, you’ll be
amazed how you will be able to solve certain
problems.
Now, again I’ll ask you a question.
Now, how many have answered the questions?
Most of them you answered very well.
Now one more question I will ask.
Very simple, not so difficult.
That: what is a difference between a baddha
and a bhoot?
How will you make out?
A hindrance and a bhoot.
Sahaja Yogi: Bhoots will move around.
Shri Mataji: And baddha?
Sahaja Yogi: Stays there.
Just describing, it’s a block at that point.
Shri Mataji: Though it’s correct, [what]
you said is correct, but it is not absolutely
precise.
It is like this, I tell you.
It’s correct.
I mean what he says is the correct answer
but it’s not so precise.
Baddha will also move.
I’ll tell you how.
Baddha is always on the centres or on your
organs, say.
If it is, say, in your, for example in the
liver, this baddha may come in the centre
and then it will start moving from your here
to here as the Kundalini will move.
Alright?
But baddha doesn’t have its arbitrary movement.
As you move the Kundalini, the baddha moves.
‘Baddha’ means the hindrance.
Alright?
But a bhoot is arbitrary.
It moves.
It will be one moment here, it will be one
moment there.
It will move this side, it will move that
side.
It will go to the right heart, then it will
come to the left heart.
If it is arbitrary behaviour, that means it
is not controlled by your movement of your
fingers through the Kundalini awakening then
you must know it is a bhoot.
Alright?
Now understand what I’m saying by decisive
thing, that, one thing is arbitrary, works
on its own, and the another is in your control.
You’re taking it out yourself.
Like you can say that if there’s some lump
in the body, it may start moving with the,
say, bloodstream or something, some force
acting upon it.
But by itself, it does not.
But if there’s a worm, living worm, it will
move by itself.
So the last question is then, how do you manage
the baddha and the bhoot?
How will you take out the bhoot of other people
without getting yourself into it?
Otherwise the person whose bhoot has to be
taken out will put three bhoots in you and
five in the others.
(laughing) I have seen many a times they’ll
come and tell Me, “Mother, he’s possessed."
Alright.
And they themselves are! (laughter) How do
you take out?
Come along.
Sahaja Yogini: Bandhan
Shri Mataji: What?
Bandhan?
No!
Sahaja Yogi:You can throw the bhoot into a
candle.
Shri Mataji: I mean, I’m saying a real one.
He’s not even afraid of candle.
Sahaja Yogini 2: Say the mantra to Mukti Devi
Sahaja Yogini 3: The Lord’s Prayer
Shri Mataji: There’s no general thing about
it.
Alright?
All answers are correct but they are not complete.
There are ways and method according to different
bhoots…(asid in Marathi with yogini)…
They are trying to solve the problems but
[she] said it’s rather difficult!
Now, first of all, you see a person who is
possessed.
I mean you are sure he is possessed, so you
do like this, you see.
[Laughter].
Take a form, you have to take a form because
you have to fight it.
You take an aggressive form.
Sahaja Yogi: Karate, Tony’s Karate [Tony
Cooly].
Shri Mataji: Karate, yes.
Something like that.
So then, I mean inside you become higher than
that person.
Otherwise if you go like (laughter from yogis).
After some time (more laughter).
So you go with a great force on that person.
You put a bandhan and say, “Now sit down."
Talk to him like this.
You don’t go and say, “Please sit down,”
because the thing will come and sit in you.
Just say, “Now sit down."
Alright.
There you have to say as if you are not compromising
on this.
No compromises.
Then you ask the person various questions,
after giving yourself a bandhan and do that
to verify what sort of a bhoot it could be.
That’s the best.
First of all you ask that person, “Have
you been to any guru?”
So now you know at least sixteen of them.
And you know how to take them out, also.
So you find out which bhoot he has been to.
If it is a guru, you just ask the person does
he still believe in that guru.
If so, you have nothing to do with that person.
You have no business.
If you say “sorry” it will come inside.
Any inviting word you should not use.
Just say, “Alright, finished!” you get
out from that one.
But in case he says, “I am possessed.
I know I am in trouble, I’ve got this thing”
and all that, then you tell that person that
“What is the name of your guru?
What is the mantra you got?
How many years you have been?”
Like that, you ask the question.
If he is truthful and if he tells you that,
then you exactly know where the mantra is,
what has happened to him.
If it is a guru, then it has to be in the
Void.
If it is in the Void you tell him to say the
mantra of Adi Guru, or ask the question, “Mother,
are You the real…[guru]?” on the photograph.
Keep the photograph in front of your face
like a mask if possible.
Don’t allow you yourself to be exposed but
give the photograph to the man.
You say, “Now ask the question to this photograph."
Now if the person asks the question, the Kundalini
will start coming here doing “gragaral gagal."
He’ll also see the thing there, you see,
bubbling up.
Then you should say that, after asking the
question, “Now you say that, ‘You are
the guru’!”
If the person is possessed by a guru, then
if you know the name of the guru, then you
know the mantra.
When he’s doing all these things, you go
on saying “Narakasura Mardini” or “Mahishasura
Mardini” or anything like that, whatever
you have to do.
Or “Sarva-asura Mardini” For guru this
thing, best thing is salt, vibrated salt.
You give some vibrated salt with water to
that person to drink.
It’s not easy to get rid of the guru, so
you tell him very firmly that he’s one of
the horrible ones we have ever known, so you
have to work very hard to get rid of it.
You give him salt, give him all that, let
him do it.
And do not hurry up.
Tell him it is going to take time, it will
be alright, and what troubles people had with
this, and [that] he’ll have to work hard.
This is one type of bhoots you will find.
Then you find these are guru bhoots and which
takes time, which are very difficult and they
can take you up, it can be very dangerous.
But say, somebody becomes blind with a bhoot.
His eyes are open and he’s blind.
That’s sure shot [that] he is blind because
of a bhoot.
Two types of blindness are possible.
The Left Swadhishthana will be catching and
you will see it is due to bhoot.
But it can be also Left Swadhishthana catching
and becoming blind could be with diabetes.
Could be the combination of both.
So you ask him if he has diabetes or not.
If the person has no diabetes, then definitely
it is the bhoot.
Now what do you do to take out that kind of
a bhoot?
Sahaja Yogi: You use a candle enlightened.
Shri Mataji: Not only candle, won’t work.
You take My hand.
Photograph, only hand.
You have photographs of My hand, and put a
candle before that photograph.
All these photographs that you have separately
have meanings.
Put the candle and behind that is the hand
and ask the person to see the light, if he
can see the light.
Gradually, you’ll be amazed he will start
seeing.
This is to be used.
You see, in Sahaja Yoga, one has also to be
precise just like the English words [laws?].
If you are precise, it comes out.
If you are not precise then you try this,
you try that, it won’t work out.
But if you have a photograph of My hands you
should ask the person to see the photograph
of the hand.
By seeing the light, gradually the person
will start seeing the hand, and then gradually
the person will become alright.
I’ve seen one person getting the eyes within
ten minutes time.
But in that, if the Left Swadhishthana is
catching, if the person has no diabetes and
eyes are open, then it is definitely a bhoot,
nothing else.
Even if some people might say, “She lost
her eyes because of, this girl lost her eyes
because there was a fire in the house."
But she got frightened and the bhoots sat
in here and she became blind.
They are connected both things.
Actually eyes cannot remain open if the eyes
are burned out.
So if the eyes are open and absolutely normal
to look at and the person cannot see, the
light is out, that means there’s a bhoot.
So these things can be very easily done.
Sahaja Yogini [in Hindi]: How do you do it?
Shri Mataji: Photograph like this, and the
light in front.
It will improve your eyesight also.
My hands should be used, very good for the
eyes.
My hands are extremely good for your eyes.
If you can see My hands with the light, very
good for your eyes.
Now what are good My feet for?
Sahaja Yogi: Agnya.
Shri Mataji: Very good for ego.
And also superego.
Is very good for people who suffer from ego
or superego, My feet.
Because, such people are very gross.
And the feet solve the problem.
So just use My feet.
If they see My Face, the ego will start working,
“This face is like that, it should be like
that – this, that."
Superego might give problems.
Even supraconscious will give you problems.
But feet, even if you are supraconscious,
they’ll correct your problems.
Feet are not only powerful but they go up
to the grossest point where you are.
[...] some sort of a man, you just
use My Feet, he’ll be alright.
Face won’t work for him.
Face is for the seekers.
But for all such people who are absolutely
incorrigible type, feet is the best.
Those who have extreme ego, those who have
extreme superego – extreme.
Feet are very important.
You also sometimes watch My feet.
That’s a very good way, exercise.
Just watch My Feet to get rid of your grossness.
Just watch with your eyes.
How are you going to watch through your Sahastrara?
(laughter) But also with Sahastrara you can
see.
Sahaja Yogi: Mother, do You think if we used
Your feet in the photo in the newspaper advertising
we’d get more people?
Shri Mataji: Will be better idea.
Sahaja Yogi: We’ll try that.
Shri Mataji: But you see I don’t know.
(laughter) Try.
Very good idea.
You see on My books and all that we have tried.
On so many things I have tried, put My feet.
Indians understand it.
Sahaja Yogi: Do you think they’d understand
in the US?
Sahaja Yogi: Well, you don’t have to say
Your name in the same thing.
Shri Mataji: Let’s put My feet.
Sahaja Yogi: Will just let it work through.
We’ll put Sahaja Yoga, we won’t say anything
about Whose feet they are.
Shri Mataji: Try.
It is very good.
They’re tremendous.
See all the lights reacting.
[Shri Mataji speaks in Hindi.]
You see?
[Some yogis start rubbing Shri Mataji’s
feet.]
Putting on the feet.
Come bring it here.
I would like to give him there, alright, give
him there so he can do it better.
[Shri Mataji speaks in Hindi.]
Mmm.
See the face.
Now give chance to others also.
May God bless you.
Come along.