I
bow to all the seekers of truth.
The other day I talked to you about the experience
of truth.
That the truth has to be felt through your
central nervous system.
If anything has to happen to your evolution
you have to feel it through your central nervous
system otherwise it is just a projection of
your mind which forms it and you are surprised
at yourself.
Like we call somebody as a friend and one
day we find there is no friendship.
Maybe one day the friend will try to murder
you or you may try to murder that person.
You just don't understand what happened to
that love.
Same thing about all our projections, we find
it has no basis, it's so superficial.
When we realise that all is so superficial,
it has no basis, we just get frustrated and
we start thinking, what is all this, we are
playing games.
One can't be sincere.
What has happened to us?
Why are we so frivolous?
Why are we so superficial?
We may start taking interest in things which
look superficially very great, but ultimately
we find that it doesn't have any depth in
it and suddenly to our horror we discover
that everything seems to be relative in this
world, nothing is absolute.
So the experience of the truth has to be absolute.
Means everybody should feel that way, if not
then it is something poetical because each
poet sees the reality in a different way,
describes in a different way.
But if he is a truthful poet he keeps the
essence at least the same.
But when we say we have to feel the truth,
by everyone in an absolute manner, what does
that mean?
That means when we get our self realisation,
when we think we have got a new awareness
of collective consciousness, that means we
are unconnected with the whole, with the absolute,
then everyone of us who is like that should
feel the same way.
For example there's a person who is sick and
you get ten children who are realised souls,
that means we say are realised souls, now
tie their eyes so that they cannot see at
all and ask them what centres are catching
in this person.
All of them will raise the same finger.
This is the finger that is catching.
And if you ask that person relative to that
finger, have you got this trouble, he'll say
yes, but how do you know?
How do these children know?
So the truth is felt by everyone the same.
Then it is absolute.
If somebody sees a blue colour, if somebody
sees a red colour then it is not the truth.
And you'll be amazed when you become self
realised, if you meet people who are self
realised, you'll be amazed they will say the
same thing in a different way in a different
, but they say the same.
It is very amazing that people who were in
India, who were in Lebanon, who were in China,
who were in England had nothing to do with
each other, had no communication what so ever
and they say the same thing.
So down within us there is something that
is absolute that tells us about absolute.
So the second experience should be of absoluteness.
The Divine power that is all pervading, if
it is truthful, if it is real, then all of
us who are feeling that power through this
realisation should receive the same message
as
this is the second proof of and you put this
test to anyone who says that this is self
realisation.
This is a very, very important thing for you
to understand that truth has to be one, it
has to be absolute and if you can establish
your report with the absolute you cannot have
any other information but the truth.
So as you ascend in Sahaja Yoga you start
learning that what ever messages you are getting
is the truth, that all these messages that
you are receiving you can your self perceive
them, can feel them, nobody has to tell you.
Even a child can sense it.
So you move one step forward into a world
call faith, which is the faith of experience.
You call say this now, how do you know it
is not artificial?
It is real because you have experience of
the artificial; and the real and now when
you feel it you can say with faith "yes it
is real".
In the same way reality can only be accepted
if you go through the experience of truth
and then have faith.
Human mind is a very wonderful mind.
English word mind doesn't explain much though
what mind is but in Sahaja Yoga it has been
very clearly explained what human mind creates.
Here you see very clearly that on top of the
head there, you see a lotus.
You can say how can there be a lotus on top
of the head Mother, this sounds very poetic
and something fantastic and even fantasy of
course I wish everybody had that lotus blooming.
But very few have it but still they have no
doubt.
Now this one, when you see the lotus, before
that if you see the brain in Sahaja Yoga is
just shown as a hollow thing.
There's nothing like brain tissue and all
that.
But there are two, one is blue the other is
yellow [somebody show John, somebody], two
balloon like structures in the brain.
Now when the first balloon only existed, when
we were just animals our brain was flat, so
was the Himalayas.
Himalayas represents our brain in the gross
life.
So the Himalaya was also flat and our brain
was also flat.
Then man started hitting with branches when
the animals attacked them, they (learned)
how to hit back and another line started which
we call as the sun line but we see another
side started developing and the brain got
transformed into a new formation of a triangular
thing.
This triangular brain, now is like a pyramid
I've seen and sometimes I find it swollen
very much more on one side ....
So all our problems started from that point
where we decided that we can do it.
We..............................
and then we started doing it that way.
This yellow stuff which we call as ego started
pushing the superego in such a manner that
the brain became a prism like structure.
But is was important this prism.
The Himalayas also developed a triangular
structure.
It was very important that it should have
happened in the human brain,
that we had developed this ego within ourselves.
We could have avoided it if we had not committed
the mistake at the stage of Adam and Eve,
but we did commit,
and that short circuit got elongated and our
evolution started going on a different line
where we wanted to find out ourselves what
is the truth.
So a journey started and started moving so
fast that they remain in the state of a balloon
, nothing else but a balloon exists.
So we became nothing but balloons floating
superficially.
The balance was lost completely and the whole
problem has started with this balloon, that
we have put in the effort, we can find , we
can discover this.
Like one scientist was forced by a King
that he should try to create gold out of perfume,
poor fellow he tried his level best he could
not, but as a result he found out how to make
beautiful china.
That's exactly what has happened to human
beings, in the search of truth we have discovered
everything else but the truth.
Because truth you cannot discover, as I told
you the other day it is a state that one has
to achieve, one has to achieve to receive
the truth, to know the truth
So some people felt that truth is what we
have found, like blind people, what ever they
have found out they called it as truth.
Even in India, where people have a great sense
of meditation, people committed mistakes and
what they found is the movement on the right
hand side and they said yes, there is all
pervading power and that is formless.
The left hand people found while praying to
God that there are forms so they talked of
the forms.
Some talked of the formless and some talked
of the form.
The right sided people being the worshippers
of the Goddess of learning wrote down everything
as Vedas [most ancient Hindu scriptures] but
in the very beginning of Vedas, Vedas means
to know, and to know means to evolve to become
self realised.
It is not when I talk to you what you know,
is not, the knowledge is which is expressed,
manifested on your central nervous system.
The truth.
So they wrote down what they found, that we
have to first excite or initiate the nature.
So they wrote all those things, now that has
become an authentic writing, big for intellectuals,
that to after many, many years
people they knew it by heart.
Authentically you might say that Vedas came
only about 800 or something like that, all
that writing, if you go by that you'll be
lost into another wild goose chase and those
who read only Vedas can never find that what
is supposed to be known.
In the first chapter or the first verse of
the Vedas that by reading this book if you
do not get the knowledge no good reading Vedas.
But there are books & books & books, libraries
& libraries & libraries, all the wild goose
chase.
Many of the systems follow, was the system
of fearing the God, then finding out the forms
of God, worshipping God as form.
The incarnations came on this earth and people
worshipped them, like Christ.
Now there is a challenge on Christ, these
intellectuals will challenge everything because
they challenge everything through the intellect.
The trouble is that they think they are the
wisest.
Such wise people they have time for, is impossible.
You have to be a little humble.
So the intellectual as usual challenge and
the others who just believe without intellectuals
were the people who just believed into things
without knowing.
Who had just faith, as our emotional songs
are, are.
All these extreme movements on both the sides
created two different types of people, one
who we can call as intellectuals and another
as
They did not create self realised people because
ego makes a person so superficial and so stupid
that he cannot grasp, it's beyond him.
He is so stupid.
He cannot grasp the truth.
Is a barrier, is a projection outside, he
is a concave personality, is a convex personality.
Brain is convex.
And the other one is so concave, is so conditioned
that you cannot compete.
That's how the quality of seekers came on
this earth, who are seeking truth.
Now we should also know that God must be worried
about his creation, he must be worried about
the people who are crated by him, who became
human beings, who are seekers, special category.
What hypocrites, you cannot tell people, you
cannot help them but those who are real seekers.
There are many real seekers and he must be
worried about all these seekers and he must
have arranged something for them and that
is how Christ came on this earth . He came
on this earth to guide and tell us that you
can find the truth by your second birth.
You are to be born again.
You are to be born again, then there are people
who just believe that I am born again, you
see self opinionated, I'm alright!
I've found it!
Stupid people, they just believe, certify
themselves they have found it.
They just give themselves a certificate, oh
I've found it, but who is the loser?
It's not God.
He can reveal himself to you if you want to
know him, through your evolution, through
your effortlessness.
But as you have seen Patanjali for the real
seekers but people took out of Patanjali also
what they tell them is the physical exercise,
I mean just imagine, it is like a person who
has been invited to dinner to do dish-washing,
it's that stupid.
And that book, even today thank God, despite
all the intellectuals attacks and all nonsense,
he just talked of the formless not of the
form so much but he does say that you have
to neutralise your effort too, you have to
neutralise your thought which are and in the
absence of that thought only the Kundalini
will rise.
Now a vicious circle is created, even when
we say we fight with that thought
a thought in the mind
so something has to happen
and that is what happens
but is all done by God Almighty within us,
that he has made these beautiful chakras.
They are made from different elements, the
essence of different elements and all incarnations
of our ascent are placed there to guide those
subtle centres.
Is already within us, we may not know about
it but they exist within us and ultimately
the residual, they call it, the residual power,
that is Kundalini; it is residual because
it has created everything but has not manifested
itself, is the pure desire to know the truth,
pure desire to know the Divine, to become
the Divine, is still sleeping.
When these chakras are in proper shape it
spontaneously rises just like a seed sprouts,
you don't have to do anything to reduce your
efforts and your thoughts.
Your thoughts are created and they disappear
again they come up and disappear, there's
a little gap in between and that gap widens
by the ascent of Kundalini and you become
thoughtless without any effort.
With effort you cannot, that's the point.
This mechanism exists within us.
Now if something happens here say for example
this is working out, then we go into the mechanism
of this and try to find out how this is working
out.
Now if you want to see, you can see the rising
of the Kundalini, you can see the breaking
of the Kundalini, you can feel the cool breeze
coming out of you.
Now how it happens
it is the cool breeze that emits on top of
your head, is the first sign that your Kundalini
awakened and then when you start feeling it
all around now you are in connection with
the all pervading power.
Before that we are denying the truth.
It's all done by God, by his grace, he's made
it all so beautiful, so very, very beautiful,
we don't do a thing, we don't have to do a
thing, but that is the point, we cannot do,
that we don't have to do anything about it.
Always they ask me, then what must we do,
I said you don't do anything, that's the point.
Is it too much to accept?
But how do we become human beings from monkeys
do we
for anything . How does a seed sprout?
By itself spontaneously.
In the same way your evolution has to take
place spontaneously.
And every time somebody has to lead, somebody
has to go forward, somebody has to be bold,
somebody has to conquer.
Maybe somebody else would have been better
for this job, as I said, I would be very happy
to retire but that's what it is, it's true.
I have to do this job, it is a thankless job
no doubt but I have to do it, so what can
I do about it?
That should not upset you.
That upsets people but I don't do anything
actually, it is a myth like the sun shines,
it doesn't do anything does it?
But when the sun shines the leaves become
green, just happens, I mean the sun doesn't
take any credit or doesn't say that the trees
must offer God their goodness or something
to him.
They are not angry with the sun are you?
Because it tans our body.
Do you?
In the same way it's somebody's nature to
do that, and somebody's nature is to ascend
and to rise
people who achieve it, don't you think so?
So there is nothing to feel unhappy about.
This is another problem which I told you last
time, that in the west it is a really big
hurdle for people.
You cannot pay for it, you cannot put in any
effort, you cannot do anything about it, it
has to work out otherwise we cannot guarantee
that.
If it is there it will work out, if it is
not there it will not work out.
If the desire is pure it will work out and
then you have to work it out to keep it there.
So by reading about it you may never understand,
there are so many people who did
so many people who did Gita , so many people
in India who know by heart the whole of Gita,
the meaning, everything but they have sickness,
they've ill feelings, they're unhappy or ego
oriented, something wrong, somewhere.
Nothing wrong with the scriptures, we have
forgotten it is said you are to be born again.
So the third experience should be of transformation.
If it cannot bring out the virtue in you,
if it cannot give you the strength of your
spirit, if it cannot transform you then it
is not self realisation.
But transformation can be taken like this
that people can just change the colour of
their clothes and say we are transformed,
now we have taken a sanyasa, also can be like
that, all such self opinionated people.
It's not that, it's no opinion, is to be in
that state is important, to be in that state
that's the truth and that's the truth you
should ask for, nothing else.
Are you transformed by it and the first transformation
you feel, before you change your temperament,
before you change your habit, before you take
anything is that your central nervous system
acquires a new dimension of collective consciousness.
Acquires!
You get it.
And you can verify it.
But human beings still think they have a right
to no Mother no much, I don't believe in it.
It's alright, who are you, I mean don't believe
in yourself.
So the first thing that should happen in this
experience of transformation or evolution
is that you become, again I say become, become,
become collectively conscious, by which you
know your chakras and you know the chakras
of others, you know the subtle problems you
have, the subtle diseases you have, the hidden
problems you have.
The whole life which was abnormal comes to
normal you see because you can see abnormal.
Supposing I am standing on the edge of this
and there is no light, I cannot see, I may
fall down.
I am about to fall down I cannot see but then
is light, I see.
So why not get into balance.
That is enlightenment.
If enlightenment doesn't give you the vision
of wisdom it is not enlightenment at all.
You drink, you smoke, you see all kinds of
things, you have temper everything exists
and you say oh God I am a very religious person
and the second thing that comes to you is
some sort of . So your virtue, your virtue
must shine and that's the time is today according
to the Shalivan calendar this is the true
faith.
This is the yuga when there is, is the age
when there is perfection means where you get
in contact, actual, with actuality.
That means you actualise it and that is the
time, today, that has come called as Krita
yuga.
That means all pervading power is actualised
and we feel the manifestation of that power
very, very clearly, on your central nervous
system.
Because what ever is evolved within you, you
feel on your central nervous system.
So this new breakthrough is to be seen through
and not to be just accepted, not to have blind
faith, nothing of that kind.
Then once you come to a certain state then
the subject gets deeper and deeper and much
more intense, but first that state has to
be established.
Many people have complained to me that Mother
Sahaja Yogis who are are rather secretive,
there are no secrets, no secrets but as a
boy enters say maybe the first class or the
first he cannot understand what areas to be
discussed.
So he might feel this fellow is trying to
hide something in his books.
One has to grow to bear that truth also to
bear that truth he has to develop that power
within ourselves and that state we have to
achieve.
I requested last time all the people of England
especially, because in the map of the Divine,
England represents the heart and the responsibility
of heart is the maximum and if they don't
pay attention to their heart the world will
have a heart attack.
So how important it is that we should seek
our ascent as seekers.
Of course I don't say, you don't do this,
you don't do that, nothing of the kind, that
is not to be said anymore.
Just first get your realisation then you look
after your self I don't have to tell you.
Then you get your light you yourself will
see that you will not put your hand into the
crocodiles mouth there, are you?
But first you must see the crocodile, because
if I tell you the crocodile in the darkness,
you say let me try even if you, that's how
it works.
It's so beautiful.
There's a very beautiful thing to achieve
that's what we say is the Kingdom of God,
that's what we say that
is
that resides within us, that joy, that fills
the whole world as bliss, with complete auspiciousness
of God's being can be ours if
we decide to be there, if we want we can go
through, no one, it is
you
who
has
to choose it
in your own freedom only you can achieve your
complete freedom.
May
God Bless You.