There are in these modern times, many seekers
of truth. It's a special category of people
born in these modern times. Perhaps we are
not aware that in every country, a lot of
people are born with this seeking. They are
a special category which, sees beyond, tries
to find something beyond, what they can perceive
through their sense organs. The truth as we
see, is through our sense organs. For example
something we see as white, we call it white,
something we feel cool, we call it cold, something
as hot, means whatever we perceive through
our sense organs and whatever is communicated
to us through our central nervous system we
accept as truth, and we should accept that
only, as truth. And not something that is
told to us, not something that we have read
in the books, not something that we can project
our mind to, and then .......................that
does not mean that I deny any one of the scriptures.
That does not mean that I deny anything that
we have known so far. But to begin with let
us start from scratch as they call it or a
clean slate. Let us see what is the truth.
Now in every religion truth has been described.
As I can see it, everybody does not see it
themselves.....................That's why
there's blindness, that's why there are these
blind alleys where you end up, arguing things.
So there must be something that is missing
within us, that we have not been able to really
relate truth to our central nervous system.
And what is that missing within us, we should
find out. In all humility we should know that
there must be something within us, that we
have been arguing about so many things, we
have been talking about so many things, reading
so many books, going into all kinds of funny
experiences, right from alcohol to other drugs
and Gurus and this and that, but still we
have not felt anything on our central nervous
system.
Secondly that we have no control over that
truth. So, so what is the reason? Is it there
is something missing in the human awareness?
Is it that we are lacking something in our
human awareness? All the books, all the scriptures,
which are true scriptures have said one thing,
that to know the truth, you are to be born
again. That's not only in the bible. You see
if you take Patanjali which is a very ancient
book, it's not that the Patanjali asked you
to stand on your heads, is wrong, it's just
a wee, wee, wee, wee bit of it. But what Patanjali
has written is that you have to achieve the
truth on your central nervous system through
your ATMASAKSHAT, the word is written, meaning
the experience of your SPIRIT.
Now English language has an advantage and
a disadvantage, that the spirit could be alcohol,
the spirit could be an alcohol! Or spirit
could be a dead body, it could be any circumstance,
but it is not so. There are three separate
things, absolutely opposite to each other.
So the ATMA the SPIRIT has to be found out,
is said even by Mohammed Sahib, he said you
are to become the PIR, is said by. Zoroaster,
is said by Loa Tse, is also said by Zen. Buddha
has said it, Mahavira has said it, everyone
of them has said it, so many religions have
started in the name of God without going to
the truth, that you have to be born again.
Now you have to be born again does mean that
you certify yourself 'I am born again'. Self
certificate, you can call it 'I am born again',
but you don't become. What is so special if
you are born again, what should be so? The
human awareness at this level is just ready
to be born again. Now in Sanskrit the word
for a bird is DWIJAHA, means born again, and
also for a Brahmin who is born again. But
those who call themselves Brahmins are not
Brahmins. They just call themselves Brahmins,
have they come to know the Brahma, the all
pervading power of God. Those who say they
are born again, should feel the all pervading
power of God around them, if they cannot feel
it they are not born again. So all these self
certificates are deception, self deception
and deception of others, is just a money making
process.
So the truth has to be achieved through your
evolutionary process which is a living process.
Again we must understand a LIVING process.
Not you just talking, mental projections,
just sitting down here big talk about it,
or by giving you some courses, or taking some
money from you. You cannot get it, it's a
STATE in a living growth, that proves that
it is a living thing. Means the state of our
awareness has to be higher than what it is.
If our state cannot rise then it is not of
any use. Like the seed becomes the roots then
the bark, the leaves, the flowers then the
fruit. Different states. In the same way a
living religion must give you a different
state and that nucleus of religion is within
ourselves. Everyone of us has it. When we
go against that living religion within us
we go into imbalances. But even today people
can ask why the religion, why should we have
a balance, what is the need, lets go into
imbalances, I mean, is that a logical question.
People can ask why the religion, why has the
religion in the stomach..........................so
what is the religion we come to that point,
is that, a religion is a valency of human
beings.
Just like carbon has four valences human beings
have ten valences, which matter does not have.
Animals have nine and human beings have ten
valences. And when these ten valences go out
of balance then, they go out of the quality
of a human being. But still one can ask why
do we have those ten valences. Because we
have to ascend, because in the evolutionary
process you have to ascend and you can never
be satisfied with yourself unless and until
you have achieved it. Especially the seekers,
that's why I say they are the special category
because in this special category men of God
will have to become prophets and they will
have powers to make others prophets, said
by William Blake. In your great country William
Blake has said it.
When is that going to happen? It has to happen
today, tonight. But there are barriers within
us, built in, not because of anything else
but only because we have misled ourselves.
We have been going to various roads of seeking,
whatever suited us, where ever we went to,
we have tried to...............and we have
insured ourselves within ourselves sometimes,
we have built up certain barriers. Now when
you become the prophet, actually become your
own master, become a free person, you have
to be a free person. So far you are not. You
cannot overcome your own weaknesses, your
own temptations, infatuations, emotional problems,
mental worries -- why? Because you are still
standing in the waves of this turmoil. This
troubled area where you just see the waves
all the time and you are frightened of breaking
down, but if you somehow or other get out
of it and get into the boat of your own being,
then you enjoy, you become a witness a Sakshi.
Even to understand the scriptures, you have
to become a free person, which you are not.
You have to be your own master, for that you
cannot pay. I am too free, that I cannot accept
it. To get your freedom of Spirit you can't
pay, because money is money. Money has no
value in the Divine field. Nothing can bring
forth this but your own ascent. And how do
we ascend? Is there anything built within
us? So what ever I am telling you today is
the knowledge of the roots. What we see is
the knowledge of the tree. We see it from
outside, we see a leaf from out side, if we
have to treat the leaf, we have to go to the
roots. But from outside, when we see the tree
we are still outside also. When you have to
treat the leaf, you have to go to the roots,
if you block out the leaf, it is dead. Then
you put it under the microscope, you can go
on seeing cells after that you can see the
nucleus, you can go on analysing it, and analysing
it making it dead, and dead and dead. But
to treat it you have to go to the roots. And
this knowledge of roots we have here.
There's nothing wrong in knowing something
new. These are not new ideas, these are ancient
ideas, very ancient ideas. In the Bible it
is described as the Holy Ghost. One priest
was asked I saw ......................a very
narrow minded priest, what do you know about
Holy Ghost? He said "I am agnostic". So then
they said, what are you doing here? He said
"I am doing my job". If that is the attitude
towards God, towards your inner knowledge,
then you can never reach there as you cannot
reach the tree through the leaf, you have
to go to the roots. This has been available
only to seers, like you can say William Blake.
Like we had many in other countries, but they
did not talk about it because perhaps that
was not the time for people to know. But in
many languages it is described.
Now the roots within us, if you can see this,
are placed in this manner. When I went to
America the Indian society invited me to talk
to them about the unconscious. I had never
read Jung, though I knew he was a realised
soul at least he got his realization at the
later time. So I said all right let me have
a look, let me see .............theory, say,
and as I opened the book I saw a diagram,
what he had drawn of a human being and I said
that's the mistake. Because he saw human beings
from outside and he described them in layers,
like first he said is the unconscious that
cannot be expressed, manifested then the unconscious
that can be manifested, then he said about
at least the sub-conscious and then he said
above that is the conscious mind, then above
that is the ego. Like layers, one after another.
Now when you are sitting here, though you
are in layers the path is laid down. In the
same way within us, God being the greatest
organiser, he has not made us into layers
but what he has made us in a parallel way,
as you can see there very clearly. Left side
and right side. Left side and right side,
the central path, three paths he has made
within us, for our evolutionary process. The
central path works out our evolution. The
left side gives us the desire and the right
side gives us the power of action. These are
just the principles I am telling you but you
can understand it slowly when you grow, all
the details of it.
The central path is evolution, has brought
you today to this level of human awareness.
Now beyond that is a very short ascent which
you have to achieve; by which you become the
Spirit. But there has to be some living process
for this to happen. And what is that living
process built within us, is the reflection
of the Holy Ghost within us in the triangular
bone, which is called as Kundalini in Sanskrit
language. This exists within us, and you can
see with your naked eyes, sometimes, in some
people where there is an obstruction in the
higher centres, it starts pulsating. And when
we can sense, we can also see it clearly in
some people when it is obstructing. Or through
your stethoscope you can feel the percussion
which we call as anahat at the top of the
head here, where it pulsates and then it breaks.
When this breaks the pulsation stops and you
start feeling the cool breeze of the Holy
Ghost coming out of your fontanel bone area.
This is a happening and not ..............................in
the sense that the happening takes place so
that you get connected with the truth.
So the connection takes place and you start
feeling on your finger tips the cool breeze
of the Holy Ghost which surrounds you. Actually,
you start feeling. But then as the rational
mind says so what! Though we feel the cool
breeze, so what? Then one should know, that
when we have eyes we start seeing, when we
have ears we start hearing, so now you have
got a new awareness, what is this awareness?
This is the awareness of collective consciousness,
that you become, again I say you become, you
are not just certified but you become, it's
a question of becoming, that you become collectively
conscious. That on your central nervous system
you can feel another person, you can feel
yourself, you can feel your centres which
are shown here, you can feel the centres of
others on your fingertips. And the best one
is, is Mohammed Sahib, I would say because
he made it clear, at the time of resurrection
your hands will speak. But who talks about
the resurrection? Nowhere! People talk about
it, they talk about the doomsday, because
they can frighten people of the doomsday first,
and take advantage of it and make money out
of it.
God who has made this universe, he feels love,
do you think he will destroy this great creation
of his without giving us the fruit, without
letting us know the fruit of his creation.
He is the wisest of wise. The greatest compassionate
source of love, how could he allow this universe
to be destroyed, especially this Earth, which
is a special present from him. So don't believe
in all these stupid ideas of destruction and
the last complete devastation. Still lot of
plans, you are suppose to enjoy the blessings
of the Divine for which he has created you.
So the experience of truth has to be felt
on the central nervous system. The problem
is, not that you belong, you may feel, but
as you know the experience is very slow in
the western countries. I am sorry, not that
you are in any way less seekers, you are very
great seekers, I would say you are greater
seekers than the Indians are, much greater
seekers. Indians have still a lot of steps
to come up to your level, no doubt, but while
coming up to this level, you have developed
a lot of problems around and that's why the
seeking is sometimes, takes time to express
itself as a fruitful gain of Self Realization.
So you'll get your self realization no doubt
but again the Kundalini goes down. I must
tell you very frankly, because I cannot be
dishonest, but it can be brought up, by you,
by understanding how to work it out. By co-operating
with your self, by understanding your self,
that you are the temple of God and that you
have to work it out with respect to yourself,
and you have to give some time. I mean in
Caxton Hall, you must have seen there, thousands
of people have got it. I have been working
in this England for twelve years now, twelve
years, is the last year now. Special reason
for that, but what I find, people get their
realization and then they're lost. Then when
they have some disease or something, they'll
telephone to me Mother, now I am.............
has happened or I am suffering from cancer...........................is
too far gone a case, but if you know how to
handle your roots, how to nourish it, how
to look after it, then you flower out, you
bear fruits, and by your fruits people know
what it is. Then you become trees, giant trees,
like moving trees. And when people come under
such trees, get realization.
English are a great people no doubt, they
are placed in a country which is the heart
of the universe, you are very important. I
have given the maximum time to England, you'll
be amazed, maximum time. But the Sahaja Yogis
who are not in the country have grown much
faster than in England. The reason is, it's
like the foundation that always gets (damp
in it) you are the ..................................................foundation.
Remove the darkness, again it gets dark. Rather
difficult! But once they are settled, you
will be circulating the Divine interpretation,
the Divine experience of truth all over the
world. You are like the hard-core and this
is what you have to do. We cannot be mediocre
in Sahaja Yoga. There is no compromise with
your self, you become so powerful that you
don't compromise also, you can just get out
of everything in no time. But you must accept
yourself first of all, have faith in yourself.
Once upon a time the English had too much
faith in themselves, I mean extraordinarily
powerful people, now they are the other way
around, they have no faith. You see now this
darkness has come and ....the darkness has
come ...................thrown out.
This is the second phase that I find is complete
lethargy. Oh what can happen, let us be destroyed
Mother, now that's the best part, completely
reconciled to our doom. Now how to get them
to be creative? We have to circulate. They
are the cells, who are like in the heart,
who have to pump the heart...............................
So I have to make a humble request, that I
know experience of Sahaja Yoga is slow but
very steady and I am sure that today I have
got people who are a rare quality of courage.
And as individual which was the English character,
once upon a time, and that they will take
it up seriously, their ascent and the ascent
of the whole world.
We'll be having about three more lectures
and there I will tell you more elaborately
about Kundalini and the Chakras, about all
this knowledge. All this knowledge is available
to you. Now, because this time was for you
to know all these secrets. Some newspaper
people asked me, Mother have you got your
disciples all very big scholars, I said no,
they are very ordinary people. Some may be,
they are more difficult, but mostly they are
very normal, ordinary people. Simple people.
But what makes you think that? They said they
are so scholarly they know so much, because
you become the knowledge.
So truth is the knowledge, the rest of it
is all mythical. Is mythical, what do we know
about things is all mythical, because what
ever we see from outside, is outside. Like
I would say we appreciate Mona Lisa, we appreciate
the miracles as we say, the great miracles
that human beings have created. Why? Why do
we call them miracles? Sometimes we think
that we have observed a very miraculous task,
they are, mentally we think. But actually
it is not so. Because they have vibrations,
they have Divine vibrations, they emit vibrations
and they appeal to you because in your heart
lies that Spirit, which is the universal being
and which gives that feeling of bewilderment
when you see these great miracles human beings
have created. At least I have seen six of
them, and all of them have tremendous vibrations.
But unless and until you become a realised
soul, how will you know? (silence)
Now this is the only .............. and to
become the realised soul you have to have
the ascent of the Kundalini and proper state
of that Kundalini to remain there and that's
the point where I found we lack in the efforts.
Lack in courage, in patience, so again and
again I request you that don't be superficial.
The Americans were superficial, you better
not be. You be solid people, serious, take
it up seriously. Because you are going to
be the Europeans, the Americans even the Greeks,
even the Italians, the problem is the horse
is behind the cart.........................but
what do I do, prove to the horse, that you
get up now because of you the cart is not
moving. That's why ...........very very special
..........to see you all, that you must decide
that if we get our Realization, we'll establish
ourselves into Sahaja Yoga. For which you
don't have to pay, there's no membership,
there's no organisation, nothing. I have nothing
to take from you. You can't give me.
So I hope today, many who are new will get
their Realization and establish themselves
and will not forget it. Because in the beginning
the experience is very great, you feel like
you are coming out of a pub. I don't know
what that experience is, must be that way
(laughter) because I've seen so many people
coming and falling down and again going in,
must be some memory of something great, must
be that. So by God's grace you should all
get your Realization and I would like to have
some questions, but in that I would like to
say that there are people I know, we have
had before also, belonging to some gurus or
something big, like some gurus have come too,
because you see they feel, the gurus are feeling
that I may been attacking them; in a way,
they feel that way because I say you cannot
pay, so their profession is finished. So they
get angry with me for that, so they might
be saying they are in .................and
attack her and all sorts of things and there
could be some people who are impressive because
of other problems of ego or something. So
you need not be offensive, I have come here
to give you what you have and you need not
be also docile about it or slavish. I have
come here to give you or tell you what is
free.
Now you may also say, it is a very common
question that arises in your mind, and justified,
that why should I do it, now that's the miserable
part of it, that I have to do it, I wish you
could do it, but you can't that's the problem.
And if I have to do it, I don't hurt your
ego. No! I don't want to hurt it. You see
this is something people don't understand,
that why should I do it. You can do it also,
but first I have to take you little bit............your
awareness has to grow a little more, then
you can do it your way, but first definitely,
I have to do that. Which is a .........it
makes me also a miserable person because............you
know...........a thankless job, but I have
to do it. Maybe I am doing it for it somehow,
I don't know...........but it should be............It's
a crucifixion, I tell you, it's not easy,
it's a very difficult task. It's like mountains
sometimes, the Kundalini is just embedded,
poor thing sometimes so hurt, so wounded that
to raise that Kundalini itself takes such
a load, effort. But one has to do it and I
know
I have to do it. When you will know
what
it is, you will not
be angry with me, but
you
will understand the task and .............all
of us, all
of
us
have to
do it.
May God Bless You.