(Shri Mataji asks the audience in Hindi
to ask Her questions.)
(A seeker asks a question.)
SHRI MATAJI: How one gets it, isn’t it?
All right, sit down.
That’s what I’ve been saying —
that it just works out.
It is a spontaneous happening.
Now, we’ll see one thing,
that how does a little seed
gets into a tree?
It’s a living process.
You’ll just say it just works out.
It is already there,
that’s why it is sahaja.
“Saha” means “with”, “ja” means “born”.
It is absolutely spontaneous.
I am an enlightened person, is a fact.
And when I touch you,
you get enlightenment yourself.
It’s a very, very simple thing.
All right?
Another question?
This was a nice one,
because we always say of “how”.
SEEKER: Enlightenment through
other methods,
with siddhis [supernatural powers].
SHRI MATAJI: Huh?
SEEKER: With siddhis,
that’s what they are called.
SHRI MATAJI: No, no, is wrong.
That is always been banned.
You see, in the olden days also
we had people who were misled.
That is the history.
There are some people…
now, for example, if we had Hitler,
that doesn’t mean he’s a praman
[right measure, authority].
If we had somebody like…
a satanic force like Ravan,
doesn’t mean that he was praman.
For us, pramani is whatever achieved
the maximum.
So the praman always remains the best.
You see, all such people
who say that it gives siddhis
are the people who are Tantrikas
[followers of the Tantra doctrine].
And they were all thrown out.
These are all known as kshudrata
[insignificance, meanness].
But some of the people
who have written books on these things
are not themselves realized,
have read this book, that book,
and then they have said
that their siddhis are also there.
Siddhis are nothing but you move on
to your supraconscious side.
And when you move on
to a supraconscious side,
a spirit comes into you.
And then what happens — you start
producing something from your hand…
We had one lady in our Sahaja Yoga,
she came to us,
and, you know, when I went to America,
she started showing
all kinds of chamatkaras [wonders].
She started telling people
that “Where is your money’s lost,
you can find there,” like that.
And she became very popular,
and she used to get one thousand people
everyday coming to her.
And ultimately she started telling them
even the number of the [UNCLEAR].
So the supraconscious things
can be like that.
ESP, you become
an extrasensory perceptive man,
and all that is nothing
but another spirit.
But human beings sit tight.
You’ll be surprised, from America
two great scientists came just to see Me.
For what?
They said, “You must teach us how to fly
in the air. We want to leave our body.”
I said, “Why? Are you not flying
already on our heads?
Now what do you want to do?”
They said, “Now we want to leave
our bodies and fly in the air.”
So I said, “But if I tell you
that this is done through the spirits,
will you do it?” —
“Yes, still we want to do it.”
I said, “Why?”
They said, “Because Russians are doing
the same, so we want to do.”
(Shri Mataji says a phrase in Marathi.)
Then I said…
and they would not, you see.
Then I asked them, “Who told you?”
So they said, “Patanjali.”
You know, Patanjali is a newspaper man.
And Patanjali… I said,
“Look at this fellow, he came for treatment
because he used to get this kind of a…
experience that used to leave his body,
and he came to Me for getting cured.”
And he is telling him, you go to Mataji
and She’ll make you that!
And these fools, you know,
they would not listen to Me!
So, the knowledge that we have…
we do not have a proper method
of discrimination.
We don’t know what is
absolute knowledge. This is wrong.
For that, you must have vibrations.
With vibrations. Now you can ask,
all those who are realized,
you can ask: “Is there God or not?”
See the answer you’ll get.
[UNCLEAR] means yes.
All answers come,
and you can record it on your hands.
Even to a small thing.
You must hear Pharkay,
today he was telling Me about this,
that when he… some gentleman
was somewhere,
and he said
that “You just find his vibrations.”
So he put his hands there,
and he said, “Let me see the vibrations” —
and nothing was coming,
and nothing you could feel,
and nothing of the chakras.
So he then said, “He cannot be there,
because I cannot feel anything.”
So, this man thought of him:
“Oh, yes, yes.
He must be on the aeroplane,
he is not there.”
To such an extent it goes!
In London, there’s one gentleman,
he said, “Mataji, can I feel
somebody’s vibrations?”
I said, “You can.” —
“Can I feel my father’s?”
I said, “Yes. All right,
you put your hands and ask a question.”
Immediately his Vishuddhi Chakra
started burning.
He said, “Mother, this is burning.”
I said, “You telephone to him just now.
Ask how he is.”
So his mother said, “He cannot talk
to you, his throat is very bad.”
And the father was very far away.
“He cannot talk to you,
his throat is very bad” —
Vishuddhi Chakra is catching.
All the information you get
on your hand, on your vibrations.
And then, when you’ll see these books,
you’ll be surprised
they’ll be burning your hands.
(Shri Mataji says a phrase in Hindi.)
You’ll be amazed that how you find out
who is a real guru and non-real guru.
It’s so correct with this!
We have got here a case of one lady.
She told Me that somebody
came to see her,
and, I mean, somebody
came to stay with her,
her own brother or someone very near.
And she started burning
all the time, this and that.
So she said,
“Do you go to Satya Sai Baba?”
He said, “No.”
She said, “No, but how can that be?
I am getting terrible burning,
as I get it from a disciple
of Satya Sai Baba.
You must have been somewhere.
You must have been.”
He said, “I’ve never been there.”
So she said, “Really?”
And she was searching him out,
and nothing was there.
So she opened his box, and in the box
there was a Satya Sai Baba’s photograph.
Our [UNCLEAR] is here, you can ask him.
His wife… his daughter-in-law
was a big problem in London.
And they didn’t know how to locate
why she was behaving like this
and she was giving them
burning like that.
They opened her purse one day,
and in the purse was that photograph.
The day they threw it away,
everything is all right.
Otherwise it was going to be a divorce,
for nothing at all — the poor lady
was vomiting, doing all kinds of things.
There are so many cases like that.
I mean, the proof is there.
(Shri Mataji says a few phrases
in Marathi.)
He called us to some place
where there was a centre
of Satya Sai Baba.
He said, “Mataji, You must save
those people.”
When I sat there,
so many children just fainted.
Then they told us that “These children
have been fainting like this.
You have to do something about it.
And so many children are lost.
They just go away.
God knows how they are lost.”
I told him, “Baba, his centre,
let him look after now. I am fed up.”
What am I to do now?
I must first of all create some doctors,
some realized souls.
When I have some more people
to work it out, we can work it out.
But one thing is there:
after getting Realization you must come,
and learn it, and master everything.
You become… I tell you,
each and everything of Kundalini,
you can just master it.
It’s very easy.
It is so easy and it helps you.
You know this is the power of love;
you must know how it is worked out.
We know all the power of hatred only.
Supposing somebody
is very unkind to you.
I’ll tell you
about My husband’s secretary.
She got her Realization.
And she said, “I have got neighbours,
some three, four young boys,
and they are horrible hippies.
They are making noise,
and they are troublesome,
and they call me an old hen.
What have I to do
if they just make fun of me?”
I said, “All right, what will you do?”
She said, “I’m really fed up,
I’m going to give up the house.”
I said, “You just don’t do like that.
You just go and put a bandhan
on their house,
every day thrice, like this,
and just think of Me with love.”
Now she says that it is quiet
like a churchyard.
“They are very quiet.
And they are very kind,
they open the lift for me.
When I go, they help me.”
(A seeker asks a question in Hindi.
Shri Mataji answers first in Hindi
and then continues in English.)
You are the instrument.
You are the instrument,
you are the medicine,
you are the curer,
you are the doctor,
you are the computer,
you are everything.
But you should become your Self.
You have to become your Self.
(Shri Mataji continues to speak in Hindi.)