Actually Christians do not know anything about His becoming.
How He became Christ or what was the need
to have Christ or a son to come down.
Why not God Himself could do the job.
And this is the reason why I would request you to read
for yourself the incarnation of
Maha Vishnu by which you realize why Christ was born.
And it is the most important incarnation
because He is the principle.
He is the principle of creation.
The Tattwa as they call it in Sanskrit language.
He is the tattwa.
Ganesha, who resides in the Mooladhara
gradually evolves to be Christ at this stage.
From that red Chakra up to this Chakra He became the Christ.
He is the principle. Now what is the principle?
Within us what is our principle?
Is say the Kundalini you can say?
In this the electricity is the principle of this one is.
In the same way the creation,
the whole creation if you take it as such,
it is the principle and the support of this creation.
He represents, He represents the essence,
the essence of creation.
Like we can say we have a family,
husband and wife and the child.
Now the child is the essence of husband and wife.
He is the essence of the family, of the house.
The whole thing is sustained for him, is created for him.
Till they did not have the child
there was no meaning to that house,
no meaning to their life.
But when they had a child
then they had a meaning.
In the same way Christ is the essence,
is the tattwa itself.
He’s the Omkara as they call it.
He is the first sound,
first sound that was created AUM
when the Primordial Father and Primordial Mother separated,
They created this sound.
And He is that sound
which is filled into All-Pervading Power
and looks after and supports,
actually it is more the support
because looking after is done by the Father
you can say or by the Mother.
But is the support of all the universe.
And because He is just the essence, the essence never dies.
Say My essence is My Spirit,
it will never die.
The body dies or the creation will die
but the essence has to be there.
If the essence is lost then nothing could be there
that’s why He is the most important incarnation.
Because He is the support.
Now this incarnation is placed in this Agnya Chakra of ours.
Here in the center where
the optic nerve or optic thalamus cross each other like this.
In the center is a very subtle point
which moves both the sides like this and like that
and it creates two sounds Ham Ksham, Ham Ksham, Ham Ksham.
Ham is on the right hand side where you have seen
the superego is there
and Ksham is on the left hand side where the ego is.
Now these two sounds create
two kinds of vibrations.
The Ham sound creates the vibrations,
which make you think, “I am, I am.
Ham, I am.”
This comes from our existence power
that we know we have to live in this world,
we’re not going to die.
Any human being who tries to kill himself is abnormal.
Normally every human being,
why every animal or any living thing tries to retain its life.
That is through this power of Ham that I am.
Now the superego on the left hand side
and the ego on the right hand side is Ksham.
But now I’ll tell you about the right hand side superego.
In this superego when you are
conditioned by so many things, then you are frightened
and you are worried because these experiences
make you that type of a person which has fear in the mind.
And this fear is all settled in your superego.
This starts from your amoeba stage you can say
and is still today is being stored there.
You are afraid of police, you are afraid of that,
you are afraid of this.
Some people are not afraid of these things
but are afraid of something else.
Because whatever have been your conditions,
whatever have been your experiences
are all put down here.
Moreover when somebody reads the book of “Dracula”
now he’s afraid of the word Dracula
but the children who do not read
they do not know what is a Dracula is.
If you say Dracula has come they say
all right lets have a look at him.
But those children have read about Dracula,
they are literally frightened and
they say, “Oh God, Dracula is coming,
something terrible is going to happen.”
So you see whatever you have read,
whatever you have gone through
whatever experiences you have had
all is in the superego.
So this superego in that this center sends message,
I am, you are, you are Ham, Ham don’t be afraid,
don’t be afraid, you are.
So the people who come to Me, and you have seen
some people who come to Me are victims of
superego conditioning.
And these are the people,
actually at this stage only you can really discriminate
between the two types.
One who are very aggressive,
the other who are absolutely
we should say subordinated, frightened.
These people when they come to Me
I have seen, they go on crying and weeping,
“Mother you know this has happened that has happened,” and
I really get tired talking to them.
And there are so many of this kind
that really you have to
pay attention to them as Sahaja Yogis
because you’ll have to deal with them, how to,
how to manage them and how to work it out.
Now at that time if a Sahaja yogi says,
now you go on saying Ham, Ham, Ham, Ham,
a Sahaja Yogi if he says
then the vibrations will drive out his fear.
Even if you are under any fear
and you are walking around and you feel that there’s
frightened, you just say Ham, Ham, Ham.
Now with this saying the vibrations will clear out
this side very nicely.
Apart from that, that is the way you can get help
from the Divine by saying Ham.
Now there are many things about Ham and Ksham but
as the time is you know,
so I do not want to go into great details about it.
But I would say the mantra
for the right hand side is Ham
and for the left hand side is Ksham.
The right hand side is the ego,
which is real problem, you understand that,
is a real colossal one you have to face them, I mean.
I say anything small here and there I find the whole thing
coming up onto my head like that.
So what is the solution for a colossal ego?
Colossal ego can only be conquered by forgiving others.
Those who have ego must learn
if they feel hurt they must say, “forgive.”
Then another person hurts them, say, “forgive.”
And not only forgive but ask for forgiveness.
Both things should be done, more asking for forgiveness.
You have to ask for forgiveness if you have too much of ego.
It is very important.
Because if you have too much of ego means what?
That you have pampered it too much.
That means you have used it too much.
You have dominated people
and that’s why you have such a lot of ego.
If you have such a lot of ego
you must all the time try to humble down in your heart.
Now in the heart resides the Spirit.
The ego, too much of ego in a person
always takes you away from that Spirit.
That’s why it is said, “Humble down in your heart.”
The reason is, in the heart
resides that part of yours which gets completely obliterated
or forgotten once you start pumping up your ego.
But ego has its limits, it ends up into stupidity and foolishness.
You take any person who is egoistical
and who’s blowing his own trumpet.
You will immediately know because he’ll be stupid.
Without understanding what he’s doing
he’ll be doing such stupid things
that you will start wondering, especially children,
“What’s the matter with this fellow, he is quite funny?”
And then the stupidity you see faces the person
then he sees for himself, “Oh God!
how did I become so stupid?”
The stupidity comes to you because
you forget the existence of God
and your relationship with the whole.
You think, “I am on my own.
Why should I not do this?
What is wrong in this,
what is wrong in that?
I should do these things.”
I mean in this country the way people are fighting for things.
I mean you must, anybody I mean, those so-called developing countries
can’t understand what kind of a thing happening to these people.
Because the other day My son-in-law Lav was reading
an article that people are demanding now that
the son-in-law should be allowed to marry the mother-in-law.
And he just couldn’t understand how can people gather together
and ask for such an absurd thing like that. She is your mother.
How can you say that way?
I mean it is something an impossibility
for people, normal people to think like that.
That a son-in-law
can marry the mother-in-law.
And what is there to make a law about it
and to talk about it. It’s a very difficult thing.
All kinds of stupid things we are doing in this country,
which really makes everybody roar with laughter.
Is because of our Mr. Ego companionship.
It is not easy to understand how he befools us.
It goes on befooling us all the time
and then we think what’s wrong?
An eighty-year-old man
running after a twenty-year-old girl.
And the twenty-year-old girl befooling this
eighty-year-old man, supposed to be a statesman this, that
and his statue is erected somewhere there.
How is it possible?
It is only the ego makes you do all these nonsensical and
stupid things.
Once you are in Sahaja Yoga
you don’t know how to control your laughter sometimes the way
people are foolish.
Extremely foolish.
And this is what it is; it ends up in stupidity absolute stupidity.
I mean even if you want to write a novel
you won’t get such beautiful characters
as you could around you, when you listen to them.
And you’re shocked, Oh God what’s this going on
and very embarrassing too.
Extremely embarrassing and they become so foolish
with their ego that one cannot understand how thinking man,
because by thinking you get your ego,
becomes foolish.
There is no wisdom
in a person whose ego is completely developed like that.
If somebody has an ego like that there is no wisdom in him.
You can see that he does not know what is wisdom.
He behaves in such an immature way.
He may be an elderly man, great grandfather of
somebody but as soon as he opens his mouth you are shocked at him.
You think from where this joker has come?
The maturity is completely lacking.
The other day somebody told Me that,
“Mother how is it our parents are so stupid and we are searching God?
And the elderly people are so foolish and we are searching God?”
And then I said, “No, maybe because of war
the parents are disturbed, you see”.
Most of the parents were disturbed during war
and they said, “Majority of them are like this.
And the younger people are searching God and much wiser
and we don’t know how to compromise with them
because they are not searching God.
Why is it they are not searching God and we are searching God?
And if there are some searching, they are very few.”
Now I said this may be due to war but somebody said,
“Then what about America? You see,
in America the people didn’t face war so much,
the stupidity that they have is sometimes surprising.”
That is the same thing as I said,
is the development of ego in a human being.
Now ego is the thing that makes you think about everything.
For example, now
we have to, say go from here to Birmingham, all right.
So we think now how will I go?
Simple way is that I’ll take a train or I’ll
take a car and go away.
If there’s no reservation needed I will
just jump into the train or going by the car.
If the car is available I’ll go by car
or by train finished.
What is there to think about?
But no,
then we must plan it out, “I’m programmed now I have to go”.
You go to the station and find the train is not there
because there was some accident so the train is not moving.
So you are absolutely upset because
you think that the train has gone now what to do.
In that upsetting you do not even remember that
you have a car and you have to go by the car.
Now that whole things upsets you because you had plans
to go by train and you had planned everything, now you
cannot reach there and what will happen?
Now you are sitting here and worrying about it.
As a person who is spontaneous what will you do?
All right depends on, I may go by train
or by car whatever I feel like at that time.
He is sitting tight.
So he goes to the train,
sees if the train is there. If it is, nicely
there’s a space available he gets into it.
If the train is not available, all right,
he comes home takes his car and goes away.
So now you have informed the people that
you must meet at such and such a place.
That’s also is there you see.
So those people are running up down there
and they will be there at the station.
Now what’s the matter?
Even if they’re at the station you can meet them at the station.
You go by train and you can meet them.
What is there to be that much upset about it?
You see you can always contact them.
But the way we get upset we have spoiled
the complete program of going to Birmingham,
which is a very beautiful program that we have got.
We have to meet new people, we have to meet
many people, we have to enjoy ourselves.
That’s all finished
because we had planned something and it
did not work out, we are finished.
All these things make us a miserable person.
And we are so miserable and so grudging and
so boring that those who are next to you just get fed up
with it and they say,
“Now shut up.
If you are not going to Birmingham,
if you are not going don’t go. But don’t eat my head now”,
is a common experience of many.
If this Mr. Ego he’s so, he doesn’t want you to be happy.
He doesn’t want you to be relaxed.
He all the time gives you ideas
and tells you, “Do this and do that
and you must get it done and this is to be done and You
had better inform that person,
be meticulous about it,”
and it will go to such details
that anything fails you are finished
because your nerves are already finished and shattered.
Anything, even a drop of inconvenience comes into you
or even a feather of disturbance is there, you are finished.
And so everybody is rattling, ”We have tensions. We have problems.”
Why?
What is the advantage of doing all these things?
No advantage you know that. But then why do you do it?
Because you have a big ego. It won’t allow you to rest.
Whatever you may try it won’t. So what is the solution of that?
Morning till evening ask for forgiveness from God.
Pull your ears from both the sides
and say, “Oh God, forgive me.
Oh God, forgive me. And, oh God forgive me,”
so this balloon of ego goes down a little.
Remember Him morning, evening, every time.
Remembering Christ brings down your ego very much.
He did everything that was possible
that you should not develop your ego.
Everything that was possible.
He was born as an ordinary carpenter’s son.
Lived in the most ordinary conditions.
Kept Himself behind the whole scene.
He could have been born as Roman Emperor.
He could have been anybody there.
But no He was born Himself.
You know that He took his birth
in a place where even ordinary people do not take their births.
But, there also the light was there.
Wherever He was born there was light and joy.
And this is the thing we have to know, that
we have lost the joy because we have forgotten God Almighty.
When we forget Him, that He is love and He is joy,
naturally joy is also forgotten.
And then we see people are not at all happy.
They have affluence, they have money, they have everything,
but still they are not happy.
All the time they are in such a mess
that you don’t know how to talk to them.
If you say this word they’ll be angry.
If you say that word they’ll be angry.
They are not at all normal human beings.
They are sick people.
Sick with their ego.
It’s a very simple thing is to ask for forgiveness.
How many times do we do that?
Not even once a day, not even once a month, not even once a year.
Even on a Christmas day if we could say,
“Forgive us Oh Lord for whatever we have done so far.”
It will work out.
But that day we must champagne to forgive Him more.
So we must have gossips
and we must have
all the arrogant things by the time it is the end of Christmas.
This ego, yellow side one,
is the one that presses your superego too much. It does.
It presses it so much sometimes that a person forgets
that others are hurt by what they talk.
On the contrary they devise methods
how to say things which are cutting,
which are hurting, which are painful to others.
They say such things, I mean all the time if you see.
A person say from a village if he comes and sees
he’ll think, are they quarreling, what are they doing?
I mean the whole discussion,
even in the parliament I was surprised
the way they talked to each other, no bull will
treat another bull that way, see.
Even a dog normally does not bark at another dog.
No animal in the world all the time is barking at its fellow man.
No animal in the whole world I can tell you this much.
Only the human beings
if two people are there all the time they are going, ha ha ha ha
all the time that way. How is it possible?
His ego and her ego or maybe both his ego
are dashing at each other.
And there is a kind of a funny type
of feeling that oh I have mastered the thing,
I have got the thing, I have got the point.
I have proved the point.
But in that I have lost everything that was so beautiful
and so much joy giving within me.
Actually a sensible person would recede
from the place where two people are having an argument.
Argument is a sign of tomfoolery.
I haven’t seen any argument coming to any end whatsoever.
If it is then it is all right.
But it never does come.
Because, if say, you ask Me questions I answer you, all right.
If you do not like the answer give it up.
But if you argue with Me still and I argue with you
where will you end?
Argument is not going to lead you to any knowledge
but a very terrible ego developing into you.
The whole modern concept is ego oriented.
All western countries are ego orientated.
They want to develop your ego and pamper it.
There are so many other ways by which they do.
Why I’m talking more about it because we are all
supposed to be western people and affluent people you see.
Supposed to be very wise and leading
or misleading, I don’t know, the developing countries.
So we have to understand ourselves where are we
as far as our understanding of things are concerned.
How ego is pampered within us is by a large-scale method.
They work on your ego throughout to have all these
so-called enterprises.
For example to a woman they’ll say,
“Oh you must have a waist like this and you must
have a face like this and you must have –“
For a man, “You must this kind of a body.
You should be Mr. Universe or you should be something,”
so the man starts working on it immediately.
You must, there so many people I have seen
running on the roads in this cold, I don’t understand.
Like mad you know and some of
them are Member of Parliament.
The whole night they keep awake and the whole day
they are running about.
I say what are you doing?
What is the need to do this?
To keep good health you must do it.
To keep good health don’t work like mad,
be a sensible and a wise person.
Wisdom is to be sought to keep good health,
to be all right and not this kind of mad ego orientated things.
So then the one way is to excite your ego about your physique.
Then there is ego about, you must have a big car.
You see people try to show off their possessions.
You have a big car,
then they’re going about. I mean they really look to me like jokers,
that’s all they are.
I mean car I can understand is a convenience
and a good quality car if somebody can afford it should have it
because it is a headache to have a bad car. So it’s all right.
But by having a car you become something great.
You may not have food in the house
but you must have a very good car to go about.
And all these ideas come.
Then they will advertise, you see, this will
be a very good car for you.
What is it for you?
It is nothing but to pamper your ego.
All these advertisements are nothing
but by which your ego is pampered.
All these things they’re treated.
Now in America if you go every handle has to be different.
Everything has to be different.
Why so much difference in everything?
Why do you want to have everything so different?
Is it some aesthetics, you think in that?
It is none of the aesthetics but is just to pamper your ego.
Even the so-called art connoisseurs
are nothing but ego pamperers.
Your stamp collections this, that,
all this is nothing but ego pampering.
And what a waste of time, you just think about it.
This ego thing comes into us
because we are first of all, as I said, that in the west
the living was very difficult.
They had to fight the nature.
And when you have to fight the nature
you have to develop your ego to fight it.
Or actually when you are fighting the nature
the ego develops within you.
And then once that momentum has started in you
it is very difficult to bring it down.
It is such a terrible disease that
people have taken it for granted that that’s a part of their lives.
You are not your ego. You are not.
When I say that you must surrender yourself to God
they think Mother why should we surrender?
Yourself means that ego with which you are identified.
I don’t say that you surrender your wisdom.
Or I can say surrender your ego to your wisdom.
But it is so difficult to give it up because
we have learned to live with it, identified with it.
We just cannot think of life without our ego, we just cannot.
And it has gone to such an extent that we don’t even realize
how far we have gone in cruelty.
Like, “I like this kind, I like that kind.”
You go to somebody’s house and you say like this.
Is indecent to talk like that.
It is vulgar to express, “I like.” Who are you?
Are you God?
I want this. I want that.
I am very particular about this. I’m very, who are you?
Just ask yourself a question, “Who am I?
I’m the Spirit.
I’m that eternal being.
Have I become that?”
On the contrary we are hurting everybody’s Spirit by our ego.
Every moment when we talk to others we are hurting them.
Actually people have lost faith in God,
because those who are in charge of God are so arrogant
and so egoistical
that it has become impossible for anybody to think of God,
which is beyond your ego.
You’ll be surprised, ego is absolutely superficial like a bubble.
It is just like a balloon,
which can burst just like that.
And it should go.
It should go so that you should rise.
It should disappear so that your attention rises in your Spirit.
And that you see the whole world as a part
of that Spirit that you are.
This is the boundary, which you have to cross
and for that we have to take help from Christ.
Christ crucified himself. Why?
Because what did He do?
Did He loot people?
Today you have thousands of these thugs coming here and looting you.
Nobody crucifies them. What did He do?
He just challenged the ego of these Romans
and of these Jews, those who were angry with Him,
and that’s why He was crucified.
And we have to crucify our ego now through His cross.
Otherwise we are going to do the same
again to ourselves that in our own being
we crucify our Christ by our ego.
It is a very symbolic gesture of Christ,
His birth in the most humble place,
in a very humble place.
He is born in the optic thalamus, you can say,
is the place where there brain, all activities coming and
all the, all sorts of problems there chasing you,
and there He lives and you have to just awaken Him there
so that your ego is crucified once for all.
But I don’t think you fight your ego
because it is not that important to fight.
You are fighting with your shadow.
You have shadow which is called as ego
which is not to be fought and wasted you,
to waste your energy on him. Just no need to fight,
only thing if you stand in the center of the light
you don’t see any shadow.
It is so simple as that.
If you stand in the center of light that is Christ
you don’t see any shadow anywhere.
But when I say this I may sound like other people who give sermons,
“Stand in the shadow of Christ or stand in the light of Christ.”
Now what does that mean?
Where is that light or where is that place where you should stand?
That place is here in the center of your
optic thalamus where there is no thought.
You have to stand in thoughtless awareness.
Many people who have had a problem with Agnya,
many people who have come
[Talk is interrupted here and a few words are missing]
…thoughts will stop and they will be beyond thought.
And this a very, very important Chakra
for Sahaja Yogis because when the Kundalini rises above,
above the Agnya Chakra immediately there is no thought.
You do not get any thoughts from ego or superego.
But there is wobbling in the Agnya because of your imbalanced ways.
And the imbalanced ways are,
that sometimes you are with ego or with superego.
This has happened to our people in the West
because we have had so much of ego we got really tired of it.
We got frightened with it.
Then we started taking to drugs and things to increase our superego.
But by doing that what we are doing is
pushing by one end and bringing back another end
and that’s how we are wobbling
our ego and superego
by which we are not helping ourselves at all.
So what one has to do
is to rise within oneself up to the point of Agnya
and try to steady your Agnya.
There are many people have asked Me one question.
How to steady the Agnya?
Agnya is placed at the crossing point of our nerves
and also optic thalamus.
Now, so it is said that
if you have wobbling eyes you’ll have a wobbling Agnya.
You have to steady your eyes.
You have to soothe them.
Now it is very, very out of date, ancient, old
and all sorts of names that you call it to a thing like that.
But you must steady your eyes and
steady them in such a way that it is very soothing for the eyes.
Which is the most soothing thing for the eyes is the green grass.
If you could see the green grass with your eyes means you walk
with your eyes on the ground.
Your eyes will be soothed, your Agnya will be all right.
That’s why Christ said that,
“I tell you about the adulterous eyes”.
He talked about adulterous eyes.
The eyes with which you do adultery.
Is a very common thing these days.
Every woman a man must see.
Every man a woman must see.
As if it is the most important job.
If you have not seen one woman you’re finished.
I mean this is being modern.
But I am an old fashioned lady.
And at the time of Christ he said,
“You should not have adulterous eyes.”
And the ones who have adulterous eyes are,
no more than any other, but our Western Christians.
Who all the time even in the church, even
when they’re giving sermons, their eyes are moving with adultery.
These eyes have to be very, very pure, very, very deep
and very loving when you want to have your Agnya all right.
Because you receive through you eyes.
Say if you have closed your eyes
you do not put your attention to anything because
your eyes are closed.
You are not adding more thoughts to yourself.
But if your eyes are open you are adding much more thoughts
because everywhere the eyes go the attention goes
and you see things and create thoughts and put in them.
So your attention which has to go to the Spirit,
which has to go to God,
which has to shine through the window of Divine.
This beautiful thing is ruined by
the way we use our eyes and we do not respect it.
There’s nothing so pure and beautiful as the grass on the ground
or the ground itself, which takes our feet,
which supports us, which looks after us, enriches us.
We should put our eyes on the Mother Earth
instead of looking at every person.
But from Sahaja Yoga point of view now many of you know
what happens to your eyes  when you look at somebody.
Maybe a entity might enter your eyes.
And it is, you’ll be amazed
that it is the play of the entity
what we call this so-called flirting is.
I’ve talked about it before also and people didn’t like it
when I told them about it.
But I have seen actual entities entering from eyes to eyes.
I have seen very simple people who come down
to such places, say in a party.
In a party people are just exchanging entities
from one eye to another.
Once it goes to another person
he puts his entity into another person.
And that third goes into another person.
All the time your attention is diverted.
And you feel it is attracted towards something,
you do not know why it is attracted.
Now the certain symbols are also made like that.
To add up to the problems,
you see all the society is working at it.
That you should appear in such a way that
every man should look at you.
Every woman should look at you.
Why? What is the use?
Supposing I look at you what do I get?
What do I get by looking at a person?
What is the advantage just looking at a person?
We are wasting such a lot of energy for what?
In the same way if you are walking on the roads,
we are seeing some beautiful things all right.
If you have to buy something, all right go ahead,
see those things, whatever you have to select is all right.
But all the time just because your eyes are such,
you are just doing it and you do not know the reason
why you are doing like this,
all the time why your eyes are wobbling.
And that is a sure and certain sign for a person to become mad.
Absolutely, that’s a sure and certain sign is,
when a person is mad
how do you make it out that a person is lunatic.
If you see his eyes the iris in the eyes are all the time wobbling.
They cannot keep it steady.
Or they are sick they’re also, you can see,
that these eyes are all the time wobbling.
There is no steadiness.
Not only this but you have seen those people who
have come in the Sahaja Yoga when they close their eyes
they find their eyes are flickering.
Their eyelids are flickering.
That means there is some sort of a disturbance
in the Kundalini rising.
Whole tension if you call it as hundred
then at least eighty percent of it comes through our eyes.
Then how important it is to protect our eyes
from all kind of useless activities we are doing.
Christ - Christ’s life shows so many aspects
of how to respect others.
But one of them which has been very much misused throughout is
that of the prostitute.
He saved the prostitute, He saved her no doubt.
But you spoil these prostitutes.
A good woman you make her into prostitutes.
You give her ideas by which she becomes a prostitute.
A good Huswife (old English word like housewife)
is turned into a prostitute by an egotistical man.
Young small girls who are virgins are being destroyed
by your dirty glances.
Do you realize this?
That you are doing just the opposite what Christ had done?
And you say that He saved, Christ,
so even if we are prostitutes He’ll save us.
But why be prostitutes?
This is such a stupid style of thinking.
That we should become prostitutes so that Christ will save us.
One has to think about all these things
in the proper light of Sahaja Yoga.
Unless and until you are realized
My talk is just useless for you.
But once you are realized you will know
that if you glance at someone
you might suddenly get a headache at the back.
You might feel a dart has gone into your head
or something has happened.
You might feel that you’re blinding
with somebody’s face and you will get all kinds of experiences
by which you will know how important are your eyes.
All your nervousness and everything can be cured
if you have pure eyes.
But it is such a vicious circle
that through your eyes you gather all the bad
and is accumulated in the Agnya and you have to clear the Agnya
to make the eyes clear.
It’s a vicious circle.
But it can start at a point as I said,
we have to ask for forgiveness.
Secondly we have to bring Christ in our Agnya Chakra.
Thirdly we have to give up all
drugs and all intoxicants and all smoking.
That happens automatically when you are a Sahaja Yogi,
it will work out.
But eyes express the whole of your being, your brain,
your body, your limbs everything.
And if your Agnya is all right then you eyes
are perfectly all right.
They emit nothing but love
wherever they glance.
Only with a glance of your eyes you can raise the Kundalini.
Only with the glance of your eyes you can cure people.
Only with your glance you can bring joy into
the destroyed and the ruined people.
So these eyes which you see are the windows
of your being, of your heart.
When the Spirit is expressed through your eyes,
you must have noticed yourself,
that when the Kundalini rises then the eyes become dilated.
And a realized soul has got
black eyes because they have these eyes are dilated.
At least when I see them they are all dilated black eyes.
Apart from that
a realized soul can be made out by his eyes which are sparkling.
There’s a sparkle like diamonds.
They sparkle all the time and
you can make out from the eyes
that this person is a realized soul.
There’s a tremendous difference between a non-realized
soul’s eyes and a realized soul’s eyes.
So you can imagine how your Spirit sees through your eyes.
But if the eyes are not pure it doesn’t stay there long.
So if we have to understand Christ
physically we have to respect our eyes.
Mentally we have to give up all that is impure in our mind.
Now, so we come to the impurities of the mind.
And the impurities of mind are,
there are so many poisons, you know, about.
I mean there are books and books written about the poisons.
And the psychologists are supposed to take out all your poisons.
I don’t know if they can do it at all.
But they have the worst Agnya.
All these psychologists have the worst Agnya
and I don’t think they are capable
of really giving any relief to people
who are suffering mentally.
Mental sufferings are of two types.
Say the same thing is that one is…
MOTHER SAYS ASIDE: Vibrations are so much, I can’t stand it.
One type of mental troubles are
where people oppress you very much.
You see you go on bearing the cross.
Now this is a very wrong idea people have about Christ.
Bearing the cross doesn’t mean that anybody who tries
to oppress you should go on taking the enslavement upon yourself.
You’re not to enslave to anyone whatsoever.
Anybody who tries
to make a slave out of you, you should deny it absolutely.
You should say Ham, I am.
Who are you to dominate me?
Anyone
whether you are of a black skin, or a red skin or a yellow skin,
nobody has right to dominate anyone in this whole world.
And if anybody is doing it, “Oh what to do now,
after all you see we are poor people,
or we are like this or he’s supporting,” and all that.
Then they are running away from their duty towards themselves.
Such people cannot get Realization.
Slaves are not going to become kings.
So the slavery that is supposed to be confused with bearing the cross
is another confusion of modern times.
We have to rise in our self-respect.
And we have to understand
that no one in this world has a right to dominate us.
But then what is bearing of the cross is?
First of all the people of His level never suffer.
It’s just a joke going on.
It’s a Leela, it’s a play going on for them.
They never suffer,
and even if they so called act as suffering
they just do it because they want to do it.
They are not helpless people.
They are not slaves.
And those who think that by bearing it up and by suffering it
we are becoming Christians
they should know they are psychological cases.
And if they are crying and weeping and all the time saying,
“What to do, you see I am in love and my lover tortures me.”
You are neither in love neither you have a lover.
It is a kind of a psychological clubbing.
That he is a dominating man
and you like his domination, that’s why you are together.
Is a simple fact.
So every human being has his own self-respect.
And he must respect his self that is the Spirit within him.
And nothing should dominate it.
Whether you belong to this country or that country,
or this ism or that ism. All this will break down.
Under the rule of God
nobody has the right to dominate anybody’s Spirit.
But when you are given freedom
you go to the other side that is Mr. Ego.
You do not know how to use your freedom.
So you try to dominate others.
Your freedom is, everybody’s freedom is in danger.
You’re on top of everyone, and torturing everybody’s souls.
And you are dominating by land
and by properties or by possessions.
So either this way or that way,
mentally if you are of this category or that category,
you are against yourself.
Just be in the center and see for yourself.
Just be looking at it.
Are you emitting love towards another person?
If you are a slave how can you love? You cannot.
If you are free and abandoned how can you love?
Love has its own bondages very sweet and beautiful.
You have to live with them.
You enjoy those bondages.
For a little child will come to your house
and he will spoil your house no doubt, and that he should do.
And you should enjoy that spoiling.
Then your freedom if it is challenged by a little child’s crying,
then you are not wise people.
This is abandonment.
Or I would say it is loneliness.
It is cutting off from the primordial, from the big one,
from the large one that you are.
Is not to be able to tolerate the freedom of others.
A child has no freedom to cry in the house.
What sort of freedom you conceive of.
A mother has no right to say
something she wants to say about her child,
which is her duty to tell him what is right and wrong.
If the son does not have right
to eat whatever he likes in his own mother’s family
then what sort of freedom do you have?
It’s such a confusion of things.
So this kind of freedom
is just the opposite and extreme of enslavement.
But in the center is love where you are bound by everyone.
I am bound by My children. Yes, I am.
I am proud of them.
They bound Me and I bound them too.
It’s a mutual bounding which we enjoy among ourselves.
There is such a give and take when there is such a bondage of love.
But do we understand the importance of bondage of love?
At the slightest pretext we break it.
Say wife says, “I would like to go out today”.
The husband says “Why?
I am very tired don’t you understand?“
Or if the husband says, “I feel like eating something,”
or some particular thing he says pancake or something,
a small thing.
“Oh I am very tired every time you are demanding.”
If she could just think by making that little thing
he would be so very happy.
She should be dying to know what he wants.
And he should be dying to do what she wants.
And then enjoy each other’s company
or you are wasting all your properties that you have as human beings.
You don’t know how much you are wasting from each other.
Every moment is filled with such beautiful bondages,
where exchanges are there. What have you gained?
The way you are fighting.
The way you are going about.
What have you gained let me see?
When you die you have to announce in the paper
that XYZ is dead and you find there is nobody.
And you have even to pay for people to visit you when you die.
This is the case today.
Such dryness, such emptiness, such loneliness exists.
What have you achieved through this.
So this bondage we have to.
And there is no question of sacrifice you see, the way.
We must sacrifice for the family. What are you sacrificing?
I mean if you pay for your family
you get the joy out of it. That’s why you do it.
If you have to lead a nice good life
you are not sacrificing anything
but you are gaining by that, leading a good life.
If your wife says, “Don’t go to the pub,”
and if you do not go there,
then you should not say she is an orthodox,
old fashioned this that, that and that and that.
But instead you should thank you stars that
in this modern times also that there is somebody
who’s telling you the truth.
Because the whole edifice has come up,
do you mean to say that truth should not be told?
All this is falsehood in which you are living.
And if you have to be happy come down to reality.
Friends, also same thing.
With the friends what sort of relations do we have with our friends?
What do we expect from them?
Sending them a Christmas card
and then if they don’t send, feeling bad about it.
There are no deeper bondages we have not lived with them.
If you allow our self to be bound by them,
they will be bound by us.
You better try this.
Try to be bound by them. Don’t be afraid of anybody else.
Just try to be bound by others
and you’ll be amazed how much they will be giving you.
I am a living example of this.
I can tell you I am a living example of this.
I am bound by all of you.
If somebody says, “Mother when are you going to leave us?”
No I cannot. I cannot. I am just bound by you. I just
do not want to leave because I love you very much.
How can I leave you?
It’s impossible for Me.
So then, what do I gain out of this life?
Everything that is in this world.
What do you want Me to get?
I cannot even count what I can get out of it.
Immeasurable, ocean.
I become an ocean Myself.
Break your ideas about your own personal
freedom and liberation, is liberating your intelligence.
You‘re liberating your own wisdom.
And the sweetness and the beauty which is never perishable
whether you are old or young.
That is going to be your own.
But these poisons that are being built outside and inside you,
please throw them away.
These are mental poisons.
Through Agnya you can take them out.
You see, this is an opening also
through which  many things go out.
Try to work it out.
Look at the tree with love
and you’ll find that the tree itself
is giving you the joy of its creation.
Because you’ll become thoughtless.
And the creator who has made that beautiful tree
will be pouring all that joy which is stored into it into you.
Every human being is a store of joy.
Unlimited, I assure you, believe Me.
And don’t waste them because somebody is not properly dressed,
or he’s not according to the way
you want him to be which you learnt in your public school.
Every doorstep, everywhere there is beauty lying, do not miss it.
But if you have possessiveness about it, an adultery about it,
then you can never enjoy them.
You can never enjoy all that beauty, all that store, all that wealth
that is in every human being every moment it is bubbling.
For Agnya it’s a good thing, Christmas is coming.
And at the time that when I have to wish you Happy Christmas,
that at this occasion I am speaking about Agnya Chakra
in which, what I said is, Agnya is
one must know what to order and how to obey.
Obey the Divine.
Obey your elders.
Obey your self and not your ego.
And then you can order also others.
Not only human beings,
but you can even order the sun and the moon and
all the winds and everything in the world.
Everything you can control, everything with this Agnya.
You try one thing.
If you know somebody is going to do something wrong,
just take his name and put it to Agnya. He’ll not do it, try it.
This is a trick I’m telling about
for those who are realized souls
not for those who are not yet realized
but those who are realized can try.
If the other person is doing something wrong
you can try your Agnya.
Anything you order on your Agnya will be respected
but your Agnya must have Christ there.
Because you have the great support awakened within you,
which does not exist here but into every man’s head.
It is all pervading into all small atoms and molecules, it is
everywhere into the sun and any place you go. It is there.
So try to develop your Agnya that is the mastery of your self.
Those who have a good Agnya can master anything
and understand that the idea about mastering
worldly things and mastering human beings and mastering this
and some of them are mastering in, say, other crafts and things,
best thing is to master your Agnya.
And you really become the master of yourself
by which you can master many things.
And today on this great day
when I’m wishing you a Happy Christmas, I wish you to have
the most powerful Agnyas,
that people when they see your forehead
should know that Christ is reborn again with in you.
May God bless you.