You see, it shows how William Blake thought
of you people; and he represents that hope
for England in this poem that I had about
you people.
As I had told you that: England is the heart;
and the heart has to be first of all established,
otherwise Sahaja Yoga is not going to be established.
Now the people who live in this country are
least believing, I think, in William Blake
as you all do.
(Inaudible) [This poem shows] Very clearly
what hopes William Blake had.
He could see the vision very clearly and he
said that England has to become the Jerusalem.
In Sanskrit language it’s called as teevtha.
Teevtha means a pilgrimage place, a place
where pilgrims come in.
And this indication here, of this poem, which
is so beautifully written by William Blake,
shows that he saw the vision of Sahaja Yoga
prospering in England in this beautiful manner.
But, as it is, this heart is so materially
bound.
There’s so much of materialism that has
come into our veins even.
And we have to realize that we have to get
it out of our mind, out of our body.
It has gone into us so much, the materialistic
approach towards life, that we have to really
take a strong action against it.
It’s so much that anybody who comes to this
country also becomes materialistic.
Imagine [the] heart becoming a matter.
Think of [the] heart becoming a stone.
And today on a day when you are here to worship
Me as a Guru.
My desire is only one and that is that you
all should become gurus yourself.
Now I have struggled for seven years here
to build you up and all the struggle that
is described has been done single-handed to
begin with and then so many of you joined.
But when you join Me you have to realize that
you have to really transform yourself.
You have to know that you are, first of all,
realized souls.
Which, also, very few people really realize
and are aware, I think, that they are realized
souls.
They are not the other, mundane, type of people,
ordinary people.
They are realized souls.
So as it is they have to get out off this
shell in which they have been living.
The ideas of securities, that you have had
so far, come to you all from materialism if
you study yourself correctly.
Everything is trickling down to you that is
materialism.
How many people read William Blake?
How many understand him and how many believe
in him?
And then how many follow him?
He is a lost poet of this country.
After getting realization, unless and until
the people of England understand that they
have to completely transform themselves into
a new awareness of understanding that: you
are now realized souls, you are part and parcel
of the whole and you are aware of it.
Firstly, materialism crawls into you in so
many ways.
Because there has been industrial revolution.
People have created many things.
Matter has been comforting you
and you got used to matter.
You just can’t do without it.
A small thing say for example – you must
have a paper napkin, or you must have a glove.
This is the minimum of minimum.
But see, how many countries use these things?
How many people in the world use these things?
It is not needed for the body.
By this over preservation of yourself and
by this domination of matter upon yourself,
you have really become delicate darlings,
absolutely delicate darlings.
Like if you go to Himalayas take it.
I went to Bhowali and other places like Nainita.
They are, all the time, colder than London,
and there are peaks which are, all the time,
covered with snow and the people there never
use shoes or socks, never.
They take their baths everyday with cold water,
every day!
You’ll be amazed every one of them, they
have rosy cheeks, they are not pale, they
are healthy people.
Their women folk carry all the wood, all the
way up the hill.
God has made your body in such a way that
it can bear up lots of things.
Of course now, suddenly, an Englishman cannot
become a Pahadi, means a man living on the
hills, that I understand.
You cannot suddenly become that.
But gradually try to give up certain things
that you think so important in life.
Try!
One day it may pain, second day it may pain.
Because unless and until you make really great
effort to get rid of materialistic body and
mind, you cannot be alright.
And this is the biggest stumbling block for
the western seekers.
You have to get out of that cocoon, as I said.
The whole transmutation has to take place.
Every time you ask anyone, he’s catching
still.
How can you become Gurus?
I mean your Guru can live in whatever conditions,
as I told you the other day.
Now there are some Indians here, ask them
if they can wash their hands in washbasins
with the water in it.
Ask any Indian.
They just can’t do it.
They can’t use paper only, they just can’t
live with the paper only.
They just can’t live like that.
Impossible.
I can’t think of one Indian who can do that.
Even in the poorest conditions in England
they cannot do it.
They might have lived here for twenty-five
years I can assure you, they just can’t
do it.
They can’t live without baths.
You may tell them a hundred times that “you
take your bath once a week,” it’s impossible.
Two weeks is out of question, they will die.
Even if they have got lung cancer they will
take.
But you have seen Me, how much I can adjust.
Though all my life I’ve lived in India.
I can live under any circumstances, I can
live in Indian villages.
In any circumstances I can live.
So the other day also I told you, and again
I tell you, first of all get out you this
mala, this filth of materialism.
Indians also become materialistic when they
come to England.
For them money is important, nothing else.
They have no time for anything else but for
money.
It’s a fact.
Anybody who touches this land becomes money
possessed.
If you tell them that money’s not everything
they can’t understand, they go mad.
Morning till evening they are also running
in the rat race.
Now you have to change, you have to come out
of it.
You have to stand out and see for yourself
that you are no more one of these mad people
who run after matter.
And you leave each and every thing, every
particle of it here and die; again you are
born, again you are doing the same thing.
You have to run away from comfort.
You must learn how to overcome your comforts.
You must train your body.
Little noise here and there.
Englishman, I am saying Englishman because
we are in England.
Americans are much worse.
Any noise fifty percent would die with any
blasting they hear.
Just by hearing.
They are so sensitive.
I mean they have made their bodies, their
everything, so sensitive that they are really
dainty darlings.
And can you imagine, read the second part
of it loudly.
Second part of it you just read it.
Where is the second part now?
Gavin – just read it.
Read it out loudly and see for yourself with
these dainty darlings how am I going to do
this.
Gavin: “Bring me my Bow of burning gold.
Bring me my arrows of desire."
Shri Mataji: What is going to happen?
You have no answer.
Gavin: “Bring me my spear Oh, clouds unfold.
Bring me my chariot of fire."
Shri Mataji: Of fire?
You can’t sit even on a chariot.
(Laughter) Really!
Because it shakes and you have to hold it
tight and you have to stand erect with it.
Gavin: “I will not cease from mental fight
nor shall my sword sleep in my hand.
Till we have built Jerusalem in England’s
green and pleasant land."
Shri Mataji: I think better give swords into
everybody’s hand.
Let’s see how many can hold it straight.
You see Sahaja Yoga is not a simple thing
like dish washing.
It’s a very serious thing and on certain
things you are very well equipped, but on
certain things where you are not equipped,
that must be sustained.
Your strong points are your strong points
so forget about them.
Whatever are your weak points, hit them there.
I mean mentally you are very well equipped.
If I have to argue with you I will give up.
I really can’t because you are very knowledgeable
people.
You have read all the books of the world,
you are over read.
You are too great.
But, as far as your body is concerned, your
body is a slave of matter.
In a way your mind is also a slave of matter.
So to understand that we have to be great
gurus, first of all a guru has to go through
a great discipline of self-emancipation, self-emancipation.
Great discipline is needed.
And the great discipline of self-emancipation
is, first of all, we must get rid of the idea
of comfort.
You can’t sit on the chair?
Alright.
You can’t sit on a particular chair?
Sit on that chair everyday till that chair
breaks completely.
You cannot sit on the ground?
Sit on the ground, everyday.
You can’t live without one thing?
Try to do that.
That’s how you make your body alright.
Make your body your slave and not you the
slave of the body.
Because if you have to become the guru your
body should be such that it should just adjust
to everything that you want to do, otherwise
what’s the use?
Imagine you have a car which you cannot handle,
will you sit in such a car?
You will bash yourself and bash others also
and that’s what you are doing.
One has to realize that: to overcome this
material drag upon yourself, you have to work
it out on yourself.
Then, once you have controlled this, minimum
of minimum, that you can sleep anywhere you
feel like.
Try to sleep on the ground for a while.
That you may do for sun tanning, and people
cannot resist all this nonsense because these
are ideas put into you.
They have exploited you.
They have told you that: this should be done,
that should be done, this is necessary, that
is necessary.
They have to sell their goods.
Try to sometimes fast.
I have prohibited Indians from fasting, because
what they do is to fast.
At the slightest pretext they fast.
I mean, as it is, there is a dearth of food
in India – so they fast.
What is the need for them to fast?
But here it is necessary that people should
learn to fast and should not get attracted
towards food so much.
I mean the attraction towards food, also,
is a sign that your senses are just driving
you mad, isn’t it?
Think of it.
Now separate yourself from your senses and
see how it drives you mad.
First of all the body, then the senses we
should attack.
The biggest enemy we have is our own tongue.
It acts in two ways.
One is the taste.
The food – taste.
And the second way it attacks is the way we
talk.
Either we don’t talk or when we talk we
just hit.
We cannot be kind.
We cannot be compassionate.
We cannot communicate our heart to anyone.
Control your tongue.
First of all try to control your tongue on
those two things.
You want to eat a cake then don’t eat cake
for a year.
This is the only way you can train your tongue,
I really tell you.
Now if you say something harsh all the time,
say you have a way of speaking some sort of
an abuse,[then] try to change it.
Try to change.
Try to make your speech a sweet one.
Make it a beautiful one, attractive.
You cannot be a guru in Sahaja Yoga, I can
tell you, with a sharp tongue.
Those gurus are finished.
We had gurus before, they used to just sit
with a big stick in the hand.
To anybody coming, first they would give twenty-five
nice ones.
Still if the fellow would stick on, then they
would say, “Alright now come closer to me."
Then they may slap him twice.
If he could bear that, I mean they could go
to any limit of torturing their disciples,
they would put the disciple upside down, in
a well and pull him up and again dip him down,
pull him and dip him down – eleven times.
And still if he survived then he would help.
They used to take physical test.
I mean their disciples had to be really wrestlers,
very healthy people, having a lot of resistance
and stamina, otherwise they would not take.
And they said “Erya gabaliyatze karma no
ahe” – “it’s not the job for any Dick,
Tom and Harry."
Thus they would only select one person.
They would make him sit on the thorns or on
the nails.
Actually there were seats of nails.
These people were made to sit on the seats
like that.
I mean I’m not telling you lies, you can
find out.
And they used to treat them as if they are
on a suicide squad, absolutely like that.
The determination had to be like that.
Then they would accept them as a disciple,
not as a guru still.
Then beating them nicely morning till evening.
You have heard of Mr.
Ravi Shankar, a great sitarist.
I remember My father was a political adviser
to the king where his guru, Allaudin Khan
Sahib, used to live.
And I remember that day when I was in college
and he was also young, might be slightly younger
to Me in age, or maybe, I don’t know what
was his age that time.
But he was studying with this fellow, this
guru of his and we went there.
So My father was a great connoisseur of music
and his guru used to respect My father.
So he asked, that, “Why don’t you play?”
My father asked, to Ravi Shankar.
He said, “Sir please,” his eyes came out,
He pleaded.
He was so frightened!
Then his guru played.
You see, he used to play on Mridangam(actually
Pakhawaj) that’s a kind of double tabla,
a double percussion.
He was a great genius, then he went away for
something.
So Ravi Shankar crawled up to My father.
He said, “Sir never ask me, before my guru,
to play.
You see?”
Then he lifted his hair and showed a big bulge
was there.
“You see, this I got yesterday for playing
one note [wrong].
My sitar was broken and this (bump) I’ve
got instead of the sitar!
This is my guru’s Prasad.
So please for heaven’s sake”.
Still he stuck on to him.
And you can see the results today he’s Ravi
Shankar.
But you have a Guru who is a mother.
I never hit you, I don’t think I have hit
anyone of you.
You got your realization.
In all my compassion I looked after you.
I have given you compassion.
I’ve never asked for anything nor have I
complained for anything or grudged for anything.
I have been extremely, extremely, extremely
patient with you.
So you have to be My prototype.
You are a guru in Sahaja Yoga in this Maha
Yoga, you are not a guru of this type who
can only create one disciple in twenty one
thousand years, sort of a thing.
You have got the knowledge of Kundalini much
more than any one of these gurus have got.
You have the powers much more than any one
of these gurus have.
Indiscriminately this power has been given
to you.
Now only those who will come up and grow as
proper trees will be called as gurus.
And that is why one has to know how to grow
properly as a guru.
First of all you must give up all materialistic
attitude towards Sahaja Yoga.
Many Sahaja Yogis even have an idea that it
should be used for certain purposes.
You see, that it should house us, it should
give us some place to live in.
Some people have an absurd idea that it should
also provide us food, free.
That it should not touch, at all, our married
life.
We can have our plans with our married life
the way we like.
You can lead absolutely, a very selfish, self-centered
married life.
Also some people have an idea that we are
not to spend a single pie for Sahaja Yoga
but take all the advantages out of it.
Such people should never hope to become gurus.
They may try to show off but they’ll go
down.
You have to learn humility.
First of all you have to be humble people.
Unless and until you have a large heart you
can never humble down.
You have to be an extremely humble person.
Humility doesn’t mean that you bow to a
person who is dominating, it never means that.
But it means a strength within you.
The person who is weak can never be humble.
He can never bear the load like this Mother
Earth bears our load so well, because she’s
so great.
You have to be strong enough within yourself
to bear the load of your disciples, of people
who try to follow you.
Humility should be that: “I was like them,
absolutely like them.
I was nothing.
Without Sahaja Yoga what was I?”
I mean you may be the governor of some place;
alright, so what?
Before God’s eyes what are you?
Nothing, nobody knows who you are.
You may be having cars and anything.
You might be a very educated anything.
What does it matter in the name (does Mother
mean “realm”?) of God?
You have known that saints have not been so
educated.
Christ never went to any university, did he?
All these ideas that we have got of our greatness
must be absolutely made zero.
The greatness is in humility and sweetness.
Speak something that will be dear to others,
that would be appealing to them in a proper
discriminating diplomatic manner.
Some people in the name of honesty just are
sadistic, or useless.
You can talk to people nicely, say something,
in such a way that they feel attracted towards
you.
That they feel that there is complete humility,
that you accept them as they are because you
want to give them.
All kinds of subtler arrogance also develops
in people, I have seen.
I can’t understand how people develop this
kind of arrogance.
Like, supposing somebody knows how to do the
puja, take an XYZ.
He becomes so arrogant.
If somebody knows some Sanskrit he becomes
arrogant.
If, say, somebody comes to see Me more often
than others, she becomes arrogant.
Somebody manages a hall, he becomes arrogant.
Or somebody programs something, he becomes
arrogant.
Anything you do, first thing that happens
is, in your tongue, you develop a big ego
like that.
You become a sharp tongued person.
Cut your tongue many a times.
Punish it.
It has no business to be like that because
it is not going to serve the purpose for which
it is there.
A guru’s vani is so great that every word
he speaks is a mantra.
Every sentence he says opens a complete universe.
It should be that powerful and that beautiful
not to close down anybody’s heart.
You speak to someone, the other person says,
“Oh God never see his face."
Sahaja Yoga depends on you more than it depends
on Me.
You have to change.
You have to change yourself very much more.
Just by taking up some sort of a role or assuming
something great you are not going to progress
at all.
Supposing a little bush says, “I am a tree."
Will it become a tree?
Supposing it behaves like a tree will it become
a tree?
It has to become the tree then there is no
need to behave, you are a tree.
A woman walks like a woman and a man walks
like a man.
If you behave like a woman will you become
a woman?
It has to be innate.
It has to be within us.
If you are a guru you are a guru anybody can
see and say, “Ah that’s a guru."
Then you can do lots of things.
We are not willing to give up these things,
that’s why we go on catching on the same
point, catching on the same point.
At least those who are here should decide
today that we are going to change ourselves
completely.
Let us start on the changing.
We meet others, we greet others, talk to them.
We should be able to talk.
There are some people who just don’t know
how to talk.
They just don’t talk, they are all the time
– never heard their voice.
If they telephone I can’t even recognize
because I’ve never heard their voices before.
You must talk.
Open out.
What is there to have fear?
Humility doesn’t mean fear, it means complete
love.
You must talk, open out, be interesting.
Try to do something for others.
I have been saying this again and again.
You have to all become gurus.
I am just a Mother.
And Mother is the first and the last guru
for everyone.
That’s how I’m your Guru and I’m the
Guru of all the Gurus.
But you have to become your own guru.
And for that you have to think that you have
to hold swords in your hand.
Not only to hold swords in your hand, you
have teach others to hold the swords.
What should be the character of that man who
has to guide others?
He himself cannot hold the sword in his hand.
What is he going to teach to others?
You just tell Me that – a simple question.
At least you should have that personality
that can hold the sword in the hand.
So the first thing one has to know is to absolutely
enslave your body and enslave your senses.
You can give justification.
I know people know how to give justification.
“I said this because he said that."
It’s not that.
It is you who do not know that you are harming
yourself.
Try to get out of it.
You are asking but now you have to face, you
have to give.
This asking is over now, finished.
You’ve got everything.
You are not aware you have got everything
now within yourself.
Just reverse the position and you can give
to others.
But if you’re hankering still, worried about
these nonsensical things then nobody is going
to respect you.
I would suggest one thing, that: take to detachment.
In a way a sanyasa absolutely a sanyasa.
You know I am a sanyasi.
Though I live in a household and all that,
I am not bothered about things.
I am a sanyasi, but the day I will announce
that I have taken a sanyasa people will be
much more impressed by Me than they are today.
If a person is over attached to things, attached
to money, attached to this, that, and all
those things, such a person is not going to
impress others in spiritual matters.
You can be a nice prime minister of England,
but you have no place in Sahaja Yoga if you
do not have a way of detachment.
That doesn’t mean that you become hippies
by any chance- not at all.
But it means that you become detached.
Specially it is very important for you to
develop that – a detachment.
Detach yourself from things that you are supposed
to be possessing.
I can tell you, you cannot take anything with
you.
Can you?
We know that we are not going to take.
Now you are aware of it, that you’re not
going to take, also.
It’s not that you are not aware.
Then why are you attached?
All kinds of disgraceful behavior ensues when
you are attached.
Become a sanyasi.
It doesn’t mean you wear that yellow or
red and all kinds of horrible dresses.
But from inside you become a sanyasi.
That’s the best way you conquer your void.
The void question first comes because of wrong
guru.
Of course, no doubt about it.
If you have been to a wrong guru then the
void will be very, very bad no doubt.
Because you have followed a wrong guru you
will always have to remember that you have
to follow the right Guru, out and out.
Absolute full surrendering otherwise it will
never go down.
And if you start sort of “Yes I know, Mother
is alright,” this kind of thing will not
work out.
You have to go all out to accept the right
Guru if you have a void problem.
And this void problem is so deep, is so deep
that, first of all, it indicates Ekadesha
Rudra.
Ekadesha Rudra is a very dangerous thing because
it can give you from left to right all kinds
of funny things, even cancer, epilepsy, all
kinds of diseases.
So those who have been to other gurus have
to go all out to neutralize it on the void
part.
And for them it is necessary to really decide
to become a sanyasi.
In the sense that – don’t get attached
to material things too much.
Because from these gurus all kinds of things
have come to you.
Some people might have picked up bad things
like telling lies.
You see, even I’ve seen people who go to
these gurus can pick up some sort of a horrible
intrigue; intriguing nature.
Anything they can pick up.
I have seen people who have been to gurus.
They have such horrible spirits in them that,
when they come to Sahaja Yoga also, they intrigue
with Sahaja Yogis.
They intrigue!
You see [whether] their bhoots intrigue or
they intrigue – God alone knows, but go
on intriguing against Sahaja Yoga.
They talk to people against Sahaja Yoga they
do this, they are not aware.
And their void goes out again and again.
So for anyone who has followed any such things,
any practices of this kind or even self-meditation
or anything like, must get to it and see to
it that you really surrender fully to the
right Guru.
Fully, hundred percent.
Complete obedience.
Not to judge or not to even ask questions.
That would help very much in the void.
But I can tell you spirituality is such great
thing that, if you accept that kind of obedience,
it fills you up with such powers, tremendous
powers.
Obedience is the key of becoming the best
guru.
If you do not know how to respect, nobody
is going to respect you.
If you have not been under any command you
cannot command anyone.
Surrendering is the best way for void people
especially.
First of all you must surrender completely,
blindly you can say.
Just jump into it.
Do not reason it out.
Complete surrendering.
Once you have done that you will be surprised
how you’ll be so blessed with the powers
of a guru that you’ll rise to heights and
you will do all that William Blake has said.
Because it is like a drop submerging into
the ocean and becoming the ocean.
And you know the ocean is the Guru, not a
drop.
It’s the ocean and the ocean has everything
in it.
So we have to learn from the ocean to be the
ocean by becoming the ocean yourself.
I have told you in many ways how it is important
that we have to have many gurus of Sahaja
Yoga.
But if Sahaja fails it fails because of Sahaja
Yogis not because of Me, always.
What I hear, “Mother we went there, there
were two Sahaja Yogis they were very rude
to us so we would like to talk to you and
not to them."
It’s very common.
Or a fight between the two Sahaja Yogis or
a misunderstanding or all sorts of things
between sahaja yogis.
You are the reflection of Sahaja Yoga.
You are the mirrors, not Me.
You have to reflect Sahaja Yoga.
So first of all you have to become good reflectors
– the good gurus.
Now look at these gurus who move about.
They have millions and millions of disciples
except that they are crooks of the first order.
They have no other qualifications to be gurus.
They have no idea of Kundalini they cannot
raise Kundalini.
They are not even holy people leave alone
anything else.
They don’t deserve to enter into any temple
of God leave alone His Kingdom.
They are from hell and they have mesmerized
people and they have got their disciples.
You can also [raise the Kundalini], just through
your character and through your abilities
as Sahaja Yogis, which are tremendous.
Even those who are great gurus in India cannot
raise the Kundalini the way you can raise.
Under their finger?
They can’t believe it.
It’s Shri Ganesha’s powers you have got.
Look at the surrendering of Shri Ganesha.
Look at His surrendering.
Completely surrendered to his Mother.
Who is wiser than Him?
And in His wisdom He has chosen complete surrender
to His Mother.
To Him His Mother is Guru, She is Brahma,
Vishnu, Mahesha everything, even SadaShiva
is Her, – His Mother; nothing else.
And his power of Kundalini raising is within
you.
You’ve got it.
You are made after his power.
He is holiness, he’s auspicious, he’s
innocence.
A guru has to be innocent, has to be an innocent
person.
His innocence can be crafty.
But innocence should be crafty, he should
not be crafty.
Innocence is the power which works the craftiness.
It’s the Krishna shakti.
It does.
It works out.
Suddenly you face it.
You try anything it will be there.
And he depends on his powers and not on his
own methods of maneuvering things.
But how many of you are religiously working
it out morning, evening, every moment of life?
How many of you are thinking that we are on
the path of becoming full fledged gurus of
Sahaja Yoga and nothing else.
You are nothing else but that.
How many of you decide like that?
Every moment.
It’s very easy just to say, “Oh it’s
alright I don’t believe in it."
Then what are you going to do?
What are you without Sahaja Yoga?
Think of it.
You can say, “I don’t want to do it."
You’ll have to do it.
You are in it now.
You better do it.
You have to do it fast.
For heavens sake better do it fast.
Achieve it!
You have all the powers believe Me, you have
all the powers.
Believe Me, you are better than all these
gurus put together.
But be humble, do not talk big.
And do not become silent bores also.
I mean some of them are real silent bores.
They cannot be gurus I can tell you this much.
That’s another quality.
They’re absolutely boring people.
Nobody wants to stay with them.
I mean, you have to have people around to
be a guru, you can’t be a guru of yourself!
(laughter).
If everybody says, “Oh, he’s such a boring
person,” nobody will be there.
You have to be interesting.
You have to be dynamic.
You should know some stories here and there.
You have to make them laugh.
They should enjoy you.
This is Sahaja Yoga guruship.
You see for such boring gurus one or two would
stick on if they are equally boring or more
boring.
But such gurus are not going to help us in
Sahaja Yoga.
They are not.
You have to be joyous, cheerful, helpful,
understanding, concerned.
You have to be concerned about others.
You have to behave in a way that they feel
that you are the security for them.
But that doesn’t mean that you get after
one person.
You see, everything you tell them goes into
some sort of a mad mould, I don’t know how
it happens – whatever I say.
For example, I say you should be concerned.
Here I find that people start then, “Alright
I am concerned."
So they start working on a person.
And then they’ll come, “Mother my left
hand is finished.
Why?
I was working on such a person."
What was the need?
You need not.
That’s not your job.
Let them also work.
You must know how to make them work also.
Otherwise, you see these lazy lumps will use
you all the time.
Let them also, tell them to get up and work,
arise.
Why can’t they work it out?
They can work it out themselves.
But then don’t tell them, “Now you work
it out."
Not like that.
Then another extreme can start.
You should say, “Now see, you have a left
side problem and I don’t think that you
should make me work it out.
I think you can work it out, lets see.
I too had the same time type, let’s work
it out.
You better put your left hand towards the
photograph, put right hand outside.
Do this way that way.
Beat yourself.
Left side is Adi Shakti’s this thing.
You can ask for Mahakali’s powers it can
be worked out."
Give him all the knowledge say, “Now try,
try yourself."
Because if you’re obliging too much also,
then you make them dwarfs, you see.
You have to be a tree which makes others grow
into trees and not to make them dwarfs under
it.
You see, no grass can even grow under such
trees, leave alone trees.
Even the grass can’t grow if the trees are
of this type.
So you should be actually the tree of brilliance,
of sun, sun’s rays.
From you the sun’s rays should flow and
they should grow.
Not to obstruct every growth of your disciples.
What sort of a guru could he be, whose disciples
are all toddlers or still sucking their thumbs?
So you should be a guru of a caliber that
makes others grow too.
I have hopes that my disciples will grow more
than I am.
I have hopes we’ll see that.
That’s my desire, that’s what I want,
that my disciples should grow.
I mean, that will be my pride.
Like Ganesha grew more than His own Mother,
who created Him.
That’s what is My desire.
And that’s what I want you to realize that
you are the hope of the world.
Either you should not have taken birth in
England.
If you have taken, you have more responsibility
not to be English and to be universal, because
you have taken birth in the heart of the universe.
You cannot be small-minded.
You cannot be chicken hearted.
Either you are frightened or you are aggressive
– this is an impossible situation.
You have to be so strong that nothing should
make you frightened, and such a person is
the most benevolent personality.
He’s not frightened of anyone, why should
he harm anyone?
Today I hope you people really don’t listen
to my lecture but put it in your heart, and
understand that you have to become very dignified
majestic gurus of this universe.
I would like to ask William Blake what is
he doing.
When is he going to take his birth on this
earth?
When people of his caliber are going to be
born in this country, or they are all running
away again to some other place to be born?
Marriage system of England is wretched.
You cannot adopt those methods that these
people are having.
You want to have the great people to be born
to you and every time you are running towards
the divorce cases.
How can they be born in this country?
You have to give up all these wretched systems
of this country.
The good of this country should be taken,
whatever is good in it, and transform this
country into a beautiful thing.
I mean if you really love this country then
create it into a lovable place, isn’t it?
You must try to destroy all that is retarding
the progress, the spiritual progress of this
country if you are a real Englishman.
Real is the word.
You should not be proud of all the weaknesses
that have crawled up in all these hills and
dales.
All unholy thoughts, all inauspicious behaviors,
all must be discarded.
We are not that.