(UNCLEAR) as it is, hopefully.
Gregore
Yes Mother.
You better announce (INAUDIBLE)
Yes.The brides come in to to wash the
boys and everybody who is not a Br
Facing the boys you should stand, the brides should stand facing.
Each bride, if  she can recognize her future husband
Place the brides where please no mistake...
Please move in, move in this side all the brides.
(UNCLEAR) All right? And now, just face them,
and now you see and
now say that would you like to marry them.
Everybody should say, "Yes, come along."
Yes, Oui.
Don't wash. Just rub the earth like
substance, just rub it off without..
Rub it in a way that you can collect it.
Rub it in such a way that you can collect it to keep it afterwards.
[UNCLEAR]
Thank you. Beautiful.
[UNCLEAR] This there is going inside that.
[UNCLEAR]
With great love and affection, with kindness and sweetness.
Sweetness, with a sweetness.
Don't put it out with fingers.
Beautiful.
Actually it is not that in India.
Now anybody who does not want to have marriage after this
can decide that.
That's the chance.
Better wipe it nicely.
[UNCLEAR]
It's alright, brush it off.
Who? [UNCLEAR]
You could have brought the children.
I think we should have two rows, can't just fit there.
Can we have two rows of boys.
Just move on, just move.
Alright. Now when you take your photograph...
What about the boys, have you (UNCLEAR)
[UNCLEAR] should be more flowers.
It is called as"Jaimaal" (garland).
Come here. Hey come along, move few of you here.
Alright now look at your eyes.
Lift her veil, you have to lift her veil.
Now lift her veil not that, that's all right!
You put it back.
[UNCLEAR] this way. No, let it be in the ear, let it be. Yes, good.
Very good. Now this is the [VIDEO INTERRUPTION]
Stand behind there.
[UNCLEAR] You kiss her now.
[UNCLEAR] Good. Now kiss her.
You just stand here, alright.
Good, now please come.
What about the boys? Your bring them now.
[UNCLEAR]
No, its alright, you stand here.
Now put her a garldand.
Great!
[UNCLEAR]
Now those who are married should go at the back.
I mean those who have been garlanded.
I was looking [UNCLEAR]. Garland, garland, go.
So now all of you should walk with your brides there.
You can never do it justice. Never.
It's raining.
It's obviously getting someone video at Mother's feet.
[INDIAN]
[UNCLEAR]
May God bless you!
[UNCLEAR] you go for a new honeymoon now.
[UNCLEAR]
Come on.
May God bless you!
They are really surrendered, both of them.
In a second they accepted.
So well surrendered both of them, in a second.
See now, surrendering is the only way you get your vibrations.
May God bless you!
So I sit down here. You see, I think the girls have to sit in front
first and then the boys.
[UNCLEAR]
I think this you can move now to another end.
May God bless you!
Come along.
Mataji, can we start?
Yes, exactly. You put, I don't know where you put.
[UNCLEAR, HINDI?]
Alright, alright, bring her here.
Come along.
[UNCLEAR] I don't know where you put this [UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR]
Put your hands under My feet. Both the hands.
Now through you America should be awakened.
Wait, sit down.
Don't cry!
Don't cry or weep, alright? You're alright.
Olimpia, Olimpia, hello [UNCLEAR].
Love you so much.
What's the matter? Where you go? Let's start.
Good, very good, excellent.
May God bless you!
So put it in the center, somebody should and then...
You've taken your photograph?
Mmm, good?
Great!
(UNCLEAR)
It's alright, very good. May God bless you all!
Beautiful. Fine.
[UNCLEAR]
Happy?
Very good.
Excellent. May God bless you! Very good, excellent.
Everybody clearing out so much.
May God bless you! Excellent, excellent.
All of you.
So you know what we suggest you all
that there should be some people sitting on this side.
Can you come forward. Come forward like that.
Maybe you also, one after another.
You all can come forward.
Sit down.
That's a good wife.
Beautiful, beautiful.
[UNCLEAR in Hindi?]
Take her.
She wants to watch.
It is too much sound, it's all right.
Now say Ganesha mantra.
Om twameva sakshat Shri Ganesha sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagawati sakshat
Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah
Om twameva sakshat Shri Ganesha sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat Shri Bhagawati sakshat
Shri Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Ganesha sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti  sakshat
Shri Bhagawati sakshat
Shri Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi
namo namah.
Now one by one you can wash My feet with the same water.
You have to put your hands in this and wash My feet.
One by one. [UNCLEAR]
You put cold water.
He is first, he is a senior.
Hm, good.
It's good.
[UNCLEAR] to wash.
[UNCLEAR]
Come along, one by one.
And everyone  [UNCLEAR]. You can wash. [UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR]
Good now? Are you all right?
Not to feel guilty, not to feel guilty, not to feel guilty.
Keep on saying:`I am not guilty'.
I'm not guilty. Mother, I'm not guilty.
Mother, I'm not guilty. Mother, I'm not guilty.
Good.
Mother, I'm not guilty.
Done. Now see?
Good now? Beautiful. May God bless you!
Come along.
Look up.
Not, not. Not with the water, not with the water.
[UNCLEAR]
May God bless you!
Come along.
[UNCLEAR] all in that water.
Mother, I'm not guilty.
Good.
Good. Very good.
It's [UNCLEAR]. May God bless you!
Good.
Well done, all of you.
[UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR]. Now,
Om twameva sakshat Shri Mata
Om twameva sakshat Shri Maha Radni
Om twameva sakshat Devakarya Samudyata
Om twameva sakshat Akula
Om twameva sakshat Vishnu Granthi Vibhedini
Om twameva sakshat Bhavani
Om twameva sakshat Bhakti priya
Om twameva sakshat Bhakti gamya
Om twameva sakshat Sharma dayini
Om twameva sakshat Niradhara
Om twameva sakshat Niranjana
Om twameva sakshat Nirlepa
Om twameva sakshat Nirmala
Om twameva sakshat Nitya
Om twameva sakshat Nishkalanka
Om twameva sakshat Nirakara
Om twameva sakshat Nirakula
Om twameva sakshat Nirguna
Om twameva sakshat Nishkala
Om twameva sakshat Nishkama
Om twameva sakshat Nirapuplava
Om twameva sakshat Nitya mukha
Om twameva sakshat Nirvikara
Om twameva sakshat Nirashsraya
Om twameva sakshat Niranthara
Om twameva sakshat Nishkarana
Om twameva sakshat Nirupadhi
Om twameva sakshat Nirishwara
Om twameva sakshat Niraga
Om twameva sakshat Nirmada
Om twameva sakshat Nishchinta
Om twameva sakshat Nirahankara
Om twameva sakshat Nirmoha
Om twameva sakshat Nirmama
Om twameva sakshat [VIDEO INTERRUPTION]
Om twameva sakshat Nirabadha
Om twameva sakshat Nirnasha
Om twameva sakshat Nishkriya
Om twameva sakshat Nishparigraha
Om twameva sakshat Nisthula
Om twameva sakshat Nilachikura
Om twameva sakshat Nirapaya
Om twameva sakshat Niratyaya
Om twameva sakshat Sukha-Prada
Om twameva sakshat Sandra-karuna
Om twameva sakshat Maha-Devi
Om twameva sakshat Maha-pujya
Om twameva sakshat Maha-pataka nashini
Om twameva sakshat Maha-shakti
Om twameva sakshat Maha-Maya
Om twameva sakshat Maha-rathi
Om twameva sakshat Vishwa-rupa
Om twameva sakshat Padmasana
Om twameva sakshat Bhagavati
Om twameva sakshat Rakhsha-Kari
Om twameva sakshat Rakshasa-ghni
Om twameva sakshat Parameshwari
Om twameva sakshat Nitya-yauvana
Om twameva sakshat Yogada
Om twameva sakshat Ekakini
Om twameva sakshat Sukharadhya
Om twameva sakshat Shobhana-sulabha-gati
Om twameva sakshat Sat-chidananda-rupini
Om twameva sakshat Lajja
Om twameva sakshat Shubha-Kari
Om twameva sakshat Chandika
Om twameva sakshat Tri-gunatmika
Om twameva sakshat Mahathi
Om twameva sakshat Prana-rupini
Om twameva sakshat Paramanu
Om twameva sakshat Pasha-hantri
Om twameva sakshat Vira-mata
Om twameva sakshat Gambhira
Om twameva sakshat Garvita
Om twameva sakshat Kshipra-prasadini
Om twameva sakshat Sudha-sruti
Om twameva sakshat Dharmadhara
Om twameva sakshat Vishwa-grasa samatmica
Om twameva sakshat Lila-vinodini
Om twameva sakshat Shri Sadashiva
Om twameva sakshat Pushti
Om twameva sakshat Chandra-nibha
Om twameva sakshat Ravi-prakhya
Om twameva sakshat Pavankruti
Om twameva sakshat Vishwa-garbha
Om twameva sakshat Chit-shakti
Om twameva sakshat Vishwa-sakshini
Om twameva sakshat Vimala
Om twameva sakshat Varada
Om twameva sakshat Vilasini
Om twameva sakshat Vijaya
Om twameva sakshat Vandharu-Jana-vatsala
Om twameva sakshat Sahaja yoga dayini
I hope you have got the ring and keep it in the hand.
First the boy has to put the ring to the hand of the girl.
All of you have, you have?
If you can do after this a big havan [UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR]
Water please. Water.
Some four cups of [UNCLEAR] we can do."
No no, silence.
Please sit down all of you. All of you sit down.
The photographer sit down now.
Now during the wedding only one person should take photographs,
not all of you, alright.
Now ladies and gentlemen,
just to start with,
may I with the whole
my devotion in my heart
pay my respect to the Holy Mother.
Whenever I have been here
from Her Holiness I have myself
learned quite a few things.
Today also there is something more addition to my knowledge
and the tremendous work She is doing
I can not describe in words the marvelous job She has been doing.
And it is our good luck and we are all fortunate
to be guided by Her. She has got infinite wisdom
and I just express my heartliest respects to You, Mother.
And now this is how we have been able to manage that.
Now this place where, where the wedding is going to take place
is called mandap - the auspicious place.
And we are going to kindle the sacred fire
not ordinarily but as commanded
by the revealed books, that is the Vedas.
Vedas means the books of knowledge
[INAUDIBLE] [HINDI] "is awake"
and they were the revealed books from the Lord
and the sages were inspired by the Lord
and they spoke these [INAUDIBLE] called mantras
collected in the books we can call the Vedas.
Now we need the sacred fire here.
In every scripture of every religion
God has been spoken as a great light -
"jyothi light prakash".
So we need the presence of the holy [INAUDIBLE]
to witness the ceremony and they are going to have certain
pledges and vows at staying together to remain
truthful and honest to each other
in the presence of something which is bright
and there can be no better image
of the Lord among all the material objects of
the world except this bright light.
And for remove the darkness
may the light of God, the light of knowledge and wisdom
remove the darkness of our mind.
Whatever is going to take place outward
it has got something to just explain.
Hidden behind all that outward show is all symbolic.
Outside we have the symbols and behind the symbols there is
something hidden and that is the real ideology,
the real philosophy. And we shall be putting glasses
filled with water here. Water is, water signifies purity,
it's the symbol of purification that purifies everything
and it is also symbol of peacefulness.
When we put water in all the four directions
we always aim at the universal peace.
May there be peace all over the universe,
in all the directions. That is why we put water there.
And flowers are there. Flowers they symbolize
the freshness and newness of life.
You are going to enter a new life of [UNCLEAR],
so flowers are very very befitting on this
auspicious occasion. And also at the same time,
just as the sweet fragrance of the flowers spreads around,
pleases everybody, may the good men
of your families from were you come and
your larger family is now the family of the Holy Mother,
that spread like a sweet fragrance of the
flowers around the universe
and bring peace and wisdom reigning everywhere.
This is why flowers are there and they are also beautiful.
Now we have this ghee - clarified butter
that will keep the fire alive there.
And well of course pieces of wood are there. Then we have this
incense.The idea is just to purify the atmosphere
and where is havan samagiri? Yes.
The gentleman is holding this havan samagiri
and that one there and these are supposed to
consist of fragrant herbs, dried flowers, some spices,
things like that so that when they're burnt in the sacred fire
then they are consumed by it and they purify the atmosphere around.
This is what the idea is there and then we have (have we got water?)
[UNCLEAR]
Now this is the right side what you call,
is the material side of love, to be purified.
And for that fire is, as we always use fire,
as you know deepa (oil lamp) I know that you use it, in the same way
it is going to be purified with this fire and the water
as we use to remove that we that, we use water also
and the flowers. They represent the fragrance of the
Flowers are the highest in the matter.
In the same way you are the highest of those who are realized souls.
So what he is saying that this is to be purified and the matter
should be purified because married life
is the epitome of materialism.
If you cannot have a good married life all your materials
have no meaning at all, is zero.
And that's why your material side should to be purified,
sanctified, should be auspicious.
And that's why these are trying to purify the elements,
elements which have created our chakras, as you know that.
So elements must be purified and they have to be worshiped
and to be in such a way that all the deities
which are of these elements can be also awakened.
Alright? So this is the purification of the elements,
within us and without. Both.
(INAUDIBLE)
Vedas did that.
How it is related to Sahaja Yoga you can see clearly.
Now, Holy Mother (CONTINUES IN HINDI?)
So give them guidance, guidance from the source of our intelligence,
source of all life and existence, the Supreme Lord,
and the Supreme Mother, you can say that,
so we pray as is contained in the Vedas, in the Holy Vedas.
[HINDI]
Now this is going to be a very important beginning
with madhupark, madhupark is there, mixture of yoghurt and honey.
Honey is very pureful, very energizing
and when it is mixed with yoghurt it becomes a bit mild and cool.
And the idea is that the brides here
they will offer their own companions this madhupark,
something sweet expressing the sweet feeling of your heart.
This is called madhupark.
And where is that madhupark, please madhupark.
It's all symbolic, as he said, is all symbolic.
You should go around there to have start.
But this is a circle you can start from anywhere.
Circle has no beginning no end.
So the brides, the bride, every bride in here, take a spoon.
You'll pass the spoon from one couple to the other.
Hold the spoons, please. No, the bride will hold.
And you say after that you pass
[UNCLEAR]. First of all you will speak after me.
I will guide you speak. Every bride. All brides, not bridegrooms.
You wills say, "Om,
madhuparko
(MOTHER SPEAKS IN HINDI?)
All the brides should take it from the spoon. Come along.
In the right.
(HINDI)
They don't have all.
Everybody has a spoon?
No, they don't.
We need more spoons.
Sixteen I think. And we can spare one there.
Sixteen we got. [HINDI]
[UNCLEAR]
All of you take.
Only keep like that, only on the hands, holding on the hands.
Now.
All you are going to say
Now all the girls have to say this. And you speak please after this.
Om,
madhuparko,
madhuparkah,
prati-
grihyataam.
You are saying to your companions,
"Please accept this madhupark
prepared from yoghurt and honey
expressing my sweet happiness.
Please accept it."
See that...
And you give it to your companion
The sense is sweetness of marriage.
and they will taste it. Give them. Alright. Let them taste.
Come along.
You taste.
Because according to Indian marriage
the place where the ceremony is going to be held,
that belongs to the bride. She comes to wed there.
And he is given the good welcome.
So this the welcome you are giving to them because
he's coming to wed you here. But here you have
This is the bride's place.
Bride's place, yes.
At the moment, for the time being it's the bride's place.
Now I read the mantra that goes along with that.
OM! Yanmadhuno madhavyam
paramgwam roopamannaadyam.
Tenaaham madhuno-madhavyen paramen.
Roopena-annaadyen paramo. Madha vyonnaadosani.
Sweet is the [UNCLEAR], sweat is the wind,
our hearts are sweet, let our heavenly Father be sweet to us.
So now you can keep it here with you and you can take it out after.
Now Mataji, the basis of the marriage ceremony
that is kanyadaan, giving away
the hand of the bride's prospective bridegroom.
Of course Mataji will bless that.
And we can get about 16 people to do that.
Now, can 16 people
Who are acting as the persons who are giving the hand of the bride.
Come 16 please.
See every parent is there, 16 parents.
Everyone has got?
No, not all.
Why did you take out your garland?
Give it to [UNCLEAR] now.
Now please,
now all these parents, they are going to speak now.
Gotra? Now they have got different gotra.
[UNCLEAR]
Alright?
And now all the parents who are going to speak please attend here.
All the parents please
say after me, all the parents who are acting as.
Om,
kashyap
gotra
[HINDI]
and now the names of the bride.
You have to say bride, bride's. Only name of the bride.
[HINDI]
kanyaam
prati
[HINDI]
You have said, each one of you:
Please take the hand of my beloved daughter,
born in family with the surname Kashyap,
that's the surname of Mataji.
Kashyap is actually a realized soul, Kashyap.
Yes, he was a very great saint.
And my daughter who is present here well dressed
I give her hand to you, please accept it wholly.
And the bridegrooms are going to say, only the bridegrooms,
Om,
prati,
[HINDI]
Thanks, I accept her.
Your offer has been accepted. You can retire now.
Now we are going to kindle the sacred fire.
Now ladies and gentlemen,
can you please attend, very important things are coming ahead.
Very important things are coming ahead now, listen to me.
Now, now let's start from here.
You take this water both of you, in your right hand.
Somebody comes and goes around.
Give each of them, both, each of them.
This is the brother. This is the brother of all the brides.
Go around and give to each one of them, each one of them water.
Balha, give it to them, the ones you [UNCLEAR]
Go round.
Just a bit quicker, we have to do it three times.
To make it adjustment Mataji, I have learned the technique from you.
[HINDI]
You have to keep it in such a way that you should take it thrice.
Thrice. First time and second time you don't have to [UNCLEAR]
Take it in three gulps, take it. [UNCLEAR]
Not the whole lot but three times.
Now I explain to you the significance of sacred water.
As we started this water is purified
and it means peacefulness.
Water means peacefulness and it is purifier.
Now we are starting the ceremony [UNCLEAR] that concern you both.
Now you are going to sip water three times.
It means, "May your hearts be purified toward each other."
So that you have regards and also at the same
time your mind should be free from any tension.
They should be peaceful, at peace, when you are
starting the ceremony and you are going to sip water
meaning, "May God in the form of water purify your hearts
and you remain truthful and honest to each other"
when you are going to take the vows after that. Ok?
Both you follow every advice that he is giving, this is a vow.
Now you are going to
Live it there.
[HINDI]
One third of it.
One, one third of it.
God is our base, this is the idea.
Second time.
[HINDI]
Second time. God is our cover, we take his shelter.
The third.
[HINDI]
Each one of them, each one of you is saying,
"God, give us prosperity,
long life, fame and good health." This is what you are saying.
And Truth, Satya.
And Truth, yes.
And now you are going to have in the
left hand a bit and that will be over.
In the, on the left hand, go around.
You are the brother.
Just a bit quicker. Don't give [VIDEO INTERRUPTION]
Now with these two fingers. Astrologically they are
considered to be better, these ones.
Mean the first one, because that is the accusing one,
don't take that, take that,
the middle one, these one. And now you're going to touch
as I told you. Not do that, you'll start doing when I tell you.
With water you're going to touch mouth, it means,
"May our speech be purified with water,
so that we do not speak evil words."
And you always speak words of love towards
your companion, ok. That is the idea.
Speech is purified and then you are going to touch nose.
"May you always live in very good environment",
where there is no foul smell, and at the same time,
"May you have no breathing trouble at all."
Because a requirement of a person who starts
a domestic life is perfect physical health.
And then you are touching eyes. "May you always see
good sights, no impure sights,
not to see evil and your eyesight should be perfect."
Should be pure.
with very long life.
And then, "You should not listen to evil words there.
Your hearing should be purified."
At the same time, "May you enjoy the perfect path of hearing."
Then you are touching there. "May your arms be strong
for such [UNCLEAR] for the protection of the needy."
And you are touching there
It means, "May your legs also be strong
so that you always walk upright and nicely"
with no limping, nothing like that.
And then you are throwing water all over the body. It means,
"All the limbs of the body impact at physical health"
as the first requirement
for a house holder which you are going to be. Alright.
And all of the chakras we can add.
I'm taking a bit so that
When we touch the chakra and then Nabhi
[UNCLEAR]
Yesterday we didn't thought.
And you do as I do.
These two. This's all symbolic. Behind the symbol as Mataji has said
much lies here. And with these two fingers you can do as I do.
OM! VAANGME AASYESTU.
OM! NASORME PRAANOSTU.
OM! AKSHNORME CHAKSHURASTU.
OM! KARMAYORME SHORTRAMASTU.
OM! BAHVORME BALAMASTU.
OM! OORVORME OJOSTU.
OM! ARISHTAANIME-ANGAANI, TANOOSTANVAA ME SAHSANTU-U-U.
Now we are ready for kindling the sacred fires before us.
[UNCLEAR]
I think who should do now because everybody can't do that.
So should I do it on your behalf, with your permission?
Now I am representing all of you kindling the sacred fires.
And now the man with the havan samagri please comes.
Come here and give them in the hand to keep
a bit of stock in the left hand. Then they have to use it.
To everybody. And when I say "swaha
you are going to put it. Not the whole lot, just a little bit.
Keep it in your left hand.
In the meantime I kindle the sacred fire to save time.
Om bhur bhuvan swaha
OM! BHOOR BHUVAH SWARDYAURIVA BHOOMNA,
PRITHIVEEVA VARIMNAA.
TASYAASTE PRITHVI DEVAYAJANI,
PRISHTHEGNIMANNADAMANNA-DYAAYAA DADHE.
OM! UDBUDHYASWAAGNE PRATI JAGRIHI,
TWA MISHTAA POORTE-SAGWAM SRIJETHAAMAYAMCHA.
ASMINTSADHASTHE ADHUTTARASMIN, VISHWEDEVAA
YAJAMAANASHCHA SEEDATA.
OM! AYANTA IDHMA AATMAA, JAATAVEDASTE
NE DHYASWA VARDHASWA, CHEDDHAVAR- DHAYA CHAASMAAN PRAJAYAA],
PASHUBHIR BRAHMAVAR-CHASE NAANNAADYEN SAMEDHEYA SWAAHAA.
IDAM AGNAYE JAATAVEDASE IDAM NA MAMA.
OM! SAMIDHAAGNIM DUVASYATA, GHRITAIRBO DHAYATAATITHIM.
AASMIN HAVYAA JUHOTANA.OM! SUSAMIDDHAAI SHOCHISHE,
GHRITAM TEEVRAM JUHOTANA.
AGNAYE JAATAVEDASE SWAAHAA. IDAM AGNAYE JAATVEDASE IDAM NA MAMA.
OM! TAM TWA SAMIDBHIRANGIRO,
GHRITEN VARDHAYAAMASI. BRIHACHCHHOCHA YAVISHTHYA SWAAHAA.
IDAM AGNAYE ANGIRASE IDAM NA MAMA.
I'll do it for you this time.
Now ladies and gentlemen, after every hymn
I say "swaha". The meaning of "swaha".
"Swa aha - what is well said in the hymn
may God accept that prayer
recited by us." This is one meaning. Then "swaha" also means
"welfare of the mankind"
which means in anyway He likes. This is the idea of "swaha"
which you repeat everytime. Welfare of mankind
and self-surrender to the deity and then
what is contained in the hymn, may that be accepted by the Lord.
This is the meaning of the word "swaha". Then it is, again I say,
"idam Na mam". "Idam" means "this, "Na" means not, "mam".
"Nothing is mine in this world, everything belongs to God."
Therefore we say,"Nothing is mine, everything God has given to us
belongs ultimately to Him because He is the Creator,
therefore He is the Master." Ok, this is the idea there and now
after that I'm going to do that for you, on behalf of you.
OM! AYANTA IDHMA AATMAA, JAATAVEDASTE
NE DHYASWA VARDHASWA, CHEDDHAVAR- DHAYA CHAASMAAN PRAJAYAA],
PASHUBHIR BRAHMAVAR-CHASE NAANNAADYEN SAMEDHEYA SWAAHAA.
IDAM AGNAYE JAATAVEDASE IDAM NA MAMA.
OM! AYANTA IDHMA AATMAA, JAATAVEDASTE
NE DHYASWA VARDHASWA, CHEDDHAVAR- DHAYA CHAASMAAN PRAJAYAA],
PASHUBHIR BRAHMAVAR-CHASE NAANNAADYEN SAMEDHEYA SWAAHAA.
IDAM AGNAYE JAATAVEDASE IDAM
No, not yet, I will tell you.
OM! AYANTA IDHMA AATMAA, JAATAVEDASTE
NE DHYASWA VARDHASWA, CHEDDHAVAR- DHAYA CHAASMAAN PRAJAYAA],
PASHUBHIR BRAHMAVAR-CHASE NAANNAADYEN SAMEDHEYA SWAAHAA.
IDAM AGNAYE JAATAVEDASE IDAM
OM! AYANTA IDHMA AATMAA, JAATAVEDASTE
NE DHYASWA VARDHASWA, CHEDDHAVAR- DHAYA CHAASMAAN PRAJAYAA],
PASHUBHIR BRAHMAVAR-CHASE NAANNAADYEN SAMEDHEYA SWAAHAA.
IDAM AGNAYE JAATAVEDASE IDAM
OM! AYANTA IDHMA AATMAA, JAATAVEDASTE
NE DHYASWA VARDHASWA, CHEDDHAVAR- DHAYA CHAASMAAN PRAJAYAA],
PASHUBHIR BRAHMAVAR-CHASE NAANNAADYEN SAMEDHEYA SWAAHAA.
IDAM AGNAYE JAATAVEDASE IDAM
It means, "Oh sacred fire, kindle.
Oh Lord, remove the darkness of my mind", which is ignorance,
"and give us health, long life and truthfulness,
honesty, give us wealth, cattle wealth, movable property,
immovable property so that we do not misuse that
but use it for good things, good works."
This is the idea in hand. Than after that
I will do it for you, we have to do a bit more.
OM! AGNAYE SWAAHAA. IDAM AGNAYE IDAM NA MAMA
OM! SOMAAI SWAAHAA. IDAM SOMAAI IDAM NA MAMA.
OM! PRAJAAPATAYE SWAAHAA. IDAM PRAJAAPATAYE IDAM NA MAMA.
OM! INDRAAI SWAAHAA. IDAM INDRAAI IDAM NA MAMA.
OM! BHUR AGNAYE SWAAHAA. IDAM AGNAYE IDAM NA MAMA.
[HINDI]
Now these are the names of God,
different names of God. God is One, Reality is One,
but the Reality is spoken by many names.
[HINDI]
"Truth is One, Reality is One but it is covered by the wise men
by different names." Ok? Sometimes we called it "shakti",
sometimes you call it "jagadamba", sometimes you call it
"the merciful lord", "the blissful lord",
the "all knowing lord". These are the different names of God.
He is the same God. Sometimes he's called "prajapati",
"the sustainer of the universe", "creator of the universe",
he is called "Agni"- the great light,
he is called "swar" - the great word that
inspired the sages and we have got these Vedas and shruti.
And sometimes he is called this "prana"- the vital breath
which is so nearest to us, on which our lifes depends. He is
so nearest to us, really the source of our lifes.
All these are names of One Supreme Reality.
Now after that, Mataji, may I have some mithai sweetnies?
[INDIAN]
Now this is another symbolic gesture,
something sweet representing the
blessings, the sweet blessing [UNCLEAR] that He has given to us.
So then we take a portion of that,
make the offering in the sacred fire
which is representing the Holy Lord at this time,
then the idea is, "Oh Lord,
all these sweet blessings which you have given to me
I offer to you because nothing belongs to me.
You are the Creator, everything belongs to You, nothing is mine."
That is the idea there. So all these you'll have. In the right hand.
Pass it on [UNCLEAR].
Pass it on, yes.
[UNCLEAR]
Take a bit of this. The other one helps.
holding in your right hand the sweet. [UNCLEAR]
and when I say "swaha" you [UNCLEAR].
So I read the mantra. And all those who have
having that please throw it in there.
[HINDI]
There is also [UNCLEAR]
"If we have missed some part of the ceremony,
if we have not been able to perform the ceremony perfectly well,
may God accept it our hearts love
and ignore our drawbacks or faults." Ok?
Now the next thing that starts
you are going to put this, little bit out of that,
little bit of. Well, I will do with you.
[HINDI]
Now "Gayatri mantra",
the great hymn, he is also called as "Guru mantra"
because at the time when the
disciples went to the guru for education,
spiritual education or any such like education,
he is taught by the guru, the guide,
this mantra. This is called "Guru Mantra"
This is also called as "Gayatri Mantra",
"gayatri" means the mantra that protects us.
"Gayatri" also means poetical meter
in this mantra has [UNCLEAR].
And it is also called as "Veda Mata" -
"the mother of the Vedas", it's the most important of that.
And that protects us like Our Mother
if we chant it with devotion. It's also called
as "Surya mantra", "Savita mantr" and "Savitri mantra"
[UNCLEAR] power of the Lord. It is a very holy mantra
and the meaning is, "Om", the meaning of "om" is "our saviour,
our protector" and it is the most sacred name of God.
[HINDI]
"God is all existence, all pervaiding,
all knowing" and "swaha" - "of blissful nature."
[HINDI]
"And may we meditate on His bright glory and may we always remember
[UNCLEAR] - the power of the Lord
that burns our sins."
[HINDI]
"May our mind and intellect be always inspired with a noble cause."
This is the mantra, gayatri mantra, so we chant it three times.
[HINDI]
Put all the samagri there, all the samagri there.
All the samagri, all. Just wait, just wait.
You are still holding that.
[UNCLEAR] don't put anymore please.
Now, more than half of the ceremony has been done
and the real ceremony, the wedding ceremony that should start now.
Now, first of all, may I...Gath Bandhan, Gath Bandhan.
Somebody, someone help me by tying one end [VIDEO INTERRUPTION]
[UNCLEAR]
The real part of the ceremony
[VIDEO INTERRUPTION]
... with the bridegroom, she goes with him.
This has been the custom everywhere.
So you ask after the marriage you will be
taking her to live with you in your house.
Mother, I will be [UNCLEAR].
You have to give assurance to her,
you have to give assurance to her [UNCLEAR]
You are giving assurance to her,
"Look, you are going with me as my wife,
you shall be respected in our family,
you shall be given all hospitality,
and you are going to protect the house." This is the assurance, ok.
And you all, the bridegrooms
can you speak after me, all of them please.
Om,
[HINDI]
You are saying, each one is saying to each
your own respective or appropriate friend
you say, "I hold your hand before the sacred fire,
before this august assembly I assure you, you shall be
respected in our family and you shall
be treated as a goddess of [UNCLEAR]".
And you also repeat, you say, "The most high
and most merciful God has given you to me
in the presence of this sacred fire, in the presence
of the Holy Mother , in the presence of whole assembly."
Again you repeat [UNCLEAR] again bridegrooms should do.
[HINDI]
Each of you is saying to the appropriate lady here, you say,
"I repeat I hold your hand. You are very auspicious.
You are my dear wife and I am your husband
and I shall love you with all my mind, with all my heart."
This is what you have said, you have given her the assurance.
Now they will stand and they will
join you. You've saying the pledges.
[UNCLEAR] [VIDEO INTERRUPTION]
Ok? Now,
both of you, and the first of all, this is on behalf of the
bridegrooms again. You will speak after me and you are,
and you are addressing her. Please after bridegroom you say.
[HINDI]
You are telling them, "Please be firm willed and strong minded
like this solid piece of rock so that nobody
succeeds in sawing the seed of enmity
and jealousy between us." You have addressed your brides like that.
And now here I'd like to explain a bit.
Now you have used the word in this mantra as the "stone".
Now there are three kinds of significance regarding the stone.
Stone represents solid thing, something very strong.
Your marriage ceremony is on the foundation of strong stone.
And it is unshakeable. This is one idea. The other idea is
stone also represents the obstacles in life
and you say, "Put your foot on the stone,
never get defeated, overcome the obstacles of life."
There are many times difficult times in life,
you have to overcome that, not get defeated, understand?
The third idea is become strong as I have told you already
so that nobody succeeds in sawing the seed of enmity between you.
Now here the next time all of you...
Mataji, now they'll be ready to go round.
Remove that. Now,
every bride here is saying this prayer
and these are the beautiful prayers everyone of you is saying.
The first says,
[HINDI]
The first prayer is the wife says, "May I continue
to receive the love of my husband."
You need to come around there.
She says, every wife says, "May I continue
to receive the love of my husband." Second
[HINDI]
Second prayer is, "May my husband and myself enjoy
long life and good health." Third,
[HINDI]
The third is, "May the family of my peers", each one of you say,
"we have good relations with each other. May we be blessed with
prosperity and God always guides us
on the right path." These are the third prayer, ok.
And you are going to [UNCLEAR]
you are going to go around the sacred fire.
Please don't go this way, this is the right way.
And the first round, "May God give us the knowledge of Dharma
and keep us righteous minded."
And the second one is, "[HINDI] May God give you
economic prosperity", second round.
Third round means "[HINDI] happiness, domestic happiness
with your companions. And the fourth is
"moksha" - God realization.
These are the things everybody needs to have in the lifetime
because the wife gives these preachings to the husband.
Therefore wife will lead in the first round
the respective husband, she will be ahead
and husband would be following her.
And then when I... Don't start yet please.
So the first round starts and when the first round
finishes you come and stay in the same position you are now.
Look, the same position you are now here, ok.
The first round start, "May God give you right".
As I was telling you, it is with the cooperation of the wife
that the man gets dharma, he remains righteous minded
if she cooperates nicely at home.
Secondly "[HINDI]". If there is peace at home the husband is able
to earn money or the wife can also earn money
wherever they go for work if the peace is kept at home
because she is the lady of the house,
therefore it is on account of her cooperation
that there is economic prosperity in the family.
Therefore she will lead in the second round also.
The third "[HINDI]". If the wife cooperates
there is happiness in the family, much depends on her.
She is the very important person in the household life
and therefore she also lead in the third round.
And in the fourth the husband will lead.
He gets realization only if the wife
cooperates in these three ways. And then
he also leads because wherever he goes
he will take his wife with him. He will not
go alone on holidays, he will take her
with him. She is not only the wife
but she is also the most intimate and trustworthy friend.
Therefore he will take her wherever he goes.
Now the first round will start this way
and I keep off that side. Please keep off the fire.
Wherever you are you have to come back
there and stay in the same position.
[HINDI]
Walk please.
Walk walk, everbody walks
so that everybody's able to walk.
[HINDI]
Go around please, full circle,
full circle, keep moving, keep moving.
You know when you are standing, you have to come back here.
[HINDI]
Go on.
Keep moving.
May God gives you the knowledge of dharma.
May you remain righteous minded.
Alright, you've, I'll presume you have taken one circle, allright.
Now second, second. [VIDEO INTERRUPTION]
[HINDI]
Again move, the second round. "May God give you",
each one of you "economic prosperity."
[HINDI]
Keep going.
I take it for granted you have done the second round.
Now the same three prayers the wife she is repeating there.
[HINDI]
Third round, "May God give you happiness, domestic happiness."
Move on please.
[HINDI]
Third round has been taken.
And now the last round. Now the husband now will be leading.
So the husband please, husband, come before your companion.
The husband should come, husband should come before.
Now the last round.
This is collectivity.
And this is, "May God give you God realization"
with the cooperation of your wife of course
and so (slowly) and wherever the husband goes
he takes the wife with him. He hides no secrets from her
because she is most trustably worthly, a sacred companion
and very intimate friend and you have to just take her
into everyone's hands and you to trust each other.
This is the fourth round. Responsibility on the
shoulders of the husband is very very great here.
Realize that and move on while husband moves on this round.
[HINDI]
Now the very important part of the ceremony is coming
and after that most of the ceremony would be over.
[UNCLEAR] two minutes after, nothing more.
Now the most important which is Mataji also spoke that word there,
that is "saptapadi".
You're going to walk seven steps together with your companions there
Now when you walk harmoniously before people outside
it is very impressive. You walk in harmony,
in peace, in a friendly way
that gives you the lesson here, an instruction here
that in your domestic life also you have to act harmoniously.
Just as outside walking harmoniously is
impressive, in domestic life work in harmony,
learn the lesson adjustment and accomodation.
You are not going to force your will, none of you, on each other,
but adjusting each other, accomodating each other,
not forcing your will but adjusting in a cooperative way,
that is life, if life is such harmoniously just taken
in the family, in the household
that is just like life in the paradise.
Otherwise that becomes the reverse of that which, God forbids,
never comes in anybody's life. So you please
are going to walk 7 steps together.
But how to, now how to [UNCLEAR] ok.
The first step, and listen to the significance of the first step,
and take the first step, stop it and wait for the second step now.
And with your companions, hold her hand
together, hold her hand together now
so that you know who is your wife, hold her hand.
So you are walking with them together
in harmony the first step and wait to
to understand the meaning of that.
[HINDI]
Take the first step please, first step, stop here.
The first step meant,
"We take the first step towards unadulterated food, pure food."
Because on the supply of pure food
depends one's health and it is very important.
And so the second now, take the second.
[HINDI]
Second step towards strength. "May you be powerful and strong."
And third please.
[HINDI]
Take the third step towards wealth and prosperity.
Wait for the fourth please.
Yes, now fourth.
[HINDI]
Take the fourth step towards happiness.
Take the fourth step towards happiness, move on.
Now, waith for the fifth. Fifth.
[HINDI]
Take the fifth step towards children. "May God bless you
with children with nobility of mind and long life
so that the continuity of the family
goes on and on." So take the fifth step.
Have you taken the fifth step please?
And now wait for the sixth one.
[HINDI]
Take the sixth step towards self-respect. You have to be
with self-esteem many times in your family life,
and also best health throughout the season.
You have taken the sixth step. Now the last step please,
and then what will happen in last step please,
please listen. In the last step
now when we started the ceremony you remember
the wife was to the right of the husband.
Now she is going to be to the left of the
husband. You're going to change after seventh step has been taken.
Now seventh step is coming, very important.
[HINDI]
Take the seventh step towards stable companionship.
"May your marriage be stable, unbreakable."
Seventh you've taken. Now the husband
to go to the right of the wife, wife to come
to the lef of the husband. Change the position.
We can now, sit now. You can sit now. Please take your seat now.
Still more enjoyable.
Now after that I tell you
why the wife after the marriage remains to the left of the husband.
Not that she is inferior in any way or she is a junior partner, no.
Now every wife now will know she is near the heart of her husband.
That is the idea there. After the
marriage in the heart of the husband
there should be only the "pratima" or "murti" of the wife
who is the trustworthy friend and she
is near that, she has occupied her
appropriate place which is the place of wife
to remain to the left to the husband near to the heart.
And that is now according to
our Dharma Shastra the ceremony is valid now
when you have walked the seven steps together.
Now after that I am going to put the auspicious mark
on their forehead.
[HINDI]
Give them sweet, give them some.
Yes yes. What are you holding there, see.
Is that? Yes, thank you very much.
Now, alright I start from here.
Circle we have that wanting in a circle you can start from anywhere.
Yes please.
So I start from the right. Where is the husband now?
[HINDI]
You put it on her
and take, draw the line, take it above. Take more color.
Yes please [UNCLEAR].
[HINDI]
And also the line there, deep line.
On the Sahasrara.
She is now, everyone of you, is now putting the
red color on the line on the head.
You are saturating the companion with your love.
So this is the color of affectionate love.
[MOTHER SPEAKS IN HINDI]
Yes, here [UNCLEAR] now listen to Mataji to what She say.
That is the realization, that is why we put the color.
Pass it over, little little to everybody,
little, you have to give them
little little, take it out and give it to all of you,
all of you. May God bless you!
Half of this then take half after. Take it out.
A little little, take, all of you should have.
[MOTHER SPEAKS IN HINDI]
[HINDI]
In such a way that she doesn't go on.
Now you are having sweet, each one of
you is having your supply of sweet.
Now the bride takes a [UNCLEAR] to the mouth of the gentleman.
[UNCLEAR] and you say, and the husband says
[UNCLEAR]
And look at the photograph, [?RAUL]
Now you are feeling in the way you are looking after each other.
It's from the other side also.
Again please, expressing the free feelings of your heart,
looking after each other. May you always look after each other well
We can finish with that.
[UNCLEAR] here also.
Tiny little birds that feeding each other.  Very nice [UNCLEAR]
Now you hold your mangal sutra after finish feeding each other.
Take mangal sutra. Now you are putting the mangal sutra.
Where is your mangal sutra? You don't have?
Mataji, mangal sutra?
He doesn't have.
Who doesn't have?
We're quite a lot.
In the back [UNCLEAR], no?
I think they were taken out of the boxes, Mother.
They were taken out.
How many do you need?
One, two, three, four, five. Five only, Mother.
Very good, very good idea.
So you, now don't you laugh, you just take the garland
and take that mangal sutra, ok. Don't take it out, just touch it.
[UNCLEAR] let them have a look.
Just wait.
Your garland, ok. Now I'm leading the mantra please
and you do it, just attend to me one of you please.
[HINDI]
Now all those others who're watching the marriage ceremony here they
will speak after me, also we can go.
[HINDI]
We have said, "May you be happy,
may good fortune be with you." We have blessed them.
Now flowers, I want flowers now.
When [UNCLEAR] ceremony we need flowers,
give us flowers there.
Somebody to take the job of taking down this basket of flowers.
What shall we do with the rice?
Ah well, hold it, just hold it.
No, yes, you hold it in your hands, throw on them.
Make a bigger cirlce please, bigger circle.
Make a bigger circle.
Now, where is your...? Yes, he's there.
Now let me bless them saying the holy mantra
and after that when I say only then you will
throw on them please. Now first of all let me tell on.
[HINDI]
Now the idea of that mantra is
that "May you see 100 autumn seasons,
100 spring seasons, 100 summer seasons.
You enjoy long life but at the same time with
very good health so that all the life time
are active and do your duties,
family duties and outside duties.
And may you show respect to your elders
and show kindness, love to your youngers.
And may you always speak to each other
with words of love and always look after each other well,
and remain true and faithful
companion and friends to each other, always trustworthy."
That was the blessing. Now you are going to
Don't please throw them in one lot but three times.
Put two portions in left hand and one portion in the right hand.
Wow, stop stop.
I have to say the mantra.
You are very impatient, they are also impatient.
And say please [UNCLEAR]:
[HINDI]
[UNCLEAR] ceremony yet.
Now [UNCLEAR] by the grace of the Lord
the ceremony has been happily concluded.
So this is what we are going to do.
[HINDI]
Everything created by the Lord is complete and perfect it is always.
Now the hymn of peace is the last hymn, peace for mankind.
[HINDI]
"May there be peace in heavenly region.
May there be peace in mid regions.
May there be peace on earth. May the water flow peacefully.
May the herbs, shrubs and crops grow peacefully.
May Brahma, the Supreme Lord, be in peace.
May all the vishwadevas, divine powers, be in peace.
And may that peace come onto me.
And may the peace itself is beneficial to mankind
and may that peace to everybody."
Om shantihi, shantihi, shanti.
That terminates, Mataji, concluded.
Again please.
Shri Bhagavati Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi ki Jay!
Bolo Shri Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi ki Jay!
[UNCLEAR]
While each wash the feet of Mataji
we all here say the mantra of Mataji.
Sahasrara.
Om [VIDEO INTERRUPTION] Shri Mahalakshmi
Maha-kundalini sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Mataji sakshat
Shri Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi
namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Gauri sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat
Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Kalki sakshat
Shri Sahasrara swamini
Moksha dayini Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Can you do up the Kundalini, Mother?
We start with Shri Ganesha.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Ganesha sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat  Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Gauri sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Saraswati Brahmadeva sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Kamala Vidya sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Fatima Hazrat Ali sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Lakshmi Vishnu sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Mataji sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Gruha Lakshmi sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Shesha sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Adi Guru sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Jagadamba sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Shiva Parvati sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Sita Rama sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Radha Krishna sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Vishnumaya sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Yeshoda sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Hamsa swamini sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Mary Jesus sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Buddha sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Mahavira sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Kalki sakshat
Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Kalki sakshat
Shri Akasha swamini Moksha dayni Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Om twameva sakshat
Shri Mahalakshmi Mahasarawati
Mahakali Trigunatmika
Kundalini sakshat Shri Adi Shakti sakshat
Shri Bhagavati sakshat Shri Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devi namo namah.
Bolo Shri Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi ki Jay
Bolo Shri Bhagavati Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi ki Jay
Devyam Mataji Shri Nirmala Devi ki Jay
[UNCLEAR] what you have to do. You should not be stubborn
[UNCLEAR]
And not feel bitter at any point. Just try to be sweet.
In the beginning especially when you...
And don't go on demanding.
Sometimes we feel we have a wife or a husband who
it's a office of demand, it's not giving. Alright?
Must learn to give and give and give,
all the time. Enjoy the giving part.
Now where is the knife? Can we get the knife?
There is one coming, Mother.
Alright.
Sixteen is a very auspicious number, you know. Sixteen plexuses.
Is for the Virata, for the collective.
Now I hope collectively all of you who are married today
will try to make your married life extremely
successful and an example for others.
Try to be sweet, nice to each other. Be kind.
Actually you should enjoy. That's the thing you don't know.
Must learn to enjoy.
Everybody is looking so beautiful.
Only thing you must learn to enjoy.
And put your ego on one side first of all.
All the egos are the things that stop your enjoyment, absolutely.
It's the ego that stops your enjoyment. Finish it off.
Tell him not to come in between
because he will just spoil everything.
He tells you, "Dont do this otherwise
you see she should take advantage of you."
Or she, if she is sitting "she'll take advantage."
No reservations in marriage between
husband and wife, no secrets, nothing.
Just be kind.
And you should not say something that is not to be said.
For example one of the keys aspects, about your past life.
Never talk. Forget it, it's over now.
That's something very wrong, talk of the past life
and to be very confessing. There's no need.
Talk of something nice. What you are going to do, what you are going
to achieve and you are going to have.
And enjoy. Not of your past life, it's over, forget it.
Alright? Be kind to each other. Be nice to each other.
Enjoy is the point. Those who enjoy the most their married life
are nearest to my heart. But they should be in Sahaja Yoga.
Those who enjoy married life without Sahaja Yoga are stupid.
Alright, so here I have to cut for the bride [UNCLEAR]
All of you, I'm cutting down here, alright?
May God bless you all. May God bless you all.
Now somebody (now you can take it there)
Now somebody who is an expert
[UNCLEAR] I don't know
Anybodiy who sings you can do it.
John. David.
Alright, David you can offer [UNCLEAR]
Light all of them. [UNCLEAR]
Now what song you sing for a happy married life?
Happy marriage to you, happy marriage
dear people, happy marriage to you.
to you, happy marriage to you,
happy marriage dear people,
happy marriage to you.
Blowing out, we're going to have these blown out.
And the blowing now, who is supposed to blow it, Me?
Yes, Mother.