his musicians all of them are so young
we must have seen and one is a blind
fellow and with realization they became
so dynamic so now they want to play for
me and sing for me because they got it
too you see
and the one who has composed it was a
chartered accountant he never knew and
is any do or renew
I mean political language but he's
become appointed emotional music and
musical devotional music is sung by
people who are realized Souls reaches
your heart reaches your Kundalini and
helps a lot awaken them so if there are
these are all realized Souls so where
there the dancer everybody the dancer
was playing the rhythm and the rhythm it
is a divine rhythm because she is now
become a realized soul she's connected
with the divine so when she dances she
creates her divine rhythm and when these
people sing
they also sing a divine devotion
otherwise without connection if you sing
the praise of God it doesn't reach God
because you are not connected like a
telephone which is not connected if you
start telephoning your telephone gets
spot so for devotion also you should be
connected with God so as they're
connected with the divine the music
image
vibrations what to call the divine
vibration as a result it creates an
atmosphere for people to receive the
realization it becomes much easier for
me to give realization because that
masseur cleanser rinses out and people
also get ready for realization because
they're realized Souls all of them so
this is the reason why I was very happy
they could manage to come they're all
professionals and they have agreed to
come here and do it further just to help
me in sahaja yoga and also you will be
surprised that this music is very
difficult indeed music is a very
difficult music it's not easy for people
to sing unless until you go into big
practices but it's so amazing that when
people get realization all these people
who are Western are people from 40
countries they all can sing these songs
with same depth and with same
understanding without making any
mistakes even in pronunciation otherwise
it is so difficult to pronounce a state
even Indian language is so difficult
that they could not even pronounce a one
sentence property and now the whole song
is has to song any song this thing's
over and you if you close your eyes you
won't believe that they are foreigners
who are singing who have never known
this language so something has gone
dynamically new in them that they just
pick it up and sing so well
of course very much music is is is a
divine gift to human beings it's a
divine we call it starts with Omkara
means the first word is that was we call
as locusts it starts with that and
that's that's a proof of it because the
when they get their realization how is
it they know such difficult language and
such difficult tunes and so correctly as
they can see it's very surprising so
music is a very inner part dancing music
all art is very kind much connected with
the divine now we have had many artists
who have been realized Souls because a
Michelangelo was a realized soul and the
way he painted hence it emits vibrations
you see if you see Mona Lisa and by they
are not of the wind say it has
vibrations it gives you abrasions those
people who were realized Souls like
Mozart when you play Mozart you get
vibrations out of it you can feel them
on your fingertips you can feel so there
are musicians who are realized Souls
also artists also people like Abraham
Lincoln was a realized soul Gorbachev is
realized so he's also a sage so when
these people are there how will you make
them out and she was asking me you have
to just put your hands towards them and
you can feel it