we are here to inform you about a power
which is within us and the power that
can give you what is promised by all the
saints scriptures and all the
incarnations today when you see the
young people in every country especially
in the West you'll find they are not
satisfied with their own atmosphere
their lives
and they think there is something
missing and they are extremely confused
now when they are confused they are
seeking for something beyond something
unknown to them in that seeking they may
take to anything extreme
drugs
could be alcoholism
or some other perversions which cause
horrible diseases incurable diseases
instead of condemning them we have to
see why they are doing all these things
what is the purpose
also some of them went to some gurus
which are in the market
especially when they see the religious
people and the religions they cannot
believe that religion can give such
horrid experiences
and some of them are anti-god
anti-religion also
but if you deal with the problem
sympathetically you cannot blame them
because they are intelligent aware
people
so now we have to category of people one
the ones who are not seeking at all
and another are the ones who want to
find out solutions of the problems
in every generation we had people who
revolutionized because they did not like
a particular system or did not like a
particular style of life whatever it was
but now the revolution has to come from
within we have to evolve from within
because the destruction is also coming
from within we are destroying ourselves
more from within because we are so
unhappy so confused
absolutely quite a percentage is peace
or anything so then we start seeking
this solution and in that seeking we
make mistakes
and we make mistakes because we do not
know what to seek
and how to find
also how to evolve to that state
so logically we have to reach some
conclusions logically that it has to be
some evolutionary happening this is
logical to transform ourselves there has
to be some evolution so like you have
said that you have to become
collectively conscious you have to
become it's an actualization it is not
just a certificate it has to be come
from within it's an honest thing it's an
innate thing it is not just a preaching
or sort of a giving a certificate it is
not or taking a name it is actually a
ssin within yourself so that something
has to happen to us now as we have
evolved from monkey stage to this stage
for example we've done nothing it is a
living process
which has taken place spontaneously
there's a big resistance to any oriental
ideas being accepted in the West weak
resistance I find it's a very big
resistance for any oriental ideas coming
to the West
now these oriental ideas which are
coming are to be seen with a scientific
open mind
because
the Western life has grown like a tree
outside but the roots may be in the East
maybe we can keep ourselves open to see
where are the roots
now if the roots are in the East
supposing it's an hypothesis so let us
have a look at it if there is any
solution in those so you go to oriental
I guess but there also is very dangerous
because you are going in the unknown you
might go to false gurus you might go to
wrong people and get completely
destroyed so what do we do first thing
we should know we cannot pay for our
evolution we cannot pay money is not
there
nor can we pray for any living process
any living process we cannot be like if
the seat has to sprout the mother earth
is sprouted we don't pray the mother
earth all right so first thing they
should have known that anybody who asks
for money is not a truthful person no
money should be more then the second
point comes in that we got to this stage
of human awareness spontaneously without
any effort effortlessly
in the same way it should happen
but first of all in every evolution
there has been one leader
we can call them as archetypes as they
say or whatever you may say want to say
so you was not very clear on that point
so now such a person can decode the
information of symbols and everything
and can help others without taking any
money without taking any gratification
can do it and here it is that people
fumble in the West they don't mind a
pope they don't mind an archbishop of
canterbury but they do mind a person who
is doing everything free just out of
love
you'd be amazed in England the
television people told me that we cannot
accept anything which does not take
money can you believe it is a fact in I
think in Boston or somewhere they asked
me a question how many Rolls Royces you
have got this is a chance at least then
the most important thing which is not
realized by modern mind that they
believe anything new is to be tried is a
very dangerous thing
if we are dealing with the living
process of evolution we have to know
that
in spiritual life whatever is going to
happen must relate to scriptures to all
the Scriptures must relate to
not to one scripture say for Holy Bible
or Holy Quran or any but to all of them
because it is like a seed that sprouts
and it becomes the stem then the
branches then the leaves then the flower
and then the fruit living process it is
based on something evolves through
something but whatever is dead like we
can create a fruit plastic fruit from
nowhere just like that you see so which
has no basis
has no meaning it must have a basis from
where it has come its origin must be
seen
as in the growth of the tree all that is
useless drops out in the same way in
evolution also all that is useless drops
are even useless tradition drop out
everything drops out but ultimately you
reach to the epitome where you become
the fruit
so the time has come for human beings to
become the spirit so every seed has
Kamri all right and the same way within
us is our Camry is the Kundalini
and this is to be actually awakened
actually awakened now in sahaja yoga we
have thousands of people all over the
world there are people who are we can
call them the highest in the society
there are people who are the lowest in
the so-called society all of them are at
par with each and every person there is
no higher lower feeling everyone belongs
to that society so it belongs to that
society moreover when this happens
because we understand what these
incarnations where the conflict of all
religions drops out like that we
understand it on central nervous system
the conflict drops out there is no
question of not worshipping Christ
Muslims Jews Hindus all worship Christ
they all worship Muhammad SAW and they
all worship Rama Krishna Odyssey because
actually they see that when the
Kundalini Rises she passes through
certain centers and there you have to
take the name of those great
incarnations so this is the knowledge of
the roots and one must know that you
have to become a subtler being to
understand that knowledge as a result of
Kundalini awakening you can claim many
things but that can be seen that cancer
can be cured so many incurable physical
diseases can be cured mental diseases
can be cured
drug addiction can be cured
the problems created by these gurus can
be cured
all these things can be done when you
become the spirit but this should be
just at a level of a hypothesis when we
do it and it's proof then you should
accept not blindly there is no blind
faith in sahaja yoga we have no priest
troops
nobody is paid it's a free society
and everyone becomes very knowledgeable