First time when I came to United States, I
came to Los Angeles first.
Because, it’s a place of angels.
Actually, I thought that it must be a very
holy place to come down.
First of all, in this great land of United
States.
Now, as you know that United States or America,
the whole of it, is the Vishuddhi chakra.
Out of which, we have three sides to the Vishuddhi
chakra.
So, the central part of the Vishuddhi chakra
is United States.
The central part of the Vishuddhi chakra is
governed by Shri Krishna.
And His power is Radha.
“ RA - DHA “ .
“RA” means energy, “DHA” is the one
who has sustained the energy.
“RA - DHA”.
“dha-re-ti-saa” .
So, she’s the one who has sustained the
energy, and so, she’s called as Radha.
She’s the power of Shri Krishna.
The word Krishna comes from the word - krishi,
means - the plowing, or you can say, agriculture
is called as “krishi”.
The one who plows and puts the seed in the
soil, is doing the krishi.
And, that’s why he’s called as Krishna.
Now, the seed that he has sown, is the seed
of spirituality.
It is Shri Krishna who said, in sanskrit - “nainam
chindanti shastrani nainam dahati pavakah
na chainam kledayanty apo na sosayati marutah.
” meaning - it
cannot be, means, the spiritual life or you
can say, the eternal life, or the spirit,
cannot be killed by anything, by any weapon,
neither can be blown away by air, nor can
it be sucked in, nor can it be destroyed.
So, to prove that, Christ came on this earth,
and through his resurrection he proved, what
Shri Krishna has said.
And most of you Sahaj yogis know the relationship
of Christ and Shri Krishna - why he was called
Christ.
Christ word comes from the same - Krishi.
And, his first name comes from the word Yashoda.
Yashoda is also called as je-su or ye-su.
And that’s why (Krish) Christ was called
as Je-su or Ye-su.
Some people call him Yesu, and some people
call him as Jesu, because of Yashoda (the
mother), the foster mother of Shri Krishna.
Also, you know that Radha was the same as
MahaLakshmi, so she was the same as the mother
of Christ, Mary.
These, all these things we can prove it in
Sahaj Yoga.
Because, when the Kundalini moves up to the
Vishuddhi chakra, and if it stops there, you
can ask the question - (“Was Krishna the
son of mother Mary - no) Was Jesus the son
of mother Mary?
Was the son of Ra, was the same as Radha,
and then the Kundalini moves.
So, Sahaja Yoga today is a thing which proves
what has been said so far.
It proves.
It’s not just a cock and bull story.
Because people do not believe into all these
things.
They think that it’s all cock and bull story.
Who was Christ?
Who was Krishna?
Who was Radha?
After all, there was no God.
But only in Sahaja Yoga, today, we can prove
it, that what we say is the truth.
Because, as through realization, you get connected
to the mains.
Your vibrations start flowing.
Like the computer, you start working.
And whatever question you ask, answer comes
to you as tremendous vibrations, or it stops
or you might get heat or you may get blisters.
So, the whole message is communicated to you
through your finger tips.
As Mohammad Sahab has very clearly said, that
“at the time of resurrection, your hands
will speak”.
But the muslims do not want to talk about
resurrection at all.
Because, they want to frighten people with
the doomsday.
They don’t want to talk about the resurrection
time which is going to come, which is the
intermediary time.
Because they want to use the time, which will
frighten people by saying that “now your
doomsday is coming”!
Now, your doomsday is coming, so everybody
is frightened about God and they think that
now we should just wait for our doom, nothing
else is in between.
So, this is how the Vishuddhi chakra is a
special one.
Now Vishuddhi chakra (is) was created on the
Saturday.
So, it is the Saturn - that’s the important
star of the Vishuddhi chakra.
So, whenever the Saturn is at the highest,
America will be in a better place to do things.
But, I don’t think they know much about
themselves.
They don’t know what they are, why they
are on this earth, what is their work, what
they are supposed to do, or what is the purpose
of God of creating America.
The first job of the Vishuddhi chakra within
us was that, when we became human beings,
we raised our heads up like that.
When you raise your head up like that, you
have become a human being, in the sense that
now, there is a new movement in your consciousness.
Now the new movement in your consciousness
started about 6000 years back when Shri Krishna
came on this earth.
That the new movement was, that it is the
Father.
The advent of the Father was celebrated, and
that’s how people developed a kind of a
new instrument within themselves, called ego.
When the brain was lifted like this you see,
it expanded in a pyramidical - it’s a pyramid
- it became a pyramid.
In an animal, the brain is flat.
And, gradually it rises.
When the head was raised, when the responsibility
was taken of raising the head, the brain started
growing in such a way that it became a pyramid.
And when it became a pyramid, the attention
became a different attention from that of
animal.
Because, when the waves of your consciousness
fell on the sides of the pyramid, they went
into the parallelogram of forces, by which
the resultant force - the resultant force
- now, it falls like this, goes like that,
the resultant force is like that - had two
sides - one was this, another was this .
So the consciousness, or we can say, the attention
- instead of going inside, started going out!
So, one part of the resultant was going outside
and that’s how, when you became a human
being, your attention went outside.
Is the human beings only, who have their attention
outside.
Not that the animals don’t have, but the
attention of human beings are such that they
create reactions.
Like, you see something.
Now, I see Doctor’s house for example, then
a reaction starts in my mind - what is this,
what does this mean, how much it must have
cost, from where did he buy it!
Anything you see, it starts giving you a reaction.
Not to the animals.
Animals, at the most they will say - this
I must eat, that I must eat, that I must get!
But, they do not think about it.
It’s only the human beings who reflect.
And this reflection comes because of the pyramid-like
structure of the brain.
And, this has a special reaction in the brain
itself, that we start developing our own ego,
our own myths, our own mental projections.
And when we develop our own mental projections,
this ego starts developing - I know - what’s
wrong, all these nonsensical things come.
And once that starts working out, the balloon
of the ego starts rising.
It starts pushing the other balloon which
was within us, is of the superego - as an
animal.
And then, comes up in the center.
That’s how we now become normal human beings.
But then we start increasing our ego.
It starts overlapping the superego, and a
calcification takes place, by which we develop
our I-ness.
So, it is all the happening that takes place
after we have lifted our head, raised our
head, and we are no more like animals.
So, Vishuddhi chakra has a very big part to
play in the human evolution, that by developing
your Vishuddhi chakra, you have become human
beings, first of all.
Secondly, because it is the chakra of the
father, who becomes again, the primordial
- as you call it, in a (marathi).
macrocosm.
You become the macrocosm.
You are the microcosm, and the father is the
macrocosm.
So, you become that because of the Vishuddhi
chakra, which is governed by Shri Krishna,
who becomes that macrocosm, called as Virat.
In the brain it is expressed in this part
In this part of the head.
It is here that you start manifesting your
macrocosm qualities - at this point.
Now, this Vishuddhi chakra has a speciality
- is that, we always say that the responsibility
on my shoulders.
Always we say that - the responsibilities
are on my shoulders.
The reason is, the Vishuddhi chakra gives
you the sense of responsibility.
And that’s why you know, the Americans feel
responsible for the whole world.
Naturally!
It’s perfectly understood, that they feel
responsible for the whole world.
But how much they are aware of their role
as the responsible people, that’s a different point.
But they feel, they are responsible, but their
role, as responsible people, if they understand
that they have to be ideals.
Ideals.
Because a person who is a responsible person
in a family, has to be the ideal for others.
It started very well, I should say, at the
time of Abraham Lincoln.
It started very well.
When you started talking about democracy,
is also - democracy is nothing but collectivity.
He started talking about the collectivity
of the people, by the people.
All that shows that the sense of collectivity
started coming right in this Vishuddhi chakra.
But then, people who are in the center, can
only remain normal.
But those who bend too much, or who bend backward
too much, both suffer from problems.
The ones who bend forward to others, are the
people who get their superego.
They get over-humble-down, like developing
countries are.
And those who bend backward, are the people
who try to dominate others.
Who have ego.
So, because of sudden blessings of God, they
discovered so many things.
The ego started developing in America too
much.
But ego is like a balloon, as I told you.
And, keeps you floating in the air.
And when you are in the air, you become shallow
people.
You have no moorings.
But, it has one more advantage, if you knew
you are floating in the air, you can have
a complete comprehensive view.
Complete vision of the Whole, if your eyes
are pure and your intentions are clear-cut.
Now (the) another thing that happens by their
coming here, was the problem, that they felt
that - we are a very new nation.
It has an advantage, as well as, it has a
disadvantage.
Advantage is that if you are new, it’s very
good because you can be transformed into something
better very easily, because there is no conditioning
in your mind.
You are very clean, absolutely ready, to become
something (?).
Or else, can be possibility that, you are
so new that you are awed by everything that
is old, which is very true about Americans,
that they bought all the old bridges from
England to bring them down here.
And the cravings about the old is too much
here.
And that, as if whatever is new, is all absurd!
So, maybe even Sahaja Yoga maybe an absurd
thing for them.
Because according to them, this is something
new.
Because they are new nations, they have started
discarding all that is new.
Is an absurd thing.
Now, we must say that Sahaja Yoga, as it is
today, is the most ancient thing.
It started with the universe and now the culmination
point has come, because it is a living process.
As you see a flower on the tree, it’s the
first new flower.
But the flower has come out of a seed, which
has got the roots and then it became the trunk,
then it became the leaves, and then it has
now become a flower.
So, though it looks a new flower, it has a
big heritage.
In the same way, Sahaja Yoga is as ancient
as this universe is.
But to people, who have such a hankering for
traditionalism, find it difficult to find
out what is real tradition.
Only those who are traditional people, can
know what is real tradition.
Last time I came here, in America, and I was
shocked that a person came to interview me.
And when he was talking, he asked about one
gentleman who was most untraditional from
Indian point of view.
His name was Ramakrishna Paramhamsa.
He married a woman and made her a mother.
I mean, it’s,
nobody has done it.
Rama has not done it.
Krishna has not done it.
It’s an absurd stuff.
But for them, he was the most traditional
man.
And he told me that , mother your Sahaja Yoga
is not traditional if you don’t believe
in Ramakrishna.
Last fifty-sixty years, all such neo-traditional
people came up.
Another one was this Pondicherry fellow.
Another absurd situation.
He called this woman a mother, and his relation
with her is ambiguous.
You don’t know what relationship they had.
I mean that is something, in Indian tradition,
is an impossible situation.
You have to have clear-cut relationship with
everyone.
You cannot have ambiguous.
Neither a friend, nor a wife, nor a mother
or a sister.
That kind of a situation is most untraditional.
Is never thought of.
I mean, you Indians can know this is not possible.
This is an absurd situation.
But, for some people, he is traditional.
What happened, about sixty years back, I think
about the time of my birth only, the negativity
started taking a new form in understanding
the western confusion.
They are all western in this, if you see them.
And the western confusion they took over for
their own advantages.
They used it for their own advantages.
And this is where the western people have
failed to make them out.
The other day, at the Jungian place, I was
to talk to Jung people with Sahaja Yoga and Jung.
Now Jung, I came to know only when he died,
because there was a little article about him.
I never studied psychology.
Of course, I tried to learn some vocabulary
to talk to them.
Sometimes I thought, I may have to talk to
them also.
But these Jungians, all very intellectuals
and great people sitting before me, you see.
(not clear)[I won’t heard of them?] the
President of American Jungian society.
I’d just gone through a book, just before
starting it, and I saw some diagrams
which really puzzled me.
The first conception they had, of course it’s
all mental conception of Jung.
I don’t blame him because he got realization
but he did not know how the state was created,
was what the framework of the state and his
movement was still of a seeker to find out
how he got his realization.
And, all movements were linear.
They were not expanding from one point all
over.
So, it was not so integrated.
Now, the thing they showed was that at the
bottom of it was the unconscious, which is
never going to be conscious.
On top of that was the (conscious) unconscious
that can be conscious.
Then, there was subconscious and on top of
that was the ego.
I mean what a mess of a thing it was I tell
you.
I told them, see, now the word unconscious
itself is confusing.
What do you mean by unconscious?
Whatever you don’t feel on your central
nervous system is unconscious - alright?
But, what does that mean?
We don’t feel the subconscious.
Then, subconscious is also unconscious.
Whatever we don’t feel - for example, there
are certain sounds of certain frequencies
we don’t hear at all.
We hear whatever is tolerable to us as human
beings.
That you all scientists know.
We don’t hear everything.
So, all that is unconscious - means it’s
a mixed bag.
All sorts of things mixed up together.
But God is not a hodge podge person you see.
He is a clear-cut gentleman.
He knows what he is doing.
He is the greatest organizer.
And, how can he put you into a bag like that
- that the unconscious is below, then on top
of it is the unconscious that is going to
be conscious, on top of it is the subconscious,
on top of the consciousness, on top of that
the ego!
So you go down, carrying all this inside you
and where do you go?
Now, how do you go?
So the first mistake was that there are layers
one on top of another - it’s not so.
They are placed vertically.
The ego is on the right hand side and superego
on the left hand side.
The future on the right hand side and the
past on the left hand side.
So the subconscious on the left hand side
and the supraconscious on the right hand side.
And the central path is kept clear cut.
I mean in any organization, say if you go
to the airport, do you have like this that
you have to pass through the walls to go to
the aeroplane.
If we human beings don’t commit such horrible
mistakes, how can God commit such a mistake?
So it was absolutely wrong to think that way.
So, the central path is in the center while
the right side is on the right side and the
left side on the left side.
And you don’t have to go to the subconscious
at all.
Because they justified all these people who
are trying to make them hypnosis or they are
trying to hypnotize them or to give them a
new type of a - sort of an experience - all
that was unconscious, we should accept that.
Even some people if they start suddenly jumping,
they say - oh that’s great.
So the sensations that you get from the subconscious
and the supraconscious
were accepted as something great.
It was a confusion of your intellectuals I
should say.
Complete.
But it is not so.
Your path is straightforward.
Absolutely for Kundalini.
Only thing, the one who has to raise it had
to come - that’s all.
But otherwise, it’s all very well, there
is no need for you to get into that horrible
subconscious.
When I told them, they were amazed.
They said - Mother it is so simple.
I said - it’s very simple.
Your unconscious is divided into four.
One is the collective subconscious, one is
the collective supraconscious, one is - you
can say - the collective hell, and on top
is the super collective consciousness.
So where do we have to go?
We should know our destination.
Then, we have to reach.
And that is how the problem of all these people
getting entangled with Muktanand.
Yes, they asked me a question - What is wrong
with Muktanand?
Why is he so dangerous?
One lady, poor thing, as Sahaj would have
it, she came, she said - oh I went there,
I broke my back and I’m finished once and
for all.
He’s such a dangerous man.
He flattered me.
I went there and I don’t know what has happened
to my back.
I can’t sit for more than ten minutes in
one place, I have to get up.
And I have a vibrator, I have to always put
it like that.
So I said, see the dangers.
Then the another theory they started that
we must suffer if we have to go to God.
Why?
I mean that’s not God’s idea by any chance.
Why should you suffer?
He made Christ suffer for you - finished now.
You better not suffer.
There’s no need to suffer at all.
So, all these ideas penetrated into these
western people.
And these mental projections - they accepted
without even understanding what is written
in other books.
We should see.
And they could only go as far as the sixty
years where all these horrible people who
went to India, very shallow people.
They saw some of these tantric books, because
they wanted to justify Freud through Indian
culture.
So they got the tantricas, erotic things and
all that and brought these books and some
of them read - I don’t know what books - to
say that Kundalini is in the stomach, somebody
says in the brain.
I mean they don’t know where the Kundalini
is.
They are writing such big big books.
Can you imagine?
Such big big books they have written.
Now, when the books are written, every book
is not a scripture.
But to them, if it is written in the book
you see, it’s a scripture.
And that’s how the whole confusion started
going on.
So these people came down, took full advantage
of it and now they have become great gurus
with lot of money.
Rich people.
But now, as the hand of God is great, one
by one, they are getting out of the heads
of these people.
And now I hope a day will come when people
will see the light.
So the task of Sahaja Yoga is to establish
the truth within yourself.
It is not that we can have membership.
We cannot have a person enroll into it.
We cannot call them as branded Sahaja yogis.
It’s the growth of the person - that is
to be seen.
Now there are so many lectures which I have
given about ritambhara pragya and all these
things and I think for every sahaja yogi it
is necessary to listen to those lectures,
go through it, understand them and to meditate
so that you grow.
Because it is not a plastic thing that we
can create.
It’s a living process of the living energy
of the living God.
And so, it has to grow.
By thinking you cannot make it grow but by
not thinking, you allow it to grow more and
more.
As it starts growing within you, then only
you realize what you are.
That’s the only way you have to reach that
state of superconsciousness and establish
yourself there.
Then only you will know what I’m talking
about.
Now today’s puja is another thing.
Now, what is a Puja.
Can you people say what a puja is?
Actually yesterday I had a puja and it’s
not easy for me to bear the pujas to be very
frank you know.
Because the vibrations are so much that I
don’t know.
And then, I went to the airport - two hours
we took out the vibrations and put them for
all the New York airport.
It was necessary.
It worked out.
Because vibrations start flowing with tremendous
force and if you people do not absorb it,
it takes time for it to ooze out from my body.
Makes me rather heavy with it.
But, then it oozes out and I feel better and
only thing that happens by saying the mantras,
you awaken the deities within yourself and
start receiving the vibrations.
And when your deities are awakened, they are
awakened through the power of the deities
within me - they have to work very hard to
do that, and that’s how they emit too much
vibrations which must be absorbed by you when
your deities are awakened.
That’s how it works.
You cannot describe it in words.
You cannot tell it in words.
It’s a happening that has to take place.
Many people who come to Sahaja Yoga first,
can go little bit like that
in the beginning.
Gradually they settle down, come round, grow
into it, then it becomes alright.
Some people just shoot off in one day, and
they are there.
Makes no difference whatsoever.
Because it’s a growing thing and it has
to grow.
With some people , the land is so fertile,
or maybe something, that it just works out
fast.
So, nobody should blame anyone.
And specially, one should not feel guilty
because that’s the vishuddhi on the left
hand side.
Specially for America, I’m wearing this
stone which is called as the black sapphire.
Because, this is the stone of Shri Krishna.
It’s the stone of Vishuddhi chakra.
Every chakra has a stone.
And this is the stone of the Vishuddhi chakra,
so I’m wearing this, just for coming to
America.
And, I hope that today’s worship will bring
out the potential of this country by exciting
the deities, Shri Krishna himself, who is
in charge.
By pleasing him.
By making him active.
And, he has great qualities, and one of the
greatest qualities he has that he has the
- sanwahra shakti - by which he can kill the
demons.
And, all those demons who are settled down
here, are really mistaken.
Because, if this is the place of Shri Krishna,
they are very dangerously placed.
Because once he is awakened here, they all
will be completely finished through his sudarashan
chakra, which he has in his hand and he can
just kill them one by one.
But first he’s to be pleased, and he’s
to be awakened, he has to be “prasanna”.
That’s the word.
Prasanna means, to be pleased.
And then, it works out.
So today first we will have Ganesha’s puja,
little bit, because Ganesha’s puja is meant
just to establish the innocence.
The innocence of the place.
Once the innocence is established, that’s
the most important.
That’s the essence of everything.
Ganesha is the essence.
And, then we will have Shri Krishna puja and
then the puja of the Devi of the Power.
So, that’s how we’ll have three pujas
- one after another, but a short time every
time.
Alright?