Now I have been already with your fiancés
and I talked to them.
I have praised you a lot.
Now first thing we have to know that this
marriage ceremony that we have organised with
a purpose.
The first purpose is that regard marriage
is very essential for Sahaja Yoga.
If somebody doesn’t want to marry, we say
alright you get out of Sahaja Yoga.
It’s alright.
Now why marriage is important, because a marriage
is like a big Yagnya, it’s like a big Tapasya,
you can call it, or it’s a great experience.
How to achieve balance, how to become a witness
and how to become a spirit.
It’s very important.
Now the first and foremost thing we have to
know (is) that he is your husband and nobody
else is your husband.
Nobody is more important than he is.
See men are very easy to be controlled.
If you can make them feel they are the most
important people for you, then you can manage
them very well.
But the first foremost ambition should be
or the idea should be that I will make my
married life extremely happy.
Because if the married life is happy you will
be happy.
Now men have a habit of sometimes losing temper.
Doesn’t matter that’s their habit.
So you shouldn’t immediately become the
same type.
But you can little bit in a womanly way try
to put your sweet device of smiling it or
laughing it out or little bit [showing you
nice?] somehow.
But not to make it serious.
It’s very important.
So how to handle the men.
Especially your husbands is an art and that
art you will achieve gradually when you start
seeing.
But if you start finding faults with the men
and start saying you can’t do this, you
can’t do this, you don’t know how to drive
or how to do this, or this things.
Then you are finished.
You must say you are the best driver.
You are the best.
That’s the way you have to deal with him.
But not that you are befooling them.
Because you say this because you love.
And love is the basis between you and him.
Nothing else.
Not Money.
Not what you have got for him or he has brought
for you.
Nothing of that.
All these things are not materialistic.
They have nothing to do with matter.
Love is something which you can express also
through matter, sometimes by giving some nice
presents or nice food or something.
But the most important thing is your heart.
You should not cheat.
In anyway you should not be hypocritical,
and you should not try to do something that
is not pure.
So in Sahaja Yoga, the purpose of these marriages
is to have you connected internationally.
So you all transcend all the barriers of your
nationality, the barriers of our racialism,
barriers of caste, barriers of so much materialism.
So you should not compare your husband with
anyone.
He is Your husband and you shouldn’t expect
too much from him.
He’s not given me this, he has not done
that for me, he’s like this.
This is not necessary.
You must always think what I have done for
him.
Also what’s wrong with me?
Now some people, especially in the west it’s
very common, that after marriage they think
that they have to work out marriages, no working
out.
You see like they think that as you work out
your kitchen or work out your things.
It’s not like this.
Spontaneously between the two human beings
who are realised souls.
It is not that you are working out anything,
but spontaneously you are going to enjoy,
spontaneously.
Now if you become extremely critical and try
to show you are very brilliant and this.
It’s not going to work.
To be humble.
Keep quiet.
Those who are really intelligent always keep
quiet and watch things.
But those who are not, are bumptious.
The more you are in Sahaja Yoga, the more
you will be respected by him and by everybody.
Apart from that, there are so many saints
who want to be born.
Once you have very happy married life among
yourselves, those saints will be born to you,
and it will be such a blessing and joy for
you.
So try to understand not to boss your husband
or try to put him right or do things and in
a very.
I have seen some ladies who are extremely
tense, very tense type.
They can never give joy.
They are themselves not in joy, how can they
give joy, are themselves not in joy.
So the tension should not be there.
At all of any kind.
Be relaxed.
You are the other side of SahajaYoga, which
gives peace, joy, nourishment and also complete
tranquillity.
In the family you are responsible for tranquillity.
Even if husband is angry, children are fighting,
if the mother is tranquil you can control
all the situation.
So the situation has to be controlled in a
way that you make life happy for everyone.
Sometimes women feel very angry when I tell
them that first feed your children, your husband
and then you eat yourself.
Because that is the job of a woman.
Like a man should go, earn living, do what
he wants to do, job and all that.
But the woman has to really look after the
husband, look after the family, look after
everything.
Also you will find our Indian husbands not
so good, as far as gardening is concerned,
or you can say, they don’t know how to mend
anything like cars or your plumbing, they
don’t know.
So doesn’t matter, take it easy.
Gradually they will pick up and they’ll
learn and they’ll do it.
But don’t become impatient with them.
Just make fun of it, you see, just make fun.
That the best way to manage it and that don’t
expect too much, that they will do this nicely.
Sometimes they cannot clean the utensils properly,
they don’t know how to do it.
So alright.
Just make fun of it and just enjoy it because
they have [unclear].
You see in England or America I have seen
anywhere, they have no servants at all.
While we have servants here so all these boys
are spoiled by the servants.
So they are absolutely good for nothing as
far as these things are concerned.
But if you just try to teach them and help
them, they will definitely go all out to do
it.
So the only thing you have to do is to love
them with a clear heart.
And all the time forgive and let them know
that that she is the only one I have in the
whole world apart from the Holy Mother.
Of course, I’m not against divorce, but
I’m not for it.
In the sense that I don’t like people when
they divorce.
But when things are impossible and difficult
and one has to go in for such a thing, doesn’t
matter.
Sometimes one has to do it.
But it should be very rare.
One should not think of a divorce at all.
People think of divorce in the west mostly
because of the laws, because the wife gets
the money or the husband gets the money.
But in SahajaYoga if you are marrying, all
these things even if you are divorced, I will
not support.
Moreover, another thing is that the wives
should not take money from the husband and
send it to her relations.
Never.
It’s a very very wrong thing, is to support
your family through the money of their husband
Absolutely not allowed.
That should not be done.
They.., you should not put the pressure of
your family on your husband.
You see there has to be a clear cut understanding
for all of you.
That you will not take.you must keep your
self respect.
Don’t ask for anything.
If he gives you anything [unclear] well and
good.
But don’t ask, don’t demand.
That means you are not a Sahaja Yogi.
If you are a satisfied soul why should you
ask for anything?
Or somebody gets something, she has got this,
she has …Nothing of that kind.
You be satisfied and this is how some girls
nag the husbands very much.
Most important thing is that you should not
talk about your past, at all.
Because past is finished.
Now you are Sahaja Yogis.
You are all realised souls.
So you don’t have to say a word about your
past.
Even if husband starts talking you just stop,
and tell him we are to live in the present.
Don’t tell us about your past.
I don’t know why people think that they
will look more attractive if they talk about
all the past nonsense they did.
Or say that my mother was so bad.
All psychological nonsense.
Not to put your parents into jeopardy by saying
that they are very bad, they are no good.
This, that..
Just forget the past and live in the present
because in the present resides the reality
and the reality is the ocean of joy.
You should not nag him for anything.
Supposing he didn’t like something, you
shouldn’t do it.
Whatever he doesn’t like, small things,
you know like, I was married in a family which
was culturally very different, very different.
And they don’t wear flowers.
You see, and in India all the married ladies,
I mean down south, I’m saying in my community,
all wear garlands around their buns and [unclear].
Always wear.
My husband said no better not do it.
Because you know here in our community only
the bad women wear that to attract man.
Since that day I have never worn it.
Doesn’t matter, not important.
So, also you must understand now you have
to take to the style of life of your husband.
He is fond of entertaining, look after that.
Women should be entertaining, they should
look after.
They should not mind if somebody comes to
stay with them or lives with them.
They should not try to show.
On the contrary they should be happy they
are able to look after someone who is a Sahaja
Yogi.
So, for the Sahaja Yogis, you must keep always
your heart open, your house open.
There are so many things which I would like
to tell you but in this short time, I have
to just say that it is the responsibility
of the women to make their marriages happy.
Depends on their intelligence and on their
dedication to Sahaja Yoga.
It’s your responsibility.
And if you see in a wider sense the responsibility
of making a good society is that of a woman.
Even if she has to suffer she can.
She is like this mother Earth.
She can suffer anything She never feels she
suffers.
She is so great.
You are Shaktis.
So as Shaktis if you have to suffer, you don’t
mind.
And what you have to feel is that we are responsible
for making our Sahaja Yoga society a perfect
society.
That’s our responsibility.
All your greed, all your ambitions, everything
should be directed towards making a very very
happy married life.
I wish, I wish all, all of you, a very happy
and prosperous married life.