We
have today come to this famous place, Hyderabad,
which was ruled by Muslim kings, but they
were very Indian and they fought also for
the independence of India with the British.
You know about Tipu Sultan, who was also a
realized soul but he was killed.
We have in our country one very big problem
and that is, individually we are all great
people, but when it comes to collective we
don't know how to live collectively, and that
is why we lost our independence. Anybody can
manage us. If we can open our eyes and see,
it is quite easily understood that when people
try to talk ill of others, involving us, there
must be some intention. This has been our
failing since long, that people use such methods
that they spoil the relationships. And this
should not crawl into Sahaja Yoga. When I
am in India I think I should put some light
on our weaknesses also.
The second weakness we have, that we are very
involved with our family; with our children,
with our parents, with our brothers, cousins,
this, that. Till you are completely deceived
or cheated by someone so close, you'll never
learn a lesson. We`are very involved; all
our problems are around them. We cannot get
out of our family. All the time we start thinking
that: "Sahaja Yoga should help my family.
Sahaja Yoga should do this for my family."
In Sahaja Yoga there's another family that
has nothing to do with your family. I have
seen people, Sahaja Yogis who are of a very
high level, and suddenly I find they have
gone down. They have no reason to suffer in
health or in any way. Then I find out that
they're attached to some brother or someone
who is doing some other kind of guru business.
Instead of we influencing them, they start
influencing us. So we have to really break
our relationships with all such people who
are negative, because we have had relations
and relations and relations all our lives.
What did we get out of them? If we do not
understand how important it is to be a Sahaja
Yogi, that you are the instrument of God Almighty.
So many things you know that even Brahma,
Vishnu, Mahesha did not know. They didn't
know much about Kundalini. They didn't know
how to raise the Kundalini. They didn't know
how to give Realization, except for gurus.
Out of them also you know that Janaka had
only one disciple. All of them had one each.
So certain things you know are more than anybody
had known before. But still if you are sticking
on to your old standards and old methods and
confusing them with Sahaja Yoga, identifying
with them as Sahaja Yoga, then your growth
will be very little. So I have to tell you
that, try to get out of this. “Who is my
brother? Who is my sister?” Of course it's
a good thing to be attached, in a way, to
the duties that you have to perform towards
everyone, but all the duties should be done
in such a manner that you do not get involved
into it. It is very important that you should
not get involved with those duties. Whatever
has to be done you should do, but you shouldn't
worry as to the fruit of it. Talking ill about
others, saying things just to spoil the relationship
is sin, in Sahaja Yoga. Always talk good things
about others. For example, if somebody comes
and tells Me that such and such person is
not good and all that, I tell them lies. I
tell them: "That person was praising you so
much. Why are you saying all these things
against that person?"
So it is important for Sahaja Yogis to create
a more synthesis, more coordination, more
combinations and more bringing in more and
more people. But people get more attached
to the negative people than to the positive
people. That means still you are not in Sahaja
Yoga fully. Once you start understanding this
it would be very, very clear-cut what you
should do and what you should not do as far
as these relationships are concerned. I mean,
in India it's a common thing for a minister
to appoint his nephew, his son, his wife,
his grandson, even his servant into some post.
It's a common thing, whether they are capable
or not. But in Sahaja Yoga you can't do. You
have to be a Sahaja Yogi. You can't just get
anybody because he's your relation and ask
that: "Mother, see now, he's my relation.
Please help this man." Why should God help
people who are not Sahaja Yogis? He does not
know them and He doesn't want to do it. So
our concept about family life has to change.
Of course the best thing you can do for your
family is to bring them to Sahaja Yoga, but
if you are sticking on to people because they're
your family, it's very dangerous.
Then there is second kind of a movement with
this behavior, that you start thinking about
your own city: "This is my city." You could
have been born anywhere. So: "My city. Mother,
You come to my city. Is important." It's like:
my home, my relations and my city. Then, my
country: "This is my country. Mother, You
must come to my country." I understand. Your
concern is good, it's patriotic, that you
are worried about other people in your own
country. But there should not be any attachment.
One should be detached, and detached in the
way, I would say, that just watch. Just watch
yourself and others. See for yourself, why
are you so much interested in your own country
or in your own capital? Why? Why is it? When
you ask this question you'll be surprised,
mostly you'll find: "Because I belong to this
place, I was born in this place, that's why
I want." Mostly; honest answer. But could
be that: "I want also that these people should
become Sahaja Yogis. It's easy for me because
I am from this place, I would like them to
be Sahaja Yogis." This is one of the basic
reasons why Sahaja Yoga does not spread, that
we get involved into pockets of our family
and we don't go across them to others. So
all our attention, all our behavior is completely
entangled into something which is not Sahaj.
So we have to go beyond and know that our
family is different. The whole world is our
family, so we have to move out. Don't get
stagnated or entangled with a small circle
of few people who are negative, but go beyond
them, because you've got the powers, you've
got everything. You can easily cross over
these barriers and see for yourself that you
are feeling now mentally very happy, physically
all right, and spiritually you are there.
In our Indian society people take to sanyasa.
They'll wear [SOUNDS LIKE "KASHAI"], go out,
many people after certain age take to sanyasa.
Why not take the sanyasa inside just now?
What is the need to wait till you get old
and then absolutely haggard and then to say
that you are a sanyasi? Even anyway you are
a sanyasi at that time, but when you are young
you should develop this detachment, a clear-cut
detachment: that is, you are attached to Sahaja
Yoga and to nothing else. Nothing is more
important than Sahaja Yoga to you. Once we
decide that, then you move in that line and
you grow in that line very mildly, very well.
But supposing you get short-circuited and
move somewhere else, then how can there be
growth? It looks extremely simple to us: we
must help our relations, we must help all
other ones. To Indians it is very easy, it
happens to them very easily. But the Western
people are not like that. They will not go
about, wasting their energy about their relations
normally. They are worried about themselves,
and they want that they should achieve the
highest themselves.
Now, once we take away our attention from
the family, you'll be surprised how this attention
works across the family, across this small
little wall that we have built. And you are
surprised how it expands, and how it gives
you all the blessings and all the grace of
Divine love. We always start thinking about
our relations, about how to be kind to them,
how to be nice to them. Or all these things,
all these behaviors of how to be nice to them,
how to be good to them and all that, can be
extended so much, can expand so much. As you
love them, as you care for them, as you are
attached to them, if you get attached to Sahaj
then the light will spread.
For example now, near Hyderabad there are
many small cities, small places, lots of them.
You can all take up one city or one small
little village or something. Go there and
talk about Sahaja Yoga. It will definitely
work out. That's how in England they have
worked it out, and in many other countries.
So I have to tell all the Sahaja Yogis who
are here in Hyderabad and who are also in
other places, like Vishakapatnam or Vijayawada
or anywhere; all of them should understand
that at least they can spread it in their
city, Sahaja Yoga, very fast, in case they
get detached from their family. I know of
certain Sahaja Yogis, their wives are so strong
at it that they cannot overcome even their
wives, leave alone other relations. We have
had an experience of such women. Specially
in India there is a rule that whatever is
the dharma of the husband, that a wife has
to follow. But still I've seen that even the
wives can be very powerful because they're
so assertive, so aggressive. And if the husband
is simple he has to suffer. So here I would
say that one should not succumb to anyone
because he's dominating or in any way assertive,
but stand back and tell that this is the dharma
we are following, and nobody has business
to check us. We are on a fundamental right,
doing it.
Now the question is about how we deal with
each other in Sahaja Yoga, how we live with
each other, how we talk to each other. What
is the net result? Do we have a complete rapport
with other Sahaja Yogis in the same city?
Do you invite them to your house as you would
invite your neighbors? In any matter whatsoever
pertaining to you, any matter whatsoever,
the relations have nothing to do with you.
That's how you will start getting detached
and not worrying about it.
Now here are the many Western Sahaja Yogis.
[SHRI MATAJI SPEAKS IN HINDI]. The description
I've given now of when people who are left-sided
actually, they have attachments of the left
side. The right side attachments are different
type, as you know very well. The first one
is that they are individualistic, they don't
like collectivity. They think it is a force
on them; it is a binding thing, so that they
cannot rise. Right-sided people have the biggest
problem is of ego, which is all the time sitting
like a snake, coiled up. Something goes wrong,
suddenly it comes up - Ha! and you see a snake
come up now. The snake is very springy. But
now with Sahaja Yoga it is getting intoxicated,
I think; it doesn't come up. So the attachments:
on what points do we get upset? We should
write it down. All right. For example, what
do I get upset with, Myself? When I see a
Sahaja Yogi becoming bhootish I get upset.
But you just try to find out: "When do I get
upset?" and you'll be surprised, most of those
things are out of Sahaja Yoga; they have nothing
to do with Sahaja Yoga. But you are very upset,
very angry, and you don't want to talk about
it.
So this attitude of mind has to be changed.
When you are set now in Sahaja Yoga, how can
you be upset? That means you are not set:
simple thing. You are now set in Sahaja Yoga.
So how can you be upset? A very common language
there is to say: "I hope you are not upset".
When you say somebody is upset, he's upset,
I mean, may be whether you hope or don't hope!
But we do not also consider how do we upset
others? We don't also find out the ways and
methods, how not to upset others. And even
the humor we have, if it is pinching humor,
if it is disturbing humor, if it is denouncing
humor, that can upset a person very much.
So what sort of language we speak, what sort
of communication we have, what sort of
harm we do to people: you need not be hot-tempered,
your ego may not be seen, but it's the style,
very sly style of the ego, just to say something
horrible. Second way is of criticizing others
all the time: "This is not good, that is not
good, this not good." Who has asked you to
judge it? So you should not judge yourself,
at the same time you should not judge others
and punish them. In our day to day life we
have to develop a very sweet language, extremely
sweet. We have to work it out, actually work
it out, because even coming to Sahaja Yoga
still it lingers, certain things, and these
habits can be corrected very simply, very
easily. It belongs to the tongue, not to us,
so it's very easy to get rid of them.
The obstinacy is another thing which is a
horrible thing. Anybody suffers from this
kind of very subtle obstinacy; obstinacy [SOUNDS
LIKE "RESTS"], these things are tied down
with a rope. Now whatever may happen, you
are tied down: "Once I have decided, I have
decided." "But what is the harm in changing?"
"No, no, no, no; we don't want any change."
Now in Sahaja Yoga I'm happy, nothing is decided,
nothing is fixed. We were to have Puja, say,
yesterday; we'll have it today, that too in
the morning. It should not upset you because
it's all done to keep your upsetting you away.
So when is the program and when is not the
program is not important. What is important
is that how you have managed with that change.
If you do not know how to manage the change,
then your transformation is incomplete.
Now this English language I have learnt in
this lifetime, and I find there are some good
points about it, that you must say ten times:
"Thank you" even if somebody gives you water,
or fifteen times: "Sorry!" morning till evening.
In a way it is good, but if it's just a lip-service,
then everybody knows that you have to say
"Thank you", so they said "Thank you" so well.
But at the same time, if you remember how
graciously he did that for you, just remember
that. Next time you meet that person, all
this graciousness will come out, because you
get a feeling: somebody does something for
you, you get a beautiful feeling of gratitude.
And once you get that feeling, if you remember
that feeling, then you'll go on adding up
to it. [SHRI MATAJI SAYS, ASIDE: "I THINK
YOU ALSO SIT IN THE SUN, IS TOO MUCH HOT"].
It goes on adding. The more you add these
beautiful feelings within yourself: "How I
felt when they did it". Every time you get
some sort of a experience of that kind, if
you keep it within yourself, any time you
open that area of your memory, all the beauty
will start pouring on you, of that feeling.
So we have to learn new methods of making
ourselves happy. Before that we used to be
happy when we hurt others, we used to be happy
when we were sarcastic with others. But now
we have to develop a new method of making
ourselves happy; and once your mind goes on
to that: "I have to be happy, joyous. What
am I doing? Why am I doing like this? How
can I be happy? By saying a harsh thing to
others or by saying something mischievous,
how can I be happy? I cannot be." Then, "This
Mr. Ego, he makes me extremely unhappy. He's
really spoilt my mood." And you tell him to
get out now, get down, get down. Then it will
go down.
At this juncture when you are so advanced
in Sahaja Yoga, I should not have told all
these things to you; I agree with you entirely,
that now the time is not for telling you all
these things regarding your behavior toward
other Sahaja Yogis. But even a slightest movement
completely changes the atmosphere. So one
has to be extremely careful and attentive,
has to know what you say, what you have to
say, how you behave, and how you create a
feeling. In the society of Sahaja Yoga we
have beautiful people, we laugh, we enjoy,
we do all kinds of things, and really we are
in the most joyous company all the time. After
all it's joy, and what we achieve in joy is
the highest. At the same time we have to remember
that the collective subconscious is there,
and that may just jump sometime and come back.
Sahaja Yoga doesn't believe in any revenge,
hatred; nothing of the kind. It doesn't believe
in any kind of a false pride, or any kind
of restrictions or anything. It believes in
the pure sense of humanity and also the great
work of Sahaja Yoga.
It gives you great pleasure to be kind, to
be nice; so subside, to subside these habits
you have to do some abyas, you have to practise,
and introspect yourself. I am not saying because
anybody has reported anything that is like
that, nothing, in no way. But at this juncture
I am just telling you, because now when you
will be going out you'll be meeting new people,
then you might have problems, might have problems
of facing people whom you would be harsh,
you would be more meticulous, you may be much
more aggressive than normal. All these things
will upset, upset them; but if you are peaceful,
tolerant, forgiving, that will definitely
make them feel that you are saints. If they
are difficult leave them alone, don't argue,
by argument you cannot give them Realization.
If they don't have wisdom they don't deserve
it, they don't, they are not destined to be
like that. But your style has to be such that
they should know that you are saints. In all
your self-respect, in all your love you have
to talk to them.
So now when you are here in this country you
have to decide how
you
are going to spread Sahaja Yoga when you go
back. Same with our Indian Sahaja Yogis: they
have to
also find out ways and methods, how they
will
spread
Sahaja Yoga.
May
God bless you.