But before we come to right conclusion about
our seeking, we have to understand that truth
is not a mental action.
If your mind says that "this is this", it
need not be that. It is our everyday experience
in life, that mentally, when we try to establish
something, we find after sometime, that we
have not been absolutely correct about it.
Whatever is known to us is already there.
But whatever is unknown, even about that,
if you have preconceived ideas, that "this
is the unknown, this is God, this is Spirit",
then it could be that you are very much away
from the truth. But scientifically, if you
have to approach any subject, you have to
keep your mind absolutely clean and open,
that it has been said by many great Saints,
many great gurus, that we are to be born again
and that we are the Spirit. Are we to believe
in them or not? Perhaps, we should reach at
least this conclusion that they did not take
any money from anyone and they could not have
been fake people, they did not do it for money
sake. So, if we have to be born again, to
reach the right conclusion we should know
what should happen to us. For example if you
certify that I am a reborn again, then it
is misleading. Supposing that I certify myself
that I am the Prime minister of Australia,
do I become? I have to become! So just by
taking a certificate we are cheating ourselves
and avoiding opportunity to be born again.
So to be honest is the first way we can really
be the seekers of truth. If we are not honest
and if we have preconceived ... (?) and want
to stick to it, I would say that it is rather
difficult. But logically we should come to
a point where we should understand, that what
should happen when we deceive the truth. In
our evolutionary process, what has happened
to us? Actually, our awareness has been enlightened
in new dimensions that lead you up in our
evolution. And animal does not understand
filth scented. You can take a horse through
any dirty but a human being is very sensitive
he has to close his noose, or sometimes even
refuses to go through that. So in our awareness
something has to happen. And that is not some
sort of an abnormal thing. Like some people,
I was told, have written books where you have
to become mad to be reborn. I mean in what
evolutionary stage did it happen? Did the
fishes become mad to become the higher animals?
When did it happen that you had to become
mad to evolve?
It's a wrong idea that people give because
they can only make you mad, nothing else.
And you like it, because one way they pamper
your ego by saying that you can pay for that.
Secondly they all give you a feeling that
you are something different. To be something
different is not to be evolved. You have so
many mad people in this world. We have so
many epileptic people, we have so many people
who jump all over the places. There is nothing
great about it. Whatever you can do easily
is to jump or to shout, to scream or to misbehave,
all these things are very easy for human beings
to do.
But if something has to happen from the Divine,
and if it is a divine process, then something
should happen within us, which is not in our
reach, which is something that is beyond the
human reach. That has to be the divine thing.
So we must understand that in our seeking,
what we have to see is a higher dimension
to our awareness. In that dimension you have
to become something, like you have become
a human being. You are no more a monkey, you
are a human being now. In the same way, you
have to become something.
In Sanskrit language, a Brahmin, who is a
Realized soul, the one who knows the Brahma,
the All Pervading Power, is called as "vijaya",
born again. And also a bird is called as "vijaya".
A bird is first born as an egg and then it
is born as a bird. There's complete transformation.
You don't have to certify a bird that it is
no more an egg. It just becomes, you see it
through that it becomes. So those who are
honest, and those who are really seeking,
must know that you have to become something.
It's not just that you become mad or you become
like some sort a funny freaky fellow, but
you become really something that is in your
awareness.
Now if you have to go through science, you'll
find out that Jung, who was a Realized soul,
who got his Realization much later, and then
he defied Freud, has clearly said that if
a human being evolves, he'll have to become
collectively conscious. His consciousness
becomes collectively aware, meaning that you
should feel others within yourself, on your
fingertips.
Mohamed has said at the time of Resurrection
[Qyama] your hands will speak. Your hands
have to speak. Now the hands have no tongue
to speak, so what happens? It is accepted
in the medical science, that the sympathetic
nervous system is expressed in your seven
centres on your fingers, but they don't know
which are where, and how it is, they cannot
put it. And they are all disturbed. But they
say there is a sympathetic connection with
the fingertips.
So in your awareness, it has to happen, by
which you have to be more alert, more noble,
more dynamic, more beautiful, more loving,
more understanding. So something has to happen
to your central nervous system. It must be
apparent that your are just feeling something
more in your central nervous system.
Now, what people are enamoured this, that,
if they see some people dancing madly, they
feel enamoured, is the sign that you have
not been able to understand. We have seen
Christ, we have seen Bouddha, Mahavira, Kabira,
Nanakar [Guru Nanak]. We had Lao Tse and so
many others. Did they behave like this? Did
they become mad? We have got Moses, did he
become mad anytime, was he mad anytime, behaving
like a mad person? All these new theories
have started I think, fifty years back, or
about sixty years back, that people believe
in these new theories and they have forgotten
all the traditional things that have come
to us, our heritage. And we depend more on
these nonsensical things, which has no moorings
at all!
Because the people who are supposed to be
the founders of all the religions, have never
behave like this and why this new type of
things that has started, that people are behaving
in this manner and accepting it, to be as
very normal thing.
So all the seekers must know that you have
to become the Spirit, means you must feel
your own powers. It is not that you feel the
powers of another person, now he is a person
who brings down some diamonds for you, so
what? Logically you reach a conclusion: do
you want diamonds or do you want your Spirit?
You can buy them in the market. Why do you
need a guru to do that kind of a job? There
must be some juggler all kinds of these spiritual
juggleries are on, and when I came here from
Perth,..., Melbourne and here, everywhere,
all the people from the medias have been asking
me that why these gurus have come from India
and they have ruined us like this. They have
so many rules, like this and that and that
[laughs]
I said thank God that now, at least, you have
realised it. But I went to America and told
them long time back that these people are
going to come, and be careful about them.
It has been already told about it, but people
did not want to follow it. They thought that
it is better that you accept a guru, live
with him, and then, when he goes to heaven,
means hell actually, you'll be there. Now
we are very happy that the awareness is coming
to the seekers, that a lot of them are realizing
that they have not found the truth. If you
are reaching that conclusion that you have
to find the truth within yourself, then Sahaja
Yoga will work wonders.
Now, our evolutionary process has not been
anything which is dead, it is a living process.
There is a force within us which brings forth
our evolution, and living process cannot be
activated by mental activity. For example
if you put a seed in the Mother Earth, it
sprouts by itself. By saying that "you'd better
sprout now" or by saying that "it has sprout"
you'll have just mental satisfaction of creating
an imaginary image. But actually, it has to
happen. The happening has to take place. And
this happening is build within you. That has
to happen within your being and is already
you're destined for it. As he has told you,
that lies in the triangular bone, which is
very [Inaudible] -you can't even see them.
I think it is drawn very small, we should
really enlarge it and show- that is the triangular
bone within us which contains this force called
as the Kundalini. Now regarding Kundalini
you must have read many books also.
In India, I saw some books I was amazed, written
by mostly foreigners, such big books and they
didn't know where the Kundalini was in the
stomach or in the nose. Such confused people
need not have written, if you are confused,
better not talk about it. You see, if you
are confused about something, what's the use
of talking that this was the confusion, I
got a choc, and I got a heat and all this,
then why are you talking? You don't know anything
you have no authority. So you have no business
to talk about it. That means you are naive
or you're being, just being absolutely a person
who is uneducated about it. Why should you
talk when you are not an authority, not only
talk but write? And books after books have
been written by people who have no authority
to write these books. And that's how they
have created another myth that Kundalini awakening
is the most dangerous thing and one should
not ? Now imagine? What a mistake it is!
Who is the photographer?
So, what is the advantage in this kind of
spreading news that Kundalini awakening, which
is the epitome of your evolution, which is
what human beings have to achieve in their
life, that's the aim of their life, to be
the Spirit. And Kundalini is the only way
it happens. So why should people talk like
this and say it is dangerous to have the Kundalini
awakened? Because, why they are doing it,
because they are under some anti-God activity.
Because they are not with God, some sort of
a sinister satanic force which is telling
these things to people that you should not
have your Kundalini awakened. Imagine, it
is like saying that you should not enter into
the kingdom of God. If that is the only way
if you have to enter into the kingdom of God,
why should you frighten the people about it?
There is nothing frightening about Kundalini
awakening I can assure you.
I've had, as you know, I've been working for
years together and so many people have got
Realization, a-mass, and nobody has got any
problem like that. Sometimes of course you
feel little heat in the body, sometimes, you
feel little heat in the body; sometimes a
little shaking in the body. If there is a
problem in the body, if your nerves are steel
[?] and anything, the Kundalini when she rises,
she little bit shakes you but it settles down.
It settles you down completely and you feel
absolutely blissful and peaceful. No problem
is created I have seen so far which can be
called anywhere near danger. On the contrary,
when Kundalini rises, she gives so many by-products,
to begin with. Of course, she is the power
of pure desire. The only desire that is pure
in human being is to be one with the Divine.
All other desires are not pure because they
do not give you pure joy. You think of anything,
you want to say have a car. All right; work
for it, try your loving best to achieve that.
Then you have the car and you want to have
something else. If that was your pure desire,
it would have given you complete joy and satisfaction,
it is not so. So matter is making you run
from one to another, but doesn't give you
joy. So the pure desire in a human being,
is this great desire to be one with the Divine.
If you do not accept it today, you will come
tomorrow. You'll have to take it, because
nothing is going to satisfy you unless and
until you receive the truth, you become one
with the Divine.
People make-I've seen people deny for the
time being, "I'm not ready", that's another
style: "I'm not ready" and all sorts of things
people say. But I say: "let me decide" why
are you worrying? "Let me decide if you are
ready or not, what is the problem is, it can
be worked out. I've really worked for years
together to know all the permutations and
combinations and the problems and the valence
you have. And it is not going to take any
time for you, it's very simple, it's a living
process, it is not going to trouble you, why
should you have fright about it?
So this is one side of Kundalini awakening.
The other side is when people think that it
can be done by themselves. It cannot be done
by yourself. Somebody has to do it for you
and then once you get it you can do it for
others. Now for example, a candle which is
enlightened can only enlighten another candle;
by itself a candle cannot enlighten. But for
that you have to have a real person, a person
who knows everything about the Kundalini,
the one who can awaken your Kundalini and
not a person who is already chocked by ?? and
who just talks about Kundalini or he makes
people jump all over the places.
There is a guru in India who used to give
Kundalini awakening and where this doctor
Warren went first of all. And they all were
jumping and saying "ah, ah, u, u, i, i" and
he got such a fright he said he thought it's
a lunatic asylum; he ran away from that place
and came to me; he said: "no Mother, don't
give me Kundalini awakening because I'm afraid.
" I said, that's not the way, that's not!
That is hypnosis, a kind of hypnosis, and
that hypnosis will create problem and not
your Kundalini, she is your mother and she
is waiting for days together, for ages together,
many lives she has waited for the great opportunity
to give you your second birth. But so far,
you have not allowed her to do her work, because
mentally you have put all books in your head,
or all gurus in your head, or all kind of
ideas in your head. And she poor thing is
waiting for that, to manifest your second
birth. And that is a big problem, how to make
people understand that by mental activity
you cannot raise the Kundalini.
I may give you lectures after lectures, not
necessary that your Kundalini will rise. But
it will rise when I pay attention to it. And
if you get your Realization, you can also
make it raise trough your attention. That
is done through the power of chitta, chitta.
But you must have your chitta shakti enlightened.
If you are not an enlightened person, you
cannot do it. Can you do it by paying attention
to somebody, raising the Kundalini ? You can
see the position of the Kundalini in many
people, those who have got problems in their
centres, like the second and the third centre.
You can see it very clearly, what happens,
and you can see it pulsating, it's just like
a heart, the bone pulsating like a heart.
You'll be amazed to see that the bone that
looks like a stiff thing is pulsating. You
can even see, say, see the raising of the
Kundalini, but if you have a stethoscope,
you can hear the "lap dack, lap dack" way
up; this is called as Anahata, means without
percussion, the sound without percussion,
and you can feel it on top of your head, so
the same thing raising which Kabira has said,
"only, shimu sharaka" means on the silent
peak of your brain you start first feeling
the Anahata, means the sound of "lap dack,
lap dack" here in your heart, you start feeling
it here (on top of the head). And when it
breaks that area, the fontanel bone area,
which is called as "Talu", you just feel the
cool breeze coming out of your head.
Now, this you cannot do. You can jump, dance,
become mad, take drugs, take alcohols, he-grow
your beard or cut it off r anything that you
want to do, but you cannot make the cool breeze
coming out of your head. And that is what
is the proof that it's a living process that
does this. Unless and until that happens to
you, you try everything else it's going to
be a big problem.
As I was telling today to the television,
many sincere [?] was the problem with us,
with Australians, when you say they are naïve.
I said : "they are naïve because they don't
know what to seek. That's one point, they
don't what they should ask for, what should
happen to them, and they are attacked by people
who are here just to make money, it's money
making proposition. Imagine, people have maid
millions and millions of pounds through you
people; it's such a multimillion big enterprise
and it's done on that level. And you people
are enamoured by these things because it appeals
to your brain some way or another and I don't
know why, because it appeals to your ego perhaps.
The lady asked me: 'if it is so simple Mother,
then why is it people don't take to simple
things?"
Now, see today I came first of all here, at
seven o'clock, and they said there are very
few people. So I went round and I came back.
I said: "that's the trouble, they don't want
anything simple." But whatever is living is
so simple. You cannot explain it mentally.
You put, as I said, a seed into the Mother
Earth, how it sprouts, how a flower becomes
a fruit, all these things you cannot explain
mentally. It's a living process done by the
All Pervading Power, which is the love of
God, and that activates and works it out and
naturalise which you cannot by your mental
process understand, nor can you do it. You
can't transform one flower into fruit.
So this is what one has to understand, that
is has to be a living process within us. And
the living process is spontaneous. That is
why we say "sahaja" "saha" means "with" and
"ja" means "born". It's born with you, it's
spontaneous. Like your breathing is born with
you, like your pulsation is born with you,
like everything which is born with you, you
take it for granted, it exists. In the same
way, this Kundalini is born with you. And
this awakening is also your birthright, as
a human being you have the right to have this
awakening within you and you should have it
and you must seek that.
But, because of no education on this point,
perhaps, traditionally, we are not educated
to understand. Christ came on this earth,
when he wanted to explain all these things
he had to go away and he lived only for four
years to talk to people and in that four years
the way people behaved, and he way they never
accepted him, it was impossible to talk to
you about Kundalini. But in the Bible it is
written, I will appear before you like tongues,
even in all the Torahs it is written, I will
appear before you like flames of tongues.
Now, what are these flames? These are the
chakras which are within us, when you see
them, they look like that, the flames, you
can see them clearly. But it is not the seeing
the that is important, it is being; people
think that if you see the light, now you become
the light. If you see the light [Shri Mataji
shows the ceiling], you become the light?
It's simple, simple thing you can understand
: you do not become a light if you see the
light [Shri Mataji shows the ceiling]. You
have to become the light, and when you become
the light what happens, that you act like
light. Your power acts like a light. When
you are there people can see how to walk,
they know how to understand the difference
between a carpet and a chair and a human being.
The discrimination is there. When there is
light, you discriminate and you start understanding
that the truth is this and this is untruth.
So when the Kundalini rises through your fontanelle
bone area the first blessing you get is of
good health. That's a minimum that should
happen, but it's a by-product. But I don't
want to emphasize more on good health because
tomorrow we'll get all the hospitals drooping
on my head, that's what I don't want. You
have to be first the Spirit and you have to
be the doctors and you, yourself, can treat
your body as well as the body of others this
is a minimum that should happen, that you
become a healthy person.
Now what does that ? Within us lies a power
which is the evolutionary power, in the center,
and it is the power which we call as the power
of Mahalakshmi, is the power by which we sustain
our own character, by which we become human
beings, from carbon, where it is four valences,
as human beings we develop ten valences.
We become eligible for our ascent through
this power to begin with, because this is
a power that gives us balance.
In the gross it expresses itself as parasympathetic
nervous system. Now, what is parasympathetic
nervous system is? That it gives a balance
to your sympathetic nervous system. Now sympathetic
nervous system is the gross expression of
the two other powers which are around us.
One is the power of desire, and another is
the power of action. These sympathetic nervous
systems come into play when we want to use
them. For example if you want to run fast-
so when you are running fast, these two powers
come into power, that they give us the force
to run fast. But what is the thing that brings
it back to normal? It's the central power
that brings it to the normal or gives it balance.
So this balancing force is the one that is
responsible for your ascent. If you are not
yet balanced, the same force will first balance
you. Because of imbalances, so many diseases
are caused, there is no and to it. Apart from
that, those people who go to extremes, to
the left and to the right, also can develop
horrible diseases. Those who go to the left
side develop mostly the psychosomatic diseases,
like cancer, like [all ??] and incurable diseases.
And imbalanced people develop - say, blood
pressures and diabetes, and all the problems
of the organs in the stomach. And the people
who are too much right sided, who are too
much speedy, who are thinking of the future
all the time, they develop problems of the
heart and also the problems of the physical
side. Those who indulge into too much physical
exercises and all that, also develop the problems
of the physical side.
So it is all our doing that we gets it, mostly,
or may be of our parents.
For example somebody asked me that "how is
it Mother, that leukaemia is caused in the
people who - children also?" They are born
with it. I said the mother must be a very
speedy woman. If the mother is speedy, hectic,
her spleen is working in a hectic way, she
sets in, in motion the same kind of a spleen
that the child should have. And if that happens,
the child develops a kind of a spleen which
is hectic and starts producing RBCs [Red Blood
Cells] which are not with the main and not
in proper shape. And these are vulnerable
to cancer and things like leukaemia. Because
at this stage, something triggers it and that
triggering takes place because of an extreme
behaviour of a personality which I'll explain
to you tomorrow.
But in any case, physically, you feel fit,
mentally you feel fit, mentally, because your
extreme behaviour disappears. Mostly we take
to habits; any habits we take to is, the reason
is because we get bored in life or we are
fed up or we are very unhappy or we are disturbed
about something or we are shocked. Under the
circumstances, we take to it. But supposing
the reverse happens that you feel settled,
you feel blissful, you feel happy, you feel
cheerful, you feel on top of the world, naturally
everything drops of. When you have got the
highest you don't want to indulge into all
these things, which are sensational, for the
time being, work out for a short period. But
you start enjoying that is what is eternal
within you, flowing all the time. Stress and
all that also disappears. Because supposing-
I give an example always of a car which is
about to finish its petrol, everybody it is
in a stress --the car as well as the driver
is worrying that the petrol is going to finish.
But supposing by some chance, you are connected
to the mains and all the time the energy is
flowing into you, then, then you have no worry,
you have no worry and just you get over all
these things.
People have a very great -- I should emphasize,
so we can say all the time a kind of a cocks
in [?] from all the sensational practices
of the society. And this quite upset us, all
the time the way we are, all the time we are
stimulated by these sensations.
Now with Realization what happens, the Spirit
doesn't take note of all this stimulus, nothing
of the kind, it is not bothered about these
things. It is just witnessing the all play
as a drama and a joke, and it doesn't take
anything into record, and doesn't react to
it as human beings do. And that's how the
stress stops, drops out.
On the contrary, I have met some people who
have been doing all kinds of things, their
hands were going like this, and feet were
going like that, all sort of contortions,
and I said "why are you doing it?" They said
"we have been to a guru, and he said your
stress is coming out." Now if the stress is
coming out and if this is the state of the
stress-laughs- when are you going to end this
up? It is not possible, you must understand!
You see what I feel when I talk about these
things people just leave me and go away because
they get angry but I'm for you! I'm for your
good! I'm saying, just understand, that how
can stress get out, by this kind of a nonsensical
thing happening to you, you're getting mad!
This is not the way the stress has to get
out, but you have to get over the stress.
And that is a very simple thing to understand,
that is you are standing in the water, the
waves start coming to you, coming and going
and you are afraid of the waves. But supposing
by any chance, the state becomes that you
become seated in a boat, someway or another,
you raided up to that part that you are in
a boat, then you enjoy the same waves, from
there, and you don't mind any kind of things.
And this is the state one has to achieve.
Unless and until you achieve that state, all
your guru, all your money is of no value,
nothing of the kind. But this should not upset
you.
Because many people also take a view that
we have paid for it, so we'd better go through
it. I mean if you have paid for the poison,
will you go through it? It's simple thing
like that because you have paid for it, better
not go through it, because it's dangerous.
You must see what is happening to the people
who are going to these gurus, or to these
cults, or to these clairvoyance and all that.
What is happening to them? Are they transforming?
Are they getting any of their powers? Have
they become peaceful people? Have they finished
their seeking? They think that they have done
it? If not, then no use going to a place like
that. But human mind, I don't understand sometimes,
like they see a person coming out of a pub,
falling in the dirty lane, and still they
walk in the same pub. So I can't understand
why people do all these things. But, mainly,
we have to know that, one day will come when
we'll face ourselves and that time, we'll
ask a question that : "why did I not use my
wisdom to understand that these are not the
things I was asking for. What I was asking
what the ultimate, the truth."
Those who talk about love of God, power of
God, it's very easy because, you see, you
can read any book and start talking, then
it's "power of God, power of love and all
that". But it must act. If you talk of compassion
it must act. It is not just I say that I'm
compassion and embodiment of compassion, so
what?
You may be embodiment of compassion. I can
gather some money from you people and start
a hospital here and say I have treated so
many people here, you give me a big prize
for- it's nothing. That's not the way the
compassion acts. Compassion acts in the same
way as the sun shine acts. If you are near
such a person- you remember that somebody
touched Christ, and something went into that
person. Christ said : "somebody has touched
who's sick". [Luc-8-46: But Jesus said, "Someone
touched me; I know that power has gone out
from me."] The person got cured. The compassion
must act, otherwise it has no meaning, it's
just talks, advertises that you are the love
power and all that. It's not so. Something
has to happen that is not also madness or
any kind of a crackpot behaviour but by which
you keep your transformation. And that what
you should ask for, for the reality and not
for unreal, and in reality, you'll be amazed,
you will see where you stand as far as you
are concerned and others are concerned. What
is the reality position? That you are the
part and parcel of the whole, you start feeling
that you are part and parcel of the whole.
And when that happens, there is no compassion
that speaks. Because supposing this finger
is paining, automatically I press this finger.
I just pres it , because it is, it is paining
and I just feel it because it's me, it's me
there so I just do it. So that's how the compassion
acts, it doesn't think it is doing any obligation
to anyone, that this finger should pay anything
to me. It's mine, it's myself, how I can I
not touch it and put it right. In the same
way it happens that you become part and parcel
of the whole. And when you become that, you
just act as a part of that whole, with all
its powers. And that should happen to all
of you who are seekers.
Normally Sahaja Yoga is better for people
who are not extremes by nature, who are centred
people, that's very good, it acts very well
on them and helps them in many things. Also
those who are in extremes are also brought
[drown?] in the center, because Kundalini
is a movement in the central path and you
are paying attention to me, and I say "you
pay attention to yourself, you cannot." But
when Kundalini rises she sucks in your attention
inside like an incident or happening within
and then the attention, even if it is on the
extremes, is sucked inside. And when it is
sucked in, it just rises out. One must know
lots of things happen when it rises. It just
doesn't rise just like a premule rising up
but lots of things happen within your body.
Lots of centers go into different kind of
banghas and all that, it happens. As a car
starts, lots of things happen in the inside
machinery, in the same way, when the Kundalini
starts rising, lots of things happen inside,
but very smoothly. Because you are fantastically,
beautifully and delicately made, with great
care.
It's not easy to destroy Kundalini, it's not
easy, but I've seen some people have got very
sick kundalini, some people have bleeding
Kundalinis I've seen. And of course, if they
are devils, they may not have Kundalini at
all. But it is not easy to destroy this bone
also. If you burn the body of a human being,
this bone is the last to be burnt and requests
very high temperature to burn it. That's why
people call it a sacred bone, But when I went
to Greece, and I asked people "why did you
call it sacrum?" They said "because we had
a rapport with a Hindu Aryan group much before
Alexander went there, and they told us this
is sacred bone. And we found out that when
you burn the body, this bone remains still
there. So we thought, must be something sacred
about it."
Now tomorrow, the day after and after that,
we're going to have 3 more programs. Today,
in a general way, I've spoken to you because
they said 'just give introduction to Sahaja
Yoga, what is Sahaja Yoga is, and that's why
I've told you that you cannot pay for it,
it is effortless, it is spontaneous, it's
a living process and through the grace of
God it works. And by this happening, you get
your transformation. And you become something
else that what you are in your awareness;
you become a more powerful person, a dynamic
person, you start feeling another person.
It's a fact. You can ask somebody who must
come now all the way from Perth. And when
he came to me, he was in a big problem because
he had been to guru, these things, and he
realized that he made a mistake and that he
could rectify but now he is rectified and
he could feel this cool breeze actually on
his head and all over. So this is the thing
one has to understand that you must honestly
ask for the truth and not for something that
has been told you before.
This is what it is, it should happen to you,
that has never happened before and cannot
happen through human effort.
So tomorrow, the day after and after that,
we have 3 more days. One day I will talk about
chakras, tomorrow, and then these 3 powers,
and last day I'll tell you what is to be done
after Self Realization, how to keep it up,
how your Spirit is your guru, and how it teaches
through your vibratory awareness, how you
understand what is right and hat is wrong.
I think that is how we'll space it up and
we'll work it out.
But today, we should try to have a session
of Self Realization also, and it might be,
might work out very well.
May God bless you.
If you have any questions, I would like to
have the questions because it's important
if you have any sensible questions. But, I
don't know, some people say "in this book
it is written, in that book it is written
or this one says like that." Please, don't
do that. Because all these books have given
you nothing, so better forget about them.