tada we start our journey
please close simply family with you I
don't offer them to be active in the
resume my back don't even put it back on
you put your left hand towards me and
right hand on your heart
now you have to ask a very fundamental
question about yourself three times to
the body because in history fundamentals
remain
you may call me mother or Shri Mataji
may be an energy so please ask in terms
in your heart mother am I the spirit
don't even read the moaning - okay ma'am
sweetie lovely marriage mystery
and I told you if you are the spirit you
are your master communities if this
privilege but we need but we meant so
please take a right hand limit they may
come from I know what about this you can
younger the table then introduce really
good here please ask me another question
whether am I my own master
three times he suppose you noticed him
maybe even compliment possesses a strong
woman I've already told you that I
respect your food freedom Iran cannot
force pure knowledge of you your grass
planet choose additional irrespective of
credibility agree with perforce P Diddy
so now please take your right hand in
the lower portion of your abdomen on the
left-hand side with even know simple
element to put the crucial he would obey
them and here you have to save six times
because this Center has got six petals
six times mother please give me pure
knowledge you see with the video safe
work as a sort of a city turned the
dividend yourseif work makes you play
dough name one of three open a sauce
as soon as you ask for pure knowledge
this power wouldn't mean starts rising
today you see two people do not develop
Japanese homes super wah set energy
capability from accessibility you will
not feel anything with the billion
something till it reaches and pierces
through the lacet Maria Sophia Tonkin
Appleton leader Hassan so now raise your
right hand in the upper portion of your
abdomen and here full confidence you
have to say click times mother I am my
own master nan committee met knowledge
man sort of participe of the to develop
the language octagon in every year
different men
[Music]
I've already told that you are not this
body smile
these conditionings miss eagels but you
are pure spirit
she digital antenna receptacle who seek
initiate mom it could easily confuse
initially pass it and collect indecent
ago mr. condition mom miss me so that
means that you have on your heart
don't make noise implementing what you
have to say full confidence twelve times
mother i they see would be do not blink
refused us for marriage feel the pure
spring this all-pervading power is the
ocean of knowledge so to go to threesome
it has so Stephanie sauce ocean of
compassion if they were still on the
composition diversity
it is the ocean maybe would you do -
Chanel even assumed so whatever mistakes
easily is over by the power of this
ocean is don't keep this one is a little
confusing if you command
it's so fancy modesty plus say on the
bottom
give yourself I don't totally for
teamwork women meeting another man to
the what here now you say sixteen times
with full confidence mother
I see the Buffalo hood is recessed for
16 now
I'm bothered but if you don't forgive
then you play into wrong hands may see
this time if you don't forgive your
country open yours st. it won't open
I sister Stephen found on a path went
soft be like yeah mister doctor
so now raise your right hand on top of
your forehead and put down your head as
far as possible
okay little bit know what matters care
it was for me to not have an office on
separately ABC let you see one thing put
it down on top of your forehead now here
you have to say from your heart not how
many times mother I forgive everyone in
you see the know what the [ __ ] I've been
a podcast before for civil tort okay you
see man should not learn to be a second
now please take your right hand on the
back side of your head and without
without computer mistakes misma cosa
phenomena but that is not materially
deannamaria for your own satisfaction
you have to say or divine power if I
have done something wrong knowingly or
unknowingly please forgive me hopefully
you see woody VD simply Oh energy yield
series effect KP analysis work the first
symposium to ASEAN simply everyone it's
from heart not how many times have a
heart no more the fun-looking
appearances with the ak-47 you can now
glass center stitch you're powerful
maybe none of this song comedy mmm
put the center of your palm on top of
your fontanel bone area which is a soft
bone in your childhood
[Music]
now here put down your head isn't it
this would only put on Yemen again I
respect your freedom and I cannot force
self-realization on you now go to
respectable 2030 engine to emphasis on
this one
push back your fingers push back your
fingers material you under here lehavot
auntie I'm here now you move your
stabbed seven times clockwise say mother
please give me self-realization in our
was apprehensive about that today
matriculation reset for the disagreement
for the arm for download if we don't the
good Monday mention today Accord a modem
access you may simply duniya
modernization we seen here the project
they don't know that my cousin Philip
did please put the right type of sweet
when your head and see for yourself if
there is a pool of hot air like please
coming from a 40-day body see with your
left hand
Cebu Glenlivet old man they are more
economic boost it's an illusion what she
that they give a supplemental to that
that they should chase you into platform
that were servants of the police of
flesh
[Music]
please don't put your hand on top of
your head see who better to ship an
ethical to the man sit with us ask us
and don't doubt in the do diplom it's
not air conditioning from your head
coming out of the bucket
no please put left and wash me and again
bend your head and see for yourself
there's a heart or a cool breeze coming
out of your head
in mathematica mangusta moi Eric Nam and
what for Casa de Machaut you see the
work simple to way you stop the piece of
flesh yeah totally worth it
some people take it far away sometime
between one dinner
don't forget but you kill away the bit
deeper but imagine what that mean even
traumatic you know if you are still not
real forgiving it will be hard coming
out see Lancome we found any talk of it
no usually such a fine something to show
now please put your right hand again as
well confess even limited command once
everyone is it other because ultimately
I'm not put down your head this is a
front end I'd see for yourself if
there's a cool breeze coming out of your
head
you may get the compliments yeah in
bliss friendship Tom develop our hearts
o bian Xiaojun
you