I hope you are all very comfortable now and
that you are enjoying the food as well. [Applause]
Also we are approaching the fag end of our
tour. This tour was arranged, as you know,
like a journey through your Shushumna Nadi.
At different, different points different,
different Chakras in the same way we have
passed through various places and now we have
reached Ganapatipule where we have to get
our Sahasrara fully drenched with blessings
of Shri Ganesh. As you know Sahaja Yoga is
a very subtler happening within us. It's a
very subtler happening and this subtler happening
gives you sensitivity to Divine joy. When
you start getting the Divine joy you don't
care for any comforts, you don't care for
all worldly type of pleasure giving things.
To you, this becomes the most important thing
and the only thing. Apart from that you start
seeing the truth as it is. When I say you
start seeing the truth many people can misuse
this word. I've seen many people saying that
they can decide things on vibrations and they
have decided certain things on vibrations.
But they commit mistakes. That means they
have not yet grown up to that state where
they can decide on vibrations. So nobody should
arbitrarily decide but consult the collective,
especially your leaders to find out if whatever
decision you have taken, whatever you have
thought of, is it all right or not. And one
may commit lots of mistakes if you start behaving
arbitrarily. The greatest law of Sahaja Yoga
is that it is a collective happening.
Now as you have seen here people are from
abroad, people are from Delhi, people are
from Calcutta, people from Bombay, people
from villages, people from various places.
The idea of all of you coming here is to,
is to create the understanding of the collective.
As people start becoming collective and collective
they do not bother others, they do not trouble
others, but they give joy to others. They
are not bothered about their going and coming,
their eating and everything, they just don't
behave like mundane, usual type of people.
But they are very patient, Saburi as they
call it. They are in the patience. Now this
patience is most joy giving. Patience gives
you the greatest joy. When you are patient
you develop all your qualities. I think in
patience you blossom the best. But patience
is not be patient, be patient. Patience is
also a kind of a state within us with just
this patience, Saburi as they call it. You
just watch and see. Wherever you are you are.
Now some people are worried that they must
get into the bus. Some people are worried
they must reach back home. Some people are
worried they must get their food in time.
According to them this is discipline. This
is not. This is conditioning. But what is
the discipline is of patience in Sahaja Yoga.
Where you watch everything and you are patient.
If you are in the bus you are there. If you
are standing on the road you are there. If
you are walking on the road you are there.
On the contrary it is a good idea to walk.
I wish I could but I can't because once I
start walking everybody will fall at My feet.
Nobody will spare Me. So I am just imprisoned
inside the house, inside the room all day
long because I just can't come out as soon
as I come out I find there hosts of people
standing outside. But your case is not such.
You are free people. You are not bound like
Me. So it's nice to walk a little bit in the
evening time, it's a good idea. It’s a very
good idea, leisurely you can walk, that will
digest your food. The food is rather heavy
sometimes. It makes you feel better and just
know that you are walking that's all. To feel
that I have to walk, I have to go there, once
you start thinking you get exhausted sitting
here, even if you have not walked. So, it
is important that patience should be made
the discipline of life.
How much patient we are for anything, for
anything. Now as you can see, I have to sit
here before I don't come you can not start,
till I have to sit here till you finish. You
are all free you can get up, walk about, come
whenever you feel like I am not. And how do
I manage all this, is through My patience.
But patience is My quality. It's My nature
which I enjoy the most of all. Now I am sitting
here is nobody is there I am enjoying it.
If I am lost somewhere I enjoy it. If I lost
My way I enjoy it because I am there to enjoy
Myself. So I think we should make a practice
now the Moon is out, beautiful moonlit nights,
try to walk down, especially the Delhi people
must walk. They don't just walk. In Delhi
is all right because you can not walk about,
there is danger and all that but here is better.
You better walk your health will improve.
Sahaja Yoga will improve. Kundalini will improve.
You'll feel much better.
That's the good part of this remote place
that nobody sees you. Nobody is bothered about
you. You can live whatever way you like you
can walk the way you like. There is nobody
to bother. There is no need to have a competition
or run about but just leisurely if you walk
it is a good idea. I am not saying just to
save some money out of the buses. But it is
just to make you feel more healthy, just sitting
all the time one feels very funny sit here,
sit there, sit there, going in a taxi, going
in a bus, going in a lift, you just don't
move your legs. There is no exercise also
in Sahaja Yoga. Walking is the best exercise
for all the Sahaja Yogis as I told you. And
that's why it is important that you all should
try to walk a little bit, if possible. For
there are ladies who have children, that is
all right, old ladies, old men but even them
it's a good idea to walk half a way and then
you can go by buses. Something like that try
to adjust yourself for these three, four days.
You'll feel much better. I promise you will
feel much better when you walk now.
And another thing, which one has to learn
apart from Saburi from the patience. One has
to imbibe within one self is the sweetness.
If you are sweet you are filled with humor,
you do not hurt others, you are not hurt either,
you see everything so beautiful and nice,
that's the quality of Shri Krishna, Madhurya.
Anything can be done with sweetness. That's
very important. Now some people might say,
“Mother, sometimes You have to get angry
and all that.” There, is no need for you
that I can do that dirty job. You don't have
to. You don't have to get angry with anyone.
You just show your patience, your love, your
kindness, your sweetness. That is how the
personality of Sahaja Yoga, which is a collective
being, is to be built by people who have patience,
who are sweet outwardly, inwardly.
And the third one is the genuineness. Without
genuineness we can not enter into ourselves
because our inner being knows what we are.
If there is hypocrisy, if there is just showing
off or if there is a kind of a reservation
within us we can not enter inside us. Also
the people who come in contact with such people
can not progress. So one has to be very genuine
about it and this is an individual quality,
is not a Samuhik [MEANS collective –SG]
quality. It is not a collective quality. All
of us have to be genuine within ourselves
because it is for our gain, for our Hitha.
So we have to be collective because it is
good for us. We have to be patient because
it is good for us and we have to be genuine
because it is good for us. It’s all Swartha.
It is all the meaning of Swa, Swartha, Swa
means ourselves, and Artha means the meaning.
And Swartha also means selfishness but actually
it is self, and self and self.
Now you are changed people. Your personality
is different. It's shining through your Spirit.
In that Spirit you have to see everything.
All your conditionings will drop out as soon
as you start identifying your Self fully,
fully with the Spirit. Fully again I say because
we do not, we are still Christians, we are
still Hindus, we are still Muslims. We are
still Indians, English this that. We are still
narrow-minded small little puddles. We have
to be the ocean. Once you are identified with
the ocean we have to throw away everything
and become absolutely clean and detached,
Nisanga. So when we are singing all these
songs we are saying this. It should not be
a lip service. It should be flow in our heart.
We should feel it. But I am happy that your
Spirits are shining and the Spirit is enjoying
and that you are moving very smoothly upward.
Little push will help you more and understanding
about it.
This time it has been a much better seminar
as I have seen it. We must have a proper seminar,
may be tomorrow morning we might try to have
a proper seminar of this brain trust or something
but most of the people who are coming will
be really coming tomorrow. So I don't know
may be tomorrow evening you can have brain
trust. They’ll be coming tomorrow sometime,
there’s hardly any time for a seminar which
I would like you all to sit down and have
a proper brain trust or something or you can
have it tomorrow morning and also you can
have it day after tomorrow sometime. So something
can be arranged by the leaders and all the
leaders of the world should meet and should
do it.
As the program stands it is so. But in Sahaja
Yoga programs are never just the same. Changing
is the sign of life. As I told you a little
root has got a very little small tiny cell
at the end of it which is very discreet and
it changes its course according to the way
it can penetrate into the Mother Earth. If
there is a big boulder it goes round and round
and round to create a bondage for it later
on for the tree to stand on. Then it goes
into all various areas in a proper manner
whichever way the best and Sahaj. In the same
way it's a living process and whatever works
out has to be worked out in that manner. Sometimes
you might sleep at ten o'clock, sometimes
you may sleep at one o'clock. Sometimes you
may sleep at anytime. It depends on whatever
way the things are moving. We have to be prepared
for everything in a very sweet manner with
an enjoyable manner.
So once, we start deciding that we are going
to be great Sahaja Yogis, we are here to be
the Nirmalites, to fight all that is wrong,
to stand for right and to emancipate the whole
humanity. If you understand the tremendous
work we have to do, then you will create your
own personalities in such way that you will
be able to shoulder this great responsibility.
So let us see, today is the beginning of this
understanding between us that we are not going
to grow by demanding, by asking, by getting
worried about ourselves. But just be enjoy,
just be enjoy and this is what is lacking
in some people and that's why they cannot
enjoy. They are all the time worried how will
they reach there, how will they come here,
what is the arrangement, what's this, what
is that. Just take it easy and things will
work out for you. That's how you are going
to enjoy life.
May God bless you all!