I bow to all the seekers of truth.
First of all
We have to know what is the truth.
People are seeking, seeking, seeking, seeking all over.
But they don't know what they are seeking and what should they get after their seeking.
This seeking can lead you into many diverse directions. Some of them could be very very dangerous and absolutely misleading.
And many must have or also felt that. I'm sure there are many who have found it out.
But they think there is no way they can return.
The seeking is very simple to understand.
That you want to know yourself.
All the time we say : i want this, i like this, i this, i that.
But who is this I? What is it?
Who is this one myself?
What am i? Do i know anything about myself?
It's very superficial knowledge we have about ourselves.
Everybody have said, all the religions have said : you should  know yourself.
There is no difference on this one. Actually in all religions, if you're go into essence, there is no difference.
According to time it was little bit stressed on one point and sometimes on another point.
But the fundamental thing is that you have to know yourself.
How do you know yourself is the point.
People will say: do this, give up everything, give up your family,  give up everything.
Wear, this kind of dress cut your hair or shave your head and all that nonsense.
It's so outward.
If you put a little bit of your intelligence you'll see it's all outward.
It's so skin deep, it has no meaning.
So what has to happen?
We talk of a last breakthrough of the evolution.
How do you achieve it?
When you are evolved up to the stage of human beings.
We have to know one thing for definitely.
That there's something missing within us.
Otherwise world would have been a most beautiful place, the paradise to live in.
But something's wrong with the human beings and what is that?
Is to understand how we have come through evolution.
And as human beings there are so many things of the animal stage lingering within us.
The way we talk, the way we try to oppress others, the way we talk to sort of dominate others.
The way we want to snatch everything, the way we are only worried about our food.This, that.
All this is not really a noble human beings sides.
These are all lingering from that animal instinct. All right. We have to accept it.
Because we are human beings so they are to be there.
Nothing so much frightening.
But also we have one more thing that we think.
And we think and think and think and think no end of ourselves sometimes.
Sometimes we think we should protest for this.
Sometimes we feel that we must become very violent
All these things are coming from our human mind.
Animals won't be violent for something just for violence sake. They'll be violent, alright.
But for their own purpose of killing some animal or something.
But here we have groups and groups of people who just enjoy violence.
This is another development in the human awareness, i think, that we enjoy  destruction of others.
But also there is a seeking.
This is the sign that people want their evolution, they want to evolve into a better personality.
That they want to become
something
which is complete.
How do you achieve it?
Now I must say that we have not achieved our evolution ourselves up to the human level.
So to achieve a higher
awareness
there must be some arrangement between us.
And that is the arrangement we are not aware of.
And that arrangement is that within you is the power.
It's your own power.
To give you this
last breakthrough
Through the awakening of that power, already you have been told about it.
It exists,  it's there.
And It is the right of every human being to get his self-knowledge, self-realization.
Sahaja,  Saha means born with you.
With you is born the right.
And why should we not ask our fundamental  rights
society that we should have our self-realization. Which is your own.
It is there already placed within you. You don't have to do anything, of course you can't pay for it.
How much did you pay for your evolution so far?
And how can it be different from different people?
Because in every human being this power, which we call as Kundalini exists.
Whether he is white, black, yellow, blue any color.
Whether he belongs to north or south, anyplace.
Whether he belongs to this country or that country.
They all have this power universally placed it their Kundalini.
Even if I say everybody has a heart.
So why should we have differentiation?
But this mind.
This human mind creates this differentiation and this problems saying that of course they are not of our country.
They don't belong to our group and like animals again we start getting into groups.
Groups of
different, I don't know, denomination. Like some people have their
fork and spoon put this way, so they are one group.
Some people drink coffee, so they have a group like that, you see. We are very good at forming groups.
This is also animal instinct, I think, that we try to form groups of such stupid things.
And then we can have wars.
Because we must fight. We are a group,something great, so we should fight others.
All these instincts that are within us are inherited.
They have come to us. They say it is in our genes.
Still, can we change the genes?
Can we
transform
Our personality into something higher and for that
I tell you there is a power within us all of you have that power within you.
And what does it give you?
It  passes through six centers, as  told you, it nourishes it
it integrates it and
ultimately it pierces through the last fontanel bone area. We can call that actualisation or the baptism.
And is
connected to the all-pervading power of divine love.
Again, I say love
divine compassion.
And divine love.
So you get connected to that power which is all-pervading?
If you ask a doctor who runs our heart, he'll say it's the autonomous nervous system.But what, who is the auto?
Who does all these things?
Who does all the living work?Look at this flowers,beautiful.
Who has made these flowers such a different different flower?
How does this mother Earth differentiates and how she gives all these flowers?
Do we think about it? We take it for granted.
All living work we take it for granted, but it is done by this divine power.
Believe me. There is this divine power
around us which protects us, which looks after us, which guides us
and also
above all it loves us.
And it cares for us.
It wants, that we should all receive
the blessings of this all-pervading power.