Please, be seated
[Hindi]...
Don't cross the limits of Shri Mataji's chair. You, there. All right.
So with Shri Mataji's blessings, and thanks to the teaching of "Maushi" [aunt in Marathi],
we would like to present you with a "Bharood" [Marathi religious song] by Sant Eknath.
It's a song that, in a style that
is designed to teach people
what will happen to them if they don't behave in a, in the correct way.
In this particular song, Sant Eknath is talking about what happens to people
if they're not if they trick people badly.
If they are, if they are rude to them if they cheat them.
Sant Eknath gives example in particular
of Duryodhana
who took Draupadi and humiliated her in his court
and it was eventually his brother,
the brother of Duryodhana drag Draupadi into the cour to be humiliated.
And was eventually punished by Bhishma,
Bhishma, Bhishma [Bema]
[Bema]
who was punished by Bhishma in a dual.
In the same way, Ravana who kidnapped Shri Sita was duly punished by Shri Rama.
And so on in many cases.
In reality, there are only four people that Sant Eknath mentions
who are free from any kind of problem in his regard.
For example, Bhishma and Hanumana,
those two are examples.
Sant Eknath concludes the song
inviting us to be
to be sweet with each other and not to abuse each other.
Otherwise- cause if we do, then our fate is a very ugly one.
Give me a microphone for tablas.
Wonderful!
May God bless you
...For their very kind and very appreciate for their treatment
and everything that they did for me and my daughter
I have no words to give them my gratitude.
And then I need not add
that my greatest thanks are to Shri Mataji
Shri Mataji has suggested a new name for this raga
Since this is a gift from the disciple to the guru
and guru is synonymous of "Purnima" that is the full Moon,
Shri Mataji says that this raga should be called "Chaitanya Purnima".
That means-
I think this is the biggest award a disciple can expect from a guru,
that She has blessed this raga with a very wonderful name.
Jai Shri Mataji