There are in these modern times, many seekers
of truth.
It's a special category of people born in
these modern times.
Perhaps we are not aware that in every country,
a lot of people are born with this seeking.
They are a special category which, sees beyond,
tries to find something beyond, what they
can perceive through their sense organs.
The truth as we see, is through our sense
organs.
For example something we see as white, we
call it white, something we feel cool, we
call it cold, something as hot, means whatever
we perceive through our sense organs and whatever
is communicated to us through our central
nervous system we accept as truth, and we
should accept that only, as truth.
And not something that is told to us, not
something that we have read in the books,
not something that we can project our mind
to, and then .......................that does
not mean that I deny any one of the scriptures.
That does not mean that I deny anything that
we have known so far.
But to begin with let us start from scratch
as they call it or a clean slate.
Let us see what is the truth.
Now in every religion truth has been described.
As I can see it, everybody does not see it
themselves.....................That's why
there's blindness, that's why there are these
blind alleys where you end up, arguing things.
So there must be something that is missing
within us, that we have not been able to really
relate truth to our central nervous system.
And what is that missing within us, we should
find out.
In all humility we should know that there
must be something within us, that we have
been arguing about so many things, we have
been talking about so many things, reading
so many books, going into all kinds of funny
experiences, right from alcohol to other drugs
and Gurus and this and that, but still we
have not felt anything on our central nervous
system.
Secondly that we have no control over that
truth.
So, so what is the reason?
Is it there is something missing in the human
awareness?
Is it that we are lacking something in our
human awareness?
All the books, all the scriptures, which are
true scriptures have said one thing, that
to know the truth, you are to be born again.
That's not only in the bible.
You see if you take Patanjali which is a very
ancient book, it's not that the Patanjali
asked you to stand on your heads, is wrong,
it's just a wee, wee, wee, wee bit of it.
But what Patanjali has written is that you
have to achieve the truth on your central
nervous system through your ATMASAKSHAT, the
word is written, meaning the experience of
your SPIRIT.
Now English language has an advantage and
a disadvantage, that the spirit could be alcohol,
the spirit could be an alcohol!
Or spirit could be a dead body, it could be
any circumstance, but it is not so.
There are three separate things, absolutely
opposite to each other.
So the ATMA the SPIRIT has to be found out,
is said even by Mohammed Sahib, he said you
are to become the PIR, is said by.
Zoroaster, is said by Loa Tse, is also said
by Zen.
Buddha has said it, Mahavira has said it,
everyone of them has said it, so many religions
have started in the name of God without going
to the truth, that you have to be born again.
Now you have to be born again does mean that
you certify yourself 'I am born again'.
Self certificate, you can call it 'I am born
again', but you don't become.
What is so special if you are born again,
what should be so?
The human awareness at this level is just
ready to be born again.
Now in Sanskrit the word for a bird is DWIJAHA,
means born again, and also for a Brahmin who
is born again.
But those who call themselves Brahmins are
not Brahmins.
They just call themselves Brahmins, have they
come to know the Brahma, the all pervading
power of God.
Those who say they are born again, should
feel the all pervading power of God around
them, if they cannot feel it they are not
born again.
So all these self certificates are deception,
self deception and deception of others, is
just a money making process.
So the truth has to be achieved through your
evolutionary process which is a living process.
Again we must understand a LIVING process.
Not you just talking, mental projections,
just sitting down here big talk about it,
or by giving you some courses, or taking some
money from you.
You cannot get it, it's a STATE in a living
growth, that proves that it is a living thing.
Means the state of our awareness has to be
higher than what it is.
If our state cannot rise then it is not of
any use.
Like the seed becomes the roots then the bark,
the leaves, the flowers then the fruit.
Different states.
In the same way a living religion must give
you a different state and that nucleus of
religion is within ourselves.
Everyone of us has it.
When we go against that living religion within
us we go into imbalances.
But even today people can ask why the religion,
why should we have a balance, what is the
need, lets go into imbalances, I mean, is
that a logical question.
People can ask why the religion, why has the
religion in the stomach..........................so
what is the religion we come to that point,
is that, a religion is a valency of human
beings.
Just like carbon has four valences human beings
have ten valences, which matter does not have.
Animals have nine and human beings have ten
valences.
And when these ten valences go out of balance
then, they go out of the quality of a human
being.
But still one can ask why do we have those
ten valences.
Because we have to ascend, because in the
evolutionary process you have to ascend and
you can never be satisfied with yourself unless
and until you have achieved it.
Especially the seekers, that's why I say they
are the special category because in this special
category men of God will have to become prophets
and they will have powers to make others prophets,
said by William Blake.
In your great country William Blake has said
it.
When is that going to happen?
It has to happen today, tonight.
But there are barriers within us, built in,
not because of anything else but only because
we have misled ourselves.
We have been going to various roads of seeking,
whatever suited us, where ever we went to,
we have tried to...............and we have
insured ourselves within ourselves sometimes,
we have built up certain barriers.
Now when you become the prophet, actually
become your own master, become a free person,
you have to be a free person.
So far you are not.
You cannot overcome your own weaknesses, your
own temptations, infatuations, emotional problems,
mental worries -- why?
Because you are still standing in the waves
of this turmoil.
This troubled area where you just see the
waves all the time and you are frightened
of breaking down, but if you somehow or other
get out of it and get into the boat of your
own being, then you enjoy, you become a witness
a Sakshi.
Even to understand the scriptures, you have
to become a free person, which you are not.
You have to be your own master, for that you
cannot pay.
I am too free, that I cannot accept it.
To get your freedom of Spirit you can't pay,
because money is money.
Money has no value in the Divine field.
Nothing can bring forth this but your own
ascent.
And how do we ascend?
Is there anything built within us?
So what ever I am telling you today is the
knowledge of the roots.
What we see is the knowledge of the tree.
We see it from outside, we see a leaf from
out side, if we have to treat the leaf, we
have to go to the roots.
But from outside, when we see the tree we
are still outside also.
When you have to treat the leaf, you have
to go to the roots, if you block out the leaf,
it is dead.
Then you put it under the microscope, you
can go on seeing cells after that you can
see the nucleus, you can go on analysing it,
and analysing it making it dead, and dead
and dead.
But to treat it you have to go to the roots.
And this knowledge of roots we have here.
There's nothing wrong in knowing something
new.
These are not new ideas, these are ancient
ideas, very ancient ideas.
In the Bible it is described as the Holy Ghost.
One priest was asked I saw ......................a
very narrow minded priest, what do you know
about Holy Ghost?
He said "I am agnostic".
So then they said, what are you doing here?
He said "I am doing my job".
If that is the attitude towards God, towards
your inner knowledge, then you can never reach
there as you cannot reach the tree through
the leaf, you have to go to the roots.
This has been available only to seers, like
you can say William Blake.
Like we had many in other countries, but they
did not talk about it because perhaps that
was not the time for people to know.
But in many languages it is described.
Now the roots within us, if you can see this,
are placed in this manner.
When I went to America the Indian society
invited me to talk to them about the unconscious.
I had never read Jung, though I knew he was
a realised soul at least he got his realization
at the later time.
So I said all right let me have a look, let
me see .............theory, say, and as I
opened the book I saw a diagram, what he had
drawn of a human being and I said that's the
mistake.
Because he saw human beings from outside and
he described them in layers, like first he
said is the unconscious that cannot be expressed,
manifested then the unconscious that can be
manifested, then he said about at least the
sub-conscious and then he said above that
is the conscious mind, then above that is
the ego.
Like layers, one after another.
Now when you are sitting here, though you
are in layers the path is laid down.
In the same way within us, God being the greatest
organiser, he has not made us into layers
but what he has made us in a parallel way,
as you can see there very clearly.
Left side and right side.
Left side and right side, the central path,
three paths he has made within us, for our
evolutionary process.
The central path works out our evolution.
The left side gives us the desire and the
right side gives us the power of action.
These are just the principles I am telling
you but you can understand it slowly when
you grow, all the details of it.
The central path is evolution, has brought
you today to this level of human awareness.
Now beyond that is a very short ascent which
you have to achieve; by which you become the
Spirit.
But there has to be some living process for
this to happen.
And what is that living process built within
us, is the reflection of the Holy Ghost within
us in the triangular bone, which is called
as Kundalini in Sanskrit language.
This exists within us, and you can see with
your naked eyes, sometimes, in some people
where there is an obstruction in the higher
centres, it starts pulsating.
And when we can sense, we can also see it
clearly in some people when it is obstructing.
Or through your stethoscope you can feel the
percussion which we call as anahat at the
top of the head here, where it pulsates and
then it breaks.
When this breaks the pulsation stops and you
start feeling the cool breeze of the Holy
Ghost coming out of your fontanel bone area.
This is a happening and not ..............................in
the sense that the happening takes place so
that you get connected with the truth.
So the connection takes place and you start
feeling on your finger tips the cool breeze
of the Holy Ghost which surrounds you.
Actually, you start feeling.
But then as the rational mind says so what!
Though we feel the cool breeze, so what?
Then one should know, that when we have eyes
we start seeing, when we have ears we start
hearing, so now you have got a new awareness,
what is this awareness?
This is the awareness of collective consciousness,
that you become, again I say you become, you
are not just certified but you become, it's
a question of becoming, that you become collectively
conscious.
That on your central nervous system you can
feel another person, you can feel yourself,
you can feel your centres which are shown
here, you can feel the centres of others on
your fingertips.
And the best one is, is Mohammed Sahib, I
would say because he made it clear, at the
time of resurrection your hands will speak.
But who talks about the resurrection?
Nowhere!
People talk about it, they talk about the
doomsday, because they can frighten people
of the doomsday first, and take advantage
of it and make money out of it.
God who has made this universe, he feels love,
do you think he will destroy this great creation
of his without giving us the fruit, without
letting us know the fruit of his creation.
He is the wisest of wise.
The greatest compassionate source of love,
how could he allow this universe to be destroyed,
especially this Earth, which is a special
present from him.
So don't believe in all these stupid ideas
of destruction and the last complete devastation.
Still lot of plans, you are suppose to enjoy
the blessings of the Divine for which he has
created you.
So the experience of truth has to be felt
on the central nervous system.
The problem is, not that you belong, you may
feel, but as you know the experience is very
slow in the western countries.
I am sorry, not that you are in any way less
seekers, you are very great seekers, I would
say you are greater seekers than the Indians
are, much greater seekers.
Indians have still a lot of steps to come
up to your level, no doubt, but while coming
up to this level, you have developed a lot
of problems around and that's why the seeking
is sometimes, takes time to express itself
as a fruitful gain of Self Realization.
So you'll get your self realization no doubt
but again the Kundalini goes down.
I must tell you very frankly, because I cannot
be dishonest, but it can be brought up, by
you, by understanding how to work it out.
By co-operating with your self, by understanding
your self, that you are the temple of God
and that you have to work it out with respect
to yourself, and you have to give some time.
I mean in Caxton Hall, you must have seen
there, thousands of people have got it.
I have been working in this England for twelve
years now, twelve years, is the last year
now.
Special reason for that, but what I find,
people get their realization and then they're
lost.
Then when they have some disease or something,
they'll telephone to me Mother, now I am.............
has happened or I am suffering from cancer...........................is
too far gone a case, but if you know how to
handle your roots, how to nourish it, how
to look after it, then you flower out, you
bear fruits, and by your fruits people know
what it is.
Then you become trees, giant trees, like moving
trees.
And when people come under such trees, get
realization.
English are a great people no doubt, they
are placed in a country which is the heart
of the universe, you are very important.
I have given the maximum time to England,
you'll be amazed, maximum time.
But the Sahaja Yogis who are not in the country
have grown much faster than in England.
The reason is, it's like the foundation that
always gets (damp in it) you are the ..................................................foundation.
Remove the darkness, again it gets dark.
Rather difficult!
But once they are settled, you will be circulating
the Divine interpretation, the Divine experience
of truth all over the world.
You are like the hard-core and this is what
you have to do.
We cannot be mediocre in Sahaja Yoga.
There is no compromise with your self, you
become so powerful that you don't compromise
also, you can just get out of everything in
no time.
But you must accept yourself first of all,
have faith in yourself.
Once upon a time the English had too much
faith in themselves, I mean extraordinarily
powerful people, now they are the other way
around, they have no faith.
You see now this darkness has come and ....the
darkness has come ...................thrown
out.
This is the second phase that I find is complete
lethargy.
Oh what can happen, let us be destroyed Mother,
now that's the best part, completely reconciled
to our doom.
Now how to get them to be creative?
We have to circulate.
They are the cells, who are like in the heart,
who have to pump the heart...............................
So I have to make a humble request, that I
know experience of Sahaja Yoga is slow but
very steady and I am sure that today I have
got people who are a rare quality of courage.
And as individual which was the English character,
once upon a time, and that they will take
it up seriously, their ascent and the ascent
of the whole world.
We'll be having about three more lectures
and there I will tell you more elaborately
about Kundalini and the Chakras, about all
this knowledge.
All this knowledge is available to you.
Now, because this time was for you to know
all these secrets.
Some newspaper people asked me, Mother have
you got your disciples all very big scholars,
I said no, they are very ordinary people.
Some may be, they are more difficult, but
mostly they are very normal, ordinary people.
Simple people.
But what makes you think that?
They said they are so scholarly they know
so much, because you become the knowledge.
So truth is the knowledge, the rest of it
is all mythical.
Is mythical, what do we know about things
is all mythical, because what ever we see
from outside, is outside.
Like I would say we appreciate Mona Lisa,
we appreciate the miracles as we say, the
great miracles that human beings have created.
Why?
Why do we call them miracles?
Sometimes we think that we have observed a
very miraculous task, they are, mentally we
think.
But actually it is not so.
Because they have vibrations, they have Divine
vibrations, they emit vibrations and they
appeal to you because in your heart lies that
Spirit, which is the universal being and which
gives that feeling of bewilderment when you
see these great miracles human beings have
created.
At least I have seen six of them, and all
of them have tremendous vibrations.
But unless and until you become a realised
soul, how will you know?
(silence)
Now this is the only .............. and to
become the realised soul you have to have
the ascent of the Kundalini and proper state
of that Kundalini to remain there and that's
the point where I found we lack in the efforts.
Lack in courage, in patience, so again and
again I request you that don't be superficial.
The Americans were superficial, you better
not be.
You be solid people, serious, take it up seriously.
Because you are going to be the Europeans,
the Americans even the Greeks, even the Italians,
the problem is the horse is behind the cart.........................but
what do I do, prove to the horse, that you
get up now because of you the cart is not
moving.
That's why ...........very very special ..........to
see you all, that you must decide that if
we get our Realization, we'll establish ourselves
into Sahaja Yoga.
For which you don't have to pay, there's no
membership, there's no organisation, nothing.
I have nothing to take from you.
You can't give me.
So I hope today, many who are new will get
their Realization and establish themselves
and will not forget it.
Because in the beginning the experience is
very great, you feel like you are coming out
of a pub.
I don't know what that experience is, must
be that way (laughter) because I've seen so
many people coming and falling down and again
going in, must be some memory of something
great, must be that.
So by God's grace you should all get your
Realization and I would like to have some
questions, but in that I would like to say
that there are people I know, we have had
before also, belonging to some gurus or something
big, like some gurus have come too, because
you see they feel, the gurus are feeling that
I may been attacking them; in a way, they
feel that way because I say you cannot pay,
so their profession is finished.
So they get angry with me for that, so they
might be saying they are in .................and
attack her and all sorts of things and there
could be some people who are aggressive because
of other problems of ego or something.
So you need not be aggressive, I have come
here to give you what you have and you need
not be also docile about it or slavish.
I have come here to give you or tell you what
is free.
Now you may also say, it is a very common
question that arises in your mind, and justified,
that why should I do it, now that's the miserable
part of it, that I have to do it, I wish you
could do it, but you can't that's the problem.
And if I have to do it, I don't hurt your
ego.
No!
I don't want to hurt it.
You see this is something people don't understand,
that why should I do it.
You can do it also, but first I have to take
you little bit............your awareness has
to grow a little more, then you can do it
your way, but first definitely, I have to
do that.
Which is a .........it makes me also a miserable
person because............you know...........a
thankless job, but I have to do it.
Maybe I am doing it for it somehow, I don't
know...........but it should be............It's
a crucifixion, I tell you, it's not easy,
it's a very difficult task.
It's like mountains sometimes, the Kundalini
is just embedded, poor thing sometimes so
hurt, so wounded that to raise that Kundalini
itself takes such a load, effort.
But one has to do it and I know
I have to do it.
When you will know
what it is, you will not
be angry with me, but
you will understand the task and .............all
of us, all
of us have to do it.
May God Bless You.