Woman : … which is the point of evolution
for all of us and it gives great pleasure
to Sahaja Yogis to see so many other people
coming along to get their Realisation. Because
the experience, once you achieve it makes
you collectively conscious and puts you in
touch in a very real way with the vibrations
of other people and with your own vibrations
of course so that you are able to feel the
exact condition of your subtle body, and your
Spirit, and your chakras, which are these
colored circles here (that) represent the
subtle transformers of energy that are placed
within us along our sympathetic nervous system.
And in the center there, between the yellow
and blue lines, the area in which the Kundalini
energy rises when it’s awaken by the presence
of another being who already has that awakened
within him. And [UNCLEAR] meeting the vibrations
that are the same as the universal Kundalini
energy.
Kundalini in Christian terms is called the
Holy Spirit, and it’s the same energy that
is described in the New Testament as a “cool
wind”. In Indians Scriptures it is described
as the “Chaitanya”, as “cool vibrations”,
and in Muslim’s scripture it is called the
“Ruh”, and also described as cool vibrations.
And these cool vibrations that you feel once
you receive the awakening, the vibrations
of absolute Truth, once you develop this awareness,
you are able to ask any absolute question.
And by holding your hands out you can ask
; if you’re () you can ask the existence
of God. And rather you get a cool or warm
vibration you can tell whether what you are
asking about is true or not true. You do need
to rely of your intellect anymore to try to
work out things, because that’s a limited
sphere of activity. But actually, when you
get your realisation, you go beyond mere thinking,
into the unlimited, into the divine area.
I think it’s a relief to be with people
who are seeking their Spirit, who do have
the desire to know the Divine, and to understand
those things that, in this society, have almost
become [to boo/taboo] subjects. There is so
much emphasis around this, upbringing on material
success and competition, doing better than
everybody else and achieving things, that
the subtles things that are much more important
get pushed completely into the background.
And sometimes we feel, as if we quite at a
step with everything because we know there’s
an uneasy feeling that there is something
wrong with the world at the moment, but we
can’t put it right ourselves. And it’s
quite distressing.
In my experience once I actually received
my realisation from Mother two years ago,
in Melbourne, at a program like this, I couldn’t
believe it. That it did actually … That
I had found what I was looking for without
even quite knowing what it was that I was
looking for. And it’s because at first you
try to understand with your intellect and
it doesn’t seems to even make sense. A lot
of people, their self esteem have been so
damaged by their seeking that it’s hard
to believe that you, yourself, can have this
quality within you that is just waiting to
be awaken.
So perhaps before Mataji arrives, it can be
good if we can all sit quietly, and don’t
try to do anything, if you’ve been in the
habit of doing particular types of meditation
or techniques, just try to put it aside and
try to have a completely opened mind about
this experience because it is different, although
the terms may seems familiar to you from readings
and teachings that you’ve had. It’s best
to sort of try to approach it like a child
with complete openness and freshness. There’s
nothing frightening about the experience,
because it is in fact a gift of God to us,
and God is compassion and love. And the vibrations
that you feel when the Kundalini is awakened
are those vibrations that come from that Being.
And there is nothing to be afraid of although
some books do say that Kundalini awakening
can be dangerous and so on, the people who
have written that have experienced something
quite different. But the actual experience
should give you peace and joy which is absolute.
So if you can just try, just be at peace now
and quite and then (633) the frame of mind
and enjoy the experience when Mother comes.
Thank you.
A man (to Shri mataji)
Shri Mataji (to the man)
The man (to the audience) : Again ladies and
gentlemen, it gives me a great pleasure especially
to the [The man stops as Shri Mataji receive
a bouquet]
Shri Mataji : Thank you very much.
The man : Especially for the people who come
for the first time, there are many who couldn’t
come either last evening or today to the workshop,
to all of you, welcome. Shri Mataji is here,
for the first time in Perth to grant Self
Realisation, not just on a one-to-one basis
but to as many people as desired from their
heart. Many got it last night, some came to
the workshop today and experienced something
more. All of you have to get it because this
is the time where the grace of God is overflowing
and all of the true seekers of ages have to
get Self Realisation. It’s the reward of
their seeking, it’s the blessing of their
past births and all the seeking of God over
the ages.
We’ve all probably been a christian, we’ve
all been a jew, we’ve all been a muslim.
We’ve been worshippers of God the Father
and God the Mother, at many, many, times in
history. And so now the times has come where
we can get that final step in our evolution
which is just to be triggered by an enlightened
being. And once you get it you can develop
to that point when you become totally one
with God.
This is the real yoga. Yoga as you know means
“union”, “oneness with God”. It’s
not exercises it’s not discipline, it’s
the actualisation of Self Realisation. And
so, without further introduction by me, it
gives me again a great pleasure, ladies and
gentlemen, to introduce to you Her Holiness
Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi.
Shri Mataji : To all the seekers of Truth
and Joy I bow. It was really nice this morning
to meet some earnest seekers come down to
the place where I live and to get their ultimate
: what they are seeking. We have to know that
God has created us with a purpose. He has
worked for so many years, He hamade us human
beings with such care and love, there has
to be a purpose behind it. We also know that
we have not yet found our purpose and that’s
why we are seeking. If we understand that,
then one must know that something has to happen.
God has to save His creation, and His greatest
creation is a human being. So this what he
has done with all the creation that He tried
to evolve, and that’s how human beings are
created.
The only thing was a human being was given
freedom to choose between the right and the
wrong for life. It so happened that human
being in their error, naiveness, I should
say, and ignorance, did lots of mistakes.
Doesn’t matter, even if they have done,
they have come to right conclusion. And that
right conclusion as I told you yesterday sums
up like this : that ‘whatever is going to
happen to us, further than this, it has to
be spontaneous. It’s a living process that
made us human being nothing dead— living
process that has to work it out, that it has
to be spontaneous, we can not work it out.
Secondly, that you can not pay for it, or
you can not maneuver it. And thirdly that
you can not put in any effort, it has to be
effortless. If it is has to be the most [UNCLEAR
1210], is has to be effortless.
So that’s how we reach certain conclusions,
that Self-Realisation, if it is epitome of
our evolution, it has to be absolutely freely
given, and has to happen in a very spontaneous
way.
Yesterday I explained to you in short all
the various type of ideas people have about
Self-Realisation, and what we have to expect
about Self-Realisation. We had another enquiry
this morning about Kundalini, that gentleman
asked me a question saying that he read a
book saying that Kundalini business is very
difficult,it comes upto a point and also not
beyond a point and all sorts of stories.
I have to tell you that that’s not true.
Kundalini is your own Mother. You have your
individual Mother. And She is waiting all
the time all these years just to give you
your second birth. She never harms you, She
never troubles you, She doesn’t do anything
of that kind …. I don’t know the people
who do not know how to do the thing or who
have no authority, must be doing all these
kind of tricks, and must be suffering from
Kundalini awakening.
I know of one gentleman, who in Kashmir said
that he’s got Kundalini awakening and he
had tremendous eat and he had tremendous burning
and all sort of things. And that it’s a
very dangerous thing. He has written a book
on that, sort of a … I’m forgetting the
name of the book. Now this gentleman himself
is leading a very horrible life ; of that,
I’ve been able to find out. He had all sort
of relation, he is leading a sort of ridiculous
life, not suitable for any saint. If such
a man has to have Kundalini awakening, I can’t
understand how can Kundalini come to him but,
must be some sort of God’s anger on him
that he has felt some kind of feeling within
Him maybe. Or maybe he has been to somebody
who is a wrong type of a person who has awakened
the Kundalini without any authority and maybe
that time the first Deity as I told you … (To
Sahaja Yogis) Is it there ? The chart is not
there. Ha here. (To the audience) The first
Deity as I told you, did not like it and got
angry and the whole sympathetic nervous system
on the left hand side and on the right hand
side got angry. And when that happen the person
may develop lots of heat and lots of blisters,
I have seen a person getting a blisters all
over all around his neck.
At the very outset I must tell you that heat
is the sign of violent action. Say for example
if you heat the helium gas, the molecules
of the helium gas start going all round, they
are very volatile. They start moving in a
way that you feel that two armies are fighting,
then you find that en armies are fighting
then you find that all of them are fighting
with each other. But if you cool it down,
their action is very collective, they move
in a smooth manner in a very collective manner.
So one can see that when we are heated up
also, you see a man is very hot tempered.
(Which) Means he is a very angry person, and
he can not carry on with others, he has no
patience. But when a person is cool, he is
collected, we say ‘he is a nice person’.
In the same way if you feel heat from your
Kundalini, then be sure that something is
wrong that is resisting you. Even while giving
Realisation in the beginning you do feel little
heat because the heat of the body has to go
out. But today I’m going to tell you particularly
more about the chakras and not about the general
things that I told you last time. In any case
you can get the book, and come to our centers
and clarify it more and more. But as much
as possible today I will try to tell you about
the chakras : how we spoil them, and what
are the effect of these subtle chakras which
look after our gross plexuses within our body.
17:30 Please be sitted.
Now the first chakra as I told you is called
as the Mooladhara chakra. [Microphone arrangement
17:45] Now this i the first center which is
a subtle center within us. And this plexus
is manifesting about in as your called the
pelvic plexus. The pelvic plexus is responsible
for all our excretions. Whether you like it
or not it is there, it is present within us
and it looks after our excretory functions.
It is important to see that this chakra is
placed under the Kundalini. So when the kundalini
rises ; the Kundalini is the power within
you, the pure power of desire : the desire
that you want to become one with the Divine.
It lies below. This chakra lies below, it’s
a very important point, that this chakra does
not play any part in the ascent of the Kundalini
because Kundalini doesn’t pierce through
it. On the contrary if this chakra is pure,
the information about somebody that wants
to raise your Kundalini can be easily communicated
through this this chakra but it does not play
any part in our evolution. That means sex
does not play play part in our evolution.
Animal know what sex is, human beings know
what sex is. Sex is a part very natural within
us and for our ascent, the sex does not play
any part. At the time when the Kundalini rises
; the Kundalini who is the Mother of the deity
in this center, this Kundalini is the Virgin.
So He is looking after the protocol of the
Virgin. And this Kundalini when She has to
rises, if you have by any chance () with this
chakra, then it takes time for Kundalini to
rises because this center has to give permission,
or you say the sanction that it’s alright
then the Kundalini can rises. This is the
sustaining force, or it’s the center of
the Kundalini itself.
Now the word Mooladhara means ‘the one who
is the support of … ’ (to Herself) ‘Moola’
is … ‘Moola’ is … (to the audience)
‘… of the root’. The root is the Kundalini
and it resides is that area which is called
as Mooladhara while the center is down. And
the center is called as ‘Mooladhara Chakra’.
that’s how you have these two things separated.
Now it is important, because it is the sustenance,
it looks after the protocol of your Kundalini.
So anybody who says that you can ascend through
sex, please be sure you are mislead by that.
I do not want to mislead you, I want you to
have your Self Realisation because you are
people who are seekers, not today, you’ve
been seekers of ages. And no use running after
something because it appeals you on weaknesses
or because it supports some sort of a thing
which you heard before like Freud.
What Freud has said is absolutely wrong. Because
what he has achieved today, you can see clearly
that all the societies in the west are finished.
This is thank to the unholy trinity, and one
of them is mister Freud. When I said this
in Austria people were very happy because
they were feeling guilty for this Freu whom
they supported always and what he has done
: he’s played a mess with everybody’s
live, he just knew one side of life. Which
start from the sex and goes up. That’s only
the desire. That’s only the desire power
but he didn’t know the other side. When
he talked that you should not be conditioned
at all, he did not know that if you did not
conditioned yourself, then there is another
side which is much more dangerous, and that
is the side of ego.
This is what exactly Hitler did. He used his
ego, and with this ego like so many such people
who are taking ‘there is nothing like conditioning,what’s
wrong, what’s wrong ?’ and what they achieved
is nothing but a very bumptious,, useless
ego which can not see the Truth. Anybody who
that ego, they run after it. They say
this is your name – big name they give you
– or just do this, you look like this, you
wear this ; you get quite satisfied with this.
You have to be honest, if you are not honest
to it, how will you get your Realisation.
You have to be honest to get your Realisation,
you have to be a human being first and last.
if you are not a human being you are just
trying to do something which is so outside.
If you are doing something outside, you can
not get it inside, you has to happen inside.
I feel concerned because you people are realised
person if you take to reality but if you don’t
take to it, what’s going to happen to you
? Because you are seekers, you are not like
mundane ordinary people, who are not seeking,
who are just seeking money or possession or
thing. You are special people, you are people
of God who have to become prophets, and you
must have powers to make others prophets as
William Blake has said about hundreds years
back. You are that type of people, and you
should not waste your energy believe in things
which is not true. Because you see the Kundalini
is placed above that point which we call as
sex.
We are not sex points to reduce ourselves
to sex points is the minimum ; I mean the
more degrading things that can happen to human
beings. We are the highest type of creation
God. Sex, everybody has, even earthworms have,
any sort of nonsense ahs sex. What so Great
about sex ? There is so much we talk about
sex as if we are impotent people. There is
nothing is sex that can give you your Realisation.
Of course, you have to lead a sanity … (Shri
Mataji correct Herself) You have to understand
a life of sanity and lead a life of understanding
about sex.
Sahaja Yoga is never against sex, we believe
in sensible marriages, bringing up children
who are really realised souls to be born on
this Earth, that is the thing that we have
to achieve. So many great people who want
to be born. But the people who are going to
give them birth are
lost into nonsensical things,they are just
lost. They have no idea as to the whole, what
() what role they have to play into it, Just
they get lost into their individual understanding
of a thing. It is not that, you have. You
have to understand it’s a very cosmic thing
that’s happening, and thousands and thousands
and thousands of people have to get their
Realisation, that’s the main thing. If you
don’t get your Realisation, I must say all
the [] of desire of yours is lost forever.
So don’t fix your mind into something that
somebody has screwed into your head because
thousands are running after it. Maybe that
reality can not have thousands, maybe… Millions
we can’t have, I know that. Reality is not
easy to accept. Never people accepted reality
so far.
When Christ came in, how they behaved, when
Buddha came in, how they behaved ? Nobody
does that way. You see, it’s like a horde
that’s walking towards it, it’s not a
shoal of fishes walking towards it, it’s
not a big mob walking towards it, it’s every
person that has to receive the Realisation.
And you have to pay full attention to it.
You have to respect yourself and know that
you are a seeker and as a seeker you all must
get your Realisation otherwise you have no
meaning no purpose nothing. And if you join
any purpose let pursue I would say : I’ve
told with all earnestness and with all my
love. But if you don’t want to understand
it, nobody can force you Realisation. So please
understand that first thing is to get your
Realisation. If you can’t get your Realisation,
then you have lost the biggest chance of your
life.
You all have to become your Spirit, your Self,
and this (Shri Mataji shows the subtle system
chart) is the great instrument God have placed
within you. And it is the greatest knowledge
of the roots. Of the roots within us. And
this knowledge, you have to understand first
of all, you need not accepted it, but you
should not deny. With opened mind, listen
to me as what happens and how these chakras
are within us and how they react and how we
falter. 2730
So one of the first things I have to tell
you that sex plays no part in Kundalini ascent
as far as its piercing is concerned, it means
it doesn’t have to pass through that. Whatever
is the Truth I have to tell you. You may not
like it but I have to tell you. I am not here
to seek votes or to have elections or to collect
money out of you, I don’t want to buy Rolls
Royces, nothing of the kind. I just here to
give you what you have, what is your own.
I am just here to give you that : what is
your own, what your own property. So it does
not matter also if you don’t like it for
the time being, but ultimately you’ll like
because you will know Mother has told us the
Truth.
Now the Swadisthana chakra, the second chakra
within us, is also very important. This Swadisthana
chakra plays a very very important part in
our lives (when) in the modern times specially.
Because this is the center we use for planning,
thinking, for all our futuristic life. As
well as doing all sort of physical work. This
center is the one that crete balances as well
as imbalances. If you use this center in the
wrong way you create an imbalance within you,
of a very very serious nature. This center
for example, Swadhisthana looks after your
aortic plexus in the gross. Aortic plexus
doctors know what it is, but this center is
placed in the … longeta, inside the spinal
cord.
Now with this center we think about the future,
or we can think about the past, we put in
physical work also with this center. So it
move to the right as well as to the left,
it is dangling in the air, it’s the only
center which moves on both the sides in such
a big periphery, all round and it can also
retract and can go further within. Now when
we have an imbalance in this, we really do
not realise that we are leading an imbalanced
life ‘til we get into a serious trouble.
This center has got to look after your liver,
your kidney, your spleen, your pancreas, and
your uterus. Plus it has a very important
work that, when you think too much, the brain’s
cells are used up, to replace the brain’s
cells from the fat cells from the stomach,
it transforms the fat cells for the use of
the brain. And this is a very important work
it has to do. – (to a yogi on stage) Can
you put on this one please ? – Now when
this chakra works more for thinking or planning
this, that, it neglects its other work which
is also equally important like liver, and
your pancreas, and your kidneys, your spleen.
And thus we develop diseases of liver, of
all these organs.
All of this liver troubles come to us because
of its overactivity, also it can come to us
because of inactivity of the liver. It can
come to us from both the types of liver. Now
if you have an active liver, a very active
liver, you develop a funny diseases called
biliousness : your attention is always unhappy
and you feel like vomiting all the time you
are irritable and you have a temperament that
you don’t feel the peace within yourself.
This is that, that means your attention is
absolutely disturbed because the liver it
the one that really sustain your attention.
So when your liver is out, your attention
is funny you don’t know what to do with
your attention and all the time it’s terrible
and you feel very nervous and agitated and
anxious. And then, doctors do not know at
this stage I think, it’s liver which is
bad. So what they do is to use something to
find out about liver, what’s wrong with
the liver but when they try to do that, it’s
not so easy to find out, till you find the
patient is lying just at the deathbed with
a sirose and then they certify “Now you
are going to die”. But in Sahaja Yoga, if
you have a liver (problem), at the very outset,
you can make it out, that you have liver (problem)
because as you know on the fingers, it can
be felt where the liver is, and if you see
that if this center of Swadhisthana chakra
is catching (Shri Mataji shows the right hand
thumb) with this center of Nabhi chakra (She
shows her middle finger) then it means you
have bad liver. And this liver is a very serious
thing because it makes a personality absolutely
useless for any communication after sometimes.
Another thing is the neglect of other center
, let say your spleen. This a very serious
thing because if you are very hectic by temperament,
and if you are all the time thinking of future
”I have to go, “I have to attend the office”,
“I have to do this, I have to do that”
(at) that time, this center, as we call it
the ‘left Nabhi center’, gets excited.
And it hasn’t got, we should say, it has
got that ‘attention’ that it requires,
so it becomes very hectic itself. It goes
into an emergency. All the time attending
to an emergency, it is producing more and
more red blood corpses and you become absolutely
hectic. For example first thing in the morning
people read the newspaper. First shock comes
to them from the newspapers : “Somebody
died”, “Something happened”, “Some
horrible things happened” ; naturally the
poor spleen goes into action and it starts
producing red blood corpses. (At) That you
start having your breakfast for example, so
also additional emergency, then you are suddenly
rushing out. On the way you see lots of this
traffic and you have to catch up with the
time and all that. All this modern life makes
you that hectic, nervous, hasty we can say
and a speedy person.
This spleen ; actually the speedometer is
your spleen, so poor spleen goes into a bizarre
state. It can not control your speed, and
it tries to keep the speed with you, your
hectic nature and it becomes hectic itself.
And then a disease which we call as leukemia,
blood cancer can develop. Blood cancer is
the result of this kind of temperament and
nature.
There are many children who get blood cancer.
I’ve seen many children suffering from blood
cancer. And these children get it from those
parents who are like this, ‘hectic ways’,
who are anxious “we must go to the office”,
“we must do this”, “We must get that”
; so many things at the same time. Such people
get this trouble called leukemia and (which)
is absolutely curable through Sahaja Yoga.
It is absolutely curable through Sahaja Yoga.
It’s not difficult to cure leukemia, but
you have to continue with the practice of
Sahaja Yoga so that you absolutely get cured,
and that you can cure the leukemia of other
people.
Another thing that can happen to you is the
kidney trouble. You see the kidney becomes
overactive. The activity in the kidney too
much create a problem within us which we call
as hypertension. By which we get high blood
pressures and things like that. People always
say “I suffer from high blood pressure.”
Doctor Warren himself when he came to Me,
was a patient of high blood pressure and many
other problems. But after Sahaja Yoga you
settle down, you find you strike the balance.
You strike the balance because you don’t
think so much. The thinking that goes on like
mad stops. If you want to think you can think.
If you don’t want to think, you don’t
think, you can stop it and sleep, but if you
want to think, you can think. When I met a
doctor, in Geneva he said : “Cut my throat,
do want you like, but stop this thinking”.
You see it’s so disgusting for some people,
because even if I don’t what to think this
brain goes on “chuk chuk chuk chuk” like
that troubling me so much. But it is because
of this center which has got out of its balance,
and it doesn’t know how to control, and
that’s why these things happen. Then also
women who think too much can become (…) They
may not produce any children. It’s possible
that they can become barren women because
there is no nourishment to that uterus and
maybe they can develop troubles of the uterus.
All this troubles come from this over thinking,
futuristic attitude, speediness in life. One
of them is diabetes
Now diabetes will not occur to any ordinary
farmer who doesn’t think so much. But it
will always happen to a man who is thinking
about a big plan, of how to project himself,
his business plan or his other plans, all
such people get diabetes. The reason is he
think so much that there is no attention left
to that poor pancreas, the pancreas gets seek,
and that’s how we get this disease of diabetes
which supposed to be incurable, not by Sahaja
Yoga. In sahaja Yoga, diabetes is absolutely
curable. Jaundice and all these diseases of
the liver are also absolutely curable in Sahaja
Yoga.
By giving the balance to the people you can
achieve a lot, because this is what all the
prophets told us : that we should lead a life
of moderation, not to go to extremes. If you
go to extremes, then you are not dharmic,
(which) means you are not sustaining yourself
properly. These are ten valences within us,
in the human beings. In the carbon, there
are four valences as you know. In every element
there are eight valances, and these valences
become ten valences in the human beings. Now
these are the ten dharmas as they call it,
or the ten kind of sustenance or ten kind
of behaviour we have got to look after. If
you do not keep that balance of these ten
things, then we go off the balance. Like Buddha
has told you that “you have to keep to the
central path of ascent” that what exactly
it is, that we have to keep to the central
path of ascent if we can not keep to the central
path of ascent then we suffer from, first
of all, the physical problems.
First of all we suffer from the physical problems
then we suffer also from mental problem because
we go into an imbalance. Now when this chakra
moves to the left side, we get into mental
problems. Because when it goes to the left
side what happens is that we start using things
[like] for our emotional behaviour and emotional
expressions and to much of it. As a result
of that, what happens to us (is) that we become
possessed by another force that resides beyond
this center. And beyond this center resides
the collective subconscious.
This collective subconscious is a very dangerous
area where people should not enter. Any person
who says “I’m very devoted, I’m very
dedicated, I must do this” without getting
connection with the God, if you do all these
things, your whole attention can be ruined.
For example supposing there is a telephone
and you are not connected and you are using
the telephone very fast then what will happen
is that the telephone will go out of order,
and you will have no connection. In the same
way who earnestly try to do something without
having connection with God, move to the left
side which is called as the collective subconscious
area. And this is a very dangerous area within
us. From there many things, which the doctors
call as ‘protein 58’, but we call them
as dead souls, are attacking. Doctors call
it as protein 58 because they don’t know
what they are. They this protein comes from
areas which are unknown but existed within
us since the day of creation. That means it
is collective subconscious. And these protein,
52 — 58 they have tried to even photograph
it and they that when they attack us, then
only cancer is triggered. But the … of the
cancer is created by our extreme behaviour.
How cancer is created, we should try to understand.
For example the left side and the right side,
as I told you there are two powers left and
right side powers which we work out. For example
the emotional on the left, and on the right
hand side, we have a power which we call as
‘the power of action’ where your physical
and your mental efforts are expressed. Now
when we go to the extreme of these, then what
happens the connection between the left and
right breaks, just breaks. And when it breaks
you start getting the power on its own, because
it breaks the connection with the whole. So
it is very arbitrary, it is not coordinated,
it doesn’t cooperate with the whole body,
it just starts growing by itself. And then
one cell becomes big or a cell in the nose
start becoming big and starts covering the
whole face. There’s no relationship between
the different organs and different parts of
the face, it just starts growing, overpowering
other cells, and that’s how we call it a
malignant growth or a malignant cell. Now
when you go on like that what happens : it
breaks ; and the Deity, the One which controls
it, the One which is inside it, just slips
off. At that time, the best thing would bo
to awaken that Deity. If you awaken the Deity,
the whole thing comes back and that’s how
we can cure the cancer of people. It’s true
Sahaja Yoga can cure cancer ; I’ve been
telling this for the last, I don’t know,
the last twelve years or so : “It’s only
through Sahaja Yoga, cancer will be cured”.
Now we have many doctors that are doing cancer
research and all that. We have one Dr. [Shrivardhar
CHECK SPELLING – 42:30], who is doing a
research now on cancer, and he has accepted
this, it is only Sahaja Yoga (that) will cure
cancer, otherwise nothing can cure it. Because
when human beings go to the extreme to the
right or to the left, they do this to themselves
and they are vulnerable to be triggered by
some sort of a protein, which enters into
your being and triggers this cancer. That’s
why doctors they can remove your ear, they
can remove your nose, they can remove this,
they can remove that but they can’t remove
the base of cancer and the base of cancer
is the center, the subtle center., And to
attack that subtle center, one has to become
a subtle person. Doctors have to become self
realised so that they can attack
In Sahaja Yoga we have many Doctors. Some
are russians, some are english, some are indians
and they are all working it out together.
Maybe that we may be able to publish a book
on ‘How to cure cancer with Sahaja Yoga’
or ‘How we have cured cancer with Sahaja
Yoga’. But the main thing is that we are
not here to cure people, not to give cure
to everyone every dicomentaria [SPELLING UNSURE
43:50] as we call it, but we are here to give
you realisation. God’s interest is in people
who are seeking God, who are God’s people,
He’s not interested in devils. Supposing
tomorrow, Hitler gets cancer, God won’t
be interested in curing him. So God’s interest
is in people who are seeking Him and those
who get enlightenment, and after their enlightenment
they can give light to others. God doesn’t
bother about people who are just wasteful,
who are good for nothing. He has to look after
the people who really will take up the cause
of God and do His work after getting cured.
Now we had a patient, today, this morning,
who came to us, who went to some horrible
guru, and paid a lot of money to get epilepsy
and then a brain cancer. Now with Sahaja Yoga
he is very much cure. He is walking about
; of course doctors had given up hope, that
‘prepare for his death’ in your Perth,
we have got a case here. He’s now completely
cured, he talks well, he walks well and everything
is going on well with him, but for this, he
had to come to Sahaja Yoga. God is not going
to fall at your feet : ‘O, please listen
to Me, you are very sick and you must get
well, and this should happen’, God is not
interested, you have to have to be interested
in Him that is one thing, ‘You have to be
interested’. (Lets) Say your prime minister,
if you want to meet him, he’s not going
to come and say ‘Alright, come and see me,
I want to meet you, please come’. You have
to [want him /UNSURE], he’s just a prime
minister. But this (the One) I’m talking
about is the prime minister of all the prime
ministers, the highest of all. So you have
to be interested about God, you have to get
to Him, you have to ask for it otherwise,
He’s not going to fall at your feet, that’s
important to understand.
Now this center, which I’ve told you about
(was) ”Swadhisthana”. Now the next center
is the center of Nabhi. They have already
explain to you what is Nabhi Chakra, but you
should what diseases are called by a bad Nabhi
Chakra. First it is on the left hand side
and right and side. There are two types of
people : left Nabhi and right Nabhi. The people
who suffer from right Nabhi are the people
who have got all the problems of the liver.
There was a gentleman who was writing as thesis
on alcohol. ‘What is the chemical reaction
on liver when we take alcohol ?’. And through
Sahaja Yoga only he realised what happened
actually to this (liver). That water as you
know is ‘H2O’, H ion are on both the sides
and ‘O’ is here is bound by that (Shri
Mataji joins Her hands before Her like a roof
showing O at the top H on both sides) “H2O”
: there are two ‘H’ and one ‘O’. Now
when you start taking water, it (the molecule)
keeps normal like that (Shri Mataji has Her
hands joined in one line, the middle fingers
touch each others) when the blood and the
water comes in contact with the liver. The
liver has the function to take away all the
poison in the body as heat, it absorbs the
heat and then transfers it as biles and it
goes out of your system. But if you take (let’s)
say alcohol and all these things in a very
strong way, not in moderation and it’s too
much, its ‘H’ (of the water molecule)
goes down like this (Shri Mataji now shows
Her hands like a high roof, the hand are close
to one and other but only the fingertips are
in contact) and when it goes near the liver,
(the) liver can not suck in the heat, it can
not suck in the heat. That’s how, the heat
is accumulated, the liver goes on malfunctioning,
and you’ll always have the trouble of the
liver. Now supposing you in Sahaja Yoga, then
the H starts moving like that (Shri Mataji
turns Her hands in the opposite direction,
all Her fingertips are pointed towards Herself)
and all that is heat within you is passed
into the liver.
You’ll be amazed when you will be doing
Sahaja Yoga just now, we’ll be raising the
Kundalini, in the beginning, lot of heat will
be coming out of your head before you start
feeling the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost.
First, the heat from the liver will be pouring
out, and you’ll feel very relieved when
it’s poured out. And then you will start
feeling the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost
in your hands which is the all pervading power
of God as I told you and first time after
realisation, you can feel that cool breeze
within you.
Now this chakra gets spoiled on the subtle
when you are very money oriented. If you are
very money oriented person, and you are always
thinking about money, how to get money like
mad, it’s a rat race for money then this
center goes out. And when this center goes
out, the person suffer from many troubles,
not from money troubles maybe, but other troubles
like he’s emotionally dried out, he becomes
an unemotional person. He becomes a person
who has no feeling for anyone. You must have
heard about the Great [decoids UNSURE] in
India, there is a lady, who was a [decoid
/ UNSURE], a small little lady of four feet
height, and she was a person (who) was devoid
of any emotions, she could kill anybody, she
could do anything as long as she got the money.
I mean the whole emotional side is completely
blocked of such a person, who thinks too much
of money all the time, and gradually he becomes
very materialistic. And a person who is materialistic
neglects his heart all the time, he neglects
his emotions, his worried more about the carpets,
more about this more about that than the emotions
of the people than the feelings of the people.
This kind of imbalance can come when your
Nabhi chakra goes out of order and you start
putting all your attention to money.
Now it’s more surprising the countries which
are affluent have more money orientation than
the people who are not. It’s very surprising.
(Let’s) Say for example in an indian village,
a person may not have so many things as you
people have, but if you go to him, he’ll
be very happy, whatever he has, he would like
to serve you, his food, anything that he has.
We would not like to see that you have not
taken your food or your milk or something
[UNCLEAR] He’ll feel so obliged that ‘you
go and to serve you him’ with that joy and
that love that he has. He would like to express
his love. Now people misunderstand. I’ve
seen people which are affluent misunderstand,
they think it’s a slavishness, it is not.
It is that they find joy in emotional life,
in expressing their joy. To them it doesn’t
matter, if he has to starve for the day, doesn’t
matter. If he has given you food, He feel
that’s his satisfaction ‘O God, he’s
eating at my place, so sweet of him’. There
is no slavishness, but it’s a kind of expression
of that love. But in the west I found that
people say that if you do that to somebody
then people misunderstand, they think you
are a weak person “That’s a sign of your
weakness”. I mean I was amazed, how can
it be ?
I live in an area that is supposed to be [poor
…/…] very very rich people live there,
very rich people. Once it was snowing, snowing
very heavily in that area. We were shifting
that very same day so I went round, there
is a square where we leave, so I went around
the square, and I deposited some things. I
saw a lady standing outside with a little
baby in a pram, and (then) another lady had
opened her door a little bit and talking to
her there and the little baby was in the pram,
and it was snowing. Can you imagine, and this
lady was talking. I came back after half an
hour and this lady was still talking like
this she wouldn’t open the door. And they
are extremely rich people. I can’t understand,
how can a person with a little baby is in
the pram. They hate children there. I’ve
seen in that area, the people just hate their
children, they beat them so badly. I’m amazed,
they give them to the servants and the servants
look after the children. In England you’ll
be amazed that two children are killed by
their parents every week. First I used to
think it is England, but it is not so it only
in London this is happening. Can you believe
a thing like that ? I mean in India I can’t
think of one woman doing that. So emotionally
they are very strong people, but they lack
(of) other things which you have which is
to be combine with east and west has to be
brought to a balance. It should be about “emotional
life”, that you want to have more children
and more children. That’s why more children
are born in that country (India) : they like
to have more children apart from that, they
are the only people that look after their
children so well, so all children want to
be born there also. They would not like be
born in those places where the mothers are
very ‘hotty’ and angry for only a carpet
being spoilt or something if the children
[UNCLEAR]. Naturally they would like to be
born with parents which natural, which are
sweet to them, and that must be one of the
reasons, why we are suffering from overpopulation.
While in Germany it is minus, in London it
is minus, you go to Norway, it is minus, (if)
it is Sweden it is minus. On top of that people
are committing suicides, they are competing
among themselves : “Who is [UNCLEAR] ?”. For
example if you go to … First I heard that
it is Sweden where people were committing
suicide more but now Switzerland has taken
over and they have doubled to number of people
that are committing suicides, I can’t understand.
I heard about three girls from Cambridge,
which came from Switzerland and they came
to me and their vibration were like [of] dead
people, absolutely numb. I was shocked, these
young girls between let’s say sixteen or
twenty, something like that : why should they
not have that feeling of exuberance, that
joy within them bubbling with life, such young
girls. And I ask them ‘You come and see
me in the house’, I mean I was really surprised.
When they came to see me I asked them ‘What
are you doing ?’ they say ‘Mother to tell
you the truth we are just planning how to
commit suicide’. Can you believe it ? It’s
such a tragic thing ! Young girls just planning
how to commit suicide but I said ‘WHY ? What
is so much ?’ (they said) ‘Nobody gives
us love, nobody loves us’ there is no love.
‘We’ve got money, we’ve got everything,
we are daughters of rich families, but there
is no love, and that’s how we want to commit
suicide.’ Just imagine. This is what is
happening when one goes too much into materialism.
Matter can never give us joy, take it from
Me. It is also an economic science that the
material things can not give you satisfaction
in general. They can give you a particular
thing then you buy now you buy this, alright
then you want to buy that, then you want to
buy something else. But in general they are
not satiable, that means “matter can not
give joy”. … I do not say that you can
not use the matter. You can use the matter
for your purpose also when you know how to
give it to others. That the joy of matter
is in giving. Perhaps we have missed the point,
but after Sahaja Yoga you will know that the
joy of matter is only felt when you see the
beauty of matter and when you see what it
is to give to others. To give to others. It’s
not for yourself that you can’t ever enjoy
but only by giving (to) others, you enjoy
the matter.
Alright, that’s going to a very subtle point,
but that is what happens to you. That you
become extremely generous, and as a result
of that you enjoy the bliss and happiness
and your own generosity within yourself. I’m
supposed to be extremely generous and sometimes
Sahaja Yogis are quite worried about Me that
by the time I return I’ll be finishing with
all my saris and nothing will be left out
of that, they are telling Me all the time
‘Mother be careful, You are extremely generous’.
But I enjoy My generosity, I do not enjoy
these possessions so called (more) than My
generosity because if have a possession it’s
a headache, you have to go to the insurance,
you have to worry that if you should be kept
alright. It’s better to give it to somebody
else and seen on other people than to have
your own. If you own it, it’s a headache
to you but if you give it to others it’s
nice. You enjoy it alright, you enjoy this
hall very well without owning it, if you have
to own it, it would have been a headache for
you to go up there (Shri Mataji looks at the
roof of the hall) and look after everything,
isn’t ? It’s better not to own it, let
others have the headache, and let’s have
the enjoyment. That’s what is the policy
in Sahaja Yoga (which) you try adopt.
So now we have another center which is very
important, it’s the center of ‘heart’,
“center heart” we called it. It’s the
center of the Mother of the Universe. In sanskrit
she is called as “Jagadamba”. She is the
One who stays there and gives you the sense
of security. She looks after the saints who
are trying to go out of this green thing (Shri
Mataji speaks about the Void around the Nabhi)
we call it as the ‘ocean of illusions’.
She protects them, She gives them all the
help, all the guidance and tries to pull them
out of the illusion, and this is the way She
kills all the devils and the demons who are
like fake gurus who try to put down the seekers
into the illusion more. She the One who is
the remover of illusions and this incarnates
again and again on this earth to help the
seekers to get out of the ‘ocean of illusion’.
But when this center as in childhood, it starts
pulsating first. The sternum bone creates
lots of antibodies and these are actually
the soldiers of the Mother, and they go and
get distributed in the whole body. When you
see something coming up on you, you get a
fear, and you get a palpitation in here (at
the chest level). The rhythm of these palpitations
informs the antibodies to be alert, to fight
the person who is trying to attack. And that’s
why it is important to understand that this
center builds up your sense of security. If
this center is disturbed, your sense of security
can be disturbed.
Now the disease of this center is mainly breast
cancer. When a woman is insecure in her life,
feels insecure, then she develops this trouble.
When she is insecure as a mother, she gets
this trouble of breast cancer. Now doctors
won’t believe it, but I have cured many
breast cancers and that can easily be cured
by awakening this special power of the motherhood
within you, you just become self confident,
and the diseases, completely cured, eradicated,
without going into any operation or anything
like that.
There are two other centers you see (at the
center heart level), the one on the right
right is of your own Father, on the right
is of your own Mother ; or we can say it of
fatherhood and of motherhood. If you are having
a bad father or if your father has been not
nice to you, this center suffers. If this
center suffers then you get the disease called
asthma. Asthma can only be cured if you tell
the person who is a Sahaja Yogi, about ‘your
father, where the problem is, if the father
has died, he suddenly died, if you are missing
him, or if there is a problem with your own
child’ anything like that : the quality
of fatherhood is [UNCLEAR 59:17] by that.
The left side is is the mother’s thing,
if the mother is not being very kind to the
child, the child can be erated and could be
very volcanic and temperamental. Very temperamental
he becomes. If he [had] not see his mother,
or the mother has been a very unkind person
then such a person can be absolutely insecure
all the time and could be all the time demanding
attention from others and would be very very
aggressive on that point. So this is what
it is, one has to understand, that these two
centers within us are important.
After Sahaja Yoga, you start understanding
your parents even if they have been very nasty
to you, you try to forgive them and they also
come round very well and good relations are
established with parents. Because you are
seekers, sometimes the parents don’t understand
you : because they have no seeking, that’s
the [age/H 1:00:14] which may not understand
your seeking. But when they see this transformation
coming into you, then you completely change,
you are completely changed. I’ll give you
an example of a swiss Sahaja Yogi who came
to Me, he has written a very big book on Sahaja
Yoga called ‘Advent’. This boy had a father
who was leading a life away from the family,
give a the mother, he used to have some sort
of a relationship and he never had any good
relations with his children. But when this
boy came to Sahaja Yoga and his younger brother
and his sister, he was amazed how they were
transformed, their ideas were transformed,
they were leading such a nice life, very sain
life, and that they were looking after him
also, and they were doing whatever is possible
just to make him happy. And this amazed him,
not like the other children who just like
to all the time say sharp things to the father
and all that. Now one of the Sahaja Yoginis
met him in a hotel somewhere. And another
person started speaking about Sahaja Yoga
and he said “I wish I was born at a time
where Sahaja Yoga had started because I would
not have wasted my life like that”. So the
parents start seeing that ’How my children
are changing’ and then they take to it,
your style of life, betterment of everything.
Now the last chakra, I can not tell you perhaps
today, is the Vishuddhi Chakra, which you
read in the book, because already there is
(Shri Mataji probably means “it has been”)
a lot of time, we have to have realisation.
But this is very important chakra because
this gives you collectivity. It’s the center
by which we know the whole, “Akbar”. They
say “Allah uh Akbar”. It’s the great
primordial Being, and we are part and parcels
of that, so you feel the collectivity within
you through this center. Those who spoil this
center ; you spoil it by mantras, you can
spoil it by talking too much, you may spoil
it by not talking at all and sorts of things,
and this reflects in sixteen sub plexuses,
aorthical sub plexuses which has got to look
after you nose, eyes, throat, neck, the muscles
of the eyes, and your forehead also. It’s
a very important center within us which gives
us collectivity.
The sixth center which here (Shri Mataji shows
the middle of Her forehead) is the center
of agnya chakra. Agnya Chakra is very important
because at this center, Lord Jesus Christ
came in. He is the embodiment of that innocence
‘Shri Ganesha’, He came on this earth
incarnated and He came with a special purpose.
He came with the purpose to cross through
that point which was very much join together
because when we have the desire too strong
and to act on it too strong, these two forces
combine together, in such a way that there
is no gap in between. So He came to go through
that gap, to go through that cross that’s
why His crucifixion has a big message. He
came through our awareness to go through that
position which is very subtles because He
was Himself the subtlest of subtle. He was
the One who was the Omkara he was the One
the was the “logos”, as you call it, the
“vibrations” as you see, He was that.
And because His body was also made of that,
He could get he resurrection. So the christianity
has the message of resurrection, and this
is the time of resurrection. Because he is
at the gate there (in the middle of the forehead),
we have to pass through that gate. But when
you pass through that gate what happens is
that the Kundalini awakens Jesus Christ. When
Jesus Christ is awakened both these institutions
of ego and superego are sucked in. When they
are sucked in, you find that this place in
your head becomes opened out. When this place
becomes opened out, you find that this Kundalini
also starts pulsating, and afterwards you
find Her coming out of your head and giving
you a cool breeze, and that’s how you achieve
your Self Realisation. So that’s how it
happens.
And the seventh chakra I think, when you come
to the program of these centers (hall to meditate)
and all that, they’ll explain to you is
(the) seventh chakra and how it is integrated
of whole the six chakras, And the seventh
one which the heart here (on top of the head),
which is the Spirit. In the heart reside the
Spirit and the nature of the Spirit, yesterday
I tried to tell you in short. That’s what
you have to be ‘Sat’, ‘Chit’, ‘Ananda’
: ‘Truth, Attention and Joy’. Your Attention
gets enlighten, you get the absolute Truth
and you become the Joy. This should happen
to all of you. I hope in this short time I’ve
been able to explain to you the subtle side
of these chakras as well as of the gross.
But the subject is so great, that you will
be amazed that least from London they have
done at least thousand tapes here, which you
can listen to them on various aspects and
dimensions of life and enjoy your realisation
like the bird after coming out of the egg,
enjoy all the dimensions of beauty and the
glory. May God bless you.
If you have any questions please ask.
There is one more thing somebody who was curing,
you see. Someone through so called spiritual
hand, He’s not God’s hands. As I told
you this is coming from the left or the right
side, it’s not God’s help. Because if
God’s power starts working in you, It transforms
you also. If it does not transform you, you
are just like a radio, the music … but if
it is transforming you completely, then it
is God’s work otherwise it is the work of
those spirits who are just trying to play
some tricks. They are busy bodies so they
just try to help you but don’t go near them,
they are horrid. They’ll remove one disease
and you will have another one.
The Yogi on the scene : Any questions ?
Shri Mataji (to him) : You can stand there.
The Yogi : Any questions ?
A man from the audience :
Shri Mataji : He’s a realised soul, so I
can hear him clearly. (To the man) It’s
true. What you say is true also ; that the
centers we have, as you see are seven centers,
then we have moon and sun : nine centers,
and they are three above us. They are called
… I don’t know if I should confuse you,
but they are called as Ardha Bindhu, Bindhu
and Valaya. These are three centers above
realisation. These you have to achieve in
your Realisation later on. Now we have twelve
of these, and these twelve things make for
the gross body of a human being through astrology.
But we have in India a method which is called
as Krishna Murti Partathi where we can talk
above the spiritual side of these centers.
We have a very nice thing developed in India,
very nice.
Now when these fake gurus came in, their birth
days were taken into account, and immediately
this astrology cast their horoscope and say
that ‘they are all fake, they are rakshasas,
they are this they are that’, and they change
all of them, their birthdates and everything.
It’s really remarkable how they change their
birthdate first, and then they say “we don’t
remember, this, that” and all sorts of things.
But you should see, they have published a
very authentic magazine which is dealing from
() astrology, horoscope and all that. It’s
amazing how they have predicted all the things
perhaps and Perth, they’ve been saying that
I’ll be touching Australia, australians
would be the great Sahaja Yogis, surprising.
The Yogi : He also asked ‘Are there chakras
on this Earth, and does Australia has a chakra
?’
Shri Mataji : It is ! Australia is the Mooladhara
itself, it’s the biggest chakra that you
could think of. (It) Is the Mooladhara itself,
it’s the first chakra. If you see, Perth
is all red everywhere, if you see it’s a
… > You have got in the center of Australia,
Shri Ganesha sitting down. (To the yogi) What
do you call that ?
The Yogi : Ayers Rock
Shri Mataji : Yes, And you can see his trunk
also, red like that. It’s the Mooladhara
itself, it’s one of the biggest centers
in Sahaja Yoga.
The Yogi : And interestingly enough, it is
exactly, the same longitude… sorry,latitude
of the birthplace of Shri Mataji> Precisely
the same latitude of the birthplace as Shri
Mataji in India. As it is one the tropic of
Cancer, so it in the tropic of Capricorn.
Shri Mataji : Yes, Australia is very important
from Sahaja Yoga point of view. Very important.
You see your basic quality is Innocence imagine
! According to Sahaja Yoga, Australia stands
for Innocence. (A woman wanted to ask a question)
Just a minute, let Me finish. And this Innocence
is your basic quality. According to Sahaja
Yoga, Europe is the liver, and Lodon is the
Heart. India is the Kundalini.
The woman from the audience , the yogi repeat
the question to Shri Mataji : Can you give
the translation of the Nabhi ?
Shri Mataji : Nabhi means ‘navel’, alright
? It’s ‘navel’. I went to Athens and
they told me ‘This is the navel of the Universe’.
I was telling them that Europe was the Navel.
And there I went, they said in Delphi, they
said ‘this mont represents the navel of
the Earth’. So I tried to feel the vibrations,
it was. But I turned down and say ‘Why these
vibrations are coming ?’ and there it was
Shri ganesha sitting there, like an elephant,
a little elephant. So I asked the translator
I said ‘What is this ?’, she said ‘a
little elephant sitting down there’ can
you imagine ? The Mother Earth has created
it. This is all created through Mother Earth
which is said in the Bible that ‘Thou shalt
not produce or reproduce something that is
created by the Mother Earth’. And what is
that ? That we call as Swayambhu ‘the one
which is created by Mother Earth’. And this
is one of them, you have Shri Ganesha created
in the center of Australia.
The woman from the audience , the yogi repeat
the question to Shri Mataji : When you do
Your Yoga concentration, as she calls it,
do you concentrate on the Void as well as
the Nabhi.
Shri Mataji : No, no not at all. Not to concentrate
on your Nabhi or anywhere. Concentration part
doesn’t take much part in Sahaja Yoga. First
you allow your attention to be absolutely
free, alright ? Then the Kundalini rises.
She rises and comes out of your ‘Brahmarandra’
as we call it. In case your attention is very
rumbly, we say that ‘pay attention here
a little bit’ but there is no need at all,
the Kundalini comes up and She’ll breaks
through. You have to leave your attention
a little loose, not to bother about it. But
later on what happens supposing, you have
a Nabhi problem as you were saying, in the
Solar Plexus you have a problem. The Kundalini
will go back and hit there, and your attention
will be drawn automatically.
You don’t have to pay attention it, you’ll
be drawn. Then by your attention you can raise
the Kundalini. So you don’t have to concentrate
anywhere just like that. Like if you are driving,
then you just have to concentrate on driving
it self. But if you concentrate on any point
you are finished. So you must know where you
are and where you have to move. Before Realisation
there is no question s of concentration, it
just spoils you completely.
Another woman : Shri Mataji, is Realisation
synonymous with ‘enlightenment’ ?
Shri Mataji : Yes of course.
The same woman : So ….
Shri Mataji : You see, it means you have to
be enlightened. It also means ‘Atma Sakshatkar’,
it also means to be the ‘Piir’ (twice
born). In Lao Tse, he says ‘Tao’, you
have to become “that”. That’s so many
things. Everybody had says, it’s “that”.
(To a man in the audience) Yes ?
The man : one occasion several years ago.
The yogi : He went up on the night of a full
moon, he was absolutely frightened and shaking
(Shri Mataji asked) on Ganesha ? (The Yogi
confims)
The man : It’s like being confronted by
Eternity (the Yogi repeats to Shri Mataji)
Shri Mataji : My child you have been to all
horrible gurus, you see. So naturally, Ganesh
was trying to frighten you there. He frightens,
not only that, He is the One who gives you
these horrible experiences of heat, these
blisters and He is the One who gets angry
because He doesn’t like the way people are.
You see, He is the One who gets upset. Kundalini
is ther He looks after Her protocol but He
can not understand why people are doing wrong
things … because He is Wisdom, He is the
embodiment of Wisdom and if you have done
something unwise, He gets angry with you.
(Shri Mataji laughs) that must be the reason.
You have seen people come to Me (they) also
shake on the beginning a little, but it doesn’t
matter.
The Yogi : Any other questions ?
Shri Mataji (pointing at someone in the audience)
: Are you alright now ? Good. Good now. (The
person answers) It doesn’t matter it’s
so good.
The Yogi (repeats the question of a woman
from the audience to Shri Mataji) : Can she
be healed, she had a stroke some years ago
?
Shri Mataji : Yes, of course.
The yogi to the woman : Have you got paralysis
? (the woman answers, then then Yogi to Shri
Mataji) Partial paralysis.
Shri Mataji (to the woman) : That’s nothing,
that can be healed no doubt.
The Yogi (repeats the question of another
woman from the audience to Shri Mataji) : She
can understand about the enlightenment, but
she can not understand about the emanations
probably she means Your powers.
Shri Mataji : You will understand that, alright
? Gradually. Everything you can’t understand
in one days can you ? You will understand
everything. You don’t worry about it, You
just worry about yourself. I didn’t say
anything about Myself, have I said ? I’ve
never said anything. I’ve been very humble.
I’ve never said anything, I dare not. Because
it is not wise, I’ve learnt it. [UNCLEAR
1:18:04] who said it had a bad time. If you
say something about yourself, suddenly the
ego will just punch at you. It’s very bad.
I’ve never said a word about Myself. So
you don’t try to understand Me just now,
first try to understand yourself alright ? Then
you understand Me.
The Yogi : Any other questions otherwise we
will have the experience of Self Realisation
? This is what Mother’s come for. Really,
a lecture is not the important part, the experience
of Self Realisation is it. We’ll swift the
fans off and you’ll feel it for yourself.
Any other questions ?
The Yogi (repeating a question to Shri Mataji)
: If they are your devotees, do you look after
them ?
Shri Mataji (laughing) : If I look after them
? Ask them, you’d better ask them, if I’ve
looked after them or not ?
The Yogi : I think it’s obvious. Insofar,
as all of us have been physically well, our
nervous, mental, psychological problems have
been healed. If we are endangered by an accident,
if there is any particular problem which we
want to solve within our own lives or within
our relationship, we put that at the attention
or our Almighty God, and by doing so, we find
that it gets solved. We’ve got all sort
of little methods by which work things out,
we showed you some of them today. In working
out how the chakra are cleared, you can learn
all of these things at the center, there are
certain aspect which you won’t fully understand
unless you actually achieve the awakening
of the Kundalini, but as you grow in it, you’ll
understand how eventually the blessings of
God actually descend upon you in a tremendous
way. Your well being is cared for, your health
is cared for, your psychological problems
are solved. You become a complete and whole
person and this is the very beautiful part.
When this lady asked is enlightenment is synonymous
with Self Realisation, the answer is “yes”,
but it’s a growth process : you touch it,
or maybe you go more than that it the beginning.
And from that touching of self realisation,
you grow from that point to a complete Realised
Being. But you are an enlightened Being because
you start this final journey in your spiritual
evolution. We’ve had a human evolution this
far, now we’ve reached our spiritual evolution.
And the road is very very rapid now because
in this lifetime, we can achieve the state
of full Realisation. Just by these techniques.
Very simple techniques that will be shown
to you by the devotees of Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji : But I must confess one thing
to you people. Your guru was very allergic
to flowers and things. I’m very allergic
to these dress, absolutely, because this is
not your style. These are to be worn by people
who lead an absolute celibate life, and it
meant for people who are not householders.
And another if you read … Valmiki in the
Ramayana, I don;t know if people read that
or not where Shri Sita said that a sanyasi
has nothing to do with householders at all,
if he’s a real sanyasi, he should stay out
of the city, out of the village only for …and
he used to be given one day [] and finished
because you know what happened with Her, Ravana
came with this dress, and that’s how I’m
very allergic to this dress because it’s
not true. It’s not true. Have you renounced
to whole world ? You have not.
So not go into thing kind of a thing, you
have to be normal people, you have to be living
normally, accepting what you are. And not
announcing something which you are not. You
see, this is what the gurus do, they give
you a dress and . So if you want to have Sahaja
Yoga ; of course today I hope I’ll give
Realisation ; but afterwards you give up all
this nonsense, you become normal people. You
have to be absolutely normal. Nothing abnormal
about it, recluses, funny type, no. We have
to get the whole world out of there to [] We
can’t just do it for ourselves, individual
some sort of a nonsense, no. We have to be
responsible for the whole world. We have to
be absolutely normal people, behaving in a
normal way, not to get an abnormal way. Alright,
so I am very allergic to these dress, I just
tell you. I hope I give you Realisation, because
you are seekers, I can see that. All of you
you are seekers, you should get your realisation.
But I’m absolutely allergic to this, because
their gurus is allergic to flowers. Imagine,
God is so fond of flowers, I can’t do without
flowers. I can not understand how can any
saintly man be allergic to flowers.