I bow to all the seekers of truth
at the very outset I have to say we
should know what is the truth everybody
is seeking the truth but they have no
idea as to what they should find there
is an urge within us because these times
are special and we are seeking but still
we don't have a clear-cut idea as to
what we should seek and what we should
achieve after our seeking now I would
like to refer to all the great books on
religion about truth they all have said
that who have to know yourself knowing
yourself is the point and that you have
to become the spirit it said in all
these intelligence but though we can
find that these regions are not really
doing that they are not getting able to
give you the truth and that's why
there's so much of conflict so much of
fights going on there are all real
religions no doubt and the essence of
every Lydian is the same despite all
that they are fighting in the name of
religion how can that be it can be
explained very well that if you have
lost over way we can go into opposite
directions
so when we know we have to know
ourselves and that is our goal of life
that is how we are going to improve on
our life as such that has been not so
clearly explained but where there is an
arrangement with in a sonata is being
told by most of them and that are in
mint as must have been told to you lies
in the triangular bone three and a half
points of energy which is divine which
can connect us to the all-pervading
power of truth which is a very subtle
energy and when that happens you get
connected with that power and that power
starts flowing through you and you can
feel it on your fingertips that power
flow this is a fact we have to first
verify before denying it if it could
happen to you all that you can feel this
all-pervading power on your fingertips
then it's an experience it's not just by
giving you a big lecture or telling you
about something fantastic but
actualization most important thing is
the actualization is the becoming of
your being the spirit this has to happen
all kinds of acrobats people may tell is
absolutely I must say
is a false pretext no amount of acrobats
are necessary it is such such means is
spontaneous it is within you all of you
have this power all of you are capable
of becoming the spirit but you must
understand what you should expect what
you should pick up unless and until you
have proper value system about it
nothing can be explained and you can be
mislead by all other nonsensical thing
of course you can't pay for it because
it's a living process of your evolution
now you are at a human awareness but
it's not subjective you have to rise
higher higher into the realm of
spirituality it's not spiritualism but
spirituality where you become the spirit
the master it's not difficult at all I
assure you it's not difficult America
has been somehow the last last place
because I came long time back to begin
with but I found people were running
after all kinds of business nonsensical
people when I gave up I said I'll go to
America after nine years and then I came
and gradually I started understanding
that they are seekers they are really
seekers not that they are in any way
hypocritical but it is the way people
are enticing them and taking them under
their own control
that they cannot see the point and the
point things you can't do anything about
a person may come and tell you you must
get the task give me all your property
all your money and I'll give you two
pair of clothes to wear and so many have
done that by doing this kind of nonsense
are you going to enter inside yourself
is it possible just think of it so many
people have come here telling you all
kinds of stories in your humble seeking
you have been mislaid and I feel very
sorry for it now try to understand that
you have been very special people as
human beings and that you have to become
the super human being we can call the
greatly evolved soul we have so many we
had so many and those we had we called
them by different name they were called
as Sufis and rick masters but they are
not intelligible normally to people
because unless and until you have the
awareness which is enlightened by your
spirit you cannot understand what they
are talking about now the time has come
for all of you to get your realization
you have been seeking for ages now and
it is already describing books that the
day will come the time will come they
call it as Kali Yuga is the worst start
that is now at this time people who are
seeking God in the hills and dales will
get into proper family life
and they will get their server ization
through this Kundalini awakening now in
the name of Kundalini also lots of
nonsense has been said which is
surprising how people accepted that a
Kundalini can be dangerous and a person
who gets Kundalini awakening will be
very much harmed now she is your mother
Kundalini is your exclusive model she
knows each and everything about she
knows about your false and so your
aspirations everything is recorded in
her and she is extremely careful when
she gives you the second birth and she
takes up all the problems upon herself
she doesn't bother you she doesn't
trouble you and she's the one who looks
after your second birth again I say is
the actualization actualization of
baptism you can call it but it is not
the way they do its actual ization it
happens that this rises passes through
six centers and pierces through your
fontanel bone area and you do feel on
your hands fingers and out of your head
the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost this
has to happen otherwise whatever story
is one matter you shouldn't believe it
has to show results now these centers
that we have all these seven centers are
responsible for our
physical mental emotional and spiritual
me so many people get cured many people
have problems mentally they get here and
spiritually you get endowed with the
absolute knowledge absolute knowledge
not knowledge that we learn in the
schools or colleges but the knowledge
which is absolute for example if you
want to know about someone you can ask a
question and you'll be amazed if the
question is yes then you start getting
the cool breeze flowing fast but if it
is no or it is wrong then you might get
little tingle or might get very hot from
those persons who are to be tested it's
a very very interesting precise and a
scientific method now if there are
doctors i would like to tell that you
get in control with the parasympathetic
nervous system luckily there's going to
be a big conference with me with the
doctors in New York I know what r
association it is called and I don't
know all right now in that they are
convinced now that what I am saying is a
fact and that helps helps you get cured
by yourself and you can also cure others
there's no need to have these horrible
modern diseases that you are afraid of
you can just find out about it in no
time apart from that
that you just know how to treat others
how to cure others how to help us out
but apart from that what you get is a
spiritual place and the spiritual
blessing is this that you get the peace
in your heart surprisingly when this
Kundalini Rises she some are other by
joining with the divine power
all-pervading power assumes a
personality which is extremely pure
extremely benevolent extremely tolerant
and extremely true them all your enemies
that we call like anger lust greed all
these anyways just drop and you are no
more in the entanglement of those anyway
and you become a free person absolutely
a free person above all you are so
beautiful you become such a nice person
that established your peace now normal
human beings what do they do they react
the reactor t see they were telling me
that still there is time people are
still coming doesn't matter you can come
late there's no don't come just now all
right but I don't know how to react and
that's why when I came visit mother
still you look very relaxed I said I
never reacted to this so you don't react
by not reaction what happens that the
thoughts that come to you count from the
future and the past and you are lost in
those thoughts because you are jumping
on the cusp of these thoughts when the
Kundalini Rises the thoughts are like
this she along gates those thoughts and
a space is created which we call it as
pause or William in that state you
become absolutely peaceful you don't
think anymore we call it thoughtless
awareness that young girl described that
means you watch anything just as a
witness see everything as a witness see
there's a bit nice carpet here I am
seeing it now supposing it belonged to
me if I was normal I would have said oh
my god i don't know how are they going
to keep it in case this belongs to
somebody else i would appreciate it and
I'll say oh I must buy this how much it
will cost I hope is insured and all
kinds of but if I am they realized
person then I just watch it without
thinking and the joy that the artist has
put into this carpet enables you to
enjoy enjoy without reaction and this
state we call it aha was da where a
person becomes absolutely one with
himself complete and when he looks at
anything he doesn't react he sees he
becomes the witness you become just the
witness of the whole your memory
improves your ideas about creation
anything I mean you become an extremely
extremely I should say creative person
and you don't develop the pride you
don't ever fall suit but you just enjoy
creating something human being is the
most beautiful useful thing and the most
beautiful thing that divine has created
but we don't know what we are that's why
always it is said know thyself know
yourself unless and until you know
yourself how can you say I hate myself
or I do I do that actually the beauty
lies within you and is to be expressed
through these divine vibration now the
health improves no doubt so many have
improved their health but i have seen in
london in the beginning so many boys
were taking drugs give it up overnight I
never say don't give up I don't say
don't if you say don't then David half
of them will run away let them play let
them get their realization then
automatically the whole thing drops out
and you shoot out out of that and you
become the real personality thus you
know the reality because you are not any
more contaminated by your ego or your
super-ego these thoughts come to you
from your ego or super you go meaning
your conditioning you are noble you're
absolutely free and you see everything
in its real position this kind of thing
happening was already destined has been
already prophesized that is going to
happen
in those days and so if you can come
here this side we have chairs
alright
so this is how we are going to become
ourselves and we will know what we are
and what we are capable of our
capabilities are fathomless but unless
and until we are connected how can we
act for example this instrument if it is
not connected to the mains it is
ruthless in the same way you are to be
connected to the mains is very important
for that you don't have to do anything
it just works spontaneously within you
and you get your self-realization
without any doubt actually I must have
given thousands of lectures all over the
world and there's no end to it now I
would like you people to ask me some
questions which I would like to answer
if you have any
there any questions you could raise a
hand
the thing is if you can do without the
photograph nothing like it but you need
something to support and that's why
people use the photograph if you don't
need it it's all right but you will find
you will need it all right
that's my job I will do it all right
it's very simple how does a mother earth
sprouts the seed how does she is
innately built in in her that power
isn't it what is gather
alright very good question Paramatma is
the God Almighty alright and his power
is the ADI Shakti is the power that has
done all the creation everything while
Paramatma is the one who is just a
spectator of the whole thing crystal
they call it while Adi Shakti the one
who does all the creation and everything
now permata is in your heart reflected a
spirit and Kundalini is reflected on
your in your triangular bone and
sufficiently I Receptus reflection is
the poodle oh you will get absolute
knowledge everything
get that
what should come first
what should come first what the
Kundalini awakening or dissolving the
jealousy no no Kundalini Awakening is
the one by which all these things
happened automatically there's no need
in sahaja yoga there's no need to work
it out the negative forces themselves
run away ninety-nine percent in one
person maybe it still sticks but
otherwise 99% they all run away with the
light of the Kundalini with the
Enlightenment of the Spirit on your
attention
yeah of course no doubt you only on the
contrary you become multi-dimensional
personality you try you cannot do it if
you are doing something wrong you cannot
do it after Kundalini awakening because
you see what is destructive for you and
what is constructive or so you don't do
it you just don't do it I told you just
now that overnight people gave up drugs
I didn't tell them is the light if you
are sitting in the darkness you don't
know where are you but if there's like
you know everything is like that is
enlightenment i am talking them
just to desire that you should get your
self-realization you must have a strong
desire yes madam
everything everything it is controlled
you don't have to do
because of practicing Christian religion
she feels that she's going to help
correct and does not mean that by
practicing now I was also born in a
Christian religion and I know that how
Christianity was just opposite of Christ
but just a minute but after realization
you are enlightened and you see the
beauty of every religion and the essence
of every religion and then you also
understand that you are capable yourself
of following a spiritual path without
any difficulties nothing destructive
nothing wrong nothing manipulated it's
your own you become your own master
those who are met and whose I have
nothing to say
I don't want to do that once the use is
done through some spirits I thing yes
madam
so many forces away from that yes it's
correct but just now just now I promise
you that you will get your realization
and then you will see all these forces
with drop off all right the decay and
substance that I selected slicking
yes this means left side is caught up
what is this written this letter that
means left side is not all right but it
can be put right
said this is a special time
he is called as Kaliyuga and also this
is the time of Last Judgment and at this
time one has to be very careful because
you are going to be judged whether you
take to truth or not if you are still
with falsehood you are just you will
judge yourself nobody needs to judge you
by so many things will happen that will
realize there's something wrong 11
I didn't give me any joy I had to give
him advice but he did say that let our
country be free then you can start your
sahaja yoga program not before that that
was his idea that we are not yet free to
propagate anything
very good question you don't have to
assess no number of times you have to do
it under once it is enlightened it is
enlightened but we have problems still
there so the Kundalini goes back to
correcting sometimes so we have here a
proper follow-up they call it and after
that we have centers where you can go
all so nobody will charge any money and
they'll find out what's wrong with you
and they'll try to tell you what is to
be done it happens with very few but
you'll enjoy going to the center because
it is all enjoyment there free of charge
they will tell you you have to meditate
that they will tell you how to meditate
and if you follow it for 10-15 minutes
at the most and it works out and you can
grow because after all is first
germination of the seed you see there
but it has to grow and some people grow
so fast I'm surprised of times that at
the very first meeting only they become
great people
dorman no it does it does not but if you
try not to pay attention to its proper
alignment or proper development then it
will become static at that point but it
never goes back
Kevin
I see me
you can you can do it if you desired so
you can really help them you can read
help I mean that's what is happening now
as you see these people say that sahaja
yoga is working in 86 countries what
happened that one person got his
realization he went to his country and
he changed the way people in a far fresh
country like Benny imagine Benny where
they have mostly Muslims there are seven
thousand sahaja Yogi's in Turkey we have
three thousand and in so many places we
have but the maximum in Benin where
there are mostly people who are who were
Muslims and I was applied are there why
did you become Muslims so they said
because the French were here and we
didn't like the way they were a model so
we thought their religion is no good so
the gay Muslims but now they're great
sahaja Yogi's very very great sahaja
yoga so many Muslim countries have
become sahaja Yogi's all over the world
we have in Russia we have thousands and
thousands and thousands and Russians are
very deeply but I tell you the so-called
freedom we had we have gone helter
skelter while the Russians had no
freedom they could not even talk about
God they did not read anything about
divine and they developed I think out of
that tyranny of communism developed
within themselves a very very deep
understanding and they are there will be
amazed that sahaja yoga is now practiced
in so many countries where I never even
thought I would reach but sahaja Yogi's
have gone and done the job
what's a lot of pussy
now can I ask you one question what was
your first understanding that you were a
human being it's like that one as you
are aware of you being a human being I
was aware
I have no religion I have all the radius
born in any family should not sort of
stop your widget you can see through
everything if you have the light
there's another one now I was I must say
here there are so many people who are
asking questions normally they I don't
find that experience doesn't matter but
how many will become good sahaja Yogi's
used to be seen out of you it's all
right to ask questions after questions
but that is of no value unless and until
you really become what I am saying a
sahaja yogi a real personality that is
absolutely spiritual so we have to see
that that is the challenge for all of
you let's see how many i must say Los
Angeles has been really a lost and
delicious so far for me but sahaja
Yogi's always felt that I can do very
well so I came now this is the fifth
question you are asking madam will you
please take your realization and then
ask your right this another one
you see once you have asked a question
you shouldn't ask another question
please because all of them are waiting
for their self-realization they are all
waiting for their self-realization only
few who want to ask questions is one is
all right but not all the time go on
asking questions what is there unless
and until you are a journalist a vehicle
as we should can you now write your
questions and let me know I'll answer
them after you get your realization then
you won't have any questions I know
again I said it is the becoming you have
to become it's not just talking
now forget your questions for the time
being better get your realization all
right now one thing is that you have to
just take out your shoes or chuckles
whatever it because this mother earth is
of a great help she sucks in all our
problems put both the feet apart from
each other
you will know everything about sahaja
yoga why I said to put your feet apart
from each other everything you will know
very clearly but they should touch the
mother earth you have to just be
comfortable and all of you should be
seated before i start i have to request
that those who want their realization
only i can give them it cannot be forced
because kundalini is the pure desire is
the pure desire not impurities are as we
have whatever desired we have we have
today one then we want to have something
else that's the principle of economics
but this is pure desire and forth is
pure desire you should be determined to
get it is your own character your own
understanding only will work it out now
I would request you all to sit
comfortably with both feet like this
very comfortable and put both your hands
towards me like
now what I find that some of you feel
guilty it's a nonsense if you feel
guilty then this Center here catches on
the left hand side and the Kundalini
don't move so if you have done anything
wrong I agree so it's finished that's
the past you don't have to worry about
that at this moment please you have to
know that you are not guilty at all for
anything so please forgive yourself
please forgive yourself now the second
thing is that we have to forgive also
others now some people say it's
difficult to forgive mother I mean what
do you do whether you forgive where you
don't forgive you don't do anything what
do you do nothing but by not forgiving
you torture yourself so best thing is to
forgive all of them forgive everybody
who has harmed you who has troubled you
was made you unhappy as hurt forgive
don't also think about them it's also
useless by forgiving you don't know what
will happen absolute really feel
peaceful be yourself just forgive it
this nobleness you should accept today
that you forgive everyone just working
now please put your hands torsion like
this comfortably perfect
now you can put your right hand towards
me and feel with the left hand on top of
your fontanel bone area little higher if
there is any cool or a hot breeze like
vibrations are coming out of your own
head on your ship bomb you can feel it
you move your hand up and down and see
for yourself if you are feeling please
remove your caps if you have please it's
better to remove now please see you must
have respect for yourself should not
denounce yourself and you should also
forgive everyone that's very important
now for the left hand towards me and put
the right hand on top of your fontanel
bone area and bend your head just when
your head and see for yourself if
there's a cool or a hot breeze coming
out of your own fontanel bone area this
is the actualization of the baptism you
may call it
once more with your right hand horse and
see with your left hand if there is a
cool or a hot breeze coming out of your
fontanel bone area please keep your head
bending
No
if it is hot means you have not forgiven
yourself or you have not forgiven others
so again please forgive please forgive
yourself and forgive others that's a
very great asset and help
now see for yourself if there's a cool
or a hot breeze coming on your
fingertips or on your palms
please forgive forgive forgive yourself
and forgive others very important
because this center here when the
crossing of the optic chiasma it get
obstructed if you have not forgiven so
please forgive because it's a myth myth
not to forgive so please forgive
I would say all those who have felt the
cool breeze in their hands or hot breeze
on their fingertips or on their path or
out of their fontanel bone area hot or
cold breeze please raise your hands Wow
mostly all of you have got it mostly may
God this may God bless may God bless you
in such a short time you have got it
that means really we have got very
wonderful people this time from Los
Angeles those who are truly signals or
real seekers may God bless you for that
now you must respect your realization
and i hope you will grow into it will
try to grow and become masters hardly
you'll take even one month maybe to
become the masters why not do it all
right may God bless
you