Today is a special day of Guru Nanaka’s
birthday.
We have celebrated one Guru puja and, as you
know that, Guru Nanak was also the incarnation
of the Primordial Master.
The same Spirit came on this Earth.
And he’s the one who tried to re-establish
the work of Mohammed.
Mohammed was the incarnation of the same Spirit
– the Primordial Master.
He came on this earth to establish the religion.
Islam is the name of that religion, is the
religion of every Sahaja Yogi, of every Christian,
of every Hindu.
We all belong to one religion which believes
in expanding our awareness to the new perception
of collectivity.
From human level to the higher level where
you can perceive and manifest the Divine Power.
This is the religion we are following.
All the religions were established on this
Earth to create the seekers.
You are the seekers.
You are the “men of God."
Now, all of you have to become prophets.
And to become prophets today’s Sahaja Yoga
has taken the form of Mahayoga.
All of you have to become prophets.
The prophets have two special qualities, as
all the prophets had: First of all, they have
to talk about spiritual education.
All of them did that.
Mohammed Saheb did it, Raja Janaka did it,
Nanaka did it, Moses did it, Abraham did it.
All of them prophesised and taught you how
to lead yourself in the right path, by the
right action, by leading a right life.
You are going to be the prophets of a little
different nature.
You are prophets, you are Islamic, you are
Jews, you are Parsees, you are all those,
but you are going to become prophets which
are called as “pir’ in Islam, in Hindu
scriptures it’s called as “Atmasakshatkari’,
“Atmajas."
In the way Nanaka has described, he calls
them “par."
But you are endowed with a greater power.
There’s more power in you.
There they had a bigger propensity.
You have another delicate power by which you
can raise the Kundalini of people.
You are going to be prophets who are going
to make others prophets.
Not only to establish religion but to make
them prophets.
This is the most important thing.
Not just to maintain a static state of righteous
religious good people but to evolve those
seekers, those righteous, good, religious
people into prophets.
And those prophets whom you will evolve will
also be the same type of prophets but they
will also have this additional power by which
they will also evolve.
That is why it is a Mahayoga.
This is the greatest work in the history of
all spiritual history, that you are the prophets
who are looking after the men of God, and
you are going to transform them into prophets.
To have so many prophets now, for me – you
can’t imagine how happy I must be feeling.
I have been, sometimes, very, very sharp with
you.
Sometimes I had to goad you.
Sometimes I had to love you, express my love
in that way, that you could feel that Mother
is very kind.
Sometimes I had to be very critical.
Sometimes also angry.
Behind all these aspects of your Mother, She
is nothing but Love.
Because She loves you so much, and She knows
that you have to be the prophets.
Your calibre may not be of the same level
as those prophets, maybe – you can’t say
– but definitely you have got special powers.
Like, you can say, an old Rolls Royce might
be a better car as far as the propensity goes,
or an effect goes, or its behaviour goes – is
a good car.
But one of the modern ones may have more capacity
to show new acrobats.
For example it may tumble down, it may go
round the whole place and nothing will happen
to it.
Maybe, after some time, you might find a car
which goes half way and comes up a little,
like a hovercraft and then goes in the air,
and then again drops back.
So, this new generation of great prophets
are here before me.
But the big difference between them and you
is this: that none of them had a Mother to
guide them, to love them, to encourage them
when they were depressed, and also to spoil
them.
But you have here a Mother who may apparently
look to be spoiling her children.
But She is the Master of Masters and She knows
how far to take them and how to correct them.
Now, for all of you, I have to tell you that
you have to develop your independent discretion.
First of all we have to know that, in this
new realm where you have entered, you have
to have proper spiritual education, about
which I have given you so many lectures and
things.
But education doesn’t mean listening to
lectures after Realisation, it means it should
be imbibed within you, it should penetrate
into your veins, and into your every artery,
into every cell of your being.
You have to educate yourself spiritually.
And Guru Nanaka prophesised, just like William
Blake, that, “The men of God are going to
come during Kali Yuga, and there will be many
prophets who will be transforming prophets,
who will be transforming people into prophet
state,” [this] he had prophesised.
They have all prophesised about you!
Now you have to prophesise (sic) about those
who are going to be prophets.
But, as it is, you know that we need spiritual
education.
Because your Guru is a Mother we lack discipline.
There’s complete freedom for all of you.
You know that if you go to a guru what kind
of discipline you have to observe!
I mean the real one, also.
Unreal, of course.
But even the real ones, how they test your
attention.
Even for the smallest thing, how they treat
you.
I’ll give an example of Ravi Shankar, who
was a very great, you know, who is a very
great sitar player: my father was an advisor
to the Maharaja of Maihar where their guru
(Allauddin Khan) was living.
This guru was a Muslim but he used to worship
Kali, Mother.
He used to worship Mother!
And [a] very self disciplined man.
They say he died at the age of 110 or 120
– Allauddin Khan Saheb.
And this Ravi Shankar was there.
I saw him as a young man, and this Ali Akbar
(Allauddin Khan’s son) whom you heard.
They were literally frightened of their guru,
who was a master himself.
He knew so many of these instruments.
One day my father, whom he used to respect
very much, always used to bow to him, though
he was a Muslim, they touched feet because
my father was a great connoisseur of music,
and a supporter of music, and he bowed to
him and he said, “Now, should I play?”
So he said, “Why not ask your disciple,
this Ravi Shankar, to play?”
And he said, “Yes, yes, come along, play."
he said, “Not today sir.
Please, not today."
he was very frightened.
Then he said, “Alright, let it be!” he
started playing.
He used to play on mrudangam.
Used to play beautiful mrudangam – tremendous!
I mean, you can’t imagine! he was a Realised-soul,
no doubt.
Then Ravi Shankar, when he finished and he
bowed to my father and he went away.
Then Ravi Shankar came to my father and he
said, “Don’t ask me to play before my
guruji!” he lifted his head and said, “See
here.
Do you see this bump?
This morning only, he hit me with my sitar,
which he broke, and this is the bump I have
got!”
So my father said, “What did you do?”
he said, “Only one note I played wrong!
That too not wrong but little out of tune,
and on that point he has broken this part
of my head and I have been in this terrible
pain and he said, “You are not to see any
doctor!”
And really there was a big bump.
He had covered it like that, with the hair.
(Laughter) That’s why today they have fame
as great masters, because to be masters you
have to obey your master and to discipline
yourself.
The spiritual education in Sahaja Yoga, under
Mataji Nirmala Devi, is absolutely left to
your own wisdom: there is no force, there
is no compulsion, there is no organisation.
It is you who has to feel the joy of your
Spirit and it is you who has to share it with
others.
It is you who has to raise the Kundalini of
Now, today, when we are thinking of a Great
Prophet who, on this Earth, came to establish
good relationships between Hindus and Muslims.
Imagine, when Mohammed Sahib came he did not
know that he was facing these horrible people
there who murdered him.
Actually they murdered him.
They gave him poison.
And when he died he said that, “There will
not be any need for any prophet to come in."
Naturally, if you torture somebody, what else
he’s going to say?
Also, he felt that whatever he has said, being
such a truth, it will definitely prosper and
the seed has been sown.
And he said, “There is no need for another
advent of a master."
But he found out that there was a big aggression
by the so-called followers of Mohammed, who
talked of nothing but rehmat (رحمت) – is
compassion.
Now, before his death he encountered all kinds
of attacks from the negative people.
Of all of them, the worst of all!
I think he has suffered the worst.
He had to move from places to places, hiding
the children away from negative forces, [from]
tribes to tribes.
It was a tremendous life, the way he led it.
And all his life there was nothing but struggle
for existence.
Only struggle for existence.
When Nanaka came in, he saw that Hindus and
Muslims were fighting, so he started his theme
with Kabira, saying that, “Ram and Rahim
are both the same, and how can you differentiate
between the two?”
All their theme was like this, of integration
of these two main religions which existed
in India.
That time, there was no question of giving
Realisation.
People were trying to defend their faiths
and fight each other and kill each other.
Imagine!
Created by the same Spirit!
Fighting among themselves!
How silly it must be, and absurd.
In many places Nanak Saheb has proved that
he was Mohammed.
Once, he was lying down and his feet were
towards Mecca.
So people said, “How can you put your feet
towards Mecca?”
He had Muslim disciples and also Hindu disciples.
He said, “Alright, whichever way you say,
I’ll put my feet."
He turned round his feet.
They said, “Still you are towards Mecca."
He went round and round and round [but] still
they saw him facing Mecca!
And they could not understand how it was that
he was facing, his feet were towards Mecca,
that Mecca was at his lotus feet.
Same with Mohammed.
Now, all these great incarnations had a special
power over water.
Because you know, in the stomach we have our
Void and Nabhi Chakra which is made of ocean.
Ocean represents the incarnation of Adi Guru
– Dattatreya.
These had great powers over oceans and over
water.
Like Moses – he crossed the ocean by creating
a road.
That’s one of the very significant things
which shows that the Void can be crossed with
the help of the Guru.
And even Mohammed Saheb had a tremendous power
over ocean.
Then, Nanaka once put his hand on a rock and
water started coming out of that.
People were amazed how it started.
And that’s why it is called as ‘Punja-saheb’.
‘Punja’ means ‘the hand’.
‘Punja’ means ‘the five fingers’,
like this.
What do you say to this, this part, [of the]
hand?
Hand with five fingers?
Yogis: This is the palm.
Shri Mataji: No, no, not the palm!
The whole thing.
Like this is a punja.
‘Hand’.
Yogis: The hand.
The open hand.
Shri Mataji: But hand can be like this (a
fist) you see?
This way.
There’s no word, alright.
So this is ‘punja’ – this is five.
And ‘punjab’ is five waters, five rivers
– in that area – are called Punjab.
Now, another thing about these: all these
incarnations had to deal with your attention.
So they were particular about looking after
your attention.
And that is why, from the time Moses or Abraham
came in, they talked of no alcoholism.
All of them.
It is written very clearly in The Bible that
the strong alcohols, fermented, should not
be taken.
If you don’t want to read it, one need not.
But they think it was Moses who said it and
Christ did not say – so Christians can take
it, the Moses people should not take it.
There is no breaking of link between Moses
and Christ.
They are of the same tree, of the same pattern,
of the same thing.
But those who want to use Moses for their
own purpose will follow as much as Moses has
said, and those who want to follow Christ
will follow only as much as Christ has said,
because it’s very good for them.
For such useless people Sahaja Yoga has no
place.
We have to understand that all these people
have said for our good and for the maintenance
of our spiritual life and none of them are
to be criticised or to be challenged but to
be fully respected as our Guru.
All of them.
Whether one belongs to Islam religion or to
the Jew religion or to the Christian religion
or to the Hindu religion.
And if they are fanatic they are going against
their guru – it is against their guru.
So, they were against fanaticism.
First thing they were against [was] alcoholism.
That’s the first thing, they thought, because
somehow human beings take to alcoholism very
fast.
At the time of Mohammed Saheb, people did
not know how to smoke.
Then they developed, became modern.
At the time of Nanaka they started smoking
so he prohibited that.
But Mohammed Sahib said that, “Anything
that goes against your awareness, any intoxication
of any kind” – he generally, he gave a
very general instruction, “is against God."
So, our training, our spiritual education
should be that we cannot be fanatics anymore.
If you are fanatic anymore, or you are identified
with any one of your old ideas, then beware!
Be very, very careful!
You cannot have fanatic ideas anymore if you
want to be a good Sahaja Yogi or a Maha Yogi
– meaning a person who is a prophet, not
only a prophet, but who is capable of transforming
others into prophets.
First is, you have to be away from alcoholism.
You should be deadly against it.
Whenever you have a chance you find it that
it is possible for you to say something against
alcoholism.
It should be absolutely boycotted.
Every place, anywhere you meet, it should
be smoking or any kind of intoxication, drugging,
anything, has to be completely branded as
anti-God, anti-Sahaja Yoga.
Then, fanaticism of any kind.
That lingers on.
This is another very deep misidentification.
I am aware of it.
I did not talk of Catholicism till the other
day I went to Portugal, when I had to talk.
So I said [for the] first time.
I never talked about Protestants before, till
I had to talk that they are another mad race
going round!
There are 27 churches of this kind.
None of them, except for we, are really Christians.
All are nonsensical fanatics: Seventh Day
Adventists and Pentecostals, and this and
that.
All are absurd ideas!
All are playing into the hands of bhoots,
take it from me.
They have nothing to do with God, they are
anti-God.
All those who still stick on to all these
churches and to this kind of fanaticism – I
am saying here of churches because here I
have to talk about churches – should know
that all these churches have now become the
place of bhoots.
You’ll go to one church and you’ll rush
to me!
From my house I see in the night, hosts of
bhoots waiting out of the church.
(Laughter) I do not know! (laughing) And somehow
it’s happening that, whatever house I decide
to stay in, there’s a big church in front
of me.
(Laughter) It may be a Catholic church, may
be a Protestant church.
And they have seen to it that they make it
really bhootish by making all those who die
stay in that church.
They are not Realised people.
Realised people only should be buried and
all others should be burnt off.
It’s better.
At least the bhoots go out of them.
And they are roaming about in the church,
and you are taking the children down there
into the cemetery!
Apart from that wherever there is a anadhikaar
cheshta (अनधिकार चेष्टा
meaning ‘unauthorised activity’) – when
it is unauthorised – Gods do not exist there.
They leave the place.
So, we have to know that we are no more fanatics.
First and foremost thing is that we cannot
be fanatics.
Now, training ourselves is very important,
spiritual education is very important.
But in Sahaja Yoga, as your Mother is a very
kind teacher, but even such a kind teacher
is not such a help sometimes because all corrections
are left to yourself, and then you commit
really blunders and then you think, “Why
didn’t Mother tell us?
Why didn’t She protect us, why didn’t
She correct?”
But this is the style I have adopted because
in modern times, Sahaja Yoga is working out
because I do not challenge your ego.
Otherwise you would have crucified me long
time back.
So I leave it to you to decide to discipline
yourself.
It is for you to discipline yourself and understand
Now, the best way to discipline yourself is
to find out, “What’s wrong with me?”
Not with others.
We are very good at that.
I have seen every day there’s some complaint
about somebody coming from someone.
But there are very few who will say, “This
is wrong with me, Mother, what to do?”
So just try to find out what is wrong with
you.
You are like a fort.
The fort has some sort of a weakness.
So, the man in charge of the fort – what
do you call him?
We call kiledaar ( किलेदार ) because
a fort is kila and the gentleman is the owner
of the kila, is called as kiledaar.
Now, this kiledaar finds out what are the
weak points of the fort and he sees to it
that they are all corrected one by one.
We are just the other way round.
We know we have weaknesses which we hide and
keep them there as they are.
Whatever strong points we have that we boast
of and we try to see the weaknesses of others,
and from these loopholes all these negative
things creep in and suddenly you find that
you are finished.
So try to find out what are your weaknesses.
One of the weaknesses, which is very common
is that we are very materialistic people,
we are still very materialistic, extremely
materialistic.
And the materialism is getting subtler and
subtler the subtler we be.
Try to give up some things.
Keep a kind of a little balanced attitude,
a little detached attitude, not too many things.
Few things of value.
Try to detach yourself.
I don’t say you become sanyasis.
That is also another thing against.
But from inside you detach.
See, I’m wearing a very nice sari, but from
inside see what is the colour.
(Laughter)
From inside you should be detached, not from
outside.
So that, try to practice this detachment.
Whatever you want to possess, you just don’t
possess.
Teach your body, teach your mind: “No!
You want a shirt?
No!Nothing doing!”
You try.
Train up your body.
Now some people want comfort, the body wants
comfort.
Alright, “You want comfort?
No, I will sleep on the ground and teach you
a lesson!”
Teach your body a lesson!
Teach your wants and desires a lesson!
Let’s see what happens.
Now, I don’t know why, but in England it
should not be so.
I mean I expected people absolutely detached
because they have got everything.
But here it is much more attachment than detachment.
There is no satisfaction of any kind.
So, a kind of a detachment must be developed,
to your desires, to your belongings, to your
possessions and whatever kind of a material
aspect you want to build up.
I always said that you must not look like
people who are coming from the lunatic asylum,
that’s true, but you should also not look
like a dandy person, with a flair, a big bow
here, and a sort of a thing.
You should be in the centre.
And how are you in centre?
When you are detached.
Then nothing can impress you.
But that doesn’t mean…some people I’ve
seen that outside they make a show, that they
are absolutely dishevelled, absolutely in
a very filthy condition, smelling like pigs.
(Laughter) They think they are going to take
an avatara of Varaha (boar incarnation of
Shri Vishnu) by smelling like pigs!
And all sorts of funny things they do in the
name of detachment.
No – detachment is within.
Try to practice it.
That is one of the educations you have to
develop.
How do you develop that detachment?
Is by giving things away.
Not to me, but giving things away to others.
Say you reach a certain state of – say you
have two suits.
If you have a third one then give it away.
Give away things.
It’s a very good way of developing detachment,
and enjoying the giving away than possessing.
It’s greater, is much greater, take it from
me, is much greater than possessing.
Now for you, at this stage, I cannot say,
but maybe after some time, it will become
that I prophesise that you will become sinless,
absolutely sinless.
You cannot do sin and whatever you do will
not be sin.
I am sinless.
Even if I rob you of all your wealth nobody
can say I have committed sin.
I am absolutely sinless.
Even if I kill thousands and thousands of
people nobody would say that I have killed
because I am sinless.
But, despite all that state, I do not commit
any so-called sin because I have to lay down
my life in such a way that you people follow.
That you should not tomorrow say that, “Mother
did this, She has done this so why not we?”
That’s why I’m so very particular.
At the same point I would like to tell you
that today Chaya, in her sweetness, went and
bought a very expensive sari.
And she brought with such love and affection
to me, that I had told her just buy me a £10
worth of a shawl and she couldn’t bear the
idea.
But she should know [that] for me anything
is valuable that you give to me.
Nothing expensive is needed.
Even if you give me the most expensive I have
every right on that.
But you must understand that if this practice
is continued too much it will create a bad
public opinion.
So, at the most, definitely decide that you’ll
give me only two saris, that’s all.
I don’t need even these two.
And I can have all of them.
So, the situation is such that we have to
be very careful about the public opinion,
and people may start saying tomorrow, “Oh!
Mother, She wears all expensive saris."
Let my husband buy for me, he has lots of
money!
And you can buy me very ordinary things.
And I told once Modi that, “You buy me khadi
(homespun) saris, that’s the best,” but
he couldn’t bear it.
It was too much for him.
He says that, “Mother, we are middle class
people and we are giving you something middle
class."
I said, “Alright."
So, once for all I told them, “Alright,
you buy some saris."
And then I bought for them, one of them is
this one, and I don’t know if the whole
money is paid – most of the money I have
paid.
But still, you know, there was somebody who
came out with an objection!
I know you love me very much and you want
to do something for me like that, but I would
request that try to get things which are sober
and simple for me.
By God’s Grace, you should know your Mother
is looked after, you don’t have to worry.
Supposing I was a beggar then you would have
had to spend much more money but that is not
so.
And it is not that it is in any way wrong,
on the contrary, it’s a very great thing.
After all these are going to be in your Mother’s
personal archives and people are going to
see what saris you people gave me, and they’re
going to be very happy – of course, no doubt
– and that’s going to be very, very great
for you.
But, still, where the public is concerned
you be careful and understand that when you
do anything like that for me, this public
is mad and we have to keep a proper balance.
Now, about training yourself, as I said, detachment,
then another thing is astuteness – astuteness.
Try to develop astute habits – astute – specially
for religious work.
First of all understand that you have to give
some money for Sahaja Yoga work.
In that you should be astute.
I was amazed to hear from some people that
for food also you want to have free – that
sometimes you had food you didn’t pay even
one pound.
I mean this is absurd.
If you were beggars is alright, but for Sahaja
Yoga, first of all, it’s not too much.
But little you have to pay.
And you should not make your Mother pay for
you.
It’s wrong.
I never said this before, but today I’m
telling you.
Not aesthetically, but spiritually it is wrong
that I should pay for you.
It’s alright – I may give you a dinner,
it’s different, I may give you anything,
it’s different, but that you should not
try to take advantage in any way or exploit
in any way this Mother of yours, who has got
lots of things other than what you know of,
which can work out against your spiritual
growth.
So just don’t do anything like that.
No exploitation.
Learn that.
Those who have done such a thing must decide
that no more like that.
Now, I’ll tell you a difference between
Indians and you people is this: that an Indian
would never do that.
We had one Indian coming here and he was not
such a big Sahaja Yogi, but he used to come
for his puja, and he would not take money
for his puja and these people had to fight
with him.
Ask him, he’s sitting down, he would not
take.
But how materialistic we are!
And then, when people mesmerise you then you
buy a Rolls Royce for that person, and here
a Mother is giving you all the freedom, so
you are exploiting your Mother!
“I have no job,” all this is wrong.
You must pay for your food, and must pay where
you have to pay.
That’s your dharma, that’s your religion,
of every Sahaja Yogi.
Alright, you need not pay too much, but you
must pay where it has to be paid.
And never take a parasitic attitude.
That will kill your growth, will dwarf you.
I am warning you about it.
Astuteness.
For payment, for accounting, for everything,
one has to be extremely astute.
Like, I’ll tell you, I have seen people
used to come to my house, long time back – I
shouldn’t say this but [it] used to be so
funny – they would go in the kitchen, take
out anything, eat anything, walk off anywhere.
It was amazing!
Our cooks could not understand.
Nobody could understand such people.
Just coming in the house, walking into the
kitchen, taking off whatever they like, eat
anything.
Like bounders!
This training has to come within you where
you must realise and understand that astuteness
towards Sahaja Yoga has to be maintained.
Like going into the ashram, walking into somebody’s
kitchen, taking out things.
Using the ashram in a state as if it does
not matter.
It’s ashram!
It’s a pure thing.
You cannot fight in an ashram.
You cannot talk loudly in an ashram.
You have to lead a pure life in an ashram.
You cannot play games with each other.
You cannot make it dirty.
You cannot spoil it, otherwise your spiritual
growth won’t come up.
This is the simplest thing one should know,
is to respect Sahaja Yoga.
Love without respect has no meaning.
You have to respect, and respect the place,
respect everything.
Keep it clean, be astute about it.
And this is one of the greatest trainings.
I don’t know how, but to a British mind
it should not be told, because they are known
for this kind of a training!
But I don’t know, because now you are saints,
I think, I feel that you have had other kind
of training before, that you are born as saints.
Perhaps you have no self-esteem yet, of the
value that should be given to your own character.
Without that, nobody is going to be impressed
by you.
Nobody is going to be impressed by you.
Nobody is going to become a prophet.
You have to first of all impress.
You have to dress up in such a way that you
impress others.
It’s a very important thing in Sahaja Yoga.
You have to talk in such a way that you impress
others.
Supposing somebody’s very fat, he must reduce,
somebody’s very thin, he must put on.
He must try to have a body of the centre.
Should not allow the body to move this way
or that way.
One has to be in a proper shape, in proper
dress, because you have to impress on others.
You must know that if the personality is not
impressive how are you going to communicate?
Because first of all the people see you, those
of you who come to you, see your outside.
They don’t see your vibrations they see
your outside.
So, all of you must learn how to dress up
and how to behave towards others, how to appear
before others, how to talk to others, so that
you become prophets who will do wonders and
who will transform many, many, many more people
into the same state as you are.
Now, this training you have to take yourself.
The another point in training in Sahaja Yoga
is that you have to read.
There are many people who have not read even
Gregoire’s book, leave alone any other.
You have to learn certain things like chakras
and centres and mantras and you have to dedicate.
Even people like Vivekanada’s who never
got Realisation – do you know, these people,
twelve people – they used to study for fourteen
hours.
Now you will know what to study, what not
to study, and even if you study wrong things,
you will know where it is wrong.
So you have to study.
For example, there are Jews with us – let
them study Torah and see there where is it,
Sahaja Yoga, in there written down.
Find it out!
If you are Christians read the Bible, find
out.
You should read Gita, you should read Upanishadas,
and you should be masters.
You’ll find that Sahaj Yoga is such a light
that you will know what it is.
We have got the Devi’s names and the Sahastranamas:
try to read them and try to understand the
meaning of that and try to understand what
it means, how far it goes.
That’s how the depth of your knowledge will
increase and your Sahaja Yoga will tell you
what is right and what is wrong.
Now emotionally, some of you have terribly
emotional weaknesses: the idea of ‘love’.
[About] that I must speak to you because it
has come from a group of people who went into
another style against the ego-oriented people.
And they believe that love means hugging each
other, kissing each other.
This type [of] nonsense is not love.
Love is this, that flows, that is love.
And understand the person through this alone.
And all nonsensical loves that people talk
of is not love.
When a person loves you he doesn’t stare
into you.
If somebody stares into you then know he does
not love you – he’s full of a bhoot.
Only when a realised soul is angry he stares
to drive out the badhas.
So, anybody who stares into your eyes and
says, “I have love,” then know that it
is mesmerism.
With discretion you will know this: that anybody
who loves, only a glance is sufficient.
But when it is an anti-Christ activity going
on then you can stare at that person and the
thing increases.
So the idea of love is so absurd.
Love is the one that corrects, that improves,
that elevates, which is blissful.
The relationship is blissful, not hallucinations.
And this blissfulness is only felt through
vibrations not through by hugging or by kissing
or anything, just through vibrations.
Of course, I don’t say you should not hug
each other and you should not kiss each other
– you should, but that’s not the way it
is expressed, it’s through the vibrations.
It’s the pure love of your being which emits
just like light.
Everything should be done in the proper education
of the spiritual love.
We are people of dignity and sobriety.
I have told you this before.
Like, some people have a habit of doing this
in the — no!
If you are sitting in a posture try to sit
for at least an hour – try.
I have sat on one posture for nine hours,
people have seen: didn’t go to bathroom
or eat anything and just sitting there nine
hours.
This is known as baithak is ‘the seat’.
And this baithak has to be great in Sahaja
Yoga.
Try to establish your baithak, that is very
important, so that your attention is brought
in line with your Mooladhara and is straight
there.
Once you do that, practice it, you will find
your spiritual growth would be better.
Walk erect, be straight.
In your talks be straight, kind and gentle.
Need not shout.
No Sahaja Yogi should shout at anybody else,
should play games with another, should not
in any way be angry with each other – is
prohibited.
Should not get into any tantrums of pulling
your hair or doing something like that – is
all nonsensical.
You have to be very, very dignified.
But another foxy method which we employ very
much is to tease and provoke another Sahaja
Yogi, which is even worse, because it hits
you at a subtler point.
Try to be straight, straightforward.
Allow your mind to come to normal when you
talk.
If you have to say something, wait and try
to say something nice, not artificial.
Try to say something from your heart, not
to show off.
In talking also too much quietness is not
good, too much talking is not good.
Some suffer from too much talking and some
do not talk at all.
It’s better to talk whenever it is necessary.
Talk something sweet, no sharpness and sarcasm.
That will spoil your Vishuddhi.
Sarcasm is not allowed in Sahaja Yoga.
You are not to be sarcastic to each other.
Because of a new generation and a new race
that you are, you have to learn that to keep
your vibrations alright you have to have collectivity
within you.
Because you are collectively so much charged
that’s why the Kundalini’s rising.
If your collectivity breaks then it’s a
very, very, very, very wrong thing.
So, try to be nice to each other, kind to
each other, try to understand each other’s
problem.
And never, never complain to me about any
other Sahaja Yogi – till I ask.
It’s prohibited!
If you have to say, tell me about yourself.
Unless and until of course something happens,
then it’s alright, but not against anyone.
Because you will only see the bad points of
the another person and you will not imbibe
the good points.
You have to meditate and think about what
you have to do to become the real prophets
of modern times of Mahayoga.
How you have to dress up, how you have to
behave, how you have to talk, and how you
have to be kindly, that you have to decide.
On this day, I would say that I have talked
a lot and only thing that you have to do is
to imbibe it in you and not on others, that’s
all.
To others you have to be kind, you have to
be sweet, you have to be patient, gentle.
Now, today’s puja has to be very simple
because it is the puja of Guru, who is an
avadhuta.
Avadhuta, as I told you, always teaches you
that the whole thing is futile, all this pattern
is futile.
He even doesn’t talk of any Deities, because
he says, “Alright, let’s worship the Abstract.
Why talk of the Deity?”
Though they will talk of the Mother, alright.
All of them talk of the Mother.
But not of a Deity, because they think if
you talk of the Deity, people will talk more
about the Deity and not about the essence.
But talk is a talk.
Only at this stage you are prophets who are
talking about the Deities, and who are giving
Realisation, and who know the Abstract is
flowing through them.
You are empowered to do that.
You know all about Deities, and you know all
about their mantras and you know how to awaken
them and you know about yourself.
You are all very great.
This may be the last puja now in London.
As a great thing we are worshipping today
Guru Nanaka, that’s me [so] that – may
you become great Guru Nanakas.
All of them were created by Adi Shakti.
All these Gurus were created by her.
And today I say that you all become as great
as Guru Nanak, as great as Moses, as great
as Sai Nath, as great as Nanaka, Janaka, Mohammed.
All [of you] have to become as great as all
these great incarnations.
Just desire!
Have earnestness in you and alertness to achieve
it.
[Only] earnestness is not sufficient, you
have to be alert.
I have already told you how to practice this
alertness.
Try to do it.
I have told Hari certain things, you can ask
him, and I have told other people also, how
to become alert, and how to change your little
habits here and there.
Anything overdoing should be stopped: taking
of too much tea, taking of too much milk,
eating too much, too much reading.
Anything like that, just try to moderate.
Moderation has to be brought in, and you will
be surprised [that] you can master your tongue,
you can master it.
May God bless you all, this day, in the name
of Nanaka I bless you all with that great
Spirit of Master, which you all should become
– the great prophets who are going to change
all the men of God into prophets.
May God bless you!
Today the puja has to be in a different way
if you don’t mind.
Gavin, first of all you do me any favour.
I have to tell you that today I want to give
some presents to you all and accordingly I
have brought some presents for you all.
Because these are material things, but all
are used by me, all are vibrated, and very
spontaneously we are going to choose them
all.
It was within two hours time we have done
some choosing.
But in this one has to understand that it’s
all done just to express the Dhanesh Shakti
of the Mother, just that She loves to give.
She loves to give.
Just out of joy that I had in Hampstead, I
felt I should now give you something.
It’s beautiful there and that’s how we
have today tried to make some arrangement
for that kind of a thing.
So just before the puja I wanted to announce
this and then we can have the puja – very
simple one, because today is a day of simplicity
– complete surrendering.
Just imagine that these two colours are in
the Void, green and yellow, and if you mix
them what is the colour you get?
Green and yellow?
You get the blue.
So the green is the Nature.
So an avadhuta has to become one with the
Nature.
This is the sign of the Surya nadi, the Sun.
That means an avadhuta has to be brilliant
like the Sun, brilliant like the Sun, and
that detached as the Sun is.
All the detachment must come into him.
He need not have liver on Sun line.
He will not have liver if he knows what to
eat and what not to eat.
Normally all these gurus ate fruits, and they
ate meat, never fats and that’s how they
kept their liver alright.
This is, these are the two combinations which
are there in the Void.
And the combination of these two, when they
combine, it makes a blue.
What is the blue?
Is the water.
So, in the water.
Now see the Gurus are surrounding the Lakshmi
on the Nabhi.
On the Nabhi is the Lakshmi is in the centre
and they are surrounding her.
They are her beauty.
Without vairAgnya, without ascetic temperament,
the Lakshmi has no meaning.
It has no meaning.
It is expressed in giving, is giving.
That is what it means, that without vairAgnya
the Lakshmi has no meaning.
Without the feeling of giving Lakshmi has
no meaning.
Why should Lakshmi come to anyone if they
do not want to give?
And that is what one has to understand, is
the significance of giving.
Now, today’s speciality is this, that: though
I am the Lakshmi – alright, I am the Mahalakshmi
in everything – but I am also Vairagyi,
I am the detached.
The One who is Nirmama, is beyond.
Nobody can tie me, nobody can.
Nothing can bound me.
I just talk but it has no meaning, I am beyond.
In the same way, all of you should try to
be beyond.
So, from the Lakshmi angle I want to give
you something, because Lakshmi looks after
the saints, and the saints have to be detached.
That is the way it is going to work out.
I hope you won’t go back and wear kashayas,
the orange robes (laughter).
Discretion, discretion, has to mature.
It’s the maturity of discretion now.
So, now, for puja today, Chaya, let’s have
a very simple puja, whichever way you like.
Now, have you got Guru’s names?
Just see it, their name.
That I know, Graham.
Guillemette: Guillemette.
Shri Mataji: Loudly.
Gavin Brown: Guillemette.
Shri Mataji: How do you spell?
Gavin Brown: G-u-i-l-l-e-m-e-t-t-e.
Shri Mataji: What’s your name, please?
Loudly.
Brian: Brian
Shri Mataji: Brian?
Rachel: Rachel
Shri Mataji: Rachel?
Christopher: Christopher
Shri Mataji: Christopher?
Christopher: Nicolas
Shri Mataji: Nicolas.
Shri Mataji: What’s your name please?
Richard: Richard Mother.
Bernard: Bernard
Shri Mataji: Bernard.
What’s your?
Ian: Ian
Shri Mataji: Now who else is here?
Eileen?
I now here.
You haven’t washed my hands?
No, Isodor has.
Alan you have?
Never?
Imagine! (laughter) Alright.
So let’s have the start.
Gavin Brown: Gurur Brahma, Gurur Vishnu, Gurur
Devo Maheshwara, Guru Sakshat Parabrahma,
Shri Mataji Nirmala Ma, Tasmai Guruve namaha.
Shri Mataji: You all know the meaning of this?
Gurur Brahma, Gurur Vishnu, Gurur Devo Maheshwara.
The Guru is the creator, Guru is the protector,
and Guru is the existence and the destroyer.
Guru is the embodiment of the Parabrahma,
it’s the beyond state.
And to such a Guru we bow.
Just a little you can take it on your fingers
you can dip it, you see, and put it on your
forehead, maybe.
It’s a water which is now [vibrated].
Haa!
You will feel better.
On the Sahasrara you can put it.
Just sprinkle it all over you can.
Let him do.
Sprinkle it all over.
Who are these?
Maria is here.
Yes.
Jaldi karo! (hindi: do it quickly)
Five people together should come forward – alright?
Come along!
Five of you.
Yes.
Come along!
Get your finger into there and to my hand.
Turn it like that, clockwise, with both the
hands.
Alright.
Now you rub your own hand.
Now come along, you do it.
Come along.
Rub it.
It’s good.