Aum..........
Twameva saakshat
Shri Mahalaxmi,
Mahasaraswati,
Mahakali
Trigunatmika
Kundalini saakshat
Shri Adishakti
Mataji
Shri Nirmala
Devyaee
namo namah.
Aum Twameva
saakshat Shri
Kalki saakshat
Shri Adishakti
Mataji
Shri Nirmala
Devyaee
namo namah.
Aum Twameva
saakshat
Shri Kalki saakshat
Shri Sahastrara
Swamini
moksh Pradayini
Mataji
Shri Nirmala
Devyaee
namo namah.
Vishwa Vandita
Nirmala Mata
Sarva Pujita
Brahm Swaroopini
Yog niroopni
shubhdam vardam namo namah
Vishwa Vandita
Nirmala Mata
Sarva Pujita
Aa, aa, aa
Jagat Janani Nirmala
mool Prakriti Akhileshwar ki
Nitya Satya Sanatana
Parashakti Parmeshwar ki
Vishwa Dharini
Mangal Karini
Shubhdaam Vardaam namo namah
Vishwa Vandita
Nirmala Mata
Sarva Pujita
aa, aa, aa
Sahajayogini Nirmala
Nirashraya Sarveshwari
Prem Murti Bhaktvatsala
Snehmayi Mateshwari
Bhakti Pradayini
Mukti Pradayini
Shubhdaam Vardaam namo namah
Vishwa Vandita
Nirmala Mata
Sarva Pujita
aa, aa, aa
Prakat Saguna Nirguna
Ridhi Sidhi ki Daatri hai
Saumya Sarla Mahamana
Patanjali guna Paatri hai
Ghat ghat Vaasini
Atma Vikaasini
Shubhdaam Vardaam namo namah
Vishwa Vandita
Nirmala Mata
Sarva Pujita
Brahm Swaroopini
Yoga Niroopini
Shubhdaam Vardaam namo namah
Vishwa Vandita, Vishwa Vandita
Nirmala Mata
Sarva Pujita, sarva Pujita
Vishwa Vandita Vishwa Vandita
Nirmala Mata
[CLAPPING]
[UNCLEAR] Isiliye
Thank you! The next song we have is a [UNCLEAR - SOMETHING?] faster number
and it really helps us a lot if you clap along, it gives us the rhythm much more so, if you'd like to clap along will be very much appreciated
[MUSIC]
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, lala
lala, lala, la, lala, lala, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la, la, la, lala, la
lala, la, lala, la,
Saat janam jo, punya kiye hain, safal hue saare,
Isiliye Mataji humko, darshan hue Tumhare
lala, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la
Dukhiyon ka dukh door kare Tu, Ma Nirmala Devi
Hum sabka udhaar kare Tu, shanti sukh ki Devi
Sab dharmon ko chod charan mein,
Sab dharmon ko chod charan mein, aaye sharan Tihare
Isiliye Mataji humko, darshan hue Tumhare
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la,
Aham bhao ko chod Tumhare, charan sharan aata
Bhavsagar ke dukh sukh se Ma, poorna paar utaar
Na aandhi ho, na ho toofan,
Na aandhi ho, na ho toofan, sankat tal hi jaaye
Isiliye Mataji humko darshan hue Tumhare
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la,
Kundalini ko jagrut karke, mere paap haro
Dekar mangal ashirwad Tum, pavan mujh ko karo
Dekar mangal ashirwad Tum, pavan mujhe karo
Janam maran ke phere mit gaye
Janam maran ke phere mit gaye, khul gaye bhagya hamare
Isiliye Mataji humko darshan hue Tumhare
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la,
Saat janam jo, punya kiye hain, safal hue saare
Isiliye Mataji humko darshan hue Tumhare
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, lala, la,
humko darshan hue Tumhare, humko darshan hue Tumhare
[CLAPS]
Hello, hello
Good evening ladies and gentlemen. I want to welcome you here on behalf of sahaja yoga, in Victoria
and in particular to draw to your attention to the fact that we have now in our midst
a very great personality, whose affect on hundreds and thousands of people round the world has been
quite dynamic and in many respects, unbelievable.
Now the Russians have flooded into sahaja yoga,
the Europeans in 64 countries is operative,
it's a very, very big undertaking in India
and it's on these occasions that one realizes the immense importance of
uh.. the individual life and the collective life
and how these are now coming together in a very, very positive way.
When our friend Steven here was talking to you about the nature of the inner
quality of dynamic, which we call the Kundalini and the chakra system
that we're looking at something which has been embedded in human-beings
and has been awakened through the great historical periods by dynamic and
uh.. highly spiritual avatars. Each of these chakras represents a stage in human development
and they're all there in every human-being. Not only that the power of the Kundalini
is so uh..as we are aware, spread throughout the whole of the human race and it's importance is so great
that when one sits awake and all those distinctions of race, of class,
of wealth, of poverty, of importance in society, are illuminated
and the human-being can, for the first time,
uh.. actually move into the consciouness of what the real self is, not the self which sits on the surface,
the self which belongs to the ego
and the emotions, but the real self which is hidden deeply in the unconscious
and these two things are dynamic of that Kundalini awakening
and the entry into consciousness of the operations of the real self
which, in fact, is linked with all other human-beings and all life,
is one of the great opportunities offered in this great critical time at the end of the twentieth century.
Now this history, if you like, of the
human-being in our civilization has been one from this operation
as it were of the left side to the dynamic of the right side.
The left side with it's emotion is particular quality of civilization is taken quite a number of centuries.
If you look at human-beings in our Western world today, they're functioning with this ego,
the personal consciousness and the dynamic of the right side or if we use the Sanskrit term, the Rajoguna,
dynamic and externally oriented. And when one takes one's attention away
as it were with [UNCLEAR - ROSETTE] from that externality, one has the chance
in meditation to reach the real center.
If you look at the history of civilization, you'll find that it's either the left or the right side,
through great periods of time, that's been dominated in the way people act and behave.
In our centuries, the acuteness of the ego is so great
that the ego now feels itself totally cut off from life, from other human-beings
and from the whole web of existence. And the ecological problems which exist in our external world
and in nature are brought by the industrial society and expression of the fragmentation
which is going on within the human-being uh.. internally.
Now sahaja yoga offers that wonderful opportunity of bringing
consciousness back into the center. We have never really tried
as a civilization, to operate in the dynamic reascending mode
which is this pathway here. And the purpose of the Kundalini is to pass through and awaken and cleanse
each of the chakras within this system and ultimately to provide
the total experience of what the self really is and that self is collective.
It's not something which we can call uh the individual 'I' anymore, it's something which is
deeply embedded in the whole totality of existence. Now, Shri Mataji is a remarkable figure,
who in hundreds and thousands of instances has brought this realization
to people all over the world. It is no longer an individual thing
for a few people with a guru. It is now something to be experienced within the consciousness
of modern man in vast numbers. In fact, the very
uh.. existence of large numbers of people enhances the experience of this collective realization principle.
So, I have the greatest pleasure in introducing this figure
of world importance in, in the field of yoga - Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi. [CLAPPING]
I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset we have to know, that truth is what it is.
We cannot change it, we cannot transform it
and unfortunately, at the level of human awareness, we cannot know it.
The reason is, as they have explained to you already,
that these two things called conditionings and the ego, are covering our brain.
Apart from that, we are not connected to the All-Pervading
power, which is the love of God.
In these modern times to talk of God, is something out of trade
and also there are many people who have talked about God,
established religions, established all kinds of huge, big organizations
and people have discovered that there's no truth in it.
I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset we have to know, that truth is what it is.
We cannot change it, we cannot transform it
and unfortunately, at the level of human awareness, we cannot know it.
The reason is, as they have explained to you already,
these two things called conditionings and the ego
are covering our brain. Apart from that
we are not connected to the All-Pervading power, which is
the love God. In these modern times, to talk of God is something out of trade.
and also there are many people who have talked about God
established religions, established all kinds of huge, big organizations
and people have discovered that there's no truth in it.
It's not based on truth though the Incarnations, prophets
all of them have been expressing nothing but truth, manifesting nothing but truth.
But somehow or other, all these organizations have deviated and what is the reason for that?
The reason for that is simple thing which was important,
is that one has to go beyond this human awareness
through their Self-realization, through their second birth or as Walihood, as they call it in Islam.
This was not at all attempted, nor the attention paid
to such an important thing, that we have to
get our Self-realization, that we have to be connected to this All-Pervading power of God.
That's why they deviated into, I think, two three things, firstly it deviated into many orientation.
It became the thing where people must make money.
And such horrible things they have done, it's surprising how could they do it, when they were professing truth.
The second was that they wanted to have power - they did for power so they mixed up politics, this that - such a mixture of things.
But they are not spirit oriented - they didn't work out that you have to be the spirit.
Now this mechanism exists within you, I say so, but you shouldn't take it for granted,
you shouldn't believe Me blindly but you must experience yourself, if it is so.
Like a hypothesis you can accept what I am saying but supposing I prove it, then you have to accept it as honest people.
Because it is for your benevolence, is the benevolence of this Australia, benevolence of the whole world.
This is what we have been waiting for all these days, this is being promised to us in all the scriptures.
But instead of seeking that, people have deviated into businesses or into political organizations
which is a very unjust, unfair treatment to Divinity.
This Divinity resides within you all, as shown here, is within you.
This power is within you, is your own power.
Maybe, I just trigger it like one enlightened light can enlighten another light
but is within you, residing just like a primule in a seed.
And whatever powers you get afterwards, when you are connected to the mains, are also within you.
You are not to feel obliged to Me nor am I in any way obligated to you.
It's just that it is your own,
this is your own property and that the key has to be found.
Of course you can't pay for it - one must understand you can't pay for a higher awareness.
What can you pay? It's something so natural - it's a living process
and what do we pay to this Mother Earth for sprouting a seed - She doesn't understand even.
So you can't pay for it - first of all understand that it is not something material that you can buy
but it's your own energy which has to manifest it.
Tomorrow, of course, I'm going to tell you about what is the nature of the spirit
but today I've just to tell you one thing that this Kundalini is within you
and when She rises, she definitely solves your physical, mental, emotional problems,
also your material problems but above all your spiritual urge.
They say that, in this
Kaliyuga, ghor Kaliyuga - these modern times - this
work will be done - is already been predicted
that people who were seeking the truth in the hills and dales
will find it within themselves, as ordinary householders.
And that's what I find, is so easy. The time is such
that it is working out in such great numbers.
Surprisingly, in a place, which we call the country called Russia
where they had never heard about God, they were not supposed to think about God, they were not supposed to even utter the word God
where thousands and thousands have got realization and such seeking.
I was wondering, what is the thing that they have that they should in thousands should come to these
lectures of Mine and I had to arrange them in stadiums - never in a hall like this.
And the way they got their realization is very surprising - how they got it.
Because they said, "Mother, we have nothing to do with spirituality,
we never heard there is something higher than this human awareness and how do we get this."
I said, 'There must be something special about you.' And the special about them, I think, that they were kept out of materialism.
They have everything provided for, whatever is necessary.
Moreover, they are very introspective by nature, extremely introspective. If you read their
writers like Tolstoy or anyone, even the hero will introspect himself.
This introspection has brought forth such personalities that they are finding,
one thing in common, that they haven't found out the Absolute Truth.
Whatever they know is on the relative terminology - even the Science.
Science, they think, is all the time changing, is nothing of a permanent nature.
And when I address there, the Scientists, they said, "Mother, tell us everything else but not Science - we had enough of it."
So this is what it is, that we have to see also what all these enterprises we have entered into.
Like Science, what has happened to us. Today we have created a big devil there, atom bomb and here a Hydrogen bomb sitting on our head.
We have created those devils and they are frightening us. We have created these ecological problems.
We have created this political problems, economical problems ourselves.
That means, something wrong with human-beings, that means, they haven't found the Absolute.
So, this human-being has to be transformed.
This transformation once takes place, you become the Spirit.
It's question of becoming, it's not just giving a sermon or a lecture or anything like that - it's, it should happen to you.
From this human awareness you have to become a higher personality, which is a spiritual awareness.
This can happen very easily. Sahaja means also very easy, simple - also it means born with you.
So you all have a birthright, you're born with this birthright, to get your Self-realization.
For that, you do not have to pay, do not have to exert, it's, it's absolutely effortless
and also you do not have to think about it because it is beyond thinking.
So many things people are talking about, so many theories -
they talk of Capitalism, Communism, this ism, that isms,
goes on like a yarn out of the brain comes out and everybody gets engulfed.
Once it is written down, it becomes a Bible - people start following it but of no avail.
Only compartments have been created - you are this, you're that, you're a Christian, Hindu, Muslim, this, that and all that - into compartments.
Human-beings are divided by all this thinking - you are a Communist, you are a Capitalist, you're this, you're that - you're not.
You are a human-being to begin with and you're the pure Spirit. And if the Spirit
is the reflection of one God, then how can we be separated, how can we put into some compartments.
We are part and parcel of one God Almighty.
The microcosm has to become the macrocosm, that's all. This happening has to take place
where the drop of your personality has to become one with the whole.
Also the concept of individuality is so wrong. This concept of individuality that we have
is against the Spirit of the whole, absolutely against the Spirit of the whole but individuality,
I mean, the way nature is individual in the sense every leaf is different from another leaf, every flower is different from another flower, to look at,
but in it's nature it is just the same - it comes from the same source.
In the same way, we have to become the Spirit though we may dress up separately,
differently - I mean, in sahaja yoga nobody is wearing funny dresses, you see, like regimentation or some sort of a uh..
orange dress or nothing of the kind. It's not the dress that matters, it's something very much inside and innate.
So the innate religion has to be awakened. Unless and until that innate religion is awakened -
you may be a Christian, Hindu, Muslim, anything - you can commit any kind of sin,
any kind of murder, any theft, anything that is all absolutely against the collective.
Nothing stops you. That means whatever you're professing, is just outside, is just mental nothing has gone inside.
Even if you are educated in that. You have seen the priest, you have seen the mullahs, you have seen all these people - they are so well educated -
they do the same thing. What's wrong there?
When they know this is right, why don't they do what is right?
The reason is, they haven't got the power of the Spirit.
In the light of the Spirit only, you become what you profess.
You walk what you talk. We don't have to tell anyone that you do this and do that because they have the light.
In their own light they see the same thing, understand the same thing, they know what is right and what is wrong
and what is good for you, what is for your benevolence.
Of course, by the raising of this Kundalini, as I told you, many diseases can be cured physically.
We have three doctors in Delhi, those who have got M.D. after doing their M.B.B.S.
in the subject of sahaja yoga. They have cured people of some incurable diseases.
And now, there are seven doctors in England, also we have doctors here, two or three, who are collecting datas to show how
sahaja yoga can cure you without wasting your time into something
that we call as the medicines and all artificial things.
So many things can be done with your own power. You don't have to depend on anybody else
but the cleansing part of your being takes place when you become collective,
when you are together. Like supposing, a nail of Mine is broken, it won't grow.
It will be just left at the same point where it was thrown away.
In the same way, if you are collective, the whole body of Spirituality will cleanse you completely,
will manifest all your powers, will give you what you're worth.
You have to know your glory, you have to know your beauty.
And no use condemning yourself that, "I'm a sinner, I've done this wrong, that wrong." After all you're human-beings
and as human-beings we're supposed to commit mistakes - we're not Gods.
So those people who tell you that, "You're a sinner, this thing, that thing," should see their own sins.
So please have no diffidence about yourself, no diffidence at all.
I assure you all of you can get realization, if you can just get over your diffidence.
It's one thing we have to accept that we're human-beings and we are
the epitome of evolution. We have evolved up to this state and a little more is needed which is
very easy and should happen to you - is already built-in within you, is already there. For example, see this instrument is
made but if it is not put to the mains, it has no meaning. In the same way you're to be put to the mains
and this All-Pervading power about which I'm saying, we start feeling it for the first time.
We see these beautiful flowers all around, we take them for granted.
How have they come out of this Mother Earth which looks so gross and out of one seed?
How these different flowers have come with different personalities?
We take them for granted. All the living work we take it for granted,
even ourselves. Look at our eye, what a camera it is! Look at our brain,
what a computer it is! We take it for granted. Why? Because we have no answer - we cannot say how.
But in sahaja yoga we'll know how it works out. I hope, you all will take your realization
and tomorrow again I'll tell you all about the Spirit, what the Spirit is.
You don't have to take Me for granted, again I'm saying that - blind faith is not needed
but as Scientist you must keep an open mind to test for yourself and see for yourself.
It will hardly take ten minutes, maybe, five minutes also for you to get your realization. There is no
necessity for you to have any kind of a reading done or any kind of a uh.. penance done.
As long as a human-being, you're a human-being and that you desire, very strongly,
your Self-realization, nothing more is needed.
This Kundalini is the power of your pure desire.
All other desires are not pure because they're never satiable.
So, this pure desire should be in your heart that, "I should get my Self-realization and let my, all my powers manifest."
I think, we can have some little time for questioning
but please don't ask Me unnecessary questions to waste time for everyone because
it's easy to answer because I'm now quite an expert
I've been working on this for twenty one years and I know all the Western minds how they work and the Eastern minds how they work
and I can answer all your questions still, I would request you that it's not important.
Even if I answer you, even if you are satisfied mentally
still, it's no guarantee that your Kundalini will rise.
Main thing is that your Kundalini must rise and you must get your Self-realization, which is the actualization of baptism.
Is actualization, it is not just putting My hand on your head and say that now you have got your realization or you have got your baptism.
This is what it is, so I would request you, if you have any questions, do ask Me, please. Thank you very much.
- [INAUDIBLE]
- What did he say?
-
- When You raise the Kundalini, don't you automatically raise the impurities and the chakras as well?
- Yeah.
You see, the Kundalini is to be understood in a very proper way.
These are the chakras, say on the Left Sympathetic and the Right Sympathetic, when they meet they make the Parasympathetic Nervous System
and these are the centers. Now, when you start using too much of right or left side, then what happens that they become constricted.
Now, when the Kundalini rises, She doesn't rise the whole of Her own body -
it's like many strings put together like a rope - so some strings rise and they try to expand
this space by nourishing those centers but completely they're not nourished,
not nourished fully. Some people do have very beautiful uh.. balanced life,
they do get it but not mostly, they don't. So what happens, when the Kundalini rises, She passes through the, nourishes there
and pierces through your fontanel bone area but it's a very small thread, I should say, in the beginning
which passes through the very, very subtle uh.. channel, we call as Brahma nadi.
When it pierces through, then it opens this,
I should say, the, as the ego and conditioning part of it, these two open out and this thousand petalled
chakra, we call as the Sahastrara, the thousand petalled lotus also opens out.
When it opens out it gets connected, of course, but the connection is not established fully.
Even if you connect this, it may not be if it is little faulty, may not be established. So it has to be established.
That hardly, it takes a  month at the most, for some people it doesn't even take one day, even one minute.
So depends on. So we have to pay respect to ourselves and understand that if there's any problem, doesn't matter, we should correct it.
Then also you must know, what it is. You must have the full knowledge as to
what is this Kundalini, what you have achieved, what are your powers, how can you work it out
everything you must know because once you're enlightened, you should be able to give light to others.
After this happening, you can give realization to others - you get that power - you can cure people, you can put them right.
Even a person who is spiritually so awakened, even if he enters any place, peace comes in,
balance, equilibrium even in the nature comes in.
So, such a personality if you create within yourself,
you have to do it and that if it is required little time, you should give that time to yourself.
And then, when in a full way you become a really a Divine personality.
That's what we have to achieve but you don't have to give up your families, you don't have to give up your anything - it's something that happens within yourself.
And that should happen to all of us. It makes no difference what age you are, it makes no difference
what race you are, nothing of the kind. As long as you are a human-being, it works out.
[INAUDIBLE]
The question is, what is actually the meaning of the term realization and what actually is happening.
We have told them.
Actually happening is the awakening of the Kundalini and you are getting connected to the mains, means the All Pervading power,
which is all the time flowing through you.
Now, what is Self-realization, that I'm going to tell you tomorrow, as I said, but in short is that you know about your own centers.
You become aware of yourself firstly.
Many things happen but one of them is, on a physical level you know.
Now people get cancer they don't know if they're getting cancer, they become mad they don't know they're becoming mad.
But you become knowledgeable, you can feel it, on your finger-tips you can feel it - your centers and the centers of others
so that you become collectively conscious. Your conscious, consciousness
is so much enlarged that you can feel the centers of other people. Sitting down here you can feel the centers of others.
Then you don't talk about a person as an Australian, Indian or anything
but you will say that this center is not all right, that center is not all right, this center is very good.
This is the language you start talking about.
And what happens is, such a lot, that in one lecture I don't think I can cover it.
But tomorrow, I'm sure, I'll be able to tell you elaborately what all the good things happen to a person who is a Self-realized.
First you get your Self-realization, is better. For example, you see here beautiful lights are here
and when you come, you have to just switch on one switch
because it's all built-in there, it's there existing.
What's the use of telling about all the history of these lights and the history of electricity
and all how it came here to Melbourne and how it was brought here. Better have your lights first and then we'll talk about it
otherwise it will be boring.
Any more questions?
I'm saying that [UNCLEAR]
[UNCLEAR]
- I didn't follow him.
- The questioner is a little uncertain about the nature of the term
desiring the Spirit. In order to achieve the Spirit, you have to desire it
and that you have to have a purity of Spirit in order to achieve the Spirit.
You see, why I said you have to desire because God has given you freedom.
I cannot be disrespectful to that freedom.
If you don't desire, I cannot force on you, cannot be done.
You have to ask for it.
It cannot be forced, it cannot be... we cannot mesmerize people, we cannot do something like that,
you cannot force people, you cannot dominate -
it is your will which has to come. Only through your sweet will it will work out.
And do you know that many have written about this - like William Blake has written
that, "Men of God," - it's a special category of people  who are seekers of truth, it's a special category. He's described them
as, "Men of God will know God and they'll have powers to make others Godly."
So many have said about this in India also but I must say William Blake was a great seer
that he could see this so clearly what was going to happen in the future.
[INAUDIBLE]
- Why not have faith in Western medicine?
- Annh?
- You should, why not. I did also western medicine, you must have.
But I'm saying, your faith in Western medicine is all right but they have no control over Parasympathetic Nervous System.
There're many things which cannot be answered by medical sciences
but if we can manage it with something else, why not do it.
- So quiet [UNCLEAR] They're in thoughtless awareness
- Looks like questions are finished.
- [SHRI MATAJI LAUGHS] All right.
Agnya chakra which is shown there. Then what happens
that these two conditioning and ego, these two institutions are sucked in like that.
With that you achieve a state which we call as
thoughtless awareness, called as 'nirvichar samadhi' in Sanskrit language.
Thoughtless awareness, means you are absolutely aware but there is no thought.
Otherwise we are always bombarded with thinking. Thoughts are coming whether you like it or not - you can't stop it.
Now, thoughts come either from the future or from the past.
In the present if I say, "Stop your thought," you cannot. And you cannot be in the present unless and until you stop your thoughts.
So, the first state that comes to you, that you become thoughtlessly aware
means you have a command over your thoughts. If you want you'll think otherwise you'll not think.
And you grow spiritually only when you are in the present.
If I say, "Pay attention to yourself," you can't. Say, "How to pay attention inside?"
But supposing Kundalini rises, then the attention, which we can say, like a sari like this and it pushes up
the attention. Attention, here, when it reaches
then the Grace starts falling or you can say the light starts falling on the attention and your attention becomes enlightened.
but you are in thoughtless awareness state.
Afterwards, when you have established your connections properly
then you are in the second state, that we call as doubtless awareness.
And this doubtless awareness state in which you start manifesting all your powers -
and this is what we have to achieve,
which is very easy, works out in a very simple way; of course, you don't have to pay at all for that.
And it works wonderfully because you get the proof of it.
You get these powers working and you understand that these powers are working.
You have to certify yourself - nobody is going to give you the certificate. It is you who's going to decide it.
Is it all right now, should we have the session for Self-realization?
- Second [UNCLEAR]
- [INAUDIBLE]
[INAUDIBLE]
Can you achieve a balance of the chakras through mantras and meditation or singing?
Of course, but it's a science; One has to know what to do exactly.
It's not just say any mantras. You see, these, there are people giving mantras
for 300 pounds or 6000 pounds - I mean, nonsense it is.
And mantras are related to your chakras, which you yourself will know.
But mostly it is not needed. If it is needed, you have to, may also have to do
some sort of a asana, as Hatha yoga is but very rarely.
So mantras do not play much role, unless and until, you have that problem then you have to use the mantras
but which is the chakra for which you need, you have to find out first of all.
That's only possible when the Kundalini rises, then you know where there is obstructed, then you have to use a particular mantra - that helps.
On the whole, all this knowledge is very easily available - it's not difficult - but first of all you must enter into the Kingdom of God
then you're looked after. Unless and until that has happened, is impossible - it will be just talk, talk and talk.
And you have had many talks, it should not be another talk to you
but it should happen - is the becoming.
All these things which we have known, part here, part there, something false, something true.-
in the light you see everything so clearly.
In the darkness of ignorance, you believe this is true, this is true, that should be such
but what you need, is the enlightened mind. Once you're enlightened, you are a different person altogether.
So now, please don't get worried
about yourself. You are all going to get your Self-realization.
Don't doubt yourself. That's the first condition is, relax.
Don't doubt yourself. You're all going to get your realization.
I have no doubts about it but if you doubt yourself, I can't help it.
Must have full confidence in yourself - that is the first condition.
The second condition is that,
you're not to feel guilty about anything, whatsoever.
It's a fashion these days also to feel guilty for nothing at all - specially in English language, we go on saying sorry, sorry, morning till evening.
Even on the telephone you see now in Our times We used to say 'beg your pardon' but nowadays people say sorry for that also. I don't know
for anything they go on saying sorry. What is there to be sorry about?
So, in short, you have to be very pleasantly placed towards yourself.
Don't have any diffidence. Whatever has been a mistake is all right, has to be corrected
and can be done very easily, if you have self-confidence. So please, don't feel guilty.
Don't start confessing in your mind, what wrong you have done to yourself or anything - please, please, don't.
And third condition is also very simple, if you understand, that you have to forgive everyone, in general.
Now, this people sometimes say is very difficult but logically understand.
Whether you forgive or don't forgive, you don't do anything - what do you do - nothing.
But when you don't forgive, then you play into wrong hands.
Those who wanted to trouble you, are happy while you are the one who is feeling extremely
unhappy, all the time torturing yourself for the sake of others.
So just forgive everyone - take it out of your mind. Now since I've come to Australia,
I find, when I meet them, that they say, "Mother, difficult to forgive, difficult to forgive."
I mean, there's nothing difficult - it's your own mental nonsense - throw it away.
You'll feel so much lighter just now. Just say, "I forgive everyone." All those nonsensical people you need not even think of.
In general, you should say, "I've forgiven everyone," and you'll be very much better off.
These are the only three conditions, which are very easy - everybody can do it.
Now, I have to request you, that you have to take out your shoes, if possible, because this Mother Earth really helps us a lot.
Now those who are sitting on the ground, it's all right but those who are not sitting on the ground, have to know
that you have to put your -
you can come in front, if you like, can come in front -
uh.. put your left foot away from the right because the left side represents
our power of desire. Now, medical science doesn't make difference between the left lobe and the right lobe of the brain but we do.
So we have to put the left foot away from the right foot and
we have to use our left hand to express our pure desire to get Self-realization -
is to put your left hand like this,
just like this as he's showing, left hand and the right hand is
the power of action. So, we'll use our right hand
to give nourishment to our centers.
This is to be done only today not all the time. Once you're realized, you don't have to do all this.
This is just for your realization and also for you to know how you can raise your own Kundalini just now.
So now, the left hand is towards Me suggesting that you are desirous of having Self-realization
and the right hand is to be used for your action.
I've already told you that I respect your freedom and those who do not want to have Self-realization
should not watch others and sit here.
They should go and that would be very civil of them, to do. But those who want
can have it very easily. But
whatever we get so easily without paying anything, sometimes we do not have respect for that.
But you don't know, this is the most precious thing to become a Spirit
and we should really respect the Self-realization and try to expand our awareness.
So please, put left hand towards Me and now the right hand on your heart.
In the heart resides the Spirit.
If you become the Spirit, you become your own guide, your own master, your own guru.
So, take your right hand in the upper portion of the abdomen
which is the center of - on the left hand side. We're working only on the left hand side - which is the center of your mastery.
Then you take your hand in the lower portion of the abdomen on the left hand side. This is the center
of pure knowledge - knowledge of the Divine laws and how to work them out.
When you get your Self-realization, you'll find,
first time you'll feel this All-Pervading power on your finger-tips,
Also you'll find a cool breeze coming out of your fontanel bone area,
maybe warm in the beginning but later on cools down.
So, this power that you get, you should know how to use it
for your benevolence and for the benevolence of others. This is the pure knowledge.
Now, please take your hand in the upper portion of your abdomen on the left hand side
and now again on your heart.
Now you have to put your right hand in the corner of your neck and your shoulder and turn your hand to your right.
This center is caught up when you feel guilty and it's a very dangerous thing because
when this, this center is out of gear, you get a horrible disease called Angina,
you get spondylitis, also you get very lethargic organs. So please don't feel guilty.
Now, raise your hand to your forehead across, put your thumb on one side
and the fingers on the other and press it hard. Now, put it down your head.
This is the center for forgiving others.
Now, take this right hand - I'm just showing you now  and then we'll do it and I'll explain to you -
on the back side of your head. Now, push back your head as far as possible. This is the center,
without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes, only for your satisfaction
you have to ask forgiveness from this All-Pervading power.
Now, stretch your hand fully - the palm is to stretch fully -
and put the center of your palm on the fontanel bone area, which was a soft bone in your childhood.
Now, put down your head as far as possible, now press it hard, your scalp, by pushing out
your fingers outward. Now, this is very important - push them out and now press it and move your scalp seven times -
you will know the reason for all this, why seven times you have to move it.
Press your scalp and put down your head -
clockwise, move it clockwise, seven times. That's all you have to do, that's all.
Now, we have to close the eyes. You can take away your spectacles,
please see that your both the feet are away from each other.
If there's anything tight on your neck too much or on your waist, you can loosen it little bit and you have to be comfortable,
not to slouch nor to stretch too much but in a comfortable state, way, you have to sit down.
Now, please put the left hand towards Me, right hand on your heart and close your eyes.
Here, you have to ask Me a question in your heart -
you may call Me Mother or you may call Me Shri Mataji, whatever you feel like.
Ask a question in your heart, three times - a very fundamental question about yourself
"Mother, am I the Spirit?"
"Mother, am I the Spirit?" ask this question three times in your heart.
If you are the Spirit, you are your master. So please, put your right hand
on the upper portion of your abdomen on the left hand side and press it with your fingers - not very hard.
Here you ask another fundamental question in your heart, three times, "Mother, am I my own master?"
With full confidence ask this question.
Again, I cannot cross over your freedom - I respect it
and I cannot force pure knowledge on you - you have to ask for it.
So, please take your right hand in the lower portion of your abdomen and press it hard.
on the left hand side. Here
please say six times because this center has got six petals.
"Mother, please give me pure knowledge. Mother, please give me pure knowledge," ask this six times.
As soon as you ask for pure knowledge, the Kundalini starts moving upward.
So now,
with full confidence you have to open your higher centers.
Please, raise your right hand on the left hand side
of your abdomen in the upper portion and press it hard.
Here, you have to say with full confidence, ten times,
"Mother, I am my own master." Say it with full confidence,
complete self-confidence. "Mother, I am my own master." You have to say it ten times.
We have to know that we are not this body, this mind,
this intellect, emotions, conditionings, ego
but we are pure Spirit.
This is the fundamental truth about yourself. So now, please raise your right hand
on your heart and with full confidence say, twelve times,
please say it twelve times, "Mother, I am the pure Spirit."
Please say it twelve times, "Mother, I am the,
I am the pure Spirit," twelve times, please.
Another thing we have to know that this All-Pervading power of God's love,
is the ocean of knowledge, is the ocean of compassion and bliss
but above all, it is the ocean of forgiveness and whatever mistakes we might have committed
can be easily dissolved by the power of this ocean of forgiveness.
So, please forgive yourself and now raise your right hand in the corner of your neck and your shoulder,
push it as far back as possible and turn your head to your right.
Here, you have to say sixteen times,
with full confidence, "Mother, I am not guilty at all."
Please say it sixteen times.
You don't judge yourself, let your Kundalini judge.
"Mother, I am not guilty at all," please say it sixteen times.
This center has the maximum number of petals - sixteen petals.
This center looks after your ear, nose, throat, face, everything, your tongue, your eyes.
I have already told you whether you forgive or don't forgive, you don't do anything
but if you don't forgive then you play into wrong hands
so, in general, you have to forgive everyone not remembering anyone of the people who have troubled you.
Now, raise your right hand
on your forehead, across, put your thumb on one side
and fingers on the other. Now press it hard.
Please bend your head as far as possible.
Here, without thinking of anybody else
just, in general, you have to say, "Mother, I forgive everyone."
or, "Mother, I forgive everyone in general." Say it from your heart, not how many times but from your heart.
Now, please take your hand on the back side of your head and push it back as far as possible.
Here, without feeling guilty, without counting your mistakes, you have to say
with full confidence, "Oh Divine power, please forgive me
if I have done anything wrong against you knowingly or unknowingly.
"Oh Divine power, please forgive me if I have done anything wrong against you
knowingly or unknowingly." This you're going to say for your satisfaction from your heart - not how many times.
Now the last center which is very important. Please stretch your hand
and put the center of your palm on top of the fontanel bone area which was the soft bone in your childhood.
Please put down your head as far as possible, push back your fingers.
Please push back your fingers, put a good pressure on your scalp. Here again, I respect your freedom -
I cannot force Self-realization on you so you have to say seven times,
"Mother, please give me Self-realization, my second birth,"
and you just move your scalp, very slowly, seven times,  saying that.
[SHRI MATAJI BLOWS INTO THE MICROPHONE]
[SHRI MATAJI BLOWS INTO THE MICROPHONE] Push back your fingers, push back, push back your fingers other there's no pressure.
Put down your heads, please put down, put down your heads. Please put down your heads, push back your finger.
[SHRI MATAJI BLOWS INTO THE MICROPHONE]
Now, please take down your hands. Put both the hands towards Me, like this.
Open your eyes, you can wear your spectacles also. Put both the hands towards Me, like this.
Now, put the right hand towards Me, like this, put down your head and see for yourself if there's a cool or a hot
breeze like waves coming from your head.
Bend your head and see for yourself. Don't put your hand on top of your head, away from it.
Some people get it far away, some get it nearer. Just see, if there's a cool or a hot breeze coming inside.
Now, please put the left hand towards Me
and bend your head and see for yourself now
with the right hand, if there's a cool or a hot breeze coming out of your head.
Again with the right hand, please try again with the right hand.
See yourself, if there's a cool or a hot breeze coming.
Now, raise your both the hands towards the sky, like this
and ask a question, three times, "Mother, is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?"
Or you can ask, "Mother, is this the All-Pervading power of God's love?"
Or you can ask, "Mother, is this the Param Chaitanya?" Ask anyone of these questions. These are the names of only one
thing which is the All-Pervading power of Divine love which does all the living work.
Just ask anyone of these questions, three times
Push back your head towards the sky. Please, put down your hands now.
Just put the hands like this.
You can become thoughtless, you can watch Me without thinking. Just put [UNCLEAR]
Now, those who have felt - please put down your hands
Put your hands like this. Now,
those who have felt cool or warm or hot breeze like waves
on the fingers, on the hands
or out of the fontanel bone area please raise both your hands.
So, that's it! May God bless you!
Everyone seems to have got it except for very few people who haven't.
Very few didn't get it - doesn't matter, you'll get it tomorrow, it's all right.
You shouldn't doubt, that's the main point is the doubting and you should forgive, most of you.
Except for 3-4 people, I think, most of you have got it so, May god bless you!.
I hope to see you tomorrow again and tomorrow
I'll meet all of you, individually, all of you.
Now, you have to inform your friends and everyone, that they should come and we should have more people
because I'm here only for tomorrow and then I'll come back after two years,
one year. I shouldn't say two years, will  be too much. All right, so I would request you
that you should inform your friends, you should inform your relations
because this is the only thing you can give it to them.
Now, you have reached a state where you are thoughtless,
so don't argue with people who haven't got it. Those who haven't got it will also get it tomorrow and those who have got it,
should know that you have to maintain it - like keeping the peace in your heart
and not arguing about it and quarreling with others
because those who won't get it will start saying something - doesn't matter, makes no difference.
You have got it, so keep your experience with yourself and we have to share it with others, so many
in Melbourne. May God bless you!
Tomorrow