Evening Program Day 1, Delphi, 1999
After such
beautiful
divine
music,
I don’t know what to say.
The,
even the heart of all the Deities
must be jumping with joy
as you all were jumping with joy.
It’s such a unison,
the oneness
with all the musicians
and the celestial musicians it was.
It was really a tremendous
experience of joy.
I must thank
the people who have come
all the way from Benin,
they did so well, I mean, I just don’t know
how rhythmically they always
have been dancing.
And in something in them,
in the African people I’ve seen,
they have
such a lot of rhythm,
all the time they are rhythmic:
they’ll walk rhythmically, they’ll talk rhythmically.
It’s sort of- I think sometimes –
"Ke"
Shri Shiva is acting through them.
All the time this rhythm is so beautifully done
and the way they change it, make it patterns,
and double it, triple it
and suddenly new patterns come out.
[Aside] Now what is the other country, this one I don’t know.
Other country?
Sahaja Yogini: Ivory Coast
Then comes Ivory Cost.
And the people of Ivory Coast are also very remarkable.
I was surprised the way
the ladies also were dancing
absolutely full of, full of rhythm.
I mean all of you should learn rhythm from them.
That is something so important to understand
and
to enjoy music
and to enjoy Sahaj.
You see, it's like a-
I see so many lights there
as if I felt you all got the lights in your throat, in your eyes,
also in your Sahasrara.
It was a wonderful time.
So we must thank them especially these two people who have come all the way to entertain us
and to make us enjoy everything.
So we have to be very thankful.
And how, see, so much far away they are otherwise,
but how they have become so much one with us.
We must thank the French for this, that they went
and governed those countries.
By their governing them, they came close to us!
If they had not governed them, there would have been no possibility of meeting them so soon.
So it’s such a beautiful combination, oneness
with all of us
and I must thank you again and again.
Then we have another little thing
which is very important at least to do.
I’ve seen now such a genius,
there is one genius born
and he must be a great musician in his last life
I’m sure!
The way he handles the violin,
I can’t believe it.
But [unsure] he can play without notations or without something, is a miracle.
And if that has happened because of Sahaja Yoga, I must say Sahaja Yoga itself
is a miracle
And then he took to Indian classical music,
he was playing
very deftly, absolutely so well,
I was amazed how a talented person like him
can take to any kind of music.
And Babamama has already told Me that: “Your Sahaja Yogis are really talented.
They are very talented people. Otherwise, how could they take to this difficult,
classical, Indian music?
Not only they have taken it but they have mastered it.”
Now, we had on tabla another French man
whom I had not seen for the last - I think-  three, four years,
but I think now he has mastered it.
The way he plays is really very remarkable.
I was surprised how he could play.
And then is this gentleman who played ” [raag] Malkans” to you.
It’s a very difficult raga.
In that one swara, we call them “madewa”,
that is being taken away from the main team [range]
and also the - I don’t know English word –
the “pa” [sol] is also removed.
It’s a very difficult, very melodious and not easily
learnt his Malkans raag.
I’m surprised how these people in such a short time
have mastered such a difficult raga
for which in India, Indians, have to work years together!
But you, being even not Indian,
you have never heard these notes
and how you have achieved this mastery is beyond Me.
It’s a real, I must say, the greatest blessing of Sahaja Yoga is
that it has given you rhythm,
it has given you “swarasasana”, means the notes.
You are not weaving out from the notes.
I’m not myself,  I myself
don’t sing myself,
I used to once upon a time
but my family is so much in music that it has gone into my heart, into my mind.
And when I see this, I say: “Look at that!
How these people have come out!”
The last but not the least is this lady, Ana.
Sahaja Yogini: Anne.
Who is another master.
Well, they're all masters can you imagine?
This little boy is already a master.
But the ways he's accompanying Indian music, I mean,
I’m amazed at him.
In the same way, this lady the way she was rendering very difficult ragas,
with such deftness with such perfection.
I mean, I'm going to now take this film to India.
They have been asking Me: “Mother why don’t you give your episodes, your programs to us.
We’d like to broadcast it from the Television.”
Now I’ll say: “Look at this, you see this,
And they will all jump at it I tell you.
They will have it and they will do it
and they’ll be so amazed that how could, with Sahaja Yoga, you could master these things.
And see the oneness of us.
You are from this country you are from that country,
and also speak different languages
and you understand different words,
everything differently.
But when it comes to Sahaja bhajans,
I don’t know how you get completely one with it.
That shows that Sahaja Yoga is going to bring the whole world together
through its music and through
its manifestation.
I am really very much honoured, I am thankful to all the artists,
all of you
for such beautiful rendering.
For all the ladies who have come here, I wish I was young to learn their dancing.
But I’m not.
Also,  I used to sing very well
But because of lecturing and all that I think I’ve lost that capacity to sing.
Now you see, after you see this, it’s like a reflection of your heart,
it’s the reflection of your ideas about your ideal, your visions.
You see this world singing together the song of Divinity.
It’s something nobody would believe, that we have such a good group of people here.
I’m thankful to you all and to the audience
who have joined and have shown their beautiful
oneness and also the expression of their joy.
May God bless you all.