We must know that Sahaja Yoga is a living
process.
It is the same type of a process by which
a seed sprouts into a tree.
It is a living process.
So it is God’s job.
I mean He has to do it.
It is not your job.
To sprout the seed is His job.
But the problem comes in because, at this
stage where human being is the seed, he has
freedom, they have freedom.
With that freedom they can spoil His manifestation,
His working.
So the first thing one has to remember that
we must have wisdom about it.
The first point of wisdom is that it is God
Almighty who is going to do this job.
We are not doing it.
You cannot sprout the seed, then how can you
sprout your seed also?
And in that wisdom we must learn one thing
and know, within ourselves, that you are part
and parcel of the whole process.
Though you have your own freedom, freedom
also is a part and parcel of the same process.
You are not separated from God.
You do not have any separated entity.
You are part and parcel of that whole process.
Alright?
So to think that you have to decide something
about it is also wrong.
You are in the same machinery, brought to
this stage when you are given freedom for
your further evolution.
So at this stage, when you have your freedom,
you must know that freedom wants to be given
to you to understand the value of freedom.
And in that freedom, you must understand what
is glorious for you.
Once you understand that, then you tell yourself
that, “Now, see: I have to become something
more.
That’s why God has done this, only thing
I have to do is to completely coordinate,
cooperate and surrender to His will, so that
I become."
This is the first preparation we have to make.
In that surrendering, you will do the greatest
thing because by that you do not interfere
with His work.
Unless and until you surrender you cannot
have the wisdom.
So first of all you understand this, through
your little wisdom that you have, and then
you’ll have the full wisdom.
First of all, understand this with the little
wisdom that you have, that, without surrendering
you will be obstructing the ways of God.
He knows what is good for you.
He wants to give you the highest which you
cannot achieve yourself.
He’s going to give you the highest.
If you want to achieve it, you cannot achieve
it.
It is His doing.
It is His daan (दान), as you call it,
His gift to you.
In that case you must know that [the] best
way to achieve it is to allow His working
to work out.
Now when you think of surrendering, first
of all the brain wave starts working.
“What do I surrender?”
You think by surrendering, say, your material
wealth.
That’s not what He wants.
It’s all wealth He has given to you.
What is He going to do [with that]?
It’s [not] equal to even a dust particle
of His feet.
So that one is not going to help.
Sometimes you may feel that, “I should give
my intelligence,” or that is what is asked.
Nobody wants to have your idiots and stupid
people!
So you don’t give up your intelligence.
Then some people think that, “I give up
my heart."
Some people say it.
We don’t want heartless people either.
Then some people will say that, “Mother,
we’ll give up our relationships with others."
That also is not needed.
Because your heart should be there where it
is and the light has to come in your heart.
What can you give your heart to whom?
When the One who has given you the heart,
what’s the use of giving Him back the heart?
Isn’t it?
The One who has given you intelligence, what’s
the use of giving Him [it back]?
Something that you have achieved yourself
has to be given.
What have you achieved is your ego and your
super-ego.
What you have achieved is nothing but your
ego.
And this ego you have to give up, which is
a difficult task.
Ego, if it comes out of money, material things,
it is better you give up some material things,
not to God but somebody else.
It’s better.
If the material things are creating that ego.
If your intelligence is creating ego that
you think you have a very high IQ, it’s
better to bring it down a little.
It is for you to judge.
Watch yourself: what makes your ego bloated
up?
If you could start looking at your ego you
will be amazed that any useless thing can
bloat it and can also deflate it.
It can get hurt from nothing at all.
It becomes so important.
Then the superego part of it also comes.
That is what also you have to give up.
And in superego you can have your conditionings
due to your gurus and wrong types of doings
and wrong types of conditionings [that] you
have had from childhood.
Like, for example, somebody is a Catholic:
for him, Pope is everything.
Or somebody is a Hindu: for him a particular
temple is everything.
All these are conditionings.
Why they are conditionings [is] that, without
finding out the truth about them, you have
just accepted them as it is.
This is the simple thing.
So if you can find out the truth about all
these things, you will give it up.
You may, may not.
There are many people who know the truth,
still they do not give up.
You see, human beings are complicated stuff.
Even if they know the truth they will not
give up.
But supposing you try to find the truth about
all these things: then you may give, may not
give.
But going back into the whole thing, to find
out each and every thing, make a schedule
of the whole thing that, ‘’Morning time
I’ll find out about this, and evening time
about this,” The whole [of] your life you
will go on finding one by one, and ultimately
you will find that you have gone now up to
the grave.
So that procedure also is not going to help
you.
By God’s grace you are Realised-souls and
you can find out in a second whether you are
on the conditioning side or not.
If your left is catching you are conditioned.
If your right is catching you are on ego trip.
Alright.
So now you know very simple method is to know
that, through vibrations, you can find out
[if] Mr Ego is there or superego is there
or you are wobbly.
This is the biggest thing we have got because
this is my preparation.
My preparation is this, that, first give you
Realisation.
First give you Realisation.
Once you are Realised then I won’t have
to say much.
If you are conditioned on the left side you
will get pains, this, that.
If you are conditioned [on] right-hand side
you’ll have problems with health or something.
So you will come to me and I will be able
to tell you.
This is my own preparation: is to make you
alert and aware so that you have light to
see things.
Now your preparation should be to use this
awareness all the time.
Further I will go to say that: to use this
knowledge within you all the time.
That people forget.
So the first [thing] we must know is that
this preparation has been done for us.
We have got the vibrations.
We have got the knowledge to verify and we
must use this.
That you are in a new dimension is the first
acceptance.
If you have that acceptance within you then
your judgement will be better.
But this acceptance is missing.
Now there is, in Sanskrit, a word, ‘abhyas’
, that every day doing the same thing in that
manner you will remember that you are Realised
and that your awareness is not that of the
awareness of ordinary people.
So, first preparation is to prepare yourself,
to tell yourself that you have this new awareness
within you, is to make yourself known.
You see, in the University when you graduate,
there is a ceremony held for that.
You have to go with a gown and they give you
a proper roll and all that.
Why is it necessary?
Because you may forget you are a graduate.
(laughter) Yes!
And that’s exactly what happens to you,
that you forget you are Realised-souls.
I mean, we have had a ceremony in the sense
that everything we have done to prove that
you are Realised-souls.
But this is what is missing from our people,
that they cannot understand that they are
Realised-souls, that they are people who are
on a level that nobody [else] is.
You are twice-born people, who are very, very
rare.
Very rarely you will find people who are twice-born.
I mean, I found nobody – can you imagine?
– all my lifetime, except for my father
and a few here and there.
I mean they are not to be counted because
my father I chose and that’s how.
So, first of all if you make yourself known
to your own intelligence that, “I am a Realised-soul!”
you’ll be seeing that your priorities will
be changing very fast.
Supposing somebody gives you a huge big property
or a huge big wealth.
Immediately you become conscious of it.
You start walking like this.
When you are a student you walk like this.
Suddenly you get the degree and walk like
this.
(laughter) What about Realisation?
So happy to see you here, very happy.
May God Bless.
What about your Realisation?
You haven’t got your Realisation?
Then what are you doing about it?
This is the first preparation: is of identifying
that you are a Realised-soul.
We have to talk in a different way – we
are Realised-souls now.
We are people of a different knowledge.
We are people of a different awareness.
As I told you.
Now see this beautiful building: we all are
enamoured by it and it looks very beautiful.
It’s done so well, beautifully and is very
important for human beings.
Alright?
But for the Divine even this green leaf is
more important than the whole building put
together and all such buildings put together.
For the Divine.
Because that leaf is living and a bird which
is more aware than that leaf is, is much more
important to the Divine.
So you, the human beings who are now aware
to this extent how much important you must
be to Divine?
How much God Himself must be interested in
you?
Just think of it!
Once you recognise this point, then relatively
you will also know that you are very important
in God’s plan.
Not world’s plan I am talking.
(laughter) It is God’s plan.
So all the forces of his blessings and all
his loftiness, all of them are with to help
you, to support you, to give you whatever
you like.
You are on the stage and they are looking
after you.
I mean, now you have entered on the stage.
But I find Sahaja Yogis, once they get Realisation,
I don’t know what happens to them.
If they give up their ego then they become
like, absolutely, I don’t know what you
call them…bananas?
(laughter)
Each one of you is the special one created
by God.
Now you see for yourself, just think of yourself.
I mean, you are the ones who know such a lot
about life.
Even if you get a little bit possessed, doesn’t
matter.
But you know that you are possessed.
Now think of it.
This is the second preparation one has to
have – is understanding that it is God Almighty
Himself [who is] worried about you.
He’s sent everybody to help you, “Go ahead!”
So you don’t have to worry about your money,
you don’t have to worry about all other
things.
The third thing comes automatically
that you don’t have to worry about all these
things at all.
They’ll be looked after.
You all have been looked after, you know that.
Everyone has been helped.
But if you know that He is Almighty and He’s
compassion and that you have fallen into His
grace – think of it!
Establish yourself at that point.
This is the preparation one has to have, that
He is the one who has given all this.
Then, the modern Sahaja Yogis are specially
blessed because they have a ‘walkie-talkie’
with them.
Any problem that they have are handled in
form, in person!
There was never such a blessing before.
But ego is the point.
To begin with it is ego.
You have seen it.
If you have ego you will not accept you are
a Realised-soul.
Imagine, how silly it is!
If you have a superego also you will not recognise
it.
You will go back to the same position as you
were.
You will never accept that you are a Realised-soul
if you have a superego.
You’ll never accept, “Oh, how can it be,
Mother?
After all I am an ordinary human being."
You’ll go on like that, “How can I cure
others?
How can I give Realisation?
It is not possible."
You see this kind of a humility, nonsensical.
I mean, it’s alright, I mean it’s like
a ??
saying, “Oh, how can I cure you?”
It’s like that.
It’s like no meaning.
This kind of a humility has no meaning for
you.
“How can I do it, Mother?
What can I do?
Oh, I am no good.
I’m of no use."
This language must be given up.
When it is ego then it is even worse.
You can harm yourself and you can harm Sahaja
Yoga, at the extreme point.
Egoistical people are extremely difficult,
they are such a drag, because they try to
do everything through their intelligence and
understanding and this and that, and such
a rambling goes on and on and on, and you
try to pull them back again and they go back.
It’s so boring, you know.
Very boring.
Because you know, I see the stuff, supposing,
I know this is it (a cup of tea) and I want
you to have it.
And between taking this cup to the lip, [if]
every time you are pulling it out, every time
you are pulling it out, then how am I to take
it to your lip?
It’s very boring!
And this egoistical temperament is very prevalent
in the West, surprisingly.
And I just don’t understand.
They can take to all kinds of filth, all kinds
of perversions without arguing about it!
Just take to it!
Any kind of perversion – “What’s wrong?”
But it is for them the most wrong thing is
to be accepting the fact that you are a Realised-soul
through Sahaja Yoga.
They’ll take anything else but not the truth.
This ego is like a horse sitting on your head.
You have to sit on the horse, and the horse
is sitting on your head.
You are carrying the load of the horse – imagine!
what is the sense in such a thing?
If you start analysing yourself, again you
will go into another trip.
You have been such ‘trippers’ like [a]
Jack in the box, you see.
Because you have been taking trips after trips,
there’s a sort of a spring.
You try to see your ego, you go on a trip
of superego.
You try to see your superego and you go on
a trip of [ego].
I mean, a person who has been bouncing all
the time to this trip or that trip or that
trip or that trip is just like a person travelling
all the time, doesn’t know whether he has
to get down or has to go further.
It’s like that!
The habit of the mind is so egoistical that
you just take the ride on the thing.
But the thing is [that] it is not that you
take the ride, but the ego takes you on a
ride.
And whenever there is any such a thing coming
up, it grabs you.
And the progress is extremely slow.
Now the trouble with the Divine is that it
has its own protocol and if the King has to
come to your house, you have to go and invite
the King.
The King doesn’t write to you that, “Please
invite me to your house,” does he?
That’s why he’s King, after all!
And he doesn’t implore people that, “Please
invite me."
This Mr.
Ego expects that
you should be invited by the Divine.
That the Divine must go out of the way to
fetch you out.
Ego, in simple words, is nothing but absolutely
wrong ideas about one’s own value: by which
you think that, “I am everything."
What are you?
Now don’t go on a superego trip.
What are we?
Nothing!
We cannot even sprout the seed.
Every day-to-day life you can see this clearly:
how ego jumps up.
Supposing somebody says that, “British have
these qualities,” one feels very happy.
“Oh, what a praise it is!
What a praise for British!
Oh, we are British!” immediately.
Somebody says that, “British lack these
qualities,” finished!
You are absolutely…then that person is the
worst person in the whole world.
First of all, you must know that neither you
are British, nor Indian nor anything.
You are just human beings.
Ignorance is responsible for this ego.
It is complete ignorance about yourself gives
you this ego.
So once we are going towards light we must
know what are our hurdles.
[This] is the preparation.
Is the ignorance that we have about ourselves
that’s why we are going to see ourselves.
And because of the ignorance, ego and super-go
both have come onto us, so at least we’ll
have nothing to do with them.
Supposing you have to go on the Himalayas
where you are going for an expedition.
You are supposed to carry the lightest things
that you have.
You don’t carry three luggage of tiffin
carriers, four luggage of this, and five things
of that, to have a nice little bed there and
sleep over.
All that you leave here.
In the same way when you are going on the
expedition of knowing yourself, all that is
loading up yourself must be put down.
So again we come to ego and superego.
Actually, these two are terrible elephants
which must be kept down on the ground.
So we make our own study.
These preparations are needed because we have
already gone on this side too much or that
side too much.
So the preparation is to bring you down, “Come
along here.
Now you stand in the centre!” or we bring
you down here and stand in the centre.
The preparation is nothing but is just to
bring you down here, that’s all.
So with ego we move on and see what the ego
has subtler and subtler and subtler forms.
Even in superego you have subtler and subtler
and subtler forms.
To understand ego you must see what do you
plan about your life?
It’s very easy.
What are your plans about future life?
To understand your superego you must know
what affects you very much, what makes you
very unhappy.
Or you can say, what makes you more happy
and what makes you more unhappy.
Both things, happiness and unhappiness, are
the shadows of these two trees.
One is ego, another is superego.
Just watch yourself.
What makes you very happy?
Good clothes?
Good living?
Or when your name appears in “Who’s who?”
(book) or all such nonsensical things which
make you laugh, you see!
All that.
You just see that.
What makes you unhappy?
When [there is] some sort of a heartbreak
and this and that.
All this kind of a nonsense.
Both things are not yourself.
They are just outside.
So what is inside, if you have to find out,
first the outside must be taken away.
If you have to taste the fruit you take out
the outside, you peel it out.
In the same way, this must be peeled out.
Now this you should see within yourself and
without also.
You can see it very clearly without.
It’s very easy.
How you deal with others is the point – what
is your relationship with others.
It is easier to know this outside than inside,
perhaps.
When you talk to others, what is the impact
they have from you?
Are you appreciated by others or not?
Among Sahaja Yogis.
Do you respect another Sahaja Yogi as a Sahaja
Yogi or not?
Do you expect that whatever stage you are,
the other Sahaja Yogi will also come up and
he must be given the due respect?
Also you must see that when any Sahaja Yogi,
who has achieved something or who is at a
better level, tries to pull you up – [do]
you like it or resist it or get upset about
it?
If somebody tells you, “This should be done,
that should be done,” do you take it as
if he has abused you?
If he is telling you about Sahaja Yoga you
should be thankful in all normal way.
I feel thankful to you if you tell me something
that concerns Sahaja Yoga.
Anything!
Even if you tell me, “Mother this may not
be alright if You say.
You see, the human beings are like this,”
I accept it and I do it according to your
wishes.
Or do you like it or not?
This is how you will judge your ego.
This is only your Mr.
Ego.
Actually, it is better to have another person
to fight your ego and yourself; both put together.
If somebody tells you that, “This should
be done,” “Oh, I see, I have been doing
that.
Yes, alright.
You come and help me.
You pull me out.
Work it out.
Try and help me.
I am horrible!”
That’s the way, if you do it, [that] you
can get over this ego.
But the other person should say, “You are
very nice.
Alright, do what you please,” and then you
feel happy.
This person is not so alright and you are
also not so alright.
Because you have to pull out people.
For example, if you understand that you are
in a crisis, you are in an emergency, people
are getting drowned and some people are trying
to pull them out, they themselves are halfway
down, halfway up, they are trying to pull
you out, at that time if they say, “Hold
my hand now!”
If you feel upset about it then you are not
wise.
Now in Sahaja Yoga there is no leader as such.
I mean, nobody is appointed as leader.
Anybody tries to do that, he goes down.
But there is an innate leadership within,
and such a person is extremely humble and
congenial and appealing and commanding too,
has to be commanding.
And one should not feel bad at that time,
because if he says, “Go and steal something,”
or “You go and join some- one of these nonsensical
things”, then of course he is wrong!
But if he is saying that, “In Sahaja Yoga
you have to come up!”
Even dominatingly (sic) if he says, I mean,
it’s a very good thing, I would say.
Supposing somebody is in your neighbourhood
who is always criticising.
In a way it’s a blessing because [if] there’s
somebody who is criticising us he’s trying
to perfect us.
I mean, we should take it.
Not to feel bad about it.
Supposing somebody is saying something about
you, if it is not true, then what is there
to feel bad?
If he is telling lies about you, there is
nothing to be frightened about.
If he is telling the truth, then you have
to be thankful.
Though sometimes the truth could be very unpalatable,
could be very, very bad.
But it is a good thing.
There is a saying in Marathi, “Keep the
house of the person who is a backbiter, the
one who backbites.
Keep the house of such a man who is your backbiter
next to you.
Next door."
That you know your defects, you see, you correct
yourself.
Is the wise attitude.
Because you cannot correct yourself, so have
a mirror by which you correct yourself.
I mean, you should thank such a man that he
is criticising you.
By pampering you if he is going to completely
destroy you, what’s the use?
This is what the gurus are doing.
They are all pampering you and destroying
you and ultimately you find out that you have
been befooled.
So if you accept the situation in which you
say, “Alright, if this is what is going
to be the truth, it’s very much better for
my ego and if it is not the truth then what
is so important?”
This attitude helps in Sahaja Yoga very much,
a very wise attitude towards oneself is.
And you will be surprised as you’ll grow
with this attitude, you won’t be easily
hurt by what people say to you.
You won’t bother.
You know how much people criticise me and
say all kinds of things, argue with me, and
I’m not bothered because I know they are
foolish.
What is there?
They are stupid people.
Even if they praise me, what is it?
After all, whatever they praise me is my nature,
nothing so great.
See, it makes no difference.
I am just watching my chakras working.
I am not bothered.
In the same way, it will happen to you and
you will not be bothered.
But this will help your unloading.
This will help your unloading.
And, the unhappy part of it: in that we should
prepare ourselves in a way that , “Nothing
can make me unhappy.
What can make me unhappy if I am a Realised-soul?”
Supposing you want to marry someone – take
a concrete thing – and you find the person
has sort of misbehaved or you cannot marry.
So what?
“I am there.
My value is myself I know."
So your value, your self-esteem should be
such that nothing should make you unhappy.
It’s all a drama going on.
It’s all a drama.
But these things must be accepted by your
great intelligence because what I find here
is the difficulty with the Western mind is
this that – it has too much of IQ, too much
over-developed.
So it is such a polished surface that nothing
stays there, everything.
The first simple thing is that you are a Realised-soul
itself should settled down there somehow,
and to your intelligence that you are a Realised-soul
now.
All of you believe in the heart, not in the
brain.
That you are a Realised-soul, is first thing
you must tell your intelligence.
And then you must tell your intelligence also
that, “Nothing can make me unhappy and nothing
can befool me."
If these three points settle down on your
intelligence I will see the rest of it.
You just fix these three points on your intelligence
then you will be amazed [that] you will become
a very loving person, extremely considerate
of others.
It will all work out automatically.
Because when your intelligence is like that
nothing goes in.
You are all the time worried about others.
Either you are afraid of others or you are
aggressive on others.
You cannot go straight forward.
This is what happens.
If you could understand these three points
clearly.
(laughing).
Yogini: Nobody does that.
Shri Mataji: She says that “Nobody does
that.
That’s the problem."
Absolutely.
She’s so practical.
(laughing).
She is so practical, you see.
Just now in the car she said, “Everybody
does something other [than they should].
They do not do what is the first to be done."
Like she said, “They’ll marry, you have
to marry and enjoy your wife and your husband
and your children.
They’ll do everything else but that."
(laughing) It is that.
You see, nobody does that.
It’s so practical if you do it.
Listening to Mataji is not the thing I want
you to do, but doing of it is.
Sit down and tell your intelligence, your
IQ, that, “Mr IQ, now please listen.
This is what has happened to me, and this
is what I am.
I am a Realised-soul and nothing should pamper
me and nothing should make me unhappy."
That’s all.
“Nobody can hurt me."
Otherwise you are, “Aaahahhahaa, aahhaahah,”
like that, it goes in two ways.
Never in a straight way.
Where you are just compassion and you are
love.
Absolutely relying upon yourself, absolutely.
And then you have me with you.
And you think of those sages who had nobody
to guide, nobody to tell, nobody to talk to.
All your granthis and all that, I am breaking.
You don’t have to do anything.
But only thing you don’t create your own
granthis, your own knots.
If you do not create, things will work out.
This is a very simple preparation.
So I don’t have to tell you, “Love your
brothers and sisters,” and this and that.
That’s going the other way around.
But you just tell your intelligence.
This is enlightenment of the intelligence.
If that intelligence comes into you then it
is wisdom.
“That anybody is laughing at me or everybody’s
making fun of me or anybody is trying to dominate
me,” all these fears or all these aggressiveness,
all this will disappear just like that.
That now you are a flower and you are fragrant
and the fragrance is blowing, and many bees
are going to come to you, that’s what you
are!
This is the beginning.
Go on telling yourself like that.
If you could do that, if you can bring your
intelligence to this level, not too high,
not too low, but in the centre, everything
can be solved in no time.
When I am now living with you people, going
through your Kundalinis, all that, I have
found out at this point only: that you just
don’t tell your intelligence this.
So that you start giving up all kinds of fanaticism,
all fears and this, and superstitions and
all nonsense.
Because nothing can harm you.
No stars can harm you, not your science can
harm you, what time you were born.
Nothing can harm you now!
You are beyond it.
So astrology is finished.
Horoscopes are finished.
All other…what other things you had like
this?
Sahaja Yogi: Karma.
Shri Mataji: Karmas are finished.
Sahaja Yogini: Palmistry
Shri Mataji: Palmistry is finished.
Sahaja Yogi: Biorhythm.
(Big laughter]
Shri Mataji: Biorhythm’s finished!
Biorhythm’s finished!
All that.
I mean, you are beyond that.
Now all these things, all such things.
Then the other side of it.
All love affairs finished.
All fear of love affairs finished.
Everything finished, nonsense.
It’s only love.
Now whosoever you will get, you will love
that person, that person will love you.
If he doesn’t care or loves you, it doesn’t
matter.
As long as you love, finished!
All expectations finished, all expectations
finished.
All expectations for happiness.
Joy is single and absolute.
When you are in joy you are at a state when
there is no movement.
You are just there.
So get rid of this both feelings of, “I
am very happy now!”
“I am now in joy.
I am established in joy and that’s what
I have to grow within me not that my old stuffs.
That’s dead, finished."
When the trees drop out their leaves, people
don’t expect them to again rise and get
attached to the trees?
(Laughter).
In the same way whatever is gone and finished
is finished now.
Now let us grow what is new coming in us,
and this is to be nurtured now – is the
joy, is that dignified majestic, that beauty
within ourselves.
Then you don’t get upset.
Not bothered what others have to say about
you.
It will happen.
It will happen if you put it down on your
intelligence.
And people will see that in you because you
don’t do anything funny, you don’t do
anything wrong.
People like you.
Even those who are not Realised will see that
dignity in you, that you are so dignified
because you have your own understanding of
yourself.
It’s a very simple thing, but as she has
said it, nobody does it.
Tell your intelligence.
Even now I find that some people do have that
joy within them trickling in.
But you have to prosper into that.
You have to come into that.
Dropping out all that is nonsensical.
Otherwise you will go off like that.
And it takes hardly any time or hardly anything.
Whatever is done wrong, is done wrong, finished!
Just to be finished off because it’s dead
now, so why bother about it?
Just to finish off.
Because if I tell you something with a harsh
tone it will not stick on there.
If I do it delicately also it will not work
out, because, what I told you, there’s a
polish.
Take out the polish, and what is the polish?
The polish is the all understanding of norms,
the all understanding of norms of life.
Because you thought [that] if you were in
this condition you would be happy, that’s
why you are doing it.
Because you thought, if you do like this,
there is a fear this, the left-side problem.
But if this all understanding of the mind,
if you clear it out with your light, with
your own wisdom, then you’ll be amazed [that]
this thing will stick into you, completely.
This wisdom will stick into you.
Forget that old nonsense.
So many things you have already sorted out
yourself, you know, so many things which were
nonsensical before.
But the identification of all these ideas
should be achieved, should be achieved, is
the point.
You know that this is all nonsensical.
But is to be achieved.
That’s the preparation.
You have the light, you have the movement
now.
you are moving into it, but the light is not
here.
[It] dangles, sometimes falls like this, falls
like that.
If you can fix your light properly, just by
this understanding that whatever were the
norms before were due to ignorance and we
have to have our norms of our own now [regarding]
what is a Sahaja Yogi.
And these norms, I am going to tell you how
these norms are going to come to you like
faith, like entire dependence on spirituality,
entire dependence on your vibrations.
All these norms of the new life, we have to
accept.
But to be achieved, I mean to say to be achieved,
you see.
Not just to be understood in a lecture.
So I’ll tell you about that in the evening,
and tomorrow I will tell you [about] the real
becoming, alright?
Thank you.
May God bless you.
Shri Mataji: Just go on saying, now are you
opening?
Sahaja Yogi: (inaudible]
Shri Mataji: You do not want to assume your
position, that’s the problem.
Better?
This is what I am saying, you see.
It’s moving out.
Just say that, “Nothing can happen.
No bhoot can catch me.
I can catch the bhoots."
That’s the truth.
Douglas Fry: Lunch is served.
Shri Mataji: Hah?
Sahaja Yogini: Do you want to take your lunch
in here?
Shri Mataji: Or else?
Sahaja Yogini: In the dining room.
It’s very nice..
Shri Mataji: Nice or not, I will have it with
you people.