1984-0708 Public Program 3 at Ilford Town Hall. Ilford (England), To Know The Truth PP 3
Let’s have our realization now all of us, but I don’t promise as I said it’s your own lookout.
If you believe in our, according to Indian thing if you believe, according to our former karmas
according to our previous things that we get Atma Sakshatkar, because it’s the highest to have.
So let’s see what happens. And also My compassion, My love,
My desire that you all should get your realisation and establish it
and become powerful Sahaja yogis and understand it fully.
Now those who are here have to follow what I say,
is very simple method by which you help yourself. As I said you are your own guru
and on different chakras we have to work it out and it works.
So please take out your shoes for one reason, that the Mother Earth helps us
to sort of earth some of the problems that have come from the Mother Earth.
Now, you have to keep your eyes shut throughout, not to open your eyes.
The reasons are many but one of them is that the centre of Agnya,
which is placed between the pituitary and the pineal body, is a very important centre.
It is the gate and it doesn’t open if your eyes are open outside just now.
So please keep your eyes shut till then and maybe the kundalini may not also rise.
The whole attitude should be that I should get my realization. You’re not going to lose anything,
I don’t take any money, nothing of the kind, and there is nothing to gain out of it anyway.
So just you have to gain something out of it so, in a humble way,
you have to sit down and put your hands on your lap.
Those people who have come for the first time, or are standing there, can come forward here
and sit down and the Sahaja yogis should give them places.
Sahaja yogis should never take the first places, I would request, it would be a good idea.
All right, just try to sit on the side if possible, those who have come for the first time.
[ASIDE ABOUT A PARKED CAR]
Now, as I told you, you don’t have to do anything. It’s an effortless thing that happens,
it’s a happening, and the kundalini rises by itself.
Only put both your feet straight on the Mother Earth. Straight, as far as possible,
straight touching the Mother Earth. But those who are sitting on the ground are all right,
they can sit with [HINDI], on the ground is all right. [HINDI]
Now put your both the hands towards Me, as I told you, and close your eyes.
We have to have a proper attitude towards ourselves.
Firstly, it’s going to be the happiest thing that is going to happen to us,
and the highest thing that we have been asking for ages.
So we are not to be in any way under any tension about it, it’s really happening to all of us.
Sit with a very cheerful mind, not frivolous but cheerful mind.
And secondly you have to respect yourself.
If there is any guilt or anything in your mind, it won’t work out, as I told you.
You must know you’re saints, born to get self-realization.
You are, as described by William Blake, you are men of God, who have to become prophets,
who will have powers to make others prophets.
So, that is the attitude we should have towards ourselves, that’s how you are here today.
Please do not condemn yourself, do not have any guilt about yourself, nothing of the kind.
Just believe in yourself, that you are the Spirit.
Now, you have to keep both the hands on your lap (you can keep your purse down, lady, you can keep it, it’s all right).
Now put your both the hands towards Me, close your eyes fully.
Some of you must have already started feeling a little cool breeze in your hands.
Put both the hands like this, open upwards, just as like you do for [INAUDIBLE] or something.
The left side, as I told you the other day, is for your desire, and the right side is for action.
So we are going to put the left hand, all the time, as it is, desiring to be one with the Divine.
And the right hand we are going to use for the action of removing the obstacles in our centres.
So, first put the right hand on the heart, just on the heart, on the left hand side.
Here resides the Spirit in human beings, so, now you ask Me a question without opening your eyes.
You can call Me Mataji or Mother, as you like, whichever way you want to call Me.
“Mother, am I the Spirit?”
Ask the question thrice, you have a right to ask Me that question.
Now this right hand has to be taken down on the stomach, on the left hand side, on the upper part of the stomach.
This is the centre of your mastery, or what we call the guru centre, it is on the left hand side of your stomach.
On the left hand side you put this right hand. Put the left hand towards Me as it is.
Now, here you ask a question, because you, as a spirit, has to be your own master, has to be your own Guru.
So you ask Me a question thrice again, “Mother, am I my own Guru?” ask Me.
With full confidence, “Am I my own master?”
On the higher part of the stomach, please put your right hand on the higher part of the stomach.
Now, put this right hand on the left hand side of your stomach, in the lower region.
There’s a centre there, in the lower region of your stomach, lower region of your stomach.
On the left hand side, keeping the left hand towards Me.
Now, this is the centre where is the knowledge of the working of your kundalini.
In this centre, called as Shuddha Vidya, meaning the pure knowledge.
As this point, I’m sorry but you have to ask for it, I cannot force anyone into it,
like you cannot force a student to accept any knowledge.
In the same way you have to say “Mother, give me that pure knowledge” or you can say “Mother, please give me that Shuddha Vidya”,
you have to ask six times, because this centre has got six sub plexuses.
So you have to ask six times, in a very humble way, “Mother, please give me that Shuddha Vidya”.
That is the first asking.
See this prayer, this is such a pure prayer. Give me the Shuddha Vidya, give me the pure knowledge of the Divine, the working of the Divine.
Now, as you have entered into that realm of asking Me for the pure knowledge, the first thing you have to assume, is that [END OF TAPE].
H.H. Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi