Today we have decided to have Mahakali Puja.
Now we must understand the Mahakali is in
totality - is a reflection of Adi Shakti,
in totality.
Or we can call it that Adi Shakti is in charge,
She’s managing all these three powers, but
Her manifestation in totality is Mahakali
in the sense that it is the desire of God
Almighty.
So first She's Adi Shakti in charge of all
the three powers and that's why we can say
that when She is in a potential stage, She
is Mahakali.
And then She divides Herself into two other
forces as Mahasaraswati and the ascending
force that we call, or as a parasympathetic
nervous system expressed in us is the Mahalakshmi,
so She has actually all these forces in Herself.
Mahakali has all these forces but She manifests,
She desires to act and when She wants to act,
Her potential force becomes these two other
forces.
So when we do the Puja of Mahakali, we must
understand that inbuilt within this force
within us is desire, so we can desire anything.
If you want you can desire everything: we
can desire, say, the joy, we can desire the
knowledge, we can desire to be compassionate
and love and we can desire also the destruction
of those which are negative forces.
But the Mahakali force is the one which is
working out the constructive force, but in
that constructive force only there has to
be destruction, because if you are constructing
something and there is destruction, which
is trying to destroy your construction, then
you have to destroy that destructive person.
And this is what people sometimes misunderstand
and they think that Mahakali force is negative
force or is a force of destruction.
It is, but in a very positive way.
And if you understand this part of Mahakali
force then you’ll understand that if you
have desires to construct yourself properly
in Sahaja Yoga, then you should also have
the desire to destroy whatever is standing
against your construction.
So one by one, we should see within ourselves
what sort of things that tag us down and thus
they do not give us this desire.
If this desire becomes intense, then you start
immediately seeing what are the forces that
are destroying your ascent.
So we have to ascend is the point.
Our goal is to ascend, our destination is
to ascend, so our desire should be that we
should ascend and construct our being in such
a manner that we can receive all the…
Hindi aside
This one is better.
So we should understand that we have to be
prepared to destroy many things within us,
if we have to become great evolved personalities.
As you have seen in evolution itself: we had
huge big animals like mammoth, this, that,
and they could not cope with the evolution,
so they were all destroyed - so many things
were destroyed.
And this destruction is built in within us:
when we ascend we just start seeing that these
are the forces which we are destroying us
and that our destruction is so much that,
if we do not desire the destruction of these
destructive forces, we’ll be finished.
So at the same time when we are ascending
higher, we have to know what we have to destroy.
For example, even in living forces when a
flower becomes a fruit, lots of things which
were the part of the flower get destroyed,
automatically.
But that is done in the will of God by his
own understanding, so it's absolutely perfect.
So in Sahaja Yoga when we desire something,
we must know what do we desire, first fix
your goal and then relate it to that.
Now there are many deviations in life, like
you are going to the airport, our attention
should be ‘we have to reach the airport’
and whatever are distractions are distractions,
we should not get lost with it.
If you get lost with those distractions, then
we cannot achieve our goal in time.
So one has to understand first of all that
our goal is to ascend and for that the distructions
are on our way, because of ourselves, because
of ignorance, because of darkness, because
the light is not so much.
The first destroying factor that is within
us is the Shri Ganesha’s power and this
Shri Ganesha is the power of Mahakali.
She first planted Shri Ganesh to emit holiness
on this earth.
So the whole thing could be vibrated and as
you know one aspect of Shri Ganesh is also
Omkara, means this vibratory awareness which
flows everywhere.
So these vibrations have four sites in it:
one is that these vibrations establish holiness,
auspiciousness through Mahakali power, then
these same vibrations also comfort us through
Mahakali power, vibrations do not give you
desires as such, if you see, they do not give
you desires, but they give you proof of your
desires being fulfilled.
Supposing you want somebody to be cured, this
is your desire and you give vibrations to
that person, so it’s a means.
So it is also the action part which is there
in those vibrations, but this action also
comes from desire, if you don’t have desire
you won’t act.
So the desire is so important even to establish
your own path, to establish your forward march:
if your desire is poor, if you’re half-hearted,
you can’t work it out.
Half-hearted people cannot achieve anything
in Sahaja Yoga, it's not meant for half-hearted
people, it's meant for people who are brave,
who have intense desire, who are intelligent
and who are auspicious.
But in case you do not have intense desire,
then the pure desire doesn't work and you
do not get your Realization.
Also after getting Realization, unless and
until you have desire to ascend, very strong
intense desire to ascend, you cannot ascend.
So for all Sahaja Yogis it is necessary to,
first of all, early in the morning, while
taking the name of Ganesha, must say “What
is my desire, this is my goal.”
This is what it is, all activity must be surrendered
for this goal.
So now, how our desires are curbed?
First of all, through conditionings, we have
certain conditionings.
After Sahaja Yoga, people become very affectionate,
so immediately - even if in the west where
the family is not so important, children not
so important, selfishness is there, people
think about themselves only, they cannot think
of others - even in those countries, it starts
developing a kind of a, another cocoon of
‘my-ness’: my child, my house, my home,
my family.
Then the attention starts working on that,
you become half-hearted towards your ascent,
because you’re ascending in a way, so-called,
and also you are spreading out.
Then the concern goes to other conditionings
we have, like the other day I met one fellow,
he said that, “Mother, I am a Sahaja Yogi,
I know, but I can’t get over the idea of
Christ.”
I said, “Who has asked you to get over idea
of Christ?
Christ is there, in Sahaja Yoga very much,
but understand it in its own comprehensive
way and see for yourself.”
But this conditioning is of thoughts.
Supposing, if you have read too many books,
if you have gone through, supposing, you are
a born Hindu or a born Christian or a born
Jew or anything, so the conditioning is there.
You were born as a human being!
You got this stamp later on (Shri Mataji laughing)
that you are a Hindu or a Christian or anything.
This stamp you did not carry when you were
born.
Supposing, the child was lost, he could be
any religion.
So these are not really your innate religions,
this is just a stamp you have got, like Christian
or anything.
Then you have another conditioning that you
belong to this nation, that nation, like we
have, we have America, this, that, that, but
still these are stamps, you were born in America,
that's why you are an American.
Anybody who is born in America is not different
from anybody else.
Only thing according to the climate of a particular
place, you might have your complexion, your
height, your face and all that, but that doesn't
mean that innately this is meant for America,
it could be anywhere.
Then all this conditionings within us start
acting on our language, on our styles, on
our lives in every way, then we start becoming
Americans.
So these are the effects of the outside that
come in us and then we say “We, the Americans”,
but if you scratch them, inside body’s the
same, heart is the same, the blood is the
same - everything is the same, there’s nothing
different, it's even not skin deep, but in
the brain it has gone that ‘I am an American’.
Then all these things that are in that society,
for example, in America so many things are
allowed, so that's all right.
In India many things are allowed, that's all
right.
Like that we start accepting the society,
the norms of the society and the conditioning
starts.
But with all that this desire is there, the
pure desire to ascend.
Aside: I think, you put these lights little
ahead because they are so, paper there and
with My force, light is going behind.
No, no, not that one, please, because they
are facing that fan.
Could bring them down here.
Still quite close to that fan you know, you
can put them anywhere, you can put them here,
if you want.
You see, because the air is blowing that way
and they are all going that way.
So the desire within us to ascend comes to
us also as a reaction to all these things.
When we see, as Americans, what's happening
to our country, what's happening to the people,
what's happening to our surroundings and then
we get a shock, “Oh God!
What is this?”
Then we also see this is artificiality.
Like in England you have to wear a tail coat,
you have to wear this, you have to have this
kind of a spoon, this kind of a glass, this,
that, so reaction builds in.
So you start anti-culture, anti-culture to
get rid of artificiality, while the desire
behind is, is to seek the reality.
To seek reality, then they have hair just
like primitive people, they live like primitive
people and the reaction is built in.
Behind all that is the same desire, is to
ascend.
So this Mahalaxmi power is acting within us,
it is giving us all kinds of shows, we can
say, “All right, you want to have, say,
variety of things, go ahead with it.”
Then you go crazy, you see, “What's this
going on?
Why should we be so mad about it?
” Now they want to have -
you want to have say, your children, your
home, your houses, then you just get fed up
with it, because children become arrogant,
they become horrid, they trouble you, then
you say, “Oh God!
I'll never have any children any more.”
Then you have wives and you find wives horrible
and husbands horrible, then you divorce.
You go on divorcing, divorcing, divorcing
and then you find it's useless, it doesn't
work out, nothing seems to work out, you feel
so frustrated and that action and reaction
works on your desires, so your desires go
on changing.
Specially when we are wanting to be affluent,
people become affluent and then they find
the problems of affluence, so a reaction is
built in.
Those who witness those problems of the rich,
they don't want to be that rich, nothing doing.
So in every way the desire to achieve things
works out, like some people want to have power,
they go into politics, fight it, get it done
and done forever.
So, lives after lives it goes on, then you
are born in modern times, when I’m here
and now your only strong desire is to become
the Spirit, I hope it is.
So now all these back things are to be crossed
over, they are finished.
Now what should we do for our Realization,
what action we should take?
The first action is to develop your Mahakali
power: by one power you destroy all that is
nonsensical, destroy all that is impeding
you, troubling you, blocking you - destroy
all that, just I don't want it, because I’ve
seen Sahaja Yogis suddenly go off, like you
have to go to the airport, suddenly you find
they have fallen into one of the gutters,
“What happened?
“ “Mother, we felt like going there”,
but why?
So keep your attention on that point.
Some people get married - in Sahaja Yoga also
they have a desire to marry, have children,
this thing - but in that also they get fixed
up.
Marriage is not the end, it’s just one of
the means to be balanced.
So we have to have desire that we have to
achieve something, so go on destroying all
that is within us, within us is - there are
six enemies, as they say, is anger, then greed,
jealousies, violence, - all these are within
us, so we have to destroy these six enemies.
But what's the power of a Mahakali is that
She destroys all the enemies that stand in
your way, all the rakshasas, all the devils,
all the negative forces, She tries to destroy,
so that your part should be all right.
But while She is destroying all of them, if
you are sticking on to them, what can She
do?
So your desire should be pure and that you
should say that, “All right, we want to
achieve that“, and She is working it out
for you.
This is the first thing, Her job.
Then the second job is that She comforts,
She gives you comforts - of every kind.
The first comfort She gives you is of your
body: your body becomes comfortable, means
all your diseases and all your troubles are
destroyed, you find that your body becomes
healthy, you feel younger, you get energy
and you can work out your Realization - this
is the first thing She does for you, is to
give you comfort.
Then She also gives you comfort of the Spirit,
so that you do not ask for artificial comforts,
you can live anywhere - you can live in a
jungle, you are comfortable, if you live in
the most busiest place, you are comfortable
- so you are comfortable everywhere and that
sort of a comfort She can establish within
you.
Then the highest of all Her boon is that She
gives you they joy, joy of every kind, joy
that emits from everything, from everyone.
So that is the highest you get when you keep
your desire, the flame of your desire burning,
till you reach that state of spiritual attainment,
then you find that no more desire is left,
but only one, if it is any, that let the whole
world be realised.
Like a drunkard, you see, he wants to enjoy
his drinking with others, like that you become:
you are drunk in your joy and why not others
enjoy, so you work for it.
But human beings, I’ve seen, they move like
a yo-yo.
They achieve their spiritual attainment, they
have the joy and then they go back to help
people, they get caught up with them.
They are not strong enough, because the Mahakali
power is not strong.
And another is the weakness of the Mooladhara.
Weakness of the Mooladhara makes you imbalanced
and in that imbalance you lose your way.
So one has to be very careful that our Mooladhara
must be fixed properly.
There are so many ways by which you can fix
up your Mooladhara.
And you must fix up your Mooladhara first,
then your desire absolutely moves like a kite
moves in the sky.
Stuck to Mooladhara and you can move into
any direction to any height, wherever you
go, you are quite in charge, you know how
you are moving.
It can bind your attention, everything, so
what we say that the roots are very important
first to be established for the growth of
your desire upward like a tree.
So they go hand in hand - Mahakali power and
Ganesha's power - go hand in hand, because
that's the foundation.
If it is based on that foundation, desires
grow much stronger and stronger and effective
and they do not deviate.
Every sort of desire is fulfilled till you
reach that state where there's no other desire
left but to enjoy, you just enjoy, without
any desire, desirelessly you enjoy.
And that state is to be enjoyed, just to be
enjoyed.
What is there to talk about it, what is there
to say about it?
You just are lost in the ocean of enjoyment.
And that should happen everywhere and that's
what you are worshipping.
So now I hope you have 108 names of Mahakali,
and if you have the 108 of Mahakali, you will
see, one by one, that Her is stages of Her
working out for you, how manifest that you
can see in those names.
So now first we'll have a one Atharva Sheersha
and then we can have these 108 names.
Can we?
When he’s here, I’m happy to see you.
We did a Puja there also, Canada also did
it.
I think, it is very important to do Mahakali
power, because that's the first
power
that starts manifesting.