H.H. Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi
Press-Conference
London, England, July 8, 1999
I bow to all the seekers of truth.
First of all, it’s important to know what
the truth is.
You find so many people are seeking the truth,
but they don’t know what to find and that’s
how they are twisted around, taken to some
sort of a false rites.
It’s important first of all to know what
is the truth that we are seeking.
The truth is, if I tell you, it’s very simple:
that you are not this body, you are not this
mind, you are not this intellect, you are
not these emotions, but you are the pure Spirit.
That’s what you have to become – the pure
Spirit.
And another truth is that the power that leads
you to the state were you know the truth about
yourself, about everything is within you,
this power is within you, is your own.
Born with you, with every human being.
That’s surprising: if all the human beings
in the whole world have this power within
their triangular bone - how can we differentiate
them?
They are all just the same, everybody has
a power based in their triangular bone known
as sacrum, that means the Greeks knew it was
a sacred bone.
This fact that there is a power in the triangular
bone was known thousands of years back, I
should say, in India and in various countries.
I was surprised – even in Sweden I found,
Norway I found, people were talking about.
I don’t know how they came to know about.
Specially Moscow I found people who knew about
it.
“How do you know?”
I asked them.
They said: “Our forefathers told us”,
like that.
Specially with Indian Americans they are very,
very down-to-earth people, very natural people,
I think – they also knew about it.
And Africans also knew about it.
But they didn’t know how to raise it.
That was the only problem they had.
And though they knew about the centres, about
which just now you have been told, they didn’t
know how to enlighten them through this power
– can you imagine?
This knowledge became – sort of - a knowledge
which people would not accept, because we
live with science or rationality.
This is something beyond that, but Einstein
has said so, Einstein has said very clearly
- that there is a torsion area beyond the
mind.
And you have to go to that torsion area where
you can get cognitive science – called science,
but I would say, cognitive personality.
So, how is it going to happen to go beyond
the mind?
If you try anything it is through your mind
only.
Whatever you do is through your mind.
So to go beyond your mind is not possible.
Now this power lies in the triangular bone,
which we can see also clearly sometimes in
some people who have obstruction, where it
cannot rise.
You see the pulsation in the triangular bone
which is just a bone.
But when it rises it is a so smooth movement
of this power.
Now there are some people who have written
that this is a very dangerous thing and this
happens and that happens, maybe because they
can’t explain, maybe because they don’t
know anything about it perhaps, maybe they
do not want to know human beings to have it.
Now, this power is kept within us because
now our last breakthrough of our evolution
has to take place.
We have to rise to that state which you can
call self-realized or there is 1001 names
for it.
So many people had this power within them
- they felt it also but they were not so much
capable I think, of raising the Kundalini.
Sufis, you have heard about.
Saints, many saints – William Blake, I would
say, from England, there were so many people.
Shakespeare is another one.
They all were realized souls.
The way they have expressed themselves shows
very well how detached they were and how beautifully
they understood the reality.
So when this Kundalini rises as they have
been told, She passes through these six centres.
And these six centres are responsible for
our physical, mental, emotional and spiritual
being.
So, when these centres go into jeopardy, some
because of exhaustion, maybe something, then
it is needed to be nourished and this Kundalini
nourishes them.
Not only It nourishes but It also integrates
them.
So you get your personality in a state where
you are completely integrated.
But then She pierces through your fontanel
bone area.
This is the actualisation of baptism, you
can say.
Actually She pierces through and gets you
connected to the all pervading power of Divine
Love.
It’s all love, nothing else but love.
Truth is love and love is truth.
And when She becomes one with that you are
a transformed personality.
Firstly your centres are enlightened.
So your health improves, mentally you get
balanced and also emotionally you understand.
But the greatest thing that happens to you
is that you become a new personality with
collective consciousness.
Jung has talked about it – “collective
consciousness”.
That you can feel another person.
You can feel your own centres on your fingertips.
First you feel the cool breeze in your hand.
That is the cool breeze described in the bible
as “the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost”.
And also in Sanskrit language they call it
“Saleelam, Saleelam”.
In Koran it is described as “Ruh”.
Everywhere it is described with different
names, meaning the same.
You start feeling this cool breeze in your
hands, specially on your fingertips and these
fingertips denote your different chakras as
shown there.
So, if there is something wrong with your
centres, then it is indicated on your fingertips;
but if it is something wrong with others also
it is indicated because you become, - again
I say, it’s a question of becoming - you
become collectively conscious.
But with that you are not disturbed, you are
absolutely at peace with yourself and absolutely
satisfied.
How it happens that our mind is always thinking
about the future, about the past.
And our mind is dancing over the cusp of these
thoughts, which are like this.
But when this Kundalini rises She elongates
them and there is a space in between created
and that space is, what we can say, is the
present.
We can be in the future, we can be in the
past, but we cannot be in the present, and
when you are in the present you are absolutely
thoughtless.
You just become a witness.
A witness state comes into you and you start
watching everything, not reacting.
And absorbing everything, very easy.
It’s a very wonderful thing that happens
to you.
So this mechanism is placed within you to
give you that special personality, to give
you that new awareness of collective consciousness,
and the last breakthrough of your evolution.
Till human awareness you are alright, till
that I must say they still are there somehow.
But we are afraid of the future of human beings,
because such a turmoil, so many problems,
so many kinds of ideas people have, which
is surprising that in these modern times what
people are thinking: they are something absolutely
primitive, I should say, criminal.
Violence and things, all this has to disappear.
And I was happy to hear that you all want
transformation, the resurrection.
You want transformation, and transformation
on a collective scale.
This is quite possible, absolutely possible.
Once you are transformed, you become a person
of tremendous love and patience.
You love everything.
You understand everything through love.
It’s not love of – some sort of a – expectations,
it’s a love of giving.
You just enjoy giving, giving everything is
so enjoyable that time, that state and you
become so peaceful.
Then, as you know, the economics is like that,
people will work very hard to have, say, a
carpet like this and then this is all done,
then they will have some motorcar, then they
want to have a house, I mean, goes on from
one to another, they are never satisfied.
The thing for which you have worked so hard
is finished.
Then again starts a new urge to have something
new.
Goes on like that, the whole economics work
like that.
But here, once I see this carpet, for example
here, I just go into thoughtless awareness.
And what do I see?
I see the joy, I feel the joy of the person,
of the artist, who makes and enjoy this.
Otherwise thinking, I would think how much
it must have cost, where can I buy this, or
if it is mine I would be worried, Oh God,
how I’ve not insured this, which has no
meaning.
But I cannot enjoy unless and until I become
thoughtlessly aware.
Also in our Patanjali Yoga it is written down
as Nirvichara Samadhi.
But he has made four stages of the whole thing
is that first is this “Sarvichar”.
Sarvichar means “with thoughts” and then
without thoughts, but in Sahaja Yoga it is
not so.
It is so quick that you become thoughtlessly
aware first, and then you become doubtlessly
aware.
That is there are no doubts about yourself.
You know there is a power flowing and you
know by experiment that this power, this power
can cure people, can help others.
And the attention, which is very high.
Like I found people say “I like this, I
want this” - that disappears.
Attention goes to others.
You want to see what others would like, others
would feel, and the whole personality gets
completely enshrined with the feeling of oneness
with others.
It’s something has to happen to all of you.
I’m happy I lived in England at least for
20 or 22 years and couldn’t meet you people.
But now, thank God, you people have thought
of it.
Now we live with science and rationality.
This is something beyond that, as I told you.
It is beyond science and rationality which
is accepted as cognitive science, people say.
And also as I’ve told you Einstein has talked
about the torsion area.
But how to achieve it, I don’t think he
has written anything about it.
So this is your own power within yourself
for which I don’t have to do anything – they
might have said it, alright.
I accept it.
But once it rises in you, it’s like one
candle can enlighten many candles.
And that’s how you can spread Sahaja Yoga
very far.
We have, say, they say so, we are now in 72
countries, possibly.
Because one person gets it, he goes to his
country, starts working.
And India, of course, Indians know this very
well, they know they have to achieve only
this.
Like some people told me that we are like
Indian culture.
So, we have taken to Indian style of life
and we are very satisfied.
I said “Is that the end?”
We have so many Indians who are following
that culture.
Are they satisfied people?
Is that the end?
What have you to do according to Indian scriptures
also - that you have to know yourself.
You don’t know yourself.
You don’t know what’s wrong with you,
unless and until you can feel your centres
on your fingertips.
You will not know what’s wrong with you
– till you end up with something horrible.
But as soon as you get your Realisation, immediately
you can feel it on your fingertips - your
problems.
Now, supposing you know how to cure it, you
can cure anybody’s and you don’t have
to pay for it.
See, again and again I’ve said that “it
is your own, it’s your power.
You can’t pay for it.”
I don’t know how people believe that for
spirituality you can pay, it cannot be sold.
In America it was very difficult.
They all came to me and told me: “You have
to sell it”.
I said: “How?”
They said: “Do something, otherwise nobody
will come to you.”
I said: “But I cannot do something that
is not done.”
So they said: “Alright, you do one thing:
take money from them and tell them that when
you come for follow-up you will get back your
money.”
So much we are bound by money that if you
have paid the money you think you are bound.
You have to do it.
And absurd things like that human beings think.
But why don’t they think that we have to
change this world?
They have to have emancipation of human being.
Why now?
Instead of doing all kinds of other things,
the best thing is to change yourself, transform
yourself and enjoy.
And enjoyment is complete.
Because enjoyment is singular.
It is not happiness, unhappiness, it’s just
enjoyment.
You enjoy everything.
Even the smallest thing can give you enjoyment.
And then you don’t start feeling depressed
or doing that kind of a tantrums that you
do to trouble others, but you are so much
enjoying and everybody enjoys you also, because
you are so enjoyable.
That’s the thing that should happen to human
beings and when it happens it’s something
really very, very great and that should happen
to all of you.
And I’ll be very happy, I was told you are
all very great dignitaries here and you can
do a lot and this is how we have a chance
of first of all getting your Self Realisation.
Knowing your Self.
And then helping people.
With a genuine love and affection.
I don’t know how much I should talk because
we’ve had so many lectures after lectures
and there’s no end to it.
But lecturing doesn’t help – it is something
else to work out within yourself.
That is the most important thing.
Now, I would like also to have some questions
from you.
If you have gone thoughtless I can’t help
it.
Question: Have you overcome all the fears
of life?
You are not afraid of death also?
Shri Mataji: I don’t know that part, but
definitely I knew that I have to find out
a way and method by which I could give en-masse
realisation.
Because people used to give realisation, no
doubt, but one person used to give to one
person.
One of the reasons maybe because anybody who
was saintly, people used to torture them,
trouble them.
They wouldn’t like a person like that because
that person was something – out of the blue,
you can call it.
So that was an attitude towards a person who
was a realised soul.
Everybody suffered, whether they were Sufis
or they were – otherwise even William Blake,
I mean, everyone whosoever said something
different, people didn’t like.
So maybe that’s the reason they used to
give it to one person.
That was the tradition.
Realisation was such that out of thousands
they used to select one person, work on him,
cleanse him, do this, do that and then give
realisation.
One person.
But I felt that the time has come that you
must give en-masse realisation.
Unless and until people get en-masse realisation,
we cannot change this world.
And I worked, I should say, for days together.
Luckily my father was a very social personality,
even my husband was.
So I had a good chance to meet people.
In my own subtle ways I used to find out what
is the permutation and combination of problems
inside the human beings and then how to work
it out.
That’s the only thing I did more, I think,
otherwise so many people used to give Self
Realisation at different times.
But what I found out a method by which thousands
of people can get realisation.
Question: How did you come upon this method?
Shri Mataji: Just, you see, I discovered it.
You see, it’s a thing I worked it out.
Have all gone thoughtless, or what?
Yes, madam?
Question: When you depart from this body,
as this lady was asking, where does the spirit,
where do the energy stay?
Shri Mataji: Spirit – it’s a very long
answer, but I would say, Spirit goes according
to its desire, alright.
Now, supposing there is a drunkard, who dies,
now he wants to drink still, even if he’s
dead.
He will hang in somewhere in the limbo, I
think, he will get hold of somebody who drinks
a lot.
This side of psychology, people don’t understand
in the west.
Because it’s nothing in the medicine about
this.
The other day I read a very nice article about
it, was published in America.
That Japanese believe that you get possessed
by a spirit.
Even in the bible it is so that you get possessed
by the spirit.
But they have said that 50 to 60% people get
possessed.
Schizophrenia, all kinds of psychological
problems come from that.
Now, in India also we believe in it.
And if you can remove the possession of a
person the person completely changes, no doubt.
But this is still in the realm of science,
you cannot get it.
I mean, I would say that, psychology is still
a childish science and in that realm they
don’t understand what is this possession.
Is a fact that so far they have not gone into
it, but we know in Sahaja Yoga very clearly,
because we get catches on the left hand side,
say here on this thumb, that means a person
is possessed.
Yes, it’s like that, it’s so simple.
And then you can cure that person.
So many persons have been cured.
So many.
Who have given up as lunatics, or schizophrenic
or all kinds have been cured, no doubt.
But it is to be seen and to be worked out,
then you can believe it.
Because people don’t believe that there
is such a thing.
But there is.
There is some sort of a negative force which
overpowers human beings, it is true.
I must tell you the truth.
We have had so many cases, even in England,
where people were possessed.
So many cases.
On the contrary I would say that cancer and
all psychosomatic troubles come to people
when they shift to the left side.
Means to the past.
Maybe some viruses which are dead long time
back are in our being – that everything
is past is in our being.
So they can attack.
And I’ve told them long time back somehow
through this cognitive knowledge that they
will call by 53 proteins and 63 progenides
[ ? UNCLEAR] I told them.
And now they know it is so.
So cancer is curable in Sahaja Yoga, we have
cured cancers, of many people.
Absolutely curable.
We have an hospital in India, already established
near Bombay.
There’s a nice hospital where people are
cured.
And we don’t charge them for any treatment,
only for the stay.
It’s a fact, you see, because people never
talk about it, they never told you.
So you think it’s a, some sort of a mythological
thing, it’s not.
It is there, it exists.
So many diseases are not cured because we
don’t know about them.
You see, I was myself in a medical school,
so I know that they know very limited things.
Beyond that, they don’t know.
But in Japan, I was surprised that they believe
in it and they treat people.
Even in India, I mean, they know.
Question: What do you give, provide the definition
of enlightenment?
Shri Mataji: Enlightened means a personality,
enlightened personality, I can tell you, is
a person who is beyond his mind.
And he is in contact completely with this
all-pervading power of divine love.
As a result everything in that person is guided,
helped by that divine love.
That power is so great that it looks after
you, it organizes everything, it thinks, it
understands, it is wisdom of all the things.
You become a person who is so collectively
conscious.
Today we need people like that.
Otherwise you always think about yourself.
About others you can only think when you are
collectively conscious.
But these days there are so many people marketing
their spirituality, you see.
That’s also there.
And just people jump to it, I don’t know
why.
Why don’t they find out what is the gain,
what did you gain out of it?
Nobody wants to know.
Question: How did you find America?
Shri Mataji: They are antipodes.
I don’t know what to say, they are very
money-oriented, extremely money-oriented.
And they can’t understand me because I’m
not asking for money, you see, they can’t
understand.
It’s very difficult.
And how to penetrate that veil of theirs?
So, this time it has been much better, I should
say, I’ve been there.
I went first, long time back, 1973 I went
there, and I saw the people how mad they were.
After one boy was a 16 years old guru, you
see.
They just giving money to him.
So, I asked him “Why they are giving money?”
What is the need to give money like this?
To this guru?
They said: “Because he is giving us spirit.”
Where is he giving you spirit?
And then this fellow, he was wiser than others
I should say, because he settled down as a
young one, he married some American lady and
used his money, but all the rest of them,
so many of them, went there to befool them.
It’s endless.
Still going on.
But unless and until you accept the truth,
you cannot change.
Accept us in the sense you have to ask for
it.
You should have pure desire.
This Kundalini is the power of pure desire
within you.
When She rises She gives you your pure desire.
Not like this, changing from one to another.
And if you have pure desire only then it works
out.
If you don’t have, it won’t work out - no.
I cannot force it.
Cannot be forced, you see.
Question: How are children, young children?
Shri Mataji: Oh, some of them are great.
These days so many realised souls have been
born, these state [or these days?
UNCLEAR] . We don’t understand them.
But there are so many, even in England there
are born so many of them.
Born realized – they are special ones.
I mean, this fact, it happens, so many good
things happen to the society, like drug addiction,
over night people in this England gave up
drugs, over night.
I’ve got one land far away from madding
crowd, I should say, in upstate New York,
and I wanted to start a curative centre for
drug addicts, because that is one of the big
problems here.
But they said the public won’t allow.
I said: “Why?”
They said: “They go amok.”
This place is so far fetched, you cannot give
a walk all the way – and if, I mean, they
allow me I could help a lot.
But somehow, even in Italy, is difficult.
And the biggest problem today, even in America,
is drug addiction.
Another you can call AIDS.
We tried AIDS also, but AIDS-people are something
wrong with them, they are extremely arrogant.
Quarrelsome, arrogant, they think they are
martyrs - something like that.
We’ve tried, we’ve helped one or two – no
doubt.
But it’s very difficult.
But these drug addicts can’t be helped very
easily.
But there is no proper way, if you all can
arrange something - I would like to.
In your, this London city only, I should say,
at least 10 or 11 people like that.
First time I talked they’ve got cured.
They were all doing very well, were very well
educated.
All these problems can be solved.
But the government should help, in a way.
Because you know they, so much time even to
take permission for something.
Sometimes like 10 years, 20 years, you go
on applying.
I am already very old and I don’t know what
will happen, if I go on like this.
For 20 years for a permission.
Very difficult.
But you people can organize something like
that.
And I can work it out.
You can see the results.
You can see the results, you can save these
children.
Alcoholism, alcoholism also can be corrected.
Yes, please?
Question: Shri Mataji, would you say a few
words about the golden age?
The forthcoming golden age?
Shri Mataji: You see, Aquarius, as they say,
Aquarius according to our astrology is the
Kundalini.
The Kundalini is Aquarius according to Indian,
I should say, Indian science of (HINDI word
– Sir C.P. explains:)
Astrology.
And, you see, they, what they say that this
age of Aquarius is very important, because
this will change the lives of people.
And that is what they have already described
about this, that now there was Kali Yuga,
means the worst possible times.
The whole Kali Yuga means the absolutely the
worst and worst possible time for our destruction.
That was over.
Then comes Kruta Yuga, I mean, overlapping.
Now, in Kruta Yuga, this all-pervading power,
they call it Paramchaitanya, becomes active.
It starts helping people to come along.
That also has been going on some days.
After this, is Satya Yuga.
It’s the age of truth.
But it’s a last judgement.
If you take to truth, alright, well and good.
But if you don’t take to truth you are judged.
It’s like this.
Now how many people take to truth, very surprising.
Like a place like Russia, you’ll be amazed
- Russia.
Country like Russia.
I went there and I first time went to Saint
Petersburg, that’s Leningrad that time.
And when I went to the hall I saw about 2000
people sitting outside.
Because there you have to pay for a hall,
I mean, the hall people.
So, 2000 seats were all occupied inside.
So these people outside, people said: “Maa,
are you not going to give us realisation?”
I said: “How do they know all this?”
Somebody must have told them.
When I went in I said: “Alright, wait, I’ll
come back then I’ll give you Realisation.”
So, I went inside.
Inside there were 2000 people nicely sitting
down, listening to me and then they got their
realisation.
All of them.
I was amazed.
What’s the matter?
How is it they’re working so fast?
And then I came out and I saw there were again
these 2000 still sitting there.
45 minutes they were still.
I said: “Alright, you all come tomorrow
morning, we’ll sit outside.”
Now, in Moscow they have huge big places,
huge big compounds and buildings.
I said: “I’ll sit on the steps and I’ll
try to give you realisation.”
You won’t believe – 2000 from inside,
2000 from outside and one thousand extra,
I mean, 5000 people gathered there next morning
and they all got their realisation.
In Moscow, you won’t believe how many people,
if somebody asks me, I cannot say, have got
realisation.
Now, the reason, I reasoned it out what must
be the reason.
I asked them: “How is it?
Had you advertised that much?”
“No”, they said, “we saw your photograph.
We knew.
We came.”
So sensitive, I say.
And thousands and thousands have got realisation.
These people are so deep, so deep, so humble.
I couldn’t understand why, why are they
so much spiritually endowed, how did they
get all this.
And what I found is that communism has given
them no freedom of any kind.
And as a result, I think, they got completely
oppressed and the whole thing growth was inside.
And also if you have read those great novelist,
even Tolstoi, or anyone - they always show
introspection, even by the hero or by the
villain, anybody, they all introspect.
And this is the one, I thought, is the very
deep personalities they develop.
And immediately they got it.
A far fetched place called Togliatti where
they make motorcars, thousands and thousands
– we could not get to any hall, because
formerly, I mean, normally what was the thing
we were taken, we would have to take a stadium
– 18 to 20.000 in Moscow or Leningrad or
a big city.
But in Togliatti we didn’t know what to
do.
So we just had it in the open.
Thousands and thousands.
But not in England – no.
Much worse is America.
I don’t know why.
Even Indians in England are no good.
I just don’t know what happens to them.
They are neither English nor Indian, I think,
something is, but we have very few Indians
even, I must tell you this, very frankly.
But in India we have so many, so thousands
and thousands who have got realisation.
Though Indians know they have to have self
realisation, even here.
But somehow they are fed up, I don’t know
of what.
Even if you read Shakespeare you feel like
understanding that he was a great realised
soul.
What he showed was the futility of human endeavour
in every line, it’s clearly shown.
That’s what he was.
I can’t understand, see, because I’ve
read so much Indian novels and English novels
and English writers.
I find all of them are so enlightened.
Can’t understand what’s happening in England
now.
Why?
Now, 20 years I’ve been in England, first
time I’m meeting people like you.
Why?
I would ask you, people.
Really, I can’t understand.
Even Austria, you have thousands.
Italy, where Roman Catholics you know, are
so many.
Italians, wonderful.
Thousands.
But I didn’t live so long there as I‘ve
lived in England.
Moreover, you see, language-wise, I know this
language, though I never studied English,
but I know English language, how to speak.
But there in their language, it’s Italian
or, I don’t know how.
I’m very happy today that you all have come
and I hope now from you it will start going
into other people.
Because it’s very important: we have to
change this world.
And, I would say, they also said, some newspaper
people have come, but I said: “I’m sorry,
I don’t know what they will think of me.”
Because they have never been very supportive.
But I think they don’t realise their responsibility.
Really!
Sometimes I see newspapers, I think they don’t
realise how much they are harming people by
wrong directions.
By sensational things.
What they have to do is to see what will be
the effect of these things that we are writing.
Is it going to help them to rise above all
these things like jealousies and violence
and all these things that are really completely
corroding our humanity.
So, I think, all those lines, I don’t find
them and by head, I would say, I’ve met
some of them, they were just after me.
“How is it you are in England?”
I said: “Because my husband has a job here,
that’s how I’ve come.”
Then all kinds of funny, funny questions they
were asking.
You know, I was surprised, they are not interested
in spirituality at all.
So, then, whenever they said “Mother, somebody
is coming from there” I said: “Now - please.”
All kinds of things they would say.
“Your country is so poor, what are you doing
here?”
Then I had to tell them why we are poor.
I said: “300 years if you have a guest in
your house without a visa what will happen
to you?”
Then another question: “Why you have got
so many, such a big population, so many children
born?”
I said: “In that also, I would say, that
what I have read about England is this, that
so many children are killed every week, by
the parents even.”
I said: “So, the children must be deciding
to be born in a poor country than in a country
where they can be killed.”
I mean, simple thing like that.
Because children want love, they don’t understand
anything else.
So like that they asked me funny, funny questions.
I said: “I am here for spirituality, talking
to about spirituality, and why should I worry
about what I am, what is this and what is
that?”
Say, we have to change our attitude.
Very important.
Of course I know some people who are very
broad, broad minded attitude towards people,
very much.
I’ve known some in India also, but there
are so few.
If this thing has to be done it has to be
mass-scale.
Now, we have Sahaja Yogis, many Sahaja Yogis,
I should say, but still I’m not satisfied.
I think we need many more.
Hindustani…
HINDI…
I don’t know why.
Such a big tradition you have in our country.
Instead of bringing that here to this country,
I don’t know what’s happening.
And they are also very, very spiritual people.
There too, you read their books you see, you’ll
be amazed.
Very spiritual.
But suddenly the whole thing has turned round,
I think so that spirituality has lost its
power.
And maybe some, you imported some of the horrible
gurus from there also might be.
That might be another reason, I think so.
But now, I think, they are very much reduced
in number, there are few still going round,
making money, doesn’t matter.
But now you people are very sensible, very
highly placed, you should do something about
it, my request is.
I’m available and never used to say, whatever
you say.
It’s a new mission where you have to do
something.
You are the ones who are going to completely
revolutionize the whole world.
You can do it.
Absolutely everybody is capable of doing that.
Question: Another question: What’s your
opinion of Avataras?
Shri Mataji: Alright, what’s the use of
my opinion about it?
There are Avataras, no doubt.
Alright?
But you don’t believe me when I say that.
Unless and until you experience you shouldn’t
believe even me.
Alright, this is something and because you
asked me I’m saying so.
But I don’t say you believe in some Avataras,
first of all you experience them.
Everything that is now – you will know gradually
into different things and on every centre
there is somebody sitting there.
Who are they and what work they do?
All this is to be consumed and to be seen
and to be experimented.
Now, I say, supposing this centre is catching
…. [UNCLEAR] it is the centre very important
because it is in the optic chiasma like this,
you see, it’s constricted.
Now, how to open this?
Very difficult.
Now, I say, you forgive everybody.
You forgive everybody – it opens.
Why?
Because Christ, Christ is on that centre.
And his message is to forgive.
Is, I mean, you should know who is on which
centre and what works out.
That’s only to be known.
Once you get your Self Realisation, only you
have to know this much, who is the one responsible
for which chakras.
That’s all.
And you, you have to do according to – like
it’s a mantra now, to say that “I forgive
everyone”.
Now, some people would say it’s very difficult
to forgive.
But logically: if you forgive or don’t forgive
– what are you doing?
You don’t do anything.
But if you don’t forgive then you torture
yourself.
That’s why you forgive everyone.
And this opens.
Most constricted – it opens like this.
Question: So, which God is for the Kundalini?
Christ is over here.
Which God is in the Kundalini?
In the triangle?
Sahaja Yogi: What is the God or the deity
in the triangular bone, the Kundalini?
Shri Mataji: Kundalini itself.
The Kundalini is your own mother.
Your individual mother.
And She has tape-recorded all your past and
your aspirations, everything.
And She rises because She wants to give you
your second birth, but She is your individual
mother.
You don’t share Her with anybody else.
Yours is a different, somebody else’s is
different.
Because the tape-recording is different.
And She knows everything about you.
So, when She rises She does, goes very slowly,
without harming you, without troubling you
and pierces through.
We say She is the reflection of the Adi Shakti
who is called as Holy Ghost in the bible.
But She rises without any difficulty.
Hardly any time it takes.
Would they like to have their Self Realisation?
Sahaja Yogi: Shri Mataji asks if you would
like to experience this and have your Self
Realisation?
Very quick, very easy.
Shri Mataji: Hardly any time.
Now, you forget the past.
Another thing you have to do is to forgive
yourself.
And not to feel guilty about anything.
Very important, because if you feel guilty
then this centre catches here on the left.
When it catches here on the left you can get
spondylitis, you can also get angina.
So why, why to feel guilty?
Whatever has happened has happened, forget
everything.
Not to feel guilty – very important.
I know here people feel more guilty, not in
India.
They never feel guilty.
But in the west they do.
But there’s no need, no need to condemn
yourself, you have to have great honour and
love for yourself, because you are special
people and that you are going to help the
whole world.
So respect yourself!
As I respect you and love you.
You, please, respect and love yourself.
Alright.
Now, what you have to do is to put both the
hands towards me, like this, just like this,
because I told you these are the endings of
the sympathetic nervous system.
It’s like this – little open, like this.
You don’t have to doubt yourself, by any
chance.
Please, don’t doubt.
Now, you put your left hand like this towards
me and right hand on top of your head here.
On top, means away, not touching the head.
You can bend your head and see for yourself.
Now see, if there is a cool or a hot breeze
coming out of your fontanel bone area which
was a soft bone in your childhood.
Just see for yourself, if there’s a hot
or a cool breeze-like vibrations coming out
of your fontanel bone area which was the soft
bone in your childhood.
Now, you can move your hand and see for yourself.
You can move it, sometimes you can feel it
higher, sometimes lower or on the sides.
See for yourself.
If it is hot that means, of course, you have
got your Realisation, but if it is hot that
means you have not forgiven yourself.
Or you have not forgiven others.
So, please forgive others, also forgive yourself
fully.
Please forgive.
Now, please put your right hand towards me,
bend your head.
And see for yourself if you have cool or hot
breeze-like vibrations coming out of your
fontanel bone area which was the soft bone
in your childhood.
Please try.
Please bend your head and see for yourself.
Now, please take down your hands, both hands
and put them towards me, like this.
And don’t think.
Just don’t think.
Because I already told you, you have a right,
it’s your birthright to have this Yoga,
union with the divine, it’s your birthright.
Now, you have to put both your hands towards
the sky like this and push back your head
and ask me – I’ll tell you about three,
three things, three questions you can say.
You have to say one question three times,
only one of them.
For example you can ask, you can call me Mother,
Mother – or Shri Mataji, whatever you like.
Mother is, is this the cool breeze of the
Holy Ghost?
Ask in your heart this question “Mother
is this the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost?”
Ask three times.
Or, you can ask “Mother, is this the all-pervading
power of divine love?”
Or you can ask third question “Mother, is
this the Paramachaitanya or Ruh?”
Ask anyone of these questions, anyone of them,
three times.
Now - let’s have it.
Alright, please put down your hands again
and put them towards me.
Please, don’t doubt, please don’t doubt.
That’s something very important.
If you start feeling a cool or a hot breeze
on your fingertips or on your palm, same or
out of your fontanel bone area, out of your
head, anyone of them, then raise your both
the hands, raise your both the hands – those
who have felt it that way.
Those who have felt the cool breeze in their
hands.
Thank you very much!
Most of you have got it.
Unbelievable…
You got it?
No – not yet?
Alright.
Who didn’t get it now?
She also.
You didn’t get it, madam?
You got it?
They can help you, let us see.
You felt the cool breeze?
Now – you felt it.
Keep it like that.
Let it flow as much as possible, is very good.
You all can do this, it’s very simple.
She has it now?
Sahaja Yogi: It’s warm, Mother, it’s warm.
Shri Mataji: It’s warm?
Alright, put her left to the right.
Raise her left.
What’s she catching on?
Sahaja Yogi: It’s left Vishuddhi, Shri Mataji.
Shri Mataji: Left….
Are you Bengali?
Seeker: I am from the Caribbean.
Shri Mataji: Now you just don’t think.
That’s what you should practice a little
bit.
Put your hands towards me, all of you and
don’t think.
What is it?
Did you feel the Kundalini?
Are you feeling it on the head?
Warm, so that’s it – put her left to the
right.
Raise her left and put down the right.
It has nothing to do with the air-condition.
You feel it on your fingers – alright?
Now better?
Now alright?
May God bless you!
Just keep go on like that.
Alright?
Are you feeling?
Cool or hot?
Cool now?
Now she’s got it.
So, thank you very much!
Thank you, all of you!
May God bless you! (quietly)
You have to practice now.
Can you not tell them to come to some follow-up
or some program like that?