Shri Chakra and Shri Lalita Puja
Brahmapuri, India
17th December, 1990
The knowledge about Kundalini has been expressed
in many Sanskrit shastras since long, and
also in Ayurveda it is described; not only
that, but the books which are for curriculum
talk about Kundalini and the chakras, because
Ayurveda is very, very close to Sahaja Yoga.
Even in the Western medicine to begin with,
if you see the history, they too dealt with
three doshas, they dealt with three problems
that we have, as in Ayurveda: the right side
which has got pitta, means “bile”; left
side which has got kaph, means “phlegm”;
and the central path, the problems of vayu,
means the “gases.” Now luckily so many
Western people have taken to Sahaja Yoga,
and have tried to bring down all the permutations
and combinations to the simple reasoning of
left, right and center.
But the knowledge of Sahaja Yoga is absolutely
basics. Even Ayurveda is one step away from
reality, or which you can say, the fundamentals.
So you are dealing with the fundamentals of
which a human being is built; and if this
knowledge was found out long time back in
India, should we not accept it? The reason
why people went into meditation in those days
and found out all these deeper things within
ourselves, because they didn’t have to fight
the nature. You have seen here nature, how
beautiful it is. You can spend all your life
under a tree, while in the West even before
getting out of the house, you have to take
at least fifteen to twenty minutes to be prepared
to go out, it’s quite a struggle! So the
nature has been so kind, and that is the reason
people took to meditation and found out all
these deeper things within themself.
When they found it out, it was all written
in Sanskrit language. I have such a big thick
book on this, which has described all the
shakti peethas and all the Shri Chakras: Brahma
Chakra, Lalita Chakras and all that. But this
was just written down, but hardly any person
got Realization. But in any other language
like Marathi or Hindi which was spoken and
written by common people, nothing was done.
Nobody knew about it. Only a few people who
read about it, specially the Shaivas, they
went into the research and they went into
the work. But very few people really got Realization,
very, very few. Then in the twelfth century
only the Nath Panthis who were experts of
Sanskrit, who were following it rigidly, that
one master should have one disciple, not more
than that: this was their tradition. But in
the twelfth century Gyanadeva, Gyaneshwara
who was another Nath Panthi – his guru was
his own brother – he asked the permission
from his brother that “Please allow me to
say all these things openly; at least to say,
in Marathi language. Because the common people
don’t know anything about this knowledge.”
So he allowed him, and he wrote the sixth
chapter of “Gyaneshwari,” in which he
described Kundalini. But it was in the twelfth
century.
After that many saints described, talked about
him. Where we went yesterday to Satara, you
know that’s the place where Shri Ramdasa
lived, he said that Kundalini - they asked,
somebody asked, “How much time does it take
to raise the Kundalini?”
He said, “Tattchada,” means “that moment.”
But the person who wants to take it should
be deserving, and the one who wants to give
should be capable. It’s a big condition.
This is such a big “if,” capital “IF,”
I tell you. As a result very, very few people
got their Realization, and those who were
born as realized souls found it impossible
to talk to people.
Gyaneshwara, such a enlightened soul himself,
wrote one beautiful book called “Amritanubhava,”
which I will try to translate, which is very
joy-giving. To Me at least it’s very great
joy-giving. He went so deep into the understanding
of this joy. I wish English language would
provide Me that subtlety to translate that
book. That he wrote all these things when
he was only twenty-three years of age, and
at the age of twenty-three years he got so
fed up that he took a living samadhi. That
is, he entered into a cave and killed himself.
They all tortured him very much. Nowadays
this antahsadha stupid thing is not tortured
as much, but all these saints in this country
or any country have been very much tortured.
And there was no police protection, there
was no-one to publish about what these people
are up to.
Despite all that, I find there are many Sahaja
Yogis who are now occupying very big positions
in the government, and a day may come when
everything will explode. The biggest problem
of our country is something you cannot understand,
because you don’t have this problem there.
The amount of corruption we have from A to
Z, for everything, that you cannot understand.
I mean, I have never known any country where
they have to such an extent. Even, say, in
Philippines it was only one person who was
doing it. Here, every person has to get the
money, and has to pay the money to hire johnnies.
For this also, unless and until you get to
Sahaja Yoga, it won’t work out. And Sahaja
Yoga can only be worked out if people understand
that it is their heritage, and that they have
the capacity to understand Sahaja Yoga and
capability to spread it.
In North India it is much better, though the
vibrations in Maharashtra are much better,
it’s something funny. Vibrations in Maharashtra
is very good. The people in the North India
are very good Sahaja Yogis, and they are many,
many, many in number. We can’t say, even
in Bombay we get about twelve thousand people
for My programs. But still, the way it is
spreading in the North India is very surprising.
Also it is spreading - this is Satara, because
it was blessed by Ramdasa, this district.
I think everywhere there is a flower there
has to be thorns, and this district has got
some really very bad culprits. Ahmadnagar
is much better. Aurangabad, we are doing much
better, it will work out in Aurangabad much
better. And then if you go to the other side,
Bela, from where I come, it’s going to work
out very fast, things are moving very fast
there. I was amazed. So many people have told
Me that in Amravati so many are Sahaja Yogis.
In Akola so many are there, and I was surprised:
I have never been. So that is how it is spreading
in Maharashtra. So your song of “Maharashtra
Desha” is working out, it’s not failing!
But I think Satara is the most difficult place.
Where we worked out yesterday, I gave them
left and right as to what they are. It has
helped them a lot, because those who came
to oppose sat down and got their Realization.
So they are misleading people to start some
sort of a new culture, like you started hippieism,
and they are collecting young people. The
young people are leaving their schools. Some
parents came and complained to Me about it.
They are not paying attention to their studies,
they are failing in their classes, and these
people are stupidly using them.
I asked some of the boys, “What is your
policy?”
He said, “We have no policy.”
“Then what is your aim?”
“We have no aim.”
“Then why are you doing this nonsense?”
They said, “Because whatever the elders
tell us, we do it.”
I said, “Have you no personality, nothing?”
This exactly happened when this hippie movement
started. Some so-called intellectuals started
this horrible hippie movement in the West,
and when they found they cannot do anything
about it, they found it’s going to fail:
so many children lost their education, so
many children I know became pregnant, girls,
and boys started squatting. All that took
them to the extreme that they became violent.
But unless and until there is a change within
yourself, how can you change anything outside?
You cannot. And the first seven people I fought
were all hippies, very difficult. They called
themselves hippies, but they used to hog like
a pig. They wanted all the comforts, everything
free, extremely dominating and quarrelsome
people. But the foundation was laid on them.
It’s very surprising! But I had to work
on them for at least four years, regularly.
So that is how Sahaja Yoga started, and today
you know how much it has spread, how far it
has gone. Only in Maharashtra this problem
is there of so-called “intellectuals,”
they’ve called themselves, but they have
no intelligence. I talked to one man; I got
fed up. He didn’t know anything about spirituality,
he didn’t know anything about medicine,
he didn’t know anything about science. I
said, “Now, what do you know?” It was
impossible. So such people who are jobless
because everybody can’t take them, they
have no work; they are starting all such things,
and we should not be upset with them. They
are trying to create problems, and they are
getting money from some sources. They are
afraid. I think the politicians are afraid,
perhaps, that Sahaja Yoga may turn their tables
down, because we believe in honesty, and maybe
a day may come when these honest people might
harm them, perhaps, I do not know why. This
may be one of the reasons these people are
frightened of us.
But whatever it is, we have to understand
that for doing any great work, one has to
sacrifice. Of course you are not going to
be crucified like Christ, no. Nor you have
to sacrifice as My parents sacrificed for
the independence of this country. Nor you
are going to be tortured, but little inconveniences
you may have. But I must thank you very much
because of your coming here and singing Marathi
songs. They are quite impressed, and they
think it is only possible because you are
all Sahaja Yogis, otherwise you could not
have done it. So if there are any inconveniences,
think that it’s a joke, that’s all.
Today I was thinking we should do the puja
of Shri Chakra and Lalita Chakra, which we
have never done. This is the right place to
do these two chakras today. Lot has been written
about Shri Chakra and about Lalita Chakra.
But to understand fundamentally: the left
side, when it reaches up to Vishuddhi, then
it uses on the right side the Shri Chakra,
on the left side the Lalita Chakra, to manifest
itself. These two chakras are the ones who
manifest all that you see. But these chakras
are the ones who emit vibrations of different
kinds, and because of their angularities,
like if you have some sort of a cardboard
attached with small, small holes of different
colors and which rotates all the time, you
get different colors, also you can get different
permutations and combinations; in the same
way different permutations and combinations
are created, and that is how you get all the
advantages of Sahaja Yoga. So these two chakras
are very important.
I do not know if you know of any mantras about
Shri Chakra, but I’ll give you a book. Later
on I’ll translate it to you and you can
compose something for Shri Chakra; Shri Chakra
on the right side, Lalita Chakra on the left
side. So what we are really worshipping today
is Mahasaraswati Power and Mahakali Power,
both put together. So now we have started
combining things, not individual. Now these
two energies are very important. Without the
energy, without the power, nothing exists.
For example, if this light had no power to
give light or to burn, it is useless. In the
same way, without getting your Realization
you are useless, because your power is not
awakened; at least not complete. But these
two powers give us lots of benefits even without
Realization. Whatever you see in this world
created is done by these two chakras of the
Adi Shakti. But here the power doesn’t move,
it’s not moving. But in the human being
the power start moving, and when it starts
moving, then we can say it is creating another
world. But movement is not the only thing.
This power acts, gives you intelligence, gives
you all kinds of things which you have as
human beings. But later on, this power itself
becomes enlightened within you, means the
left and right side both become enlightened.
This enlightenment, you get it when you get
your Self Realization, but not immediately,
not immediately, this one should understand.
For example, if you have pain or if your chakra
is catching, you have to use your hands. You
cannot say that “The energy is flowing within
me, so it’s all right, I can manage.”
It’s not like that. You have to use your
hands to impart that power to yourself or
to others. If you have pain in the stomach,
then you can say that “If there’s energy
in my stomach, why should I have pain in the
stomach?” But the play of these chakras
have to come, and that is why you have to
use your power of your hands. If you cannot
use your hands, then you cannot impart this
energy.
Many people have asked Me that “Mother,
when will it move horizontal?” It will move
horizontal, no doubt, it does. But even that
horizontal movement is to be guided by these
two very important chakras. So you must understand
the importance of these two chakras within
yourself. That’s why I’ve told many-a-times,
don’t move your head too many times. And
this way, many people talk, I mean it’s
style of talking, “no, this, that”; very
common, with French specially. That’s another
way you are not respecting your chakras. Shouldn’t
move your shoulders too much. Mostly they
talk like this: it’s anti-chakras, anti-chakras.
Should keep your shoulders straight. When
you are singing you can move your whole upper
part, is all right, but not your shoulders.
This is the thing one has to understand, that
these two centers are to be looked after.
You can move your neck, your body when you
are singing, is important, that helps; but
not your shoulders. Shoulders are to be kept
intact. But while saying just “yes,” you
need not go on “yes, yes, yes, yes.” It’s
very, very simple thing, but it can have a
very bad effect. And those who move their
shoulders too much do not feel vibrations
much, because the chakras are not all right.
It’s a very simple thing to be understood,
that they are the most important chakras we
have, and whatever is to be used out of this
Paramachaitanya, they have to be used by these
two centers. Even supposing your some chakra
is catching on your spinal cord, you have
to use your hands. Somebody can say, “ I
can just put my attention.” It doesn’t
work out that good, because yet your attention
has not that, reached that stage where these
chakras like Lalita Chakra and Shri Chakra
obey your attention; they do not. So you have
to work out with your hands. Be careful, don’t
move your shoulders too much. And if you see
now, Indians when they sing bhajans, they’ll
move the whole body, they’ll do like this;
but never their shoulders. The shoulders will
move in the same way as the neck is moving.
They might move their neck also, but they’ll
never move their shoulders like this, and
is regarded as inauspicious, according to
Indian standards.
Because of this culture, based on what the
saints have told and also about many seers
have told, it is more related to spiritual
life than to materialistic life. Now the materialistic
life, unless and until there is the foundation
of the spiritual life, takes you to a very
partial development, you can say. But to get
a full development, you must have your foundation
on spirituality. That’s why spirituality,
being the foundation, has to be deep, has
to be fully equipped, has to be absolutely
perfect. Then the whole building can be built.
But it’s gone wrong in the West, it doesn’t
matter; now you can build it up, and then
you’ll be surprised how you’ll become
really solid people.
This is a very short talk about Shri Chakra.
I
think I
should sit down and write all about it, and
it will be nice, handy thing for you
to read. But you must know that beyond thought
when you go, these chakras become extremely
efficient. Because the thought puts a pressure
on them, and because of the pressure the movement
of these chakras is very slow and ineffective.
But once you can get out of your thoughts
and go into thoughtless awareness, then these
chakras start working it out, and you start
moving much deeper into your own being.
(End of English part of talk)