Modi must have told you very clearly about
how to grow in Sahaja Yog because he’s one
of them who has really taken very positive
step to see that he grows.
Now one has to understand one simple point
about realisation is that, just mere awakening
of the Kundalini is not sufficient, that’s
just the beginning.
You get your realisation but you must become
the tree, you have to grow, you have to become.
If you cannot grow then you have not achieved
what you wanted to be.
And you grow very fast, very fast with meditation
and with understanding about meditation.
Now one of the few hurdles that we have, that
I’ve seen it, that are innately built in
Sahaja Yog itself.
One of them is that you get it spontaneously
so easily that you take it for granted.
This is in the pattern of it, only innately
built.
You see what ever you get so easily you just
take it for granted.
But the another side of it is like that, that
when you have your eyes you don’t know the
value of your eyes, you take it for granted.
But when you don’t have them then you know
the value of eyes, it’s like that.
So when you lose vibrations and when you get
out of Sahaja Yog, then you start feeling
much more lost and then you come back to Sahaja
Yoga again.
Like a person becomes rich, he enjoys the
riches and then you make him poor then he
feels it more.
So this is the correcting point.
But it is very true that Sahaja has this thing
innately built in its self that it all happens
very spontaneously and you get it for doing
nothing at all.
So, may be so many of you may lose it because
you might find that it is just you got it
because of something.
I’ve also known of people they get vibrations
and they say, “Now it’s all right I don’t
need Sahaja Yoga, I am on my own."
Again they’re back like bad pennies with
some troubles and some problems and then they
go out.
Now I would say that Modi is one of those
first twelve people who got realisation, after
two years I’ve worked on them, while you
got realisation in such a short time.
Two years I’ve worked on twenty five people
out of which twelve got realisation you can
imagine, two years! As I’ve told you in
London I’ve worked on six people for four
years to give them realisation.
But once a certain number of people of particular
ideologies of permutations and combinations,
once they get realisation I find the rate
of realisation increases very fast.
Like formally we never use to have anybody
in the program who has been to any other Guru,
just avoid them.
Even up to the point that this Modi himself
used to tell people there’s no program today,
no program.
And they would ring Me up and find out that
there was a program and why they were not
allowed.
They said “Mother we get headaches you see.
They break our necks and they just disturb
us and they are good for nothing."
But now, it’s very different, once we have
built up our strength of collectivity we have
so many channels, things are working out very
differently.
So the value that Modi would attach to his
realisation is much more than you would attach
normally.
Because as you see, first even say to have
a ordinary oil lamp was a problem.
So the oil lamp was very important for people.
They would see to it that they would not use
out all the oil and they were so careful.
But today we have no problem, we have got
electricity we take it for granted.
Only when the electricity goes off we know
what is electricity is.
In the same way your realisation also, when
it is lost you understand the value of it.
But supposing you have just touched it and
then you lose it, then you do not understand.
But if you’ve got it you’ve enjoyed it
then you lose it then you want it back again,
so best thing is to be steadily moving towards
your evolution.
Now after I go away that’s the fears people
have here that people start doubting.
They said, “It happened with people they
started doubting."
Doubting what?
Your doubting yourself is the main point is.
You cannot believe that you can get realisation.
This is the basic.
You see to Me, it seems that you feel that
how can you get realisation?
Only those who are very highly realised souls
know that you are realised, they know that
you have been given realisation, but they
also sometimes ask Me, “Why did you give
them realisation.
What have they done?” Because you also think,
I mean we still have to look forward to something
else.
How can we get realisation, this is the trouble
You don’t believe in yourself.
That’s what you have to have confidence
in yourself and then you’ll have confidence
in Me also.
Because there are so many ways, by which you
can verify.
First of all
you can ask questions to the photograph or
to Me in your heart, about Myself, My relationship
what ever you think could be, what ever you
think, put your imagination and see that what
you think I could have been.
Ask that question.
Your vibrations will answer.
Put your, stretch your imagination to the
last, what could be the last word you could
think of Me.
You see, some people will put doubts saying
that, “Kundalini awakening is very difficult,
it is not easy."
Yes it’s true, it’s not easy, it’s a
very difficult things for human beings.
You just can’t do it, is a fact.
You have to work for days with some guru in
some jungle all alone, seeing nobody, working
out your chakras by chakras, sometimes you
have to starve, sometimes you have to eat,
sometimes you have to breathe, you have to
do all kinds of things.
And then the guru can work out.
But there could be someone who is somehow
the master, could be someone.
Kundalini is the Holy Ghost within you.
So there could be someone like that who can
do the job and that is what it is.
These things put you into doubts, because
you can’t believe it.
In relation to yourself you can’t believe
it.
You can believe in God, you can believe in
Holy Ghost, you can believe in Christ but
you cannot believe that it has any relationship
with you, that you could be that great, that
you could get your realisation.
So just feel it and enjoy it.
First of all, don’t think, that’s why
I say, “Don’t think."
Because as soon as you start thinking, Mr.
Thomas in you will get up and say that “Hello,
this cannot be Self-realisation."
Mr.
Thomas was great, you see.
Christ had all the disciples and I find all
those types around, permutations and combinations
and some how Judas also, but they’re rarely
to be found.
But there are, no doubt and some are Thomas’s,
and these Thomas’ are described as murmuring
souls by Christ Himself.
He said, “These are murmuring souls,”
and they murmur and one murmuring soul comes
to you, another murmuring soul in you joins
hands and you start all murmuring together,
start thinking.
Now at that time what have you to do on rational
grounds is very simple.
What have I done so far?
I’ve done everything, did I get cool breeze?
Did I get my self realisation?
Did I feel my own powers?
Have I been able to feel myself and others?
Because you see your still not fully realised,
you may not be able to feel the vibrations
of another person, neither you will be able
to feel your own vibrations.
But there are so many people here who are
realised and they can feel yours, and they
can verify.
Supposing they ask you, “How is your father?”
There was one gentleman in England he came
and told Me, “Why is everybody asking me
about my father?”
I said, “Because there’s one particular
centre that’s catching,” and I called
a child I said now tell Me, “What is the
centre catching?” She pointed out this one
and I said, “This is the centre."
Everybody is catching on this centre, this
is the father centre so they’re asking you
about your father.
He said, “Yes he’s dead and he died of
cancer and he had this and that,” and we
had to treat him.
For example anorexia is a disease can be cured
by curing this centre.
It’s such a deep knowledge and it is such
an all pervading knowledge.
Because once you know in a tree the sap that
goes to all the leaves and all the ends of
it and if you can move the sap, your attention
can move with the sap, you can know the whole
of the tree.
You cannot know leaves and then know the tree.
How many leaves can you count?
But to know the tree the best thing is to
get to the sap.
To treat a tree is best is to get to its sap,
isn’t it?
In the same way when you go from inside out
then you find that you know yourself and others
very well.
It’s very simple even small children can
do it.
So the first doubt comes about yourself, “Oh
this is one of them” because there’s a
guru shopping going on, you see.
There’s a guru shopping, there’s a float,
you go to one guru to another, to ESPs and
what you call them, all sorts of things, mediums,
and all sorts of things they do with the dead
bodies or anything.
All these things you have been to and you
will have found it.
So now suddenly you have to come to a temple,
where you don’t pay anything and you just
get the blessings.
So can’t believe it, you just can’t believe
it, it’s too much to believe.
This is what happens you get
confused.
You are all ready confused, but confusion
could be over by understanding that something
is happening to you just wait and see, give
it a chance.
There’s no way we can bind you to Sahaja
Yoga, because there’s no mesmerism here.
This is another innately a problem with Sahaja
Yoga.
Second problem I should say is that you’re
too free to do what you like, absolutely free,
there’s no binding force except that you
feel the love of your Mother.
Supposing you are not feeling the vibrations
in your hand, there’s no way of binding
you down to Sahaja Yog, nothing.
We just advise “Go ahead, it will work out,
let it work out."
There is no fees, there’s no registration,
there’s no compulsion, nothing.
It’s your own free will.
If you want to stick on you can stick on,
if you want to go away you can go away.
There’s no force on you of any kind.
There’s no registration of your names with
some fees or anything, I mean you are not
bound to pay anything.
If you paid something then you feel, “All
right I’ve paid for it, so go through it
what ever it is, good or bad..
Supposing you go to see a play and it’s
a horrid play but still you say, “All right
I’ve paid for it so let me go through it."
But that you cannot do with Sahaja Yog because
you’ve not paid.
There’s nobody will force you down, nobody
will go on telephoning to you, “Come along,
please come along,” and all that.
So the attitude has to be changed, it is I
who has to gain.
Say there’s a beautiful spot somewhere.
Now that beautiful spot doesn’t send an
invitation card to anyone, everybody goes
there.
But if you have not yet discovered the beauty
of Sahaja Yog in that way and have not enjoyed
it fully, you’ll have to go again and again
and see for yourself.
It is a deliberation on your side not on the
side of the Sahaja Yogis or Sahaja Yoga.
It’s not going to fall at your feet.
That please come to Sahaja Yoga, please donate
something, nothing of the kind.
If you come you are welcome, if you don’t
come, welcome.
On the contrary, you will be surprised there’s
more rejection than acceptance in Sahaja Yog.
That’s also innately built.
I’ve seen some people who are very insincere
type they just go out from Sahaja Yoga like
a tangent.
There was a gentleman who was very troublesome
to us in Bombay and we didn’t know what
to do with him and he just got transferred
from there and we got rid of him.
So you just go out of Sahaja Yoga like a tangent
and we are saved from the botheration.
Because you must understand, if you have problems,
if you are not all right it’s a problem
for Sahaja Yogis to correct you.
It’s just the other way round, if you understand
this, then you will understand the thing,
what works out.
For example if I have to cure somebody it’s
a problem for Me and not the problem for the
person who’s sick.
Now if the tree has to grow is the problem
for the gardener not for the tree.
So the tree must see to it that it co-operates
with the gardener and gets itself developed.
If this understanding is developed, that it
is I who has to gain, it is I who has to go
forward, Mother has not to gain from me anything,
She wants me to have all my powers manifested.
She wants me to grow through it, if this attitude
is developed then you’ll work hard to grow
and you’ll work it out.
But on the contrary you see at the slightest
protest if you ego stands up and says, “Why,
why should I do this?”
To overcome this hurdle you see, we have to
build up certain stages.
That’s what Modi was telling Me.
That you first become thoughtlessly aware,
see that silence is established.
There are certain things that you do much
later, everybody is not allowed in there,
because truth can be only born by people who
are strong enough to bear it.
That’s why I’m not going to tell you who
am I, till you reach a certain stage, because
you cannot bear the light.
That’s what happened with Christ.
They crucified Him because they could not
bear Him.
Human beings are like that, they can’t even
bear an incarnation of love.
They can’t even bear love, it’s too much
for them.
Even if you give them too much love they get
upset, they get disturbed, they just can’t
bear it.
So you have to build up yourself to come to
a certain stage of understanding of Sahaja
Yoga.
It’s a state, which you achieve.
It’s a state.
You are not to be certified by anyone on the...But
it’s a state where you will start giving
realisation to others and the whole way you’ll
be talking you will be in a very different
manner as if you are completely detached.
You’ll say “It is going, it is coming."
It happens.
You will not say my mother must get, my father
must get, you will never say like that.
Because you’ll understand that the problem
of Sahaja Yoga is that it cannot give to anyone.
Like
the sunshine can shine it is for the trees
to expose themselves to the sunshine and get
the advantage of it.
The sunshine is not going to run after you
all over to see that you get it.
This is the point here, it will shine the
whole day and you take it.
But it’s not that it will run after you
all the time requesting you, “Oh please
get me, oh please get me, have it, have it,”
like that.
And this is what one has to understand very
clearly, that it is you who has to ask for
it, and not anybody is going to force on you
anything.
On the contrary if anybody tries to say something
more your ego gets like that.
So try to be careful.
I am very happy to know that also, that in
all the ego orientated societies I’ve seen
that Sahaja Yoga works like wonders.
Because first thing they see is their colossal
ego.
And that’s a very positive point about it,
because once you start seeing this horrible
balloon in you, you just start watching yourself
and enjoying, “Oh Mr so and now get along
with your ego."
You see it’s a very interesting life you
start leading.
If your ego you see, is a very good sign.
If you cannot see your ego then there’s
danger.
But some can even see their super ego if they’re
possessed.
See people see how they get possessed suddenly
because the frequency of possession becomes
very little so that there’s a big gaps you
see to see the time when you are normal and
when you get abnormal also you can see clearly
that you are abnormal.
By seeing that you start judging, “Oh God
I have again been caught up, I’m again lost,”
and you come back to normal.
The whole thing becomes a very beautiful understanding
of the reality about yourself and you laugh
at yourself all the time.
All the time you laugh at your self and you
laugh at everything and you find the whole
joke going round how people are seriously
indulging into nonsensical things and how
it’s such a big joke you’ve been yourself
worrying about things which have no meaning,
which has no significance.
Like I went first to Paris and people told
Me, “Mother they are not going to like you
very much, because they believe a person who
is so happy is ignorant.
You should not be a happy person.
You should be a crying baby so they’ll believe
You."
They’re all les miserable, very unhappy
people, extremely unhappy and if you tell
them you are a happy person so they are going
to be shocked at such a thing.
I said, “Really this Les Miserable, let
me (inaudible).
Let Me do something about them and I made
them laugh so much at their miseries that
they got all right and they understood that
the joy is just there.
You have to just peep in your heart and you’ll
find the source of your joy and then the whole
thing vanishes into thin air.
But it has to work, it has to happen.
There is no quick way of doing it in the sense
that I say, “All right you give me five
rupees or five dollars, Australian dollars
and you get it."
NO, no, no, no, you may give Me any amount
it won’t work out.
It has not worked out with My own daughters
you’ll be surprised.
I’ve never forced them or I’ve never asked
them.
I’ve only two daughters they’re not realised
I’m not bothered.
When they’ll ask for it they’ll get it.
But My four grandchildren are born realised.
And one of the eldest ones one day very seriously
said, “As it is you cannot commit mistakes
I know but it would have been nice if you
have given them realisation when they were
children."
You see this is what it is that you cannot
force these things on anyone and you have
to take a very detached view.
You are a seeker, your mother and you are
there but they are not your responsibility,
you can tell them about Sahaja Yog.
But if they are opposing you better have,
let them be alone, they’ll come round.
When they see the transformation in within
you, they’ll definitely come.
So leave them alone.
Don’t bother your heads.
Just leave them alone and you will be amazed
that they will see you transforming so well
and acting so well and they’ll change themselves
and they will come to you and ask you, “How
are you so much changed and transformed?”
You see proof of the pudding is in seeing
the pudding up there changing people.
And this transformation you’ll be amazed
coming into you so suddenly that you will
be amazed.
But as I told you that on the left side is
the desire or you can say the super ego, the
desire to do something.
And the right side is the ego which we try
to sort of please and which feels happy and
the one by which we have ambitions.
But in the centre is the will power to do
this.
And this will power has to be increased by
you, “I have to do it, I have to do it."
First you’ll feel tired because
your left heart is weak, then I will tell
you how to do it.
‘Then know how to raise your left heart
if you’re tired.
See most of the people these days are very
tired people.
They talk, “Ah,” they sit down “Ah."
They can’t, I mean they are very tired,
absolutely fagged out people.
Morning till evening what have you been doing,
nothing.
Just sitting in the sun you got tired, just
lazing out you got tired.
Why, why did you get tired?
Firstly because you’re not integrated you
are fighting with in yourself.
You’re head is fighting your heart, your
heart is fighting your liver.
Secondly, you are thinking and wasting your
energy.
So you have to learn how to settle your heart,
what has to be done to raise your heart to
make it peaceful and how to get the energy
from your spirit.
Once you start doing that your tired feeling
will go away.
Then your aggressiveness also will decrease
and you’ll be amazed that you will just
watch the whole thing.
Neither you’ll aggress nor you’ll take
aggression and the whole reaction will be
very different.
Then everything has a meaning, your feelings
have a meaning.
Supposing you have a feeling today for Poland,
which is in trouble, all of you should ask
just now, “Mother solve the problem of Poland."
Because I have no desires you see, I am desire
less, you have to ask and it works, you’ll
be amazed because your attention is enlightened
now, it just works.
You have to desire for it and it works.
You have to work for it and it works.
And so many miraculous things people will
tell you just believe them that’s all true.
Money problem solved, because of Lakshmi Tattwa
within, financial problems solved, social
problem solved, family problems solved because
you are solved.
See in relation to you all everything seems
problematic.
When your problems are solved everything is
solved.
It’s so simple as that.
We have to solve ourselves and it is solved
through the awakening of the Kundalini.
Now I would like to have some questions from
you and then I would like you to go into groups
with the Sahaja Yogis and talk to them on
intimate level and also you must tell Me your
problems.
If you have any intimate problems, you can
talk to Me also.
But best is to talk to each other.
I would like Warren to see to it that he organises
all these groups properly.
But I would love to have some questions from
you about Sahaja Yoga now.
Question: How can one laugh at abortion.
He's talking about abortion, you are taking
the view that it is bad?
Shri Mataji: I’m not saying you have to,
I said you are not to laugh, means you laugh
at silly stupid things I meant, you see.
But at abortion as I can’t understand you
see.
This is a very funny situation in this country.
As it is the birth rate is minus and you are
having abortions.
Question: Does it exist in India much abortion
Shri Mataji: Not much, people don’t like
it at all, they hate it.
And you know the trouble is like this.
You people are having no children so we have
to have the load on us.
You see what to do?
Nobody to be born here, they don’t want
to be born here because there is no love in
the heart.
See when the other day when somebody told
Me about the doctors here some of them are
butchers I couldn’t believe it.
Because in India at least, doctors are not
butchers by any chance.
I was surprised; this is because everything
has become a butchery here, because the heart
is covered with ego.
There’s no heart left.
You have to raise the heart.
That’s important, once you raise the heart,
you see you cannot stand all this nonsense,
you know.
Why do you want to have abortion I still can’t
understand?
Question: Does it affect Swadisthan charka?
Shri Mataji: Oh, it affects many chakras,
I mean.
There was someone I knew who always used to
catch on right heart, I must tell you this,
very nice person, always on right heart.
His father was a good man everything was fine,
asked him, “How are you catching on right
heart?” He was not married and when he came
very close to Me then he confessed to Me that,
“I lived with a woman and she was going
to have a baby and she went in for an abortion
and I conceded, and since then
I have been feeling very sad about the whole
thing."
But the whole view about life has to be changed
then only you can avoid these things.
You see it is a symptom of a disease.
It’s not the disease itself, abortion is
not the disease, is a symptom of a disease.
Now what is the disease with in us is, is
that, that we have allowed our sex to be let
loose completely, talking too much about sex
from childhood.
What is the need to give education in sex,
I’ve been failed to understand?
Openly, there’s no need to teach about,
you see, do the animals need any sex education,
they still produce.
Then they told Me, “They tell about sex
only because they think by telling about sex
they can protect people from not going into
sex."
I said, “No, they create too much of curiosity
in children."
For example, in India we never talk about
sex to children, they do not know, they are
so innocent.
Even till the marriage takes place some of
the girls do not know what sex actually is,
how it works out and all.
But they are told this is something filthy
to do and all that and when the girl gets
into puberty it is told and to the boys also,
somehow or other it is a very different society.
This question doesn’t come, it never comes
into the head of the boys and girls.
You see if you keep them pure, like it doesn’t
come in the head of a sister and a brother
even today, thank God.
Many sisters and brothers I should say despite
Freud’s all efforts to spoil your minds,
but still there are brothers and sisters relations
today.
In the same way it doesn’t come into their
heads at all.
And when they get married they are to be told,
this is what it is.
And that’s why they say these koarak and
all these places were built where they could
take young brides and young people to see
that.
This was called as Koomari Kar Temple, means
the married women when they were not virgins
could go there and see those places to understand
what is sex is and they got so exhausted with
this early sex life, I mean you go into all
kinds of tantrums then.
Because you’re so exhausted then you go
into perversions.
The basics are wrong.
We are trying too hard to be sexologists.
There’s no need to be sex points you are
that already.
But you don’t want to be only sex points,
do you?
I don’t know what makes you feel that that
is the end of every, every endeavor, everything
should end up there.
May be that advertisement and all this is
coming to you too much because they think
that by exploiting these things they will
help you.
But it’s such a perverted thing and
Seeker interrupts and asks Shri Mataji about
people in India being given a gift like a
transistor radio for sterilization.
Does it have a purpose?
It has a purpose to a point.....Oh I'm sorry
this has another point....
He is talking about in India where they give
a transistor radio....
Shri Mataji: That’s what they try, this
is also, you see western ideas coming to India.
Oh, they did all sorts just to sterilise them.
Oh! that’s how the lady lost her last election,
last election she has now pulled her ears
for that.
You see, they are all westernised people you
see, they try to try all these tricks in....
People don’t like it you see.
There’s a bridegroom who went for his wedding
and poor thing saw that there was a team of
people standing there for sterilisation.
He jumped out of the bus and he disappeared
forever, nobody knows where he is, disappeared.
‘And they even sterilised people who were
very old and who were not even married you
see.
It’s so funny, so indiscriminate, I think
they were possessed by some bhoots I don’t
know what to call them.
You see population is a problem in India but
what to do now, you should solve the problem.
And there is something working out in a very
funny way, I must tell you.
I went to Colombia, I found lots of these
Norwegians carrying Colombian children with
them.
And they looked so different from Norwegian
children, Norwegian people and these Colombian
children.
I asked them, “Why do you acquire these
children where are you carrying them?
They said “We have adopted them”.
I said, “Why don’t you produce your own?
That would be better, to produce your own."
"No we don’t want to go through the process
of it, it’s better to have ready made."
So the supply has started in having all this
in developing countries to give you ready
made children.
Isn’t if funny, it’s funny things going
on, instant babies.
Question: If a chakra is blocked and you clean
the chakras wouldn’t you being undoing the
karmic cycle that a person has to go through?
Shri Mataji: Very good idea, Because I think
you people...I know the question is this,
that he is saying that if you try to clean
the chakras you will be undoing the karmic
cycle and all that you see this is the typical
things that are being circulated in the west
you see.
That you have your own karmas you see and
we are the gurus so you have to go through
your karmas, you must suffer for your karmas
you see like that is there.
Now, this theory was all right before Christ
came in, not after His coming.
And why are they here then?
Why are we paying them, for what?
You better pickle them out.
They’re worth nothing because they just
take money from you, and we have to go through
our karmas.
They make you dance, jump go into all kinds
of things.
Put spirits in us and say, “You are suffering
your karmas.
Why should we suffer?” At least they should
suffer for our karma’s minimum of minimum.
Now Christ has done that for you.
He has taken all these karmas, your karmas
upon Himself.
He has made way for us, that’s why you have
to pass through Him.
Once you pass through Him, through Agnya chakra,
your karmas are sucked in by Him, that’s
your ego.
It’s the only ego that says you have done
this wrong, and that wrong.
You see an animal doesn’t think that way.
It thinks it’s it own sva bhavah the way
it has to be.
But it’s only the human beings who think
I’ve done this wrong, I’ve done that wrong.
I’ve done this good, that bad because we
have ego.
But when your Kundalini passes through your
Agnya chakra your ego is sucked in, your superego
is sucked in.
Christ has done double job in one shot you
know, it’s great.
That’s why He was crucified, it was to be.
He took all your karmas upon Himself and put
it into hell.
So what ever karmas you have done are all
sucked in.
But the door must open fully.
In the beginning it happens that only a thread
comes up, you see, and the ego is not fully
sucked in so sometimes it still comes up and
all that.
The best weapon to get rid of them is to forgive
others.
Forgiveness is the greatest weapon Christ
has given us, which we have to use, forgive,
forgive and forgive.
That’s a very good way, Lords Prayer is
the solution for your Agnya charka, you’ll
be amazed.
You have to say Lords Prayer after realisation
to open your Agnya.
Then you become thoughtlessly aware.
After realisation again I say, not before
realisation, it has no meaning.
Before realisation what ever you have said
has gone into karmas.
Only after realisation you are baptized and
get an opening here and all your karmas pass
through that.
Also you will find when you get realisation
lot of heat comes out these are the karmas
you see, that are coming out.
Let the heat go out and all karmas are finished.
It’s like that.
This is what is Self-Realisation.
Like an egg is in a egg shell is very different,
but when it becomes a little chick and the
mother breaks the tip of the egg a new bird
comes out with out any karmas or the smell
of the egg.
So clean and nice, every thing converted into
something beautiful.
It’s like that, this is the rebirth.
This is how we become a new personality a
new being.
So to forget about your karmas after your
realisation, all right.
He has said it
that, “He died for your sins."
Didn’t He?
And the wages of sin is fear.
If you still have fear within you of your
karmas, you are still sinning.
There should be no fear about it.
Do not have any guilt, I’ve been telling
you not to have any guilt.
What can you do?
What sins can you commit?
Do not have any fears.
This is very common as I told you the other
day left Vishuddhi, I have to talk about it
quite a lot.
It’s so common, in Australia, in America
and in all the western countries, to feel
guilty.
Everything collapses there and nobody can
rise through the Agnya because it collapses
down here onto left Vishuddhi where you feel
guilty.
What are you feeling guilty about?
And why did Christ come on this earth.
You are just wasting His incarnation by feeling
guilty yourself.
He has taken all your guilt upon Himself.
What do you thing He was?
He was Omkara, he was Pranava, He was the
word, He was that power.
He’s not attached to anything but He can
take away everything that you think is sin,
because He’s sinless, He so pure, immaculate.
All right does that give you some hopes?
Or still you are indulging into your own miseries?
Question: Can You give us some guide about
diet.
Shri Mataji: Diet?
All right.
This diet theory is also coming from some
horrible Brahmins you see.
Don’t listen to them.
They are the greatest rakshasas ever born
on this earth.
Devils, rakshasas are monsters.
They eat like hell, they eat such a lot and
they always tell you, “Don’t do this and
don’t do that."
You can eat anything you like except don’t
eat the meat of animals which are bigger than
you.
I mean other wise you will develop muscles
which will have funny contours and things.
Eat animals which are smaller than you is
the point is.
And if you eat those animals they do not also
have much sense of compassion and all that.
It’s all right they are just like vegetables
sort of things, so it doesn’t matter.
You don’t kill them, they are killed in
the machine and all that, you have to eat
that, and you need it, you have to eat.
But that doesn’t mean that if you are vegetarians
you should become non vegetarians.
It doesn’t mean that.
What ever you eat, you can eat.
Eating is not going to change your spirit.
Spirit doesn’t eat, it does not, makes no
difference to the spirit except that, to your
body which is the lamp.
So if you have to keep the wick all right,
you have to keep the lamp all right and for
that don’t eat anything that is a very big
animal compared to yourself.
Cows meat for example in India they don’t
eat, because, “Have you ever seen Indian
cows they’re very gentle."
And the cows are in the house, just like mother
they start giving milk to the children they
see.
Every day they are taking the milk of the
cows so they develop a feeling, you see.
And that’s why they don’t drink, you see.
But it doesn’t mean that if your Australian
cows are I don’t think are like that.
Because what I’ve seen they look like buffalos
to Me sometimes.
Like My granddaughter, she came to England
and she asked Me, “Mother, Grandmother,
why the buffalos in England are white?”
Yes, so, it’s all right.
But you’ll come down on diet.
It will be different you see, you’ll see
gradually.
But don’t worry about it.
Gradually everything drops out into very little
things.
But you allow yourself to develop.
Question: Eggs?
And things like that?
Shri Mataji: Oh, eggs you better have, lots
of it.
But if you have liver it’s not good to have
eggs.
Eggs is very heating,, pork is otherwise good
but not good for the people who have liver
problem.
See you must understand that every person
is different.
Now today I met a lady who is very left sided.
So I had to tell her, “You eat pork, eggs
everything.
You see it is how you are.
Even the Indian Ayurveda is like that.
They want to know the prakruti, the character
of a person how he is.
We have evolved from different types of animals.
I saw the nocturnal ones.
You see the nocturnal ones must eat a lot
of meats, those who have evolved from nocturnal
side, you see.
Left-sided, the ones who are afraid and frightened
and who are not egoistical at all you see.
Such types they should take more meats and
things but those who are too much aggressive
better take to vegetables, is better.
All right now, what’s the question?
Question: Does forgiveness stop the rich getting
richer and the poor getting poorer?
Shri Mataji: It does absolutely, absolutely.
Sahaja Yoga is the thing that balances the
society.
Those who are poor become richer and the rich
understand that they must share.
Willingly they start sharing their money.
But you become really rich in a very miraculous
manner.
Now there’s a girl here and I would like
her to tell you what happened to her, it’s
miraculous.
But she’s an Australian and she doesn’t
tell lies you can see that very clearly and
she’ll tell you what happened to her.
Where is she gone?
Sharon come along..is she here?
No let her tell, is better, she’s Australian
they’ll believe her more.
But never trust an Indian that’s even worse.
You know some of the gurus have introduced
some Indian bhoots, Indian spirits into English
people, and Americans and also European and
I find they behave just like Indians.
They’ll cheat, they embezzle, they’ll
take away things, not the women, they’ll
not touch the women you see.
But they’ll touch the things they take away
the empty cans, is typical Indian you see.
It’s rather
surprising, yes there are some, I’ve seen
them like that.
It’s surprising to see such things happening
to a western person who behaves just like
an Indian must be some possession of bhoots
put by these gurus.
So if you believe Me then I can tell you what
she’s told, it’s really miraculous, very
miraculous, you see.
Cheryl was telling Me that she wanted to come
to India and she had no money.
So her daughter was very anxious to come to
India and they didn’t know what to do, they
didn’t have sufficient money.
So they just said, “Mother we want to come
to India can you arrange it for us, that’s
all."
And it so happened that this girl had taken
a trinket she had in the house, a bracelet
to the school for a sale, whenever they have
the fetes all over.
So she took that for the fete and the teacher
said, “I think this is gold."
She couldn’t believe it.
She brought it home and they got it valued
and they found that the price of the thing
was equal to what they had to spend for both
of them travels.
But this is nothing.
And then she got some money from somewhere
in the house, somewhere I don’t know how
she got some money and she didn’t sell even
the bracelet.
And that’s still there she said, “For
the next trip."
I said, “I hope so, you sell it."
“May not."
Like that you see, things work out, because
your Laxshmi Tattawa, your centre of well
being gets enlightened and then you are looked
after.
So many things happen.
Like today they told Me so many things of
this kind happening to them and I too.
You see when these people came in, I had told
them all right, you give Me so much money
may be required for your stay there.
Very little it was, very little for them to
be there in India after all, you see India
is also now becoming very expensive.
And when I went to India I had discovered
it had become very expensive, doesn’t matter
I said, “I’ll put it in the bank.
“Let it be there."
And anybody ask Me, “Have it, you want it,
have it, now spend go,” and it was all right.
I could manage, see that’s what he did,
and so many of them have done it.
It’s looked after.
You go to right places, you get right things,
don’t spend too much, you do not repent
for spending and you feel happy for whatever
you have.
You feel very joyous, not worried about counting
but if you make a budget you had it.
You don’t worry your head about budgeting,
how much your going to spend, you’ll be
surprised.
You won’t go to things which are unnecessary,
useless but you’ll buy something that is
very good and ultimately these things will
be very precious for you to sell.
Many things have happened like that.
Many things have happened.
Question: Why is Australia important for the
future?
Maybe about Shri Ganesha?
Shri Mataji: Only thing I don’t want to
pamper the ego.
Question: Is Australia blessed?
Shri Mataji: Very much, very much blessed.
It’s a very much blessed place, specially
created.
Australia was the first continent to be created
and if I dare to answer this question, I hope
you’ll believe Me and not get into ego trips.
Australia is a place which is described in
the ancient Puranas that a great saint was
sent to Australia and another heaven was created.
And that saint is called as Thrishanku which
is your Southern Cross...what do you call
that?
That shows the Southern Cross and you can
only see Southern Cross from Australia.
This is one of the Puranas, the Vedas have
also mentioned this and even before that Australia
is the place which has the Ganesha.
The first is the Mooladhara Chakra, the first
centre is in Australia.
How much wise you should be.
Did you hear Me?
Question: She wanted your opinion about the
Australian aboriginals.
Shri Mataji: Oh, they must have been good
people to begin with, I am sure of it.
They must have been very good and holy people
and nice people but I think later on they
deviated because of too much jungles and things
you know, they started feeling the fear of
the nature too much.
They must have worshiped things, which were
good to begin with and later on to some things
like spirits and this.
More over the dead bodies the way they disposed
of must have been something wrong.
So maybe they might have gone into a left
sided action into primitive ways of exciting
these bhoots
and things, spirits and spiritualism and all
that.
But in Australia must be the minimum, in Africa
is horrible.
African countries have too much of it but
it should be the minimum of minimum because
you see, Ganesha’s chakra is connected with
the left side, you see is more on the left
side isn’t it?
So also one can go drift more on to the left
side that is what it is.
And even today I feel there’s kind of a
lurking inferiority complex that works in
Australians.
They try to copy the west, there’s nothing
to copy there, they’ve nothing sensible.
They have to learn from you.
You see this is a little inferiority complex
we have that all the best things are in the
west.
That’s wrong, you are much better of in
so many ways.
At least you’ve not lost your moorings.
So I would not pass a general remark about
a community as such but there is a possibility
that they can come up very well too.
I mean they can get out of all that left-sidedness.
In India also we have big communities in the
south where people have lived with too much
ritualism and all that and have taken to left-sided
behaviour of attracting you know spirits and
this and that, and giving those [telesmart?]
and all that.
They have done all that they are doing, like
witchcraft, witch doctors and all that.
They must be doing it, but it can be cured
there’s no problem.
As the west, people are over developed and
very ego orientated and right side.
Both are extreme cases, but you can be correct.
The people who are left side it’s easier
because they have to move forward but it’s
difficult for ego orientated to move backwards.
But if we can do that there why not here,
so nothing is lost.
One should not worry too much about these
things.
Human begins are just the same everybody has
Kundalini, finished.
As long as you have Kundalini I have no problem.
Question: Is there anything wrong with eating
chilies?
Shri Mataji: No, it suits some people very
much.
Some people should have, those who suffer
from colds will be a good idea, suffer from
constipation is a good idea.
But don’t eat too much of anything.
But it’s good for some people, something
is good for some people, something is good
for some people, you have to just find out.
For people who get constipated it is better
to have a little of green chilies all the
time, it is very rich in vitamin C.
It is very rich in vitamin C is good for people
who catch colds very easily.
Question: Do you know anything about the teaching
called Mahikari
Shri Mataji: I know.
You see Mahikari thing was, the person who
started Mahikari was a realised soul, though
not so well equipped.
I’ve met him before his realisation and
he got realisation I think through Me only,
what ever it was.
I do not want to claim anything like that.
But only thing is he was not equipped, well
equipped.
Like anybody here who gets realisation starts
doing something.
And his daughter I think, mislead the people
because she’s not a realised soul.
She became very money-orientated, she started
putting it, it’s happened with every one
of them.
But poor thing, this one was not, he just
got realisation he was not an incarnation
also, you see.
Even incarnations who came on this earth like
Christ you see, like Mohammad Sahab, like
Rama, Krishna see such great incarnations
were purest of pure.
Even those people have been mishandled and
people have raised organisations, which are
just money making propositions.
Everything some how man makes into money.
I don’t know how, it’s something that
happens to human beings you see.
Then they start giving [Telesmart?] then they
start giving this, that, cross, this I mean
it’s a money-making proposition through
out.
You see this is the trouble.
Warren: She said you are right.
Shri Mataji: And you may lose lots of your
powers, even ordinary, normal powers with
this kind of a wrong attitude you see, or
misguidance, because it happens like that,
you can make mistakes, you can do so many
things.
You know I’ve seen people, one girl whom
I had given realisation she went to a lady
who was a medium.
She used to get “Ho, ho, ho, ho,” like
that, and this thing.
And she
gave her a talisman and she became actually
blind, actually blind.
Now she’s blind, her eyes are open, I mean
I have to still cure her.
This is the report I got about her.
Question: Would you say the same of the Hari
Krishna Organisation?
Shri Mataji: Oh, now you are pulling Me into
controversy.
But I will tell you the other way round.
You see if you go on calling say the name
of anybody, even your name would you like
it?
So then how can God like it?
On the Oxford Street you stand up, you should
see the site, they even sell those things
see like wigs, they sell them like wigs in
the market.
They shave off and sometimes they wear wigs.
See it’s not show, it is something that
has to happen within.
It’s not the show that you put up is something
that has to happen.
You see most of them end up with throat cancer
and very violent, very violent people.
They are beggars’ absolute parasites.
Warren: with expensive cars.
Shri Mataji: You see this is very nice,
I met somebody in England and I told him,
“What do you do here?” He said, “I deal
in opium."
I got a fright.
I said, “Opium, how do you deal in opium?”
“Other people’s money,”
I said, “That’s very good, other people’s
money."
You see you can float an enterprise.
It’s very easy because you are such seekers
such great seekers of ages and you are so
naïve, very good.
You go anywhere they’ll take a square, sit
there with saffron cloths with some circles
on, another fellow will be fanning.
Oh this one is very great, coming direct from
Kashi.
Then have nothing to do with horrible people.
Kashi is one of the worst places now.
So you all go and prostrate.
This is what it is.
I mean, why are you enamoured by these circuses,
aren’t you fed up with them?
We had a lady from Norway, this one was very
interesting.
She came to My house stayed with Me, very
badly caught up, and she told Me the story
of a lama who came to Norway.
First he told all these Norwegians, “You
see, if I have to come to Norway you have
to make a place with the floor which has got
all marble."
Look at that.
They’re such parasites these Lamas are.
First they have sucked the blood of these
poor Tibetans and now they were willing to
suck the blood of these Norwegians.
Now these poor young people you see, I should
say the young people in the west are really
not rich because they’re parents do not
give them money the way we give our children
you see.
So they starve themselves, they ate only potatoes
and this and that and for one year they starved
themselves to create this floor for these
horrible people.
And this fellow came you see, with his shaved
head and all that.
He stayed there and this lady told Me that
she had to go and just bow to him one thousand
times for three months.
One thousand times.
Imagine, just to go, as it is he’ll be finished,
even three times is sufficient to finish you
off.
And three months she did it.
And with Me she was arguing morning till evening.
I said, “Look at that, her arguing with
Me, eating My head off and here your bowing
to him."
They would not allow anybody to go near the
lama, the great was sitting on the seventh
step somewhere hanging in the air.
Is very common you know, the more you are
missing from the scene the more you are difficult
to be seen you see.
Is something great, “Oh, ho! I’ve seen
the glimpse of that
horrible thing,” that’s what people think.
You see this is what they play upon you emotional,
what you call it emotional blackmail.
That’s what it is.
They will tell you first of all they’re,
we call them chumchars, we call them spoons.
They’ll come and tell you, “Oh this is
very difficult, you know.
He may not give you any interview, and you
have to at least you should shell out five
hundred rupees, see it is not easy, it’s
very difficult.
Only you should send your photograph with
five hundred,” all this nonsense.
If you are the river Ganges, what can malign
you, what can dirty you, what can make you
impure?
If you are here for purification then nothing
can impure you.
One two three four, now the one who has not
asked at all should ask
Question: Over the years it seems we have
lost our power to believe in our self that
we had in Egyptian times the power to believe
in ourselves but we went wrong..
Warren: the question is the loss of power
within ourselves, perhaps back in the days
of Egypt we had these powers, we seem to have
lost our power to believe in ourself.
Shri Mataji: I don’t know even if at that
time you had those powers very much.
But Egyptians indulged more on the ego side
you see, those who were rulers.
And the slaves were on the left hand side
too much because they obeyed the rulers you
see.
So the sensitivity came to them from spirits,
not directly from themselves.
And some of them were really, very realised
souls and you’ll be amazed if these extreme
cases are there they understand an incarnation
better.
Say if you are taking LSD too much, you will
see only lights coming out of Me, you won’t
see Me.
There are many who must have seen that, auras
and things, if you are on the right hand side
too much.
If you are on the left had side you’ll be
awed, you’ll be shaking before Me and you
may see My previous births and you’ll be
quite frightened because you’ll know what
it is.
So they understood the incarnations better,
but evolutionary you are much higher than
they are.
Though there’s confusion because of so called
freedom you had which you misused.
But as a whole I think this is the time for
blossom.
Only thing you must know that you’re a seeker
and you are a seeker then you must get it
and if you get it why should you be surprised.
But it’s like a seeking has become like
a fashion, seeking here, seeking there seeking
there, seeking you stop no where you see.
You see you go on fixing the bolts you see,
you’re just going with an inertia, even
if you stop fixing you still go on like that.
It’s like that, you see, it’s a style
you have developed going from this to that,
that to that, that to that and you cannot
stop it.
Question: I’d be interested in Your opinion
of philosophy for Rudolf Steiner and secondly
you concept of Papa tax sungar in India.
All these are all people playing on bhoots
and things, that’s all I can say.
(Shri Mother asks the seeker what does Steiner
say and he says million words.)
Word, words, words and words, what does he
say?
This Steiner his vibrations are very good,
Might be a realised soul but what does he
say?
Seekers tries to tell Shri Mataji what he
writes about.
He might be a realised soul like Khalil Gibran
is, you see his vibrations are good.
He might be, but still you have to become
realised souls you see.
Reading that even Zen is all that.
Zen is everything is, nothing but his realisation.
But you’ll be amazed that the head of Zen
himself reads all Zen without being realised,
and he’s a hopeless fellow.
I just talked to him and he said, “Oh, he
cannot get realisation."
He’s confirmed on that point.
Imagine the head of the Zen saying that, and
he said we had kashapas only twenty six kashapas
we had in six centuries can you believe it.
And he wouldn’t take his realisation and
he was so frightened.
He accepted Me all right but he said, “I
am nowhere, Mother, compared to You."
“What is this?
But I am telling you can get."
Warren: Steiner catches on Agnya and swadisthan.
Shri Mataji: So it’s good to read somebody
who is a realised soul, but you better get
it yourself.
You become Steiner, all right.
What I’m saying, you become a realised soul.
And you can write about your own experiences.
Yes, please.
Question: Seeker asks about opinion of Dadaji.
Shri Mataji: Dadaji, he’s arrested.
Warren: In Calcutta
Shri Mataji: He’s already in jail.
No, he was in Pune where he was arrested,
this Dadaji.
This happened about I think, I don’t know,
but I heard about it.
I don’t know when it happened.
No it was not because of any political thing.
But they found some income tax things and
all that and lots of, I don’t know, I didn’t
pay much attention but he’s arrested that
I know.
There are these sorts of things but the best
part of the thing is that all that is untruth
is exposed, gradually.
Whatever things they may put out, whatever
story they may put out, whatever they may
try, they may entice you, you may be interested
in them whatever it is.
But they themselves meet their end.
Because all that is falsehood has an end and
truth is endless, it is anand, it is eternal.
The truth is eternal.
Question: What do you see as the future of
the United Nations?
Shri Mataji: That’s a tricky question.
My husband is one of the secretary generals.
I better not speak all right.
Let it be.
We’ll see about it, work it out.
Some tricks we have to play.
Question: Do you know of Krishnamurti?
Shri Mataji: Oh, very much, he’s another
one.
Krishnamurti is another blah, blah, blah.
I’ll tell you about Krishnamurti very well.
You see what Krishnamurti does?
He says this part what I say that “There
are false gurus."
But I don’t say there are not real ones.
If there is falsehood, if there’s artificiality,
there has to be real.
If there are artificial flowers there has
to be a real flower, too.
So he negates you from the other side completely
and he puts up your ego by saying, “Oh you
can find it,” so you are finished.
He’s a blind leading others into blindness.
(Delete-Yogi relates story of a seeker about
his meeting with Krishnamurti to Shri Mataji.
He saw him personally asks him “why do you
do what you do” and Krishnamurti said, “Does
a rose ask why?”)
Shri Mataji: I mean it has no awareness, simple
answer is as that.
A rose has no awareness.
By any chance he’s not a rose.
he’s just thorns that’s what I know.
Those who have come from him have had a very
bad time I must tell you.
You see they are really so depressed and so
horrid.
We had one architect; I mean his life was
finished.
So many of them I’ve met, horrible they’re
very argumentative.
The best example I’ll give you about this
because you’ve brought forth.
There was a fellow who came to see Me, he’s
the grandson of his guru.
His guru was Yogananda, Yogananda, the Kriya
yogis, you see.
He was the grandson of the Dadaji or something,
Babaji, called Dadaji then Babaji
are there.
This Babaji, his grandson, you see, his Yogananda’s
guru was somebody else, and he was the son
of this fellow, but I mean the grandson of
his guru, so the great grandson of Babaji.
So the whole family was Kriya and he did all
the Kriya Yoga and everything he did.
He went there and he got so frightened.
One day he happened to see this Krishnamurti
that there should be no he said, “No Kriya
and all that, you see, that you are your own
guru,” and this and that."
So he said, “Oh God, what have I been doing?”
So he gave up Kriya Yoga and came to Mr.
Krishnamurti.
He said, “I became such an expert that I
spoke better than Krishnamurti did."
And everybody was surprised and said, “Second
Krishnamurti is coming and I ran away for
there.
I said, “Now this is that thing is happening
to Me.
And he came to Me, you’ll be amazed I’ve
not been able to give him realisation till
today.
I must tell you this, he comes to Me still
often.
Often, very often he comes to Me.
I’ve not yet given him realisation.
Imagine the grandson of this Babaji has to
bear I don’t know what things, poor things
has been done to him, I ‘m very sorry for
him.
Question: Do you know Rajneesh?
Shri Mataji: He’s another horrible one.
Why do you need a guru for such a thing?
You are masters, he’s a fool, he doesn’t
know compared to what you know.
But you see what you thought of, that inside
you are human beings, you feel guilty that
you talk of sex with animals, sex with this,
this, that.
If there’s something lurking in you, there’s
something wrong in all this perversion and
homosexuality this that and all that.
So you thought it better to have a guru at
least he’ll certify.
But he is going to make you take two running
jumps to go to hell, I tell you.
And he talks, just there and he talks, “That
you’ll go to bottomless pit,” in the bible
a bottomless pit is the hell.
You see he’s very honest in a way, he says
so.
He said, “You’ll go to bottomless pit."
He has criticised Christ to such an extent
that he said that Christ had bad relations
with his own Mother.
Oh to that extent, he said about Mohammad
having bad relation with his daughter.
All sorts of things he is talking and you
know people publish it.
He’s getting such a publicity.
He pays money to people that they write against
Me and doing all kinds of things.
Indians don’t like him at all, at all, they
hate him, they want him to get out but he’s
so localised he cannot smell a flower and
he calls himself Bhagavan, means God.
In the book you see, anywhere you read, any
Indian book where they have described God,
the names of God, they’re thousand names
supposing, of Vishnu or of the Goddess, anything.
At least fifteen or twenty of them are that
they are fond of flowers, they’re fond of
fragrance, they’re fragrant.
That they’re fond of Kamalas, Champas they’re
fond this that all is there and this fellow
cannot see, if you show a flower to him he’ll
run away.
He cannot bear to have any incense being burnt
anywhere.
When you go there you they see and you can
only put phenyl to go and see him.
I think he’s a bathroom cleaner, that’s
what he is.
The way he’s so much afraid.
I don’t know what he likes the bathroom
smell.
And he does all dirty things, very dirty fellow,
is filthy I don’t want to tell you what
he does but I know what he does.
Question: Could you explain the meaning of
satoori and samadhi.
Shri Mataji:That’s Zen.
You see Zen satoori is the same as samadhi
but it’s a, you see the Zen were as I told
you in six centuries were twenty-six and whatever
they wrote people never understood you see.
Because they were realised souls, some of
them were born realised, some got realisation.
Now even when you will talk people won’t
understand you, it’s a very surprise thing.
But it happens like that because your language
changes.
Now they call it satoori is a samadhi but
it’s not so clearly given, they could not
explain so clearly about it not properly to
people, it’s not so clear cut.
Now in our Sahaja Yoga we have first of all
Nirvichara samadhi.
Samadhi, dhi means awareness, and samadhi
means enlightened awareness.
Nirvichara means thoughtless.
Thoughtless enlightened awareness is first
thing, is clear.
Sahaja Yoga is very clear cut practical, every
word of it.
You see it so clearly there’s no vagueness
about it.
Even you’ll understand Bible better, Zen
better, everything better if you know Sahaja
Yoga because your eyes are open to it, all
right.
So the first thing is Nirvichara Samadhi.
With Nirvichara Samadhi when it crosses your
Agnya chakra you get Nirvichara, means when
your ego is pulled down.
With that you get powers.
Like you see if you become a deputy governor
you get powers if you become a governor you
get powers.
The first powers you get is curative powers.
You get cured and you can cure others.
Many people whom I have cured are not Sahaja
yogis they’re useless people actually.
I’ve given up curing people for the same
reason because they just come for cures they
get cured and lost.
What’s the use of curing people who are
not going to give the light?
You see you don’t repair lights which are
not going to work out.
It’s a horrible stuff you see, curing people,
but you do cure.
You start curing people automatically with
raising [sounds like das?] not with spirit.
There are another faith healers and all that
nonsense is not there.
Also Kundalini can rise to a point with a
person like that.
But one should not stay at that point must
go higher.
Because the movement on right and left you
start getting either supra conscious or your
subconscious experiences which can be very
alluring and you can be quite lost in them.
You start seeing lights, you start seeing
something different, you might see an aura
around Me.
I mean you see lots of things, you may see
something else in My past , that should not
be there.
You should forget about it.
You have to go to the airport to catch the
plane isn’t it, so don’t see all the things
around, it’s all not wanted.
Many people get lost at that point when they
stop at Agnya, if you have concentrated here
this can happen more because this is broken
or if you have had this third eye business
and all that you may go to the side.
It can be quite dangerous.
You see if you use these your samadhi for
some sort of a sensation.
So you should not.
I mean all wise people should not use this
movement at all, as far as possible say, “No
we don’t want to see that.
We don’t want to have any supra conscious
sensation,” and all that.
Then you rise higher and then you try to feel
your silence in the limbic area and you have
to feel your vibrations coming out from your
head.
It is the vibrations when they are flowing
that’s the best stage, when you have pierced
through your Bramarundra.
So the second stage starts from Nirvikalpa
Samadhi growing into, which many of the Sahaja
Yogis have achieved in Australia, is called
as Nirvikalpa, where the is no doubts.
You have no doubts left about Sahaja Yoga,
you have no doubts left about yourself.
It’s a state, it’s not that by mentally
or rationally but it’s a state.
Where you see it so clearly, white is white,
you don’t have to doubt that whether my
eyes are showing white or black, you see.
That state is reached is called as Nirvikalpa
where the no vikalpa, you just go, move steadily
and that’s the best stage where you really
grow faster because you’re so steady and
that stage must be achieved.
So try to achieve that stage through negating
things, “Nethi, nethi, vachinay nigamoor,”
by saying, “Not this, not this, not this,”
and you reach that stage, is very clearly
given.
You see the trouble is, so many of these books
which are so great are never translated, people
do not know about them.
Now after coming to Sahaja Yoga you will be
exposed to them and you will see what truths
there are and how Sahaja Yoga verifies it
and proves it.
Question: What influence are you likely to
have on those around him or on people who
live with You who are not realised.
What is the realised souls influence in that
type of environment?
Shri Mataji:You see if you have stones and
if you have living trees, stones do not receive
anything from the sun but the leaves receive
something isn’t it, they are more sensitive,
that’s the difference.
Then in Sahaja yoga there’s a possibility
that you can convert stones into living beings,
can be done.
Yes, because they see, you see they see you,
they understand the value that you are, gradually,
rationally they start understanding then they
reach certain conclusions, then they come
to Sahaja Yog, then they get realised, it
works out that way.
But with seekers it’s very different, seekers
just jump into it.
They do not think about it they just get it.
They get it so fast that they don’t think
about it, they just they get it.
So they are so sensitive that’s the difference.
Question: Can we help our loved ones who do
not want to listen to anything particularly
about Sahaja Yoga?
Shri Mataji: You see there’s nobody else
that you help someone, they are all within
yourself.
On the contrary, I would say better to have
them together who are Sahaja yogis because
those who are not will trouble you, it will
be a problem, leave them alone, they’ll
be all right, they’ll come round.
Let them come on their own you cannot force
them, they’re loved ones, you’ll change
now your priorities, you’ll understand that
those who are really loved ones are not really
your brothers and sisters.
As Christ has said, “Who are my brothers
and sisters?” Now we have to ask that question.
Because you speak another language, you are
a different person, not that you give them
up, but they exist.
But they haven’t got your awareness so is
a different thing all together.
But you help them in a way, gradually they
see you but if you force them they’ll run
away.
No use forcing or telling them anything about
it but you show your satisfaction and happiness
and your growth and others get impressed by
it and they just come to you.
Question: how can you..Do You help them?
Shri Mataji: Yes, I do.
But you should put them out of your minds
and say, “Mother, You help.
If You try to help, then I’ll leave it to
You."
Question: He cannot understand why You say
that Christ died for us.
Why did He die for us?
Shri Mataji: What else could He have done
with the stupid people?
They crucified Him, He didn’t say, “You
come and crucify Me,” did He, you see?
They’re stupid, horrible people, donkeys.
They didn’t understand Him, stones as they
were what to do?
They crucified Him, He didn’t ask.
But when He was crucified the sins that they
committed in crucifying Him were to be forgiven.
That’s what it is.
He was, what did He do?
You see He died because of you because people
like you only crucified Him.
You represent them.
When you are realised then you are different
people, then you are resurrected.
His message was resurrection not crucifixion
but that shows the stupidity of these people,
isn’t it.
I mean you may do that again I can’t say,
there are people.
Question: Is it possible to exercise love
and acceptance when as she says You’re judging
people as to whether they’re right or wrong.
Warren: We are using vibrations
Shri Mataji: I am not judging, you are judging
because when you get your vibrations you start
judging yourself.
You see I am not judging it’s only your
own judgment.
It’s your own judgment.
Are you getting your cool breeze in the hands?
No, then let it happen.
I’m not judging you it’s you are judging
it yourself.
All right, then you will know yourself.
Just now you are judging that you’re not
getting vibrations.
Question: Is it true that Indira Gandi is
worshiped as a Goddess?
Shri Mataji: oh don't, That's all political
stuff, you see Indian people are like that.
Warren: that's useless
Question: She’s confused about the fact
that You talked about love and acceptance
at the beginning but then when peoples names
were brought up we often scoffed at them.
Shri Mataji: ah About the gurus?
Ah, that’s it.
It’s a very important point.
That’s very much with you people.
You see you have all of you, you see have
developed a philosophy where you say that
nobody is evil, everything is fine.
This is a very good philosophy to work with
because you also fit into the thing.
That nothing is evil about you also, isn’t
it?
It happens like that.
You remember when Christ was criticising these
horrible people they asked Him, “How do
You criticise them?
They do not criticise You."
Then He said, “Will the devil talk against
its own house?”
There is a negative force working, very much
active and you have to not only scoff but
get rid of these things because they are acting
as your destroying forces and they destroy
you, I see them very clearly and I have to
tell you.
So love doesn’t mean that I love a snake,
will you go and love a snake, a snake must
understand first of all.
In the same way we have to understand there
are evil people, that’s true.
That is what is very much in the West, I see,
“Oh, you love everyone is all right.
But you don’t love a snake, do you?
Go and have, ask snake, “I want to love
you."
He’ll just finish you off.
So many of you are harmed so much by these
people and I have to cure you.
You don’t know what I have to go through,
such a lot of work to cure you when you are
affected by these people.
You don’t know how much I’ve worked, morning
till evening.
This morning I started six o’clock till
I came here just ten minutes I got to change
My sari and I was here.
These are affected by other gurus and things
and I have to take it out.
I know what harm they have done to you.
You have no idea.
Question: What are Your objections to chanting
and singing the holy scriptures?
Shri Mataji: Not at all, who told you I am,
I’m not but you must understand that without
understanding what chanting is needed it’s
like a medicine.
Chanting is a mantra.
Mantra means a thing that acts as a sound
to correct a particular thing within you,
all right.
It’s you can say sound therapy it is, all
right.
Now you have to know what medicine is needed
for which charka, also you must know where
is the problem with you, or with anybody else.
I mean it would be chanting at random means
sometimes it would be sort of an indiscriminate
drinking of all the medicines, you see.
Taking all the medicines bottles into your
stomach emptying them without understanding.
We do chant but we know where to chant, what.
You see, not indiscriminate, just like that.
And it’s very dangerous because when you
go on chanting say, Rama’s name or Krishna’s
name.
Now when you say Krishna’s name, Krishna
is here, if your Kundalini has not reached
there up to this point if you take Krishna’s
name it’s very, very annoying for Krishna
Himself and He recedes, sleeps off.
He freezes sometimes and by that you develop
problems of the chakras and sometimes you
develop throat cancer, it’s very serious.
So first, you must know where is your Kundalini,
where it has gone, where it has stopped.
Then you should know what is the problem,
then you must know what exactly is the chanting
to be used, all right, and then cure that
part.
You see so it’s a big science, which has
to be understood in Sahaja Yoga, it’s not
at random.
You are suffering from whatever trouble you
are suffering from, you must know first of
all.
See many people who are Christians catch on
Agnya I told you, they do, because it’s
unauthorised.
Christ, we treat Him as if I don’t know
what, some passion fruit hanging in a tree.
Do we know who He is?
There is a protocol, great protocol.
Even Brahma, Vishnu Mahesh could not reach
Him.
So for us because we think we are born among
Christian families and because the church
has given us a certificate so called do you
think we are authorised to chant His name
all the time and trouble Him?
And what do we ask?
Do we ask for our spirits?
Do we ask to give our realisation?
Do we ask that we have to be born again?
No, what do we ask something nonsensical.
Question: What is Your opinion about practicing
spiritualists.
Shri Mataji: Very dangerous, never go near
them.
Never touch them even with a barge pole, horrible
things they are.
You see it is very simple to understand that
if you get connected with any area what so
ever, and somebody is connected to that area
you are exposed to that and there can be any
indiscriminate aggression on you from that
area.
You would not know who’s coming on you.
So never go near them.
May be you want to talk to your father say,
whose dead, you want to talk to him.
Why?
Release him, free him, why do you want to
talk to him?
Now let him be alone, let him decide for himself
what he wants to do.
Why do you want him to hang around?
It’s too much, it’s too much of a load.
Then you want to, when you use some medium
for that you do not know he might get somebody
else.
It’s very dangerous for your children also,
so many children have died with this kind
of a thing.
I mean you develop especially cancer, this
multiple scleroses or anything like that.
All these come from spiritualists.
These are all spiritualists, these gurus are
spiritualists only.
They’ll believe is spirits, they’ll handle
the spirits they’re working out, these are
very dangerous things I may be able to tell
you some time how they work it out and how
they master it.
It’s very dangerous.
They’re like vampires, what you call it,
vampires.
More surprising is that there are so many
things in English language, which we don’t
have, like witchcraft and the witches were
sort of punished, all sorts of things are
there.
In England, they talk of all these things
supernatural and all this but still I don’t
know how they go into it.
Warren: somebody asked me a question on the
way up.
Is it wrong to be a medium?
This relates to the previous question, so
perhaps you could answer that Mother?
Shri Mataji: Oh God, I need not tell, it’s
very, very wrong to play into the hands of
the spirits.
You are enslaved completely; you don’t know
what happens to you.
Horrible, it creates problems absolutely you’re
an abnormal personality.
Never do it.
It’s sinful, sinful.
If you accept My words really it’s horrible,
never do that.
Question: What is the difference between western
spirituality and eastern spirituality?
Shri Mataji:Now this word spirituality means
by these spiritualists you mean?
Warren: No.
Philosophy
Shri Mataji: Is just the same, spirit is just
the same.
Is universal, there is no difference at all,
I do not find any difference.
Spirituality means the spirit that is the
Atma, you mean the spirit that is the Atma,
the one....
Question: I’m talking more about the quest
for the spirit.
Shri Mataji: Search is just the same.
But Indians you see now, modern Indians are
sort of developing you see, they have to go
to that height to see where you have landed
yourself.
See they can short circuit, they can short
circuit if they want but if they want they
may have to go to various types of problems
you had with that affluence and they may come
back.
But it is better to short circuit it I tell
them.
While yours is a problem so easy because you
have discovered now that matter is not sufficient.
Matter doesn’t give us joy, no use running
after matter.
But still some of them are running after sex
you see and all that.
They have to finish another circuit, once
they are over with that also then things will
be better.
But in all this kind of a quest you have lost
something indefinitely, no doubt.
Going through the matter, going through the
sex and going through the power all these
trips you see you have lost something, which
requires correction.
While Indians if they understand with their
wisdom they better short circuit this need
not go into plastics and nylons.
You see I have to carry nylon saris from England
for Indians while they have their silks they
want to wear nylon.
So this is the difference in the basic development.
But Indians if they take to Sahaja Yoga they’re
very good and easy, especially Indian villagers
are excellent.
They don’t understand all this they have
no mental problems you see.
I don’t have to discuss with them all these
things, they have not gone into all this nonsense
so they suddenly become beautiful fruits,
that’s all.
So this is the difference of little degrees
I would say that you are gone to other extreme
and you still have to move to that extreme
or they may finish off and we can achieve
results.
But your quest is much ardent, very sincere
and truth.
One more thing I always felt and today also
I feel that really some great souls are born
in the west, that’s why is such a sincere
desire, very sincere in their desire.
Indians first they come to Me for curing,
if not for curing for getting children if
not for that for jobs or money all sorts of
thing they come up.
Or they’ll say, “My mother is sick, my
father is sick, my brother is this,” all
this goes on.
But I have met many, many seekers in the west
who just want realisation, very beautiful
people no doubt.
But you have lost something in your seeking,
no doubt, doesn’t matter.
Kundalini is that ardent desire within you,
which works it out.
Question: It seems as though the simpler the
life we lead the better we are, it is much
easier for us.
We get away from thinking and so on.
Shri Mataji: I agree is a good idea of simplicity
but is a, you must understand that also very
clearly because we had somebody who was a
hippy I should say.
He was a real hippy, such big grown, he had
grown hair up to this much and all that.
He came to Me and scarcely wearing anything
in the horrible English cold you see.
I said, “What are you doing to yourself
why don’t you clad your self properly into
proper clothes and better cover yourself,”
and I was really didn’t understand him.
I said, “You are not living in Africa why
are you dressed up like this, it’s like
a primitive dress."
He said, “I want to be primitive."
I said, “You cannot by dressing up.
Your brain is so over developed how can you
be primitive."
You see by dressing up something do you become
that.
I mean it’s just a drama you are playing
with yourself, you do not become primitive.
This is the point is that and then the problem
is the brain is thinking the same way, that
the same rate and everything the same, only
by changing is something that is not good
because you should accept as you are.
Why to do something like that?
But simpler life means this way, that’s
another extreme.
But you see too much of formality like having
a tail coat or wearing morning dress, grey
suit and then having a particular type of
a glass for a thing and all that nonsense
you see you better finish off.
That’s bit too much going too far with it
and also caring for all these small, small
things like matter that’s something that’s
grown in you.
Preservation of horrible things and useless
things and all that it’s [really?].
And then to think, think, think, think about
everything, sit down and think how miserable
I am and when there is no misery you just
sit down and make miseries by thinking.
I don’t find any thing miserable here, what
is there?
You see in India these people where there
people are so happy, chirping just like birds
enjoying themselves.
They don’t have all the things that you
have.
So you see to get out of materialism is a
better idea, to say that a simpler life means,
but you must live beautifully.
Beautiful doesn’t mean that you should have
ten types of things and all that.
Beautifully means you should not be as a morbid
stinking, you see.
Clean and beautiful you can make beauty out
of the soil anything; with love, you can do
anything.
So you see it’s alright I mean what ever
way you dress up or anything makes no difference
that’s what I’m trying to say.
That it is the inner thing that has to change
not the outer.
Again the Sahaja Yoga is this.