I am happy to know so many of you have come
here and I feel this is a very important puja,
not only for Australia but for the whole world,
because it has the greatest message which
we have actualized now in Sahaja yoga. We
have to understand the message of Christ.
There are many people in this world who try
to show off that they are very great rationalists
and that they have a right to pass any remark
they like about Christ.
I was reading the newspapers today. I was
surprised where they are all saying one by
one that, "I reject this part of Christ that
He was born with Immaculate Conception. I
reject that He was resurrected. I reject this
and I reject that." Who are you? Because you
can write, because you have a flair, how can
you say such things? Just without finding
out. You are a scholar, maybe you are very
well read, maybe that you think you are capable
of saying whatever you like about any subject,
but subject of spirituality cannot be dealt
by people who are not even self-realized.
Because it's a very divine life, it's a very
different life. It's a area where your mind
cannot enter. It is beyond the mind. And so
the poets or artists, all of them who have
worked on Christ's life and have tried to
say things about Him, mostly were realized
souls and if they were not, they could not
do any justice to His life.
It's very surprising that I should be celebrating
this resurrection in Australia. You know this
is the country of mooladhara, and mooladhara
itself then expresses itself or manifests
in the agnya. So, such a great connection
you have that first of all is the country
where mooladhara is established, was established
I should say, and later on that it was manifested
in the life of Christ on the agnya center.
I must say that you have really created some
very great people signifying this beautiful
manifestation because, as you have Dr. Bogdan
who is an Australian, in the sense that he
lived here and then he went back to Russia
which is the right agnya, where he worked.
In the same way, as Sahaja yoga has prospered
here to begin with, among all the European
countries, or we can say, among all the countries
which were not Indian, maximum growth took
place in Australia and the maximum growth
now first took place in the Eastern Bloc,
in Russia.
Now the other part of the agnya is China.
And it is you people only... out of you only
some people have to look after that. And as
it is you're all looking after Taiwan, Hong
Kong, Thailand. All these are Chinese races.
Apart from that, they worship Buddha. It's
very interesting. Buddha, as you know, is
on the left side of your medha, as they call
it, this is the medha plate, is the lower
plate of the brain. So the Christ is in the
center and we've got Buddha on the left side.
Or, you also are looking after the countries
which are influenced by Buddha. It's all working
out like a plan. Perhaps you're not aware
of it, that we are all people belonging to
one Virata and that our needs or our work,
all of them have great significance and connection.
About Australia, there's a myth in India that
there was a big saint and he was very good,
but somehow he made some mistakes... or maybe
lots of mistakes. So God cursed him and said
you better go away from India. It was connecting
India and Africa. So the land was brought
down to this point. He gave him the land - God
- and He said, "Now you resurrect this land
and make something out of it." And this star
is called as this Trishanku [MEANS As per
Indian Mythology, a saint king who wished
to go to heaven alive, but was stopped & kept
hanging in between by Gods, as he was being
sent by Sage Vishwamitra, and then became
a star], which is your Southern Cross. This
Southern Cross is called as Trishanku, as
in... mentioned in our Puranas [MEANS One
type of Indian scriptures] as this saint who
became like that and God made him into a star
which is hanging. Trishanku is hanging on
top of this land and is working out the building
up of this country. He was told that you go
there and make a heaven for the human beings.
This has so many mythological and historical
backgrounds.
And there are some very good points also I
have seen about Australia, which are very
surprising because they believe in the multi-racial
society and they preserve it. They try to
help the people through justice if some people
are troubled and tortured. It's a very bold
attitude towards progress that we should have
multicultural society and this comes, again
I would say, after resurrection of political
thought. America is multicultural society,
full of it, and as a result of that, as a
result of that they have progressed very much
financially. But they didn't learn anything
from the multicultural society. For example,
Spanish went there. Spanish, as you know,
are bullfighters. They went and destroyed
all the cultures of the ancient times and
the new people who have gone, they don't have
any rapport with them. Like Indians have a
separate identity, then we have other cultures
like Islamic and all that, so they don't keep
any connection with them. The original aboriginals
are also kept out as something very low-level.
But here I find people have a curiosity and
also knowledge about the other cultures which
are around them. That shows the sense of collectivity
is within your genes, we can say, that it
is working out in such a way that this country
believes still in the multicultural society.
All these are manifestation of Shri Ganesha's
quality. See if you have, say, a group of
even ten people with husband and wife and
they don't have the purity of Shri Ganesha,
they cannot exist because there will be always
a very great conflict between husband and
wife. Also, not only the conflict part, but
people will become extremely superficial.
Like, in America a woman would marry a man
because he wears such and such dress; or a
woman is appreciated because she has a particular
type of hairstyle. If the hairstyle changes,
the man can ask for a divorce. So superficial
they are. The fight is with the husband that
you didn't buy a particular coat which I liked,
so there's a divorce. It's so superficial.
So the relationship between husband and wife
is established by Shri Ganesh and He gives
you the pure idea about how to enjoy your
married life. Why people like Freud become
so important? They start replacing Christ
and people become enamored by that. Because
human beings, if they know that in potential
state they are all divine, they all have to
become divine and not to go down to the level
of animals, even worse than that. If they
realize it that their main object of life
is resurrection, that they have to rise above
all these so-called temptations of life. If
they know this potential, then they have to
believe in it also, so that they do not have
these absurd ideas about life.
As a human being, Christ came. He came as
a human being, but He was not a human being.
He was divine. Absolutely He was nothing but
Aumkara. That's why He could walk on the water.
There was nothing materialistic in Him, you
can say, no matter in Him. If there was any
matter, He could not have walked on the water.
But if people start discarding all these facts,
about His birth, about His walking on the
water and all that, then what is left of Christ,
I can't understand.
Now this message of His resurrection is very
important, but what you find that, as you
get three days holidays, people are just doing
what one should not do. They have gone to
some places, maybe with their wives, may not
be with their wives, with anybody, into some
sort of a rubbish and they enjoy things which
cannot be enjoyed by anybody who is a realized
soul. So we have to know ourself that now
we have got our realization. We got it. Not
that it is in a potential state, but it is
in a kinetic state. So, for us Christ should
be a model, what kind of life we should lead.
In those days of Christ, there were no aeroplanes,
there were no cars, nothing, but He went from
places to places and talked to them about
spiritual life. The people were not yet evolved.
They were not matured enough. So He could
not give them realization, but He talked about
dharmic life. He went to the extreme of the
ten commandments that He said not only that
you should not do adultery, but you should
not even have adulterous eyes. Pure eyes.
Now how is it possible? When you see Christians
and Christian nations, they suffer from this
disease of not having at all clean eyes. There's
a kind of a lust and greed in the eye and
they're not ashamed of it.
Thank God, Sahaja Yogis all over the world
have changed so much, transformed so much.
They've become so beautiful that this problem
we don't have. And if somebody has it, we
want that person to get out of Sahaja yoga
till they cure themselves and come to normal.
The main problem of the Christian nation is
that they have become too much mental. Even
sex they do mentally, in the sense [that]
they flirt. The eyes are so much all the time
looking at something and reacting to it. They
cannot witness anything. Anything they'll
see they start thinking about it, react to
it. Then the reaction, because they are not
evolved, can take them to any level of bestiality
- Worse than beasts. For example, an innocent
person sees something, he goes into thoughtless
awareness and he just enjoys the beauty of
that; but a person who is full of lust and
greed can never enjoy anything. On the contrary,
he would like to possess that thing or would
go beyond limits of his authority and enjoy
somebody else's wife, somebody else's husband.
It's a very subtle thing, which we should
understand when we make friendship with others.
What do we enjoy in the friendship? What do
we see in that friendship? As realized soul,
how your friendship should be? The friendship
should be pure - nirvajya. That is, you're
friendly with somebody because just you enjoy
the pure friendship, where there's no sense
of possession or also the sense of destruction.
Such a friendship is a Sahaj friendship. I
have seen people all over the world, when
they come to Ganapatipule, the way they laugh,
the way they enjoy and I feel so happy there's
this new world of such innocent people has
been created on this Earth in My lifetime.
You should also realize that you belong now
to a very higher type of people, very higher
type. There's no justification for any Sahaja
Yogi to indulge into such dirty stuff, because
he is beyond it. He has developed a new sense
of beauty and cleanliness. He cannot bear
anything, which makes him look like a person
who goes towards all kinds of filthy things.
This is a specialty, which you have got it,
which was potentially within you and despite
the atmosphere in which you lived and you
saw, you just got out of it and became like
beautiful lotuses in the pond of filth. And
these lotuses themselves can give such beautiful
fragrance to others that they can make the
whole pond fragrant and beautiful.
So the responsibility on you is much more
than, I would say, on Christ because Christ
was divine. I was asking them to get Devi
Mahatmyam, if possible. In that He's described
as the son of Lord Krishna and Radhaji and
that He has been given a special power and
is called as a Support of the Universe. Just
imagine. Mooladhar. He is the Support of the
Universe. And the birth is described in a
beautiful way that first He was created like
an egg. This purity, this auspiciousness was
made into an egg. That's why during Easter
you people give eggs to friends. Now this
egg was nicely also kept for ages and then
it was broken into two. The first one became
Shri Ganesha and the second one, which evolved
fully... like an egg when it is evolved and
is fully mature, the second one was Christ.
You may say that, "How is it one egg has two
forms?" I must say these are divine happenings.
They have very different from what we see
in the mundane world.
Now, this egg, the second part of it, became
a child and He was crying for His Father.
All His life, Christ talked for His Father
and when He knew He] will be crucified, He
prayed to His Father saying that "Oh Father,
save Me from this cup of crucifixion," He
prayed. And if you see His two fingers, these
two fingers are always out - expression of
His blessing. This is the one, which stands,
as you know very well, for Shri Krishna, and
this one for Vishnu.
So always He showed these two fingers. There
are so many things by which we can, as Sahaja
Yogis, find out how Christ has been ruling
throughout. He is not dead. His body might
have been perished in Kashmir, as they say,
but He was the spirit and the spirit that
was in Him was a living, eternally living,
great personality. We may say that He might
have had little bit of, we can say, the human
aspect to camouflage Himself, after all spirit
just cannot come in, and that might have been
dead, that part, that camouflage that He was
using.
In divinity, as Ganesha is pure, He is absolutely
beyond any kind of contamination. Other incarnations
who came on this Earth, they had to do many
things. Like Shri Krishna had to go in the
war of Mahabharata. Rama had to go in the
jungle to deal with people. Same with Christ,
we can say, that He did go to all these places,
but He never behaved like a human being. Others
did. Shri Rama cried a lot, wept a lot for
His wife. Then Shri Krishna married so many
times - because they were His powers so He
married them.
So, though they were incarnations, they had
to very much do the things which human beings
do. Christ was never married. He never wept,
as far as we know, except when He was praying
to His Father. He just asked that "If You
could remove this cup from My mouth I'll be
very happy."
So it's shown in His character that He came
on this Earth as a divine personality, lived
as a divine personality and died as a divine
personality. I think that way it is much easier
to be because you are a divine person, you
come, give some sermons, lectures, this, that
and just go away.
He didn't take the responsibility of giving
realization to people, which is the greatest
headache, I think, to give realizations to
people. Because, if you give them the resurrection,
if they get their realization... Christ accepted
His resurrection as a natural thing because
He knew all about it, and that He didn't have
to change. He didn't have to transform Himself.
He was the same as He was because He did not
need any resurrection. He just tried to show
in His life that we human beings can have
our realization and we can be resurrected.
His message is not the cross but the resurrection
and this resurrection if you understand, then
one can understand also one more thing - that
we are now resurrected from ordinary human
beings to the divine level.
It was easier for Christ because He didn't
have to face any problems, while you are coming
out of that human life to a such a higher
life. Suddenly, it is too much. I agree. It
is too much to accept. But because you go
beyond your mind, it's not difficult - because
your mind stops thinking. Otherwise, normally
people would have been thinking, "Now, I am
resurrected. All right. So what should I do?
What should I drop out? What things should
go away? What is the goal?" All these ideas
of human beings would have followed you slowly.
But no, you just felt, "We are there. Now
what to do? We are there." You became conscious
of your qualities, of your virtues, of your
greatness and those who were conscious became
very confident that we have these values already
existing within us; we have these powers,
which are manifesting and these powers are
flowing through us.
Nobody doubted it. Some did, but very few.
As you grew up, immediately you knew that
the Divine is acting through you. Is there.
Everything is tangible. You know everything
about your inner being. Gradually, you start
spreading out your self, spreading out your
personality. And then you don't have the weaknesses
as human beings have. We had some funny people,
no doubt. I know that people start thinking
about how to make money out of Sahaja Yoga,
- and that's still a human nonsense going
on - or how to show your powers, how to show
how your powers can assert, how to sort of
use your ego to put down people. All these
are human style of lives and it existed for
some time, but now I find you all are washed
as if through this kundalini has just washed
you completely.
You all have become very beautiful people,
extremely beautiful, and even people... they
see you at the airport and they think that
these are some unique people. Even in this
area when we came, they were telling Me that...
the gentleman who is the caretaker was saying
that he has never seen such a group - "They
don't fight; they don't argue; they don't
make money; the children are so sweet. It's
remarkable, such a society in these modern
times never existed anywhere and how is it,
it is existing here?" They were quite surprised
as, also you should be, that you have achieved
this without any much effort or any penance
or going to Himalayas. You got it because
it was all there. It was all there and you
found it. Our marriages are, ninety percent
are successful. We have problems from the
parents sometimes, from the society, but it's
too little to be mentioned and it makes one
sense to Me - that we can really change this
world. No doubt about it. If you remember
that the message of Christ is resurrection,
that has already happened.
Now, after resurrection what? Your attention
should be there. If it is still on your job,
on your money, on your car, your house, this,
that, then you are still a human being. You
have not yet lost that attachment. Or on your
children and your spouses and all. That is
all being still absolutely human. But a person
who is divine has all the relations but doesn't
get attached and involved into. I've given
many a time a very good] example of the trees.
See in the tree the sap rises, goes to various
parts of the tree, either it is evaporated
or it goes back to Mother Earth. It never
gets attached to anything. As long you are
attached to your children, attached to this,
attached to that, then try to understand that
divinity has not fully manifested. That detachment
is not neglect, never. On the contrary, it
is the most pure detachment, which really
nourishes every area of your life. Wherever
you go, it nourishes. So you have to test
yourself. Nobody else has to do it. "How far
I have been kind to others? How far I have
been helpful to others? How far I have been
collective?"
I have seen glimpses of this many a times
and it has given Me great joy. Like, once
we had a program of Sahaja yogis and the gentleman
had invited Me alone for dinner. So the program
was there and I just thought that how can
all these people eat in his house, you see?
So I waited till they disappeared, all the
Sahaja Yogis disappeared. This gentleman came
to say, "Mother why did you ask them to go?
I had cooked for all of them." See this made
Me so happy. He had a small house. I don't
know how he cooked for all of them. And so
much food he had cooked already and he was
waiting - all of them to have some food, and
I just thought that it is too much for him
to feed so many people.
In the same way, we have to have this feeling
that we are all collective and we have to
help each other. It is, say in the body, if
I have any problem in any finger, any hand,
anywhere, the whole body runs for it, the
whole body suffers for it, whole body knows
about it. In the same way, in Sahaja Yoga
there should be a common feeling all over
the world. If something happens here, one
person is affected, the whole world should
know. Not only that know, but they should
make efforts. If one person is suffering,
the whole world will suffer for that and this
is what is the culmination of our collectivity.
Those who try to keep out of it, you see,
in the collectivity, cannot grow also.
About many things I have to say, but specially
I would say that when we see somebody in difficulties,
say financial difficulty, at that time we
should try to suggest or try to help that
person as just a part and parcel of the whole.
Then that person will realize that I have
so many people here. I am not alone. Somebody
might get more, somebody might get less, makes
no difference. But the activity of the collective
should be such that you should feel that oneness,
that innate feeling for another person, innate.
You not have to think about it, but is innately
you should feel attached to that person and
you should feel that you have to do something
about it. "After all, why should he not have
the same joy as I have?" So the first thing
that you will do, of such people, is normally...
is to help him in his chakras, help him in
his endeavors.
It is very easy now to do Sahaja Yoga. In
the olden times, it was very difficult. If
you had tried Sahaja Yoga say, in the early
time of Christ, you all might have been crucified.
Could be. What did Christ do after all? Why
was He crucified? But nowadays that's not
so. Then you... like other saints, any people
in India, "Thousands of years," they said,
"we have been meditating. We started our meditation
when we were nothing and now years after years,
our different births after births, we have
worked hard to get to this situation, that
now we have got realization." You don't have
that problem. There's no problem at all. Except
for one, that you have to have full assessment
of yourself, that you are the pure Spirit
and that you are in the kingdom of God. Just
like Christ - it did not matter to Him. He
had to oppose something that was wrong, He
did it. When He had to support something was
destroyed and saved, He did it. He had nothing
to do with Mary Magdalene, but when people
started stoning her, He went and stood before
her and He said, "Those who have not committed
any sin, can throw stone at her." See this
courage, this confidence was in Him because
He was a divine personality, because of divinity.
But you have become divine. In a way, you
know better about life than He knew because
He never touched all these points that you
have touched from what problems you have come
out.
So, you should have much more understanding
for people who are not in Sahaja Yoga or who
want to come to Sahaj Yoga. Like, as soon
as they come to any program, you should not
start saying, "You are a bhoot, you are that."
You were a bhoot before you came here. Quite
a big bhoot, if you ask Me, I can tell you.
But when you realize what is your importance
- now you have become qualified. You know
everything about it. When you know that this
has happened, then try just to follow few
rules about Sahaja Yoga. It's very easy for
you to follow because you are divine. No problem.
No problem. You can follow it very well, but
don't yield to human pressures that still
linger in you or may be in the society. You
keep to your own style, to your own behavior
and you'll be amazed that the rest of the
world will worship you - not hang you, but
worship you. In your lifetime, it's going
to happen. But try to understand that you
are being resurrected for a purpose, and that
purpose is to transform this world into a
beautiful place for which all of you should,
with full attention, with full understanding
about yourself, about your responsibilities,
should jump into it.
Australia has a special responsibility. As
I told you, some are so over-responsible and
some are not at all. I can't understand why
it is so, why it (is) happening like that.
I see people who are so attentive and some
whose attention is still not all right - moving
like this, moving like that. So, you should
try to follow people who have reached a certain
height. Try to follow their life, their lifestyle
and then you will be amazed that you can do
it very easily because you are mature. It's
like, I have said that we are like an egg
and it has to be hatched once you are mature,
but some chicks come out and just start walking
nicely, with little, little legs you see them
very nicely walking towards the mother. And
the others are still there covered with all
kinds of filth on them and not able to walk
and then these ones who can walk just bring
them, you see, they poke them with their beaks
and say, "Come along, come along, come along"
and they bring it to the mother. It's very
interesting. You must watch them.
This Easter has a great meaning that we are
now newly born chicks and we have to now follow
a new path. It's a very simple path, but still
we are conditioned so we are afraid, maybe,
or we have an ego, whatever it is. So drop
out all these things. Just humble down and
just start walking on this path of Sahaj and
one day Australia should be able to cover
the whole world. I can't see why not? After
all you are the mooladhara and the mooladhara
must play its own role as the wisest people.
Wisdom is the power that you get from Shri
Ganesh. So you have to be wise, absolutely
wise and know that you have been seekers.
You didn't get it because I asked you or we
paid you or anything, but you were seekers
struggling to know the truth and that's how
you got it and once you have got it, you should
establish it fully in your life and also in
the lives of others. Let others also feel
this gentleman is very unique or this lady
is very unique. She's very different, she's
not selfish, she's not cunning, she doesn't
manipulate, but somehow by her character,
by her nature she is trying to create light
for us and enlighten our path, enlighten the
path of others.
May God bless you all.
Of course, today we must have Shri Ganesha's
puja for doubly reasons because of Australia
and because of Christ. It's very important
that our Ganesha must be beautifully fixed.
And that His light should really emit in our
day to day lifestyle and also it shows on
our face, in our eyes because you know the
eyes are governed by Christ himself. And where
the light comes in, you see, when you get
your realization, the tingling in the eye
comes because of His awakening within us.
So, we have to today really pray that we should
have that magnificent character of Christ
which was expressing Ganesha's or manifesting
Ganesha's qualities.
[ASIDE: Attharvasheesh karna chahiye. To per
dhulva do (MEANS Let's do Ganesha Attharvasheesha.
So get the feet washed)]
Now children have to come up here: I think,
say 5 to 10, the children can come up.