Shri Mataji: I bow to all the seekers
of truth.
[Short introduction of Shri Mataji
in Arabic by the Tunisian interviewer.]
Interviewer (Lady): Shri Mataji, which are
the benefits one can get from Sahaja Yoga
and what is special about this technique?
Shri Mataji: First of all, one has to know
that it is the breakthrough
into a new awareness and the last
breakthrough of our evolution.
The benefits are, first of all,
that the fundamental energy centres
within us are called as chakras,
and they are responsible for our physical,
mental, emotional and spiritual being.
So when this power, which is a Kundalini
in the triangular bone called as sacrum -
that shows the Greeks knew it was
a sacred bone -
which is awakened and passes through
six centres,
as a result, these centres are integrated
and are nourished and enlightened.
So your physical, mental, emotional and
spiritual problems are solved.
As a result also your financial, political
and income problems are also solved,
because you become a transformed
personality.
And when this transformed personality
starts behaving in a manner
that is so congenial to spirituality,
people are amazed!
Now our problem is that we don’t know
the absolute truth.
By this you know the absolute truth and you
become empowered
that you can give Realization to others.
You can solve their problems.
So it is something that, like one
enlightened light can enlighten many.
This is Resurrection as described
in the Koran.
[Question in Arabic and in French what
are Shri Mataji’s feeling about Tunisia.]
Interviewer (Lady): Shri Mataji, which is
your feeling coming to Tunisia?
Shri Mataji: I think, it’s a very spiritual
place.
Then I heard that there was a great saint
who died here.
That is, I could feel it that his blessings
are here on this country.
And there is such a balance, I’ve seen,
the women are treated so well
in this Islamic country, it’s something
remarkable.
And a thing of hope for all the women
of the world in Islamic countries
who are really suffering very much.
Interviewer: Thank you very much,
“merci, madame”.