I am sorry, I was dealing with some newspaper people, journalists,
and they came very late,
whatever it is.
I found them to be very sensible
and very understanding.
All of us have come to Aurangabad now,
and it seems this place is full of vibrations.
Maybe here Shalivahana has ruled in this area,
but also there have been many saints
who were born on this side of Maharashtra,
and they perpetuated Dharma.
They always talked about self-realization.
Dharma gives you the balance.
It gives you the establishment
into proper behaviour,
proper understanding,
proper living,
but it doesn't give you the completion of your journey.
It doesn't give you the satisfaction of reaching the destination.
And your personality is still incomplete.
So, one has to have the experience of the spirit.
As I was discussing with them today,
I told them that those who do not have ...
the experience of the spirit ...
are not only incomplete, but are limited people.
So whatever they see, or whatever they know,
or whatever they criticize, is limited.
As in English we say that "hate the sin and not the sinner".
Like many people who find something wrong with Christianity
start blaming Christ.
Christ did not created Christianity, first of all.
He did not create Christianity.
He did not create Christians.
So there is no relationship between the two.
As you know, recently, they have found out
the books written by Thomas,
the disciple of Christ who was coming to India.
On his way he went to Egypt,
and there he wrote these treatise
and had put them in a big earthen vessel,
or perhaps it was a metallic thing,
and it was discovered fourty-two years back.
The people ...
whom he considers to be ...
authorized Christians, he calls them as Gnostic.
"Gne", "gne" in Sanskrit language means, "to know".
"Gne" means "to know".
And he has written that to know,
and to have the personal experience
is the only way to follow Christ.
Clearly.
Not only that,
it's said that God Allmighty who is so kind,
why will He ask you to suffer?
So it challenges all the Christian principles of suffering.
In the same way, in all religions,
people have diverted from the right path,
and have come to the wrong path,
and are indulging
into self-created religions,
which has no relationship with reality,
or with the incarnations,
those who started those religions
or who gave the ideas of the religion.
I hope you won't do that to Me,
because you are gnostic people.
You are the ones who know,
who have had self-realization.
Without self-realization you cannot have a complete personality.
But as you see in Sahaja Yoga,
you don't have to go to Himalayas,
to give up your families;
you don't have to be away from the society
to get your realization.
You get your realization in the circumstances where you are born.
In the same society, in the same family-life.
But, you rise higher then them,
and try to pull them out of the mire in which they are existing.
This mire of ignorance has to be crossed,
and some of you have to do it.
And when you realize that,
then you should know that you all have to be very strong people.
You all have to be extremely strong.
If you are not strong enough,
how can you pull out the rest of them?
People who are mediocre
think that gradually they'll be allright,
and that they'll come up.
But I would suggest that you should make all-out-effort
to become strong Sahaja Yogis.
To become strong Sahaja Yogis is not difficult.
Because you have all the powers within yourselves.
You have the Kundalini within yourselves.
And you know the way, how to become a realized soul.
The problems are of you being dragged into your ego
or into your conditioning.
Only two problems,
not more.
Like somebody asked, "How many turns there are in London?"
Only two, left or right.
So either you go to the left or to the right.
All the permutations and combinations of this left and right
starts working and then you get into trouble.
And then you get into problems.
But actually it is a very simple thing.
To get out of your ego should be the simplest
and that is where you try to understand yourself.
You see yourself. How you are reacting.
Where is your attention?
What are you doing?
What is your attitude towards Sahaja Yoga?
So many people think that "this is my house,
this is my family, this is my car,
this is my horse, this is my dog.
I don't know how far it goes - "my, my, my, my, my".
But nothing is yours.
Yesterday, as Kabira has said it,
that "some cheat", that is the death, "will come
and take away everything that is not yours".
Then "my family" ...
then "my children" ...
All this is a nonsense,
and so, when you start getting attached to this word "my",
there where you fail completely
into your own understanding of your ego,
you're completely blinded by this ego.
First of all you should say that "nothing is mine".
Kabira has said that when the goat is living
she goes on saying "Mei, mei, mei ..."
means "I, I, I ..." in Hindi language.
Made a pun on the word "my".
And when she dies, and her intestines are taken out,
and are made into something that spins the ... cotton,
they go on the street, these people,
telling people that they are around,
they go on playing on that string
which is made from the intestines
of these goats,
it says, "Tuhi, tuhi, tuhi ..."
meaning "You are, you are, you are ..."
So one need not be like a goat,
that till you leave you go on saying "I, I, my, my ..."
When you die then your intestines have to be taken out
and put on that thing
just to make the sound "Tuhi, tuhi, tuhi ..."
So this sound of "I, I, I ..."
is made only by egoistical human beings,
but this ego is so much identified with you,
that you think that "I am this ego
and ego is me".
And in that ego you start doing all kinds of nonsensical things.
This ego takes you nowhere,
it takes you nowhere
but into a complete mire of ignorance about yourself.
Ultimately you become stupid,
others can tell you that you are stupid,
or you become idiotic,
or you get a bad name,
and everybody knows that you are doing all wrong things,
but nobody there tell you,
because you are to be reached with a barge pole.
Such a hot-tempered personality you become,
nobody dare come you and say that this is wrong,
it should not be done, it's stupid, idiotic,
and you, yourself, in that idiocity and stupidity
think no end of yourself.
This is the extreme of your ego.
But it's nice, we have people like Hitler to see.
So if you put Hitler as the ideal egoist
then you will not go on that road.
Because it's a very slippery road
and maybe  one day you land up there.
The second side of ours,
which is a very, looks very morbid
and very mild, is the left side.
The movement on the left side is the emotional side.
You develope habits with the left side.
Now, some people have very dangerous habits,
some have simple habits.
Like I have a bad habit, or a good habit, you may say,
that i must put my right hand under my foot,
because it's all the time working, so I want to controll it.
So, I put it under my head like this, while sleeping
and sometimes under my foot,
just to make it little bit stop working, it works too hard.
Just to give it rest.
So under my pillow I put it and sleep.
But I discovered once, I hurt myself,
that I now cannot put it under my head.
I said, "It's a very funny habbit I have got."
But it's not such a dangerous one. It's quite good.
So I am continuing with it.
But I can get rid of it. It's very simple.
But when I get rid of it
I think the people become overactive
so I put it again, under my pillow.
So as Sahaja Yogis all your habbits should be under your control.
Now the ...
habits we have formed through drugs,
from drinking, from anything, are very dangerous habbits.
Also, people have their attention being all the time around.
All the time is attention here, there and there,
attracting people, looking after them,
not looking after yourself.
This attention has to be brought under control. Is very important.
That's very simple, that whenever it happens,
you just put down your eyes.
Keep your eyes down.
That's one of the ways we ...
allow our attentiion to fritter away,
and also our growth becomes stunted.
This is a very very dangerous thing
which in the West specially we have developed.
Here, also, people must read every shop's name.
Indians have a bad habit,
because they have just now started reading,
so they want to read everything that they find, anything.
So on the road if there is a road of shops,
they read every name of every shop,
turn round again and see if they have missed anything.
It sounds stupid. But they all do it.
And all the time they are doing it.
So the attention, wherevever it goes,
has to be under our control.
We have to keep it, all the time under our control.
As Namadeva has said very clearly,
in Guru Grant Sahib has written,
that when a little child is flying the kite,
he's talking  to everyone,
he's playing in a way,
but his attention is on the kite.
And when a housewife is carring her duties,
putting her child on her waiste and working,
then she's doing all kinds of work,
but her attention is on the child.
The Ladies who are carrying
three-four earthen pots on their heads,
water filled up to the brim,
are walking, talking to each other,
having mirth and enjoyment,
but the attention is on the earthen pot, on their heads.
In the same way, whatever adventure you are into,
whatever you are doing, your attention should be on your spirit.
Then everything is under control,
and you can never get enveloped
into anything where attention should not be lost.
So, these two problems we have,
and those problems even after realization people have it.
So please try, when you are not meditating,
to keep your attention on your spirit.
Now, the person who is left-sided or right-sided,
he has developed a mechanism within himself to justify himself.
Through his intellect,
or maybe if they are ladies they have water power,
they'll start crying.
And you just don't know what to say to them.
If you tell them anything, first thing they'll do is to cry,
means sometimes I feel there are thousand arrows on My head
when they start crying.
It is impossible to say anything to them.
And if you talk to some men
the'lll give so many explanations
that you would feel like, just, going off to sleep.
It's so boring.
It''s easy to read some book like "War and Peace"
than to listen to the arguments of such people.
But they don't want to see
that this is all ego, which is talking,
It is not, they are talking,
it is not their spirit.
And if the spirit has to evolve
we have to be extremely wittnessing, in a full way,
very alert, extremely alert
and wittnessing ourselves, what are we doing.
Then only we reach the completion of our realization.
Unless and until you reach the completion of your realization,
you can never be masters of your attention,
and you can never be the enjoyer of your joy,
and you can never know the truth fully.
Achieve this Sat-Chit-Ananda swarupa
you have to be extremely careful
about the instrument that God has given you,
this body, mind and emotions.
You have to keep them in check,
because wherever your habits are
they can never be joy giving, it's a joyless pursuit.
and wherever your ego is, it's a destructive effort.
So both things are detrimental to your growth,
apart from that, they are extremely dangerous thing for yogis.
So, as you are, in whatever conditions you are,
in whatever situations you are,
whatever may be the surroundings,
like a dirty mire full of creatures and filth,
you can become like lotuses.
When you become like lotuses
all that is filth, all that is horrible, can become fragrant.
And this is what we have to achieve.
When people will see the lotuses they'll come to you,
not to see the worms and to see the filth,
but to see the lotuses.
So please, this time, correct yourself,
you don't need anybody to correct you,
you just correct yourself,
watch out for yourself, and see for yourself.
If something doesn't work out just give up.
Don't go to extrems for anything.
Must learn to give up at a point
and be happy about it.
If you are contained within yourself,
if your hand is attached to your body,
then you reach up to a point and then leave it,
but if it is not attached, if it is disintegrated
then it goes all round and round and round
and comes back without anything.
That understanding has to be there in you people
because you're standing in the central part,
and you're attached to the central part, not only,
but you are identified with it.
So you cannot go too far to the left,
cannot go too far to the right,
if you do that you get lost.
Then you are no more a Sahaja Yogi,
and then no use having you here artificially or superficially
because it will be hypocrisy.
Whatever is needed to put you back into right frame you must accept.
And whatever is needed to understand Sahaja Yoga you have to do.
As I have said, please try to learn English language.
I cannot learn fourteen languages.
Very difficult.
It's surprising how I have learned this English language also.
So now to learn fourteen languages
I've to take fourteen Avataras again.
I don't ask you to learn Marathi.
Because that's the best language for Me to speak.
But at least try to learn Engllish.
aA d then we can see if you can learn Marathi or Hindi.
[VON 24:28 bis 41:15 TALK IN HINDI OR MARATHI]
May God bless you all.
Now We should read the translation in English,
because I have told you that Ganesha-principle came as Jesus Christ.
So let Us see the singularity
between the two principles
of Shri Ganesha and of Christ.
It's not cleare at all, it's not cleare at all,
it's not cleare at all. Will you please adjust it properly
and speak properly. Or get somebody else to speak,
but you must be very clearecut,
Whatever you are saying,
you should be able to hear everybody must take.
Put your mouth a little away from it, they can't hear it.
It's getting confused.
Read it again, please have.
Not yet cleare. Can somebody come and read it?
Brian! Come along!
See little bit the english language should be understood by Indians.
You are very good at Sanskrit,
but in English We can't understand english English.
Sorry! Brian would be better I think.
Come up!
Now little bit use indian English, you see?
Keep your mouth properly and in a way
that everybody should be able to listen to your translation.