Shri Mataji: Is it for the loudspeaker?
Yes.
We can wait for some time more to organize.
It is so unfortunate that it was not
published in the newspaper properly,
that day – it’s very unfortunate.
Yogi: Excuse me Mother, I think to get
this microphone a little closer to you.
Shri Mataji: Eh? Yogi: Do You want to get
this a little closer to You?
Shri Mataji: I’ll have it in My hand.
Yogi: You’ll take this in Your hand?
Shri Mataji: Yes.
Yogi: Okay.
Shri Mataji: Then that won’t slip out,
you know. Yogi: Ah, okay.
That’s ok, this. This is the one…
When we say in the newspaper or
in an advertisement
that you come to such and such hall
for your Self-realization,
I don’t know what people think about it.
Perhaps they think that it is another
hocus-pocus
or some sort of a cult or some
money-making proposition.
But there are some who may not think
that way,
but they want to have their Self-realization
and they come here.
But one must understand that the attitude
we should have towards our Self
has to be really very earnest. To raise
your Kundalini is not so difficult
and to give you so-called realization
also not difficult,
in the sense that you can feel the cool
breeze of the Holy Ghost
coming out of the fontanel bone area,
you can get your baptism.
But I call it "so-called"
because the journey later is the difficult
thing, you see.
If the attitude is not earnest, then you
just lose it in no time.
So where the people are very ego-oriented -
I should say, convex personality is there -
it is even difficult to give realization
to begin with,
and even if you give realization,
to maintain it
and to make them grow is even more
difficult, much more difficult.
Now sometimes Sahaja Yogis ask Me,
“Mother, how is it that in India
You may give realization to thousands
and they all stick on,
while here when You give realization
to people
they just come and go away, are all wasted
as described
in the parable of Christ of the seeds, that
some seeds just were lost on the rocks?”
So why it happens here?
I would not blame them, but I would say
that they have had no knowledge
what Self-realization is, how difficult
it is.
If you read Patanjali’s “Yogashastra”
you’ll be surprised
how they were taught how to lead a good,
righteous life after marriage;
what was the relationship of a husband
and wife;
what was rhythm of sex life; how they
should treat their children;
how to develop their attention towards God
every day.
All these things are absolutely missing
from the lives of people
who have turned their backs to God.
Now, whatever you may try to turn
your backs to God or to your Self,
to your Spirit, it exists and it asserts
its own existence in you. It does.
Even if you try to defy it and deny it,
it comes up,
and so people are seeking and seeking.
The tragedy of the whole thing is that very
great seekers are born in the West
where people have no knowledge what is
Self-realization
and what one has to do to achieve it and
what a great blessing it is to have it.
This is the biggest problem we face
all over and now as I am going to America
I also dread the same problem there.
Now the thing is, people have full idea
as to the value of a diamond.
They know if the diamond weighs so many
carats, it means this.
If it is flawless, it means this. If it is
purest blue then it means this.
But they don’t know the value of their
spiritual life;
they don’t know what it is to be spiritual.
Under these circumstances, naturally,
what happens that when even they get
Self-realization
they cannot stick on to Sahaja Yoga and
go further with it.
Not that they lack in quality. I would say
it is not so.
I would not say that they are the people
who are good for nothing,
they are not good for spiritual life.
So all the Sahaja Yogis must have
a very compassionate and understanding
attitude towards them,
that when they come to you they have
no knowledge about it.
They are not trained that way. They are
not taught that way.
I wish the people in the countries where
they have lost themselves
in the material gains should again read
some of these books into details
and try to find out what kind of life human
beings were supposed to lead
and what kind of life we are leading now.
Now the word there is yama niyama, is a word
in the Patanjali Shastra, yama and niyama.
The niyama are the rules for yourself,
what rules you have to observe.
And what rules you have to observe
for others is yama,
where - how to deal with others, what
should be your relationship
to your wife, to your children, to other
relations that are there,
and how you must respect particular things
and to prepare yourself for
Self-realization, the ascent.
All this balance has to be there if you
have to ascend in life.
Even to lead a proper good life you have
to be like that.
I tell you, if you go to India you’ll find
the country
hasn’t got any sanitation whatsoever,
hasn’t got all the food that you have,
hasn’t got any of your railways or any one
of these your telephones as they are.
And when I go to India I forget that
there are telephones existing.
They never use this for Me there. Everything
that is so dislocated, mismanaged,
all kinds of funny things are there.
Sometimes there is a drought.
Sometimes there is a flood. All these
things are there.
Despite that, people are existing only
because they know
how to lead a proper life, to adjust
themselves to natural things.
Now the new disease that has come up
in America, AIDS,
has really upset Me very much. And I know
that it was to come, because today,
according to predictions it is not Kali
Yuga anymore, it is Kruta Yuga.
Is the time when things will happen,
Kruta Yuga means when the spiritual powers
will work out.
This is the time is already - you know that
in our books it is written
that the Kruta Yuga has started about sixty
years back, and that is how it is,
that now the spiritual powers are going
to react.
It’s easy to say, “What’s wrong? Who is
God? We don’t believe in God.”
You’ll have to pay for that.
If you go against the nature you’ll have
to pay for it.
If you do things according to your own ego,
you’ll have to pay for it.
This is the time that has come. This is
for our good.
This is not for our bad,
because it has been told many-a-times
not to do certain things.
Of course, in the Western countries where
Christianity is followed
is precisely told not to do this, not to do
that.
But then people say, “Why they have
said it?”
The only difference is that in the East
it is explained
why not to do this, why not to do that,
what happens. It has gone into the details
of it.
But I must say here also people know that
this is not to be done.
But when you talk about these things,
“This is not to be done”,
they will brand you as Victorian, or
they’ll mock at you,
laugh at you, make fun of you.
But when they face all these things
happening to you,
then they don’t know where to go, what
to do and how to face up to it.
This is the time where the spiritual powers
are going to work out;
they are going to prove the existence
of God.
They are going to prove the existence
of Divine laws and their operation.
They are going to prove all that is said
in all the religions,
their unity, and their integration.
Everything is going to be proved now today.
Even if you say this many-a-times,
many people will not pay any heed to it.
They will say, “Oh, Mother is just
brainwashing us.”
That’s what people told Me when I came
first to England.
That I said, “This is not the life human
beings should lead.
Even for animals it is not suitable.
How can you dare into these things
and get involved into problems? Later on
it will be showing results.”
But nobody was willing to listen to Me at
that time and everybody was angry with Me.
They said, “This woman is matronly.”
There are certain words in English
which are very condemning. Like first
one of them is Victorian.
If you are Victorian you are a gone case,
absolutely,
that you are branded on; then you
can’t talk.
But I would say even Victorian was better,
where there was some hypocrisy I agree.
Hypocrisy is a bad thing. But shamelessness
is much worse.
If you become shameless the thing spreads
like fire. There is no protection.
Hypocrisy is at least a little protection
from the spreading of it.
And everybody today thinks what’s wrong
in it,
and I, when I came here, I had such
a shock.
I couldn’t believe that human beings could
go to that extent to ruin themselves.
This is ruinous, absolutely ruinous it is.
And when a person like Christ, who was
nothing but purity, said
that, “Thou shalt not have adulterous
eyes”;
to that extent, to that subtle extent
of purity He talked -
I was amazed how people have denied Him
completely and how all other people
like Jews, like even Hindus here,
Christians, every sort of people
didn’t think what they were professing,
what they were claiming and what they were.
Today again, one-by-one you will see
more results of wrongdoings to yourself.
This is because you have crossed
all the limits of niyamas,
how you should be to yourself. Everyone
seems to be sick today,
either mentally or physically. Why?
Why are they mentally sick there? This is
the physical side of it.
The mental side is, they can run into
any sort of thing like witchcraft,
like spiritualism, like any guru who comes
and talks about God,
without finding out the credibility of it,
without finding out
what others have achieved by it.
Not only that, but I have seen people
after being harmed very much,
who have been tortured by these gurus,
who have been completely made beggars
by these gurus,
still profess, still fight for those gurus,
as if they have lost all their freedom,
all their independence to fight it back.
The other day one lady came to tell Me
that she went to a relation’s place to stay
with her,
and the relation was so funny that she
wouldn’t even give them full food to eat,
and in the house there was limited food,
and she would lock up everything
and they really starved themselves, you
see. But she – I knew her very well –
so she telephoned to Me. I said, “You come
along to My house,” and just called her
and I was amazed why these things happened
in the life of that woman.
How could she do it? She had no conscience!
Somebody starving next door to her.
The reason was she was a drunkard.
She used to drink a lot.
Her husband used to drink. Now with the
amount of money they earn you cannot drink.
Is a simple thing, leave alone all
the other side of it.
And she was drinking, her husband was
also drinking.
And they, whatever money they have,
they don’t eat much, they just drink,
and they were waiting for this woman
to disappear.
Because once you become enslaved to one
particular madness like this,
like drinking or anything, then you forget
all your relationships
with all your other duties that you have
to perform.
It’s like one madman, you see, doing work
like mad,
has no consideration of relationships
or any duties that he has to perform
with others.
Then also he has no time to think about
the duties towards himself.
He becomes such a dry personality that
he has no conscience even.
And he just shuts up his mind from all
that is gracious,
all that is sublime, all that is compassion.
He is just busy with himself.
He wants to drink. He wants to drink,
that’s all.
Very seriously he’ll say, “Yes, I have
to drink now. I like it”.
So it doesn’t matter if his dog doesn’t get
the food
or if his children have to starve or if
they have to work on the streets.
He doesn’t mind because he has to drink.
Then there is another thing, like today
I saw so many people enjoying cricket –
I Myself can enjoy cricket very well and I
understand cricket very well.
But how much time do they pay to themselves
in the sense they are just enjoying
what is something entertaining. But what
about the entertainment of your Spirit?
Have you thought of your Spirit at all?
Have you ever peeped into yourself
and found out that there is Spirit, which
has to be satisfied and entertained?
And once you entertain that Spirit you
don’t need any entertainment.
If you have it, well and good, if you don’t
have it, well and good.
That is the highest type of entertainment.
That’s the highest type of enjoyment.
That’s the highest life that one can
ask for.
So all these things come to a level where,
“What’s wrong?
What’s wrong in this and what’s wrong
in that?”
So the nature is now going to show you
what’s wrong.
Because intelligently you understand,
rationally you understand,
logically you understand it is wrong.
But still there is somebody else who says,
“What’s wrong?”
So now, experiencing it you understand.
That’s the only way left for nature
to make you understand:
now experience it, suffer it.
There is another way, is that you can
experience your Spirit.
Also it’s possible only this Krita Yuga can
do that,
that you can experience the enjoyment
of your Spirit.
Both things are there. When it does
one thing, it does the other way also.
It also gives you the experience
of reality, the experience of truth,
the life that is eternal, and that’s what
one has to look forward to.
But enslavement has to be brought down
to a proper shape, little bit.
That also it does. I was amazed some people
who had been drunkards and alcoholics,
in Sahaja Yoga they came;
next day they left it. It does that.
Enslavement of any kind, of any habit,
is detrimental to our growth in Spirit.
It is detrimental, but doesn’t matter:
if you have some habits
they just drop out, as you have seen.
Sahaja Yoga is such a kind, compassionate
happening that it really makes you
a different person who is a master
of himself; no more enslavement.
All this slavishness goes away. All this
fear disappears.
You become master of yourself and in that
mastery you are the master of love,
master of compassion, master of wisdom.
This should happen to all of us.
You are all due for it. You are
created for it.
You all have evolved for it. You have
to have it.
But there are so many misidentifications
in us
with which we are drawn to wrong things,
to things which are anti-God, which are
anti-Spirit.
So many things are there which divert
your mind to that
because you have drawn certain conclusions
about reality.
You think this is the reality. You believe
that this is the reality
and you want to stick on to that. But that
is not so.
I tell you, you have to understand that
reality is what it is.
You should face it and enjoy it. Don’t try
to put your ideas on it.
Don’t try to organize the reality. It is
what it is.
And once you decide within yourself,
“So far I have not known
and I have to know,” with that humility,
you’ll get it.
It doesn’t mean that you have to surrender
your money or anything,
your self-respect or your freedom.
On the contrary, you have to enter
into that area where there is supreme
freedom, supreme freedom.
You are not free. If you think you are
free, you are sadly mistaken,
because we are still slaves of so many
things.
But once a person is free he is not
bothered about anything.
Nothing can make him habituated
to anything. Nothing.
Such a person lives like a king, whether
he is in a hut, on a street or in a palace.
He is not bothered. Whatever it is he is
the king. He doesn’t want anything anymore.
He gives. He gives. He’s so rich that
nobody can give him anything.
He gives and gives and gives.
And only thing that it can do is to give;
it cannot take anything.
The capacity is such that he cannot take
anything from anyone.
No more these attitudes, how to save money,
how to save your labor,
how to save your chairs, your powers,
your positions.
Nothing remains there, because you are
the master of everything.
Nothing is more important than your own
Spirit, which you enjoy, which manifests.
It’s so fortunate that you are born
at a time when it is Krita Yuga,
and you have taken your birth deliberately
to get this realization.
That’s why you are here. But how many
realize that you have to come
to terms with many things? You have to seek
the truth and not the untruth.
You don’t have to run after people who
make fools out of you
or those who try to pamper your ego,
or who put spirits in you, and make useless
cabbages.
You have to become something greater,
healthier, mightier
and loving, affectionate, compassionate.
That should be the picture of
the personality that has to evolve
out of human beings. Otherwise we cannot
save this world.
With the kind of people we have we cannot
save.
They are all compromising, they are all
manipulating, maneuvering
as if they are all getting drowned, and
everybody has to somehow or other
pull out the person ahead of them
to come up.
All funny things happening in this world.
That is only because we are so insecured.
The insecurity will all go away once the
light – the light of your Spirit shines.
Let the light shine through and see your
beauty and glory and your strength
of that great power of love of God
within yourself
and then you’ll be amazed what it is.
As you know, Sahaja Yoga is not one
lecture, is not two,
can be hundreds, but the happening takes
[a] split of a second. It should happen.
Once it happens you can achieve
your realization
in such a way that you won’t even feel it.
But afterwards you have to put in
deliberations.
You have to look after yourself. You have
to respect yourself and go ahead with it.
There’s no use arguing about it. Even if
you argue I can take you up to a point
because this is the realm beyond the mind,
because mind is a limited thing.
We have to achieve the unlimited and
for that a happening has to take place.
We can’t promise you that it will take
place. If it takes place, well and good,
we can help you in a way to achieve it, but
we cannot be sure that it will happen.
So be in a receptive mood and be kind
to yourself and achieve your realization.
This is the last time I’m speaking now
in London.
For quite some time I won’t be here, maybe
in November if I come for a short time;
I may be in London, may be outside London,
somewhere in England; I can’t say.
I hope all those who are today should
decide that if they have
to achieve their realization as a permanent
blessing from God,
then they have to go further with it.
You cannot just stop it at this meeting.
You have to go further with it with greater
enquiries. You have to go
to different ashrams and centers that
we have; you have to work it out.
If you are a big man, like the other day
somebody came as a managing director
and tried to be funny, I said, “If you are
a managing director
this is not the place for you.” God doesn’t
understand. You may be the king.
You might be the president. You might
be anyone.
God doesn’t understand these man-made
positions. God’s positions are different
and if you have to enter into the Kingdom
of God come as a humble person.
Give up all your ideas about your big
positions and big education and all that.
Be a humble person. If you are humble
then it will work out,
and not only that it will work out but
it is the only chance
we human beings have to change the whole
world. There’s no other chance I can see.
I hope all of you will pay full attention
to it
and ardently, with full devotion, seek your
Self and its ascent and its establishment.
May God bless you all.
If you have any questions you can ask
Me today.
Yes. Seeker: Shri Mataji, could you say
something about collective
and the need for people who have been
realized to be together?
Shri Mataji: What did he say?
Yogi: Mother, could you please say
something about the collective
and the need for realized souls to be
together?
Shri Mataji: Oh, all right. That’s a very
nice suggestion.
I would like to say something about
collectivity.
So far as you know, in the history of
spirituality people have got realization.
Many people have got it. One after another,
many people got it
but I would say one in a million, one
in a ten million, like that,
because we have to have some people to talk
about it, to begin with.
We always see what was written
in the past, you see,
but those people who got realization
single-handed suffered a lot,
and they could not transmit what it was
needed to be given to others
in a way that would be acceptable.
Now as you see, any discovery is made,
like that people can benefit individually.
Every person can say, “Oh, I have got it.
So I can have it in my house,” you see;
but it is of no value. It is of no value,
I can tell you.
I would say a personality like Christ came
on this earth. We had Christianity;
what have they done about it? I mean,
it’s a sad affair.
I mean, to think such a personality to come
and what a great job He has done
to establish Himself on Agnya chakra,
what people have done out of it, you see.
The reason was He was seldom; He was
alone. It was not a mass thing.
That was not the time, because He had
to establish this center.
Without that it could not be mass,
all right?
It could not be an en masse realization
but He talked about,
“You have to be born again,” and all that.
But the whole thing fizzled out
because they could not get to the essence
of it.
One person of that caliber coming
on this earth
found it impossible to convince people
and talk about it.
So one has to understand that anything
that is evolutionary
first happens to one or two persons only,
but then it happens to many people.
Now in Sahaja Yoga there’s another problem
apart from that, that it is happening
to many people, it is there, no doubt.
Thousands are getting realization,
it’s no doubt. It’s working out that way,
that now the evolution has come to this
stage, as I say it’s the blossom time,
many flowers are there and they have
to become the fruits.
But now why is it necessary to have
collectivity when people are getting
realization like that, is a very important
point one has to understand.
The thing is that now, when you are getting
realized, what is happening to you?
You are getting related to the whole.
Our microcosm is getting related
to the macrocosm.
Say your body is there and you are
sleeping. First you get a little awakening.
You open your fingers, all right? Then you
open your, another finger.
Now there is a little trouble on your
finger and you can’t see anything.
So you open your eyes and you pay your
attention to your hands.
So that trouble may be all right but you
need another hand to help me.
So you want the another hand also to be
awakened to that point, like that.
So when the Sahaja Yogis are getting
awakened more and more, you see,
the problems that are facing us, we can
solve them better,
because so many people are working out
the problem.
Do you understand My point now? Together!
When we are together
we understand now there’s a problem,
now I’m going to America.
I’ve gone in 1970 - 1973 first, I think,
yes.
1973 I went first. I was alone! I mean,
I gave them very good lectures,
we had very big halls filled up and
everything – but everything fizzled out.
The reason is the people who got
realization didn’t have anybody
to look after them, there was nobody
to support them, give them assistance,
so they got lost. I mean, they are there,
some of them are here and there.
Now what has happened now? Today when
I’m going to America everybody is praying.
In Australia they are praying. In India
they are praying.
Like attention, you’ll be surprised some
people are coming from India
to go down to America. Some are coming
from Australia to go down to America.
Some are coming from France, some
from Switzerland.
They are all rushing to America.
Now the job is in America.
All right, so, like the attention you see,
as soon as somebody pricks Me here,
My hand goes there, My head goes there,
everything works it out.
So the collective working-out effort
is going to solve the problem.
But supposing if this finger is fighting
with this finger, can I write anything?
Or if they are secluded and alone,
can I use them?
All this body has to become absolutely
in concord with each other.
But so many are still sleeping. Those who
are awakened at least must stick together.
Otherwise Sahaja Yoga cannot work out.
Today I find it much easier to give
realization, much easier.
I was struggling with six people for four
years in your London.
Four years, six people. But once they got
realization it started working faster
and the more people we get – because
the channel that is to be used
is like nerves in the body. You become
a nerve of that body which is awakened,
and once the nerves start working out
together
realizing that there’s one force that is
flowing through them,
all of you have to work it out together
with understanding of the Divine.
It works faster. Any person whose all
nerves are at work
will be much more dynamic than a person
who is half-dead or is full-dead.
So you can understand how collectivity
is important.
Then another thing is that going to
a very enjoyable part of it,
that when the Sahaja Yogis are collectively
there, they really enjoy.
Because for the first time you start
enjoying human beings, first time.
Before this you never enjoyed them.
You enjoyed flowers, you enjoyed everything
else, but not human beings.
Pure enjoyment of human beings starts
coming when you become fully realized.
I’ll give you an example. We went
to Calcutta for one day
and I was in a room in one hotel
and there were three, four Sahaja Yogis
in another hotel - another room,
and one gentleman came to Me
for his realization.
And when I raised his thing, the Kundalini,
you see, they all got vibrated
and they all rushed to My room
to know “What has happened, suddenly how
is it we got such joy within ourselves”.
They came to see, and this man was there.
He was a great soul
and they felt the vibrations, tremendous,
you see.
So it is not the happening of an individual.
It is the happening of the whole.
And the individual effort is going to be
absolutely useless.
It will be all neutralized. If you sit
at home, do your meditation,
it won’t work out. You won’t go very far.
Because the whole has to come up.
I’ll give an example that when you churn
the butter -
in India, I don’t know, we don’t do that
way; we do it very naturally –
you put a little butter inside that and
then again you start churning.
So the butter starts gathering round that
butter, all of it comes together.
But some particles are left out. They stick
to the sides, stick to that.
They are no more as butter; they are thrown
away as buttermilk. Is as simple as that.
You see, the more you gather together,
you really enjoy the spirit of friendship,
spirit of mirth, spirit of love in pure
form. So far the love is biased.
There’s sex, there’s lust, there’s money,
there’s this, there’s relationship.
This is, “You are British; so I must love
you,” “I am Indian;
so I must love you.” All these nonsensical
barriers are there.
There you love a human being because
he is a human being
and he is a yogi, speaks the same language.
Now today I have attended a wedding party
and the bride and the bridegroom said,
“We are coming to Paris with you, Mother.
There are hundred people coming to Paris,
because we have to change Paris”, you see.
“But,” I said, “you are recently married.
Now better enjoy your honeymoon.”
They said, “What are we going to enjoy?
We’ll enjoy there our honeymoon”,
so they are coming up there.
Even if I tell them, “You don’t come,”
they won’t listen.
They will enjoy their honeymoon there only.
I never said, “You come”, on the contrary,
I’m saying, “You go away.
I will give you money to enjoy your
honeymoon wherever you feel like.”
They wouldn’t go, because they know
where enjoyment lies,
with their brothers, with friends and
sisters. It’s absolutely so,
I tell you, that the enjoyment of human
beings has not been there.
Now there are people who live in India,
who live in Australia,
who live here, all over the places,
but when the Sahaja Yogis go to India
you should see them,
the way the Sahaja Yogis in the villages,
the way they embrace them,
the way they feel the oneness. Never
they have felt like this for a white skin.
If they saw a white skin they would just
run away
and hide themselves under this thing,
you see. And even now
people are sometimes frightened to see
a white skin in a village.
They say, “Oh, God, they have come just
to destroy us!” or something like that.
But now that’s over. Now it’s a human
being, a human being is coming.
They are all embracing. For there is
nothing like a black or a white
or anything left now. It’s such a love that
grows and an understanding.
That’s only possible if you learn how
to live collectively.
And collectivity also teaches you where
you are. Very important it is.
A person who has not lived collectively
cannot understand.
I have seen people who have their own
families, live with their families,
they are Sahaja Yogis - but once they come
to the ashram
they know they are not yet there.
Because you have to adjust, you have
to learn to adjust,
you can’t have private bathroom
to yourself, private room to yourself.
All right, you can have if you want to have,
but you should also know how to adjust.
As you know, I live very comfortably
Myself,
but if it comes to living I can live
anywhere,
I have no problem of comfort or anything.
In the same way we are not barred from
enjoyment. Because of all these things,
the way we carry our bathrooms with us,
we do not enjoy life.
[You] see, [you] want to have everything
absolutely first class that has, say,
that even when we go to the picnic we take
all the metropolitan with us.
In the same way we cannot enjoy life.
We cannot enjoy nature.
We cannot enjoy anything as long as we
become just an individual,
“Oh, I am the one who is going to get it.”
The last of all we must know by
individualism we become malignant.
I don’t say become communist, because
that’s another malignancy;
but by becoming individuals we become
malignant. What is malignancy?
That an individual cell takes up upon
itself, “I will grow, I will grow.”
It doesn’t know how to grow with the whole.
It has no coordination with the whole.
That’s why you say it is a cancer.
Cancer is nothing but is a malignant cell
which is alone
and is saying that, “I have to achieve it.
I can do it, I can manage it”.
And once it starts growing like that,
whosoever it touches, that person becomes
the same.
All these ideas – we are higher race
or we are greater people,
we are moneyed people, we are something
special,
we are of this club – all this disappears.
It’s all nonsensical. We are identified
with nonsensical things
and making ourselves miserable and others
also miserable.
And then you give up all that. Suddenly
you find, “Oh, what enjoyment!”
You don’t want anything, you just want
to be in the company of Sahaja Yogis.
I have seen people, ambassadors, very
highly placed people,
just getting lost with the Sahaja Yogis.
The other day I had a businessman from
Bombay. I took him down with Me
to a place called Gurai; and it was all
in a mess,
in the sense there were no proper
bathrooms, there were…
It was just like a God-forsaken place,
I tell you.
And there weren’t even places to sit down
properly,
only the beach and the palm trees and all
sorts of thing was there.
And the man got lost into that, absolutely
lost.
And he said, “I never wanted this day
to finish.
Is the only day I’ve really enjoyed myself
thoroughly”.
Because there was such spontaneity,
such spontaneous love,
such attention and such purity
in the atmosphere.
To enjoy that purity you have to be
in the collective.
Sitting down in the room, you can’t
understand, there is no reflection of you.
You can’t understand where are you,
how far you are going.
Collectivity is the most important thing,
and those who try to break the collectivity
are doing anti-Sahaja activity.
[You] see, we call it a-Sahaja movement
or you can say a-Sahaja activitiy.
You have to be one with the whole. Those
who have tried to separate themselves,
all of them go down in Sahaja Yoga.
Try to be one with everyone, to share
and enjoy everybody’s being,
because God has created you so beautifully.
You are so beautiful.
And the enjoyment should not be lost
because you have certain barriers;
like some people can’t take out their
shoes, I mean, just imagine
how much they are identified with their
shoes.
They can’t take out their shoes. To that
extent they are stupid!
[You] see, all this kind of stupidity
drops out
once you meet really wise people
around you.
To get rid of all these nonsensical ideas,
which have really
haunted your head all these days, you get
rid of them
and you really enjoy everyone, whether
he is a doorman or he is a chairman,
all of them are men for you. It’s nothing
more than that.
All that drops out and you start enjoying
your Self.
That’s why collectivity is the only way
I can work out Sahaja Yoga.
I can’t think I can work out through
the people who are separated, divided.
It is said, Christ has said also that…
They said, “What have we to do?”
He said, “When you love each other you have
done the greatest justice to Me”.
It’s true. And when I hear the loving
conversation of the Sahaja Yogis
I feel the happiest. That’s the greatest
happiness for Me,
that all of you should love each other
in purity, without any return,
only for love’s sake you all should love
each other. And that is what it is!
And also Krishna has said, “Wherever people
are there gathered together
in the name of God, I reside within them”.
So in that joint - so-called joint, because
you are all one,
moving with one rhythm, with one
understanding, with one language,
so you all should always meet, call each
other and have rapport with each other.
It’s so beautiful. It’s musical.
It’s poetical.
Do you understand that? May God bless you.
And see for yourself when you cut out
your collectivity.
Just abuse yourself at that point. That
this is one thing
you are trying to teach Me now, I’m not
going to listen to this nonsense.
We are collective being otherwise also.
I mean, we cannot,
people cannot take even drinks without
somebody being there.
You can’t take your food alone.
In so many things,
I mean, if you are not absolutely
a recluse you can’t live alone.
Then in religion, in the seeking,
especially in the realm of God,
how can it be?
You all have to be there.
I think it was a very good question,
rightly asked.
This individualism must be given up.
That doesn’t mean you all should dress up
like military people –
that’s not necessary –
or you should all behave in the same
manner – that’s not necessary.
Variety brings all the beauty. But that
doesn’t mean that
if I say it is East you should say
it is West.
That’s the main trouble is, I think,
isn’t it?
That you can’t agree to each other.
What’s the problem in collectivity,
you think.
I can ask the question.
Must get out of individual limitations.
I think everybody should for some time go
and live in an ashram, is a good idea.
But ashram must be such where there is
collectivity.
In the ashram if they are fighting and
quarrelling -
then what’s the use of being in the ashram
also? But I leave it to you.
It’s all freedom to you. You just decide
yourself.
I have not put any rules and regulations
on you much,
because I want you to use your wisdom
and put everything right yourself.
You are all very wise people but must
have concord.
Listen to others. Talk to them. Find out
what’s the problem is.
On small, small things people fight.
It’s a very wrong thing.
Moreover, you have to have one person
as a leader to whom you should listen to.
If I find that fellow is useless I’ll throw
him away. You know that very well.
Throw him away, not in the way people
throw away,
but he’ll just get out of Sahaja Yoga.
You know that very well.
So there should be no problem. But
everybody should not
try to dominate each other. That’s
a wrong idea.
Try to change your attitude. As I would
say, how far can you adjust?
How far can you accommodate? Let’s see
that way.
You have to learn that from Me, isn’t it?
You must find out ways and methods of
accommodating yourself with others.
Just try to learn. It’s not difficult.
That’s the whole attitude of life,
is of competition and this and that - should
be changed. You must compete in loving,
compete in doing good things, compete
at working for others.
Like “I’ve opened the door, now I’ll not
take the phone”. Is very common.
“I’ve washed the things this morning, then
I will not wash in the evening”.
Then people start taking advantage as this.
Let them take advantage;
it is a disadvantage for them. Actually,
if you see the other side,
compete in service, compete in love,
compete in good things,
of saying good words, of communicating
in a sweeter way
that others feel happy, making others
happy.
Try to change your attitude towards others
and you’ll really enjoy, I tell you, you’ll
enjoy. That’s the way.
You know, if you say something to hurt
someone and upset someone,
it must be upsetting you definitely.
You may not show but it must be,
because whatever you do to others comes
back to you. Straightforward march,
I tell you. It doesn’t stay there
altogether; it comes back to you.
So just try to be kind to others.
You may say that the other may try to harm
you, doesn’t matter.
Nobody can harm you because you are
the Spirit. Who can harm you?
You are the Spirit. So just try
to understand the person.
I tell you, after some time you’ll find
that person will become very soft.
So many Sahaja Yogis have become like
that automatically.
They all are here for seeking God,
isn’t it?
So to help them you have to be patient.
Give up your old methods and ways,
I must tell you:
to be curt, to be stern, to be angry,
there’s no need at all!
I’m telling you from My experience.
I’ve tried all these things.
It works, isn’t it? It does work.
And you have to have faith in them and
faith in their ascent, in their quality.
I like people who praise others to Me.
I don’t like people who criticize others.
Try to support each other, help each other
and never talk about their past or anything
like that; it’s very sad.
Sometimes I’ve seen people are very hard
and in anger they say things
which one should never say. It’s not
gracious.
It’s not in the mannerism of Sahaja Yogis.
You should never say these things.
Do I ever say anything like that to you
about your past?
When you write to Me, even if I know
everything about you,
did I ever mention those things to you
at all?
Then why should you say things of the past?
I have heard these things people just rake
it up and flung it back.
I have heard this kind of thing that they
bring it on other people, it’s not good.
One should be very gracious, very kind,
and understand that everybody has
tremendous potentiality.
Respect, respect and respect. Respect
yourself and you’ll respect others.
I hope now you won’t have problem
of collectivity after this lecture,
and if you have, you can listen to this
lecture again and again;
and My special humble request that try
to curb down your angles.
Automatically other angles will calm down.
But if it is a non-Sahaja Yogi then you all
should fight it together.
All should join together if [it] is
a non-Sahaja Yogi.
Nobody dare torture you or trouble you.
Those days are gone now.
None of you will be troubled.
These are all satanic forces and they can
work through you also.
You must know when they give you such ideas
to fight and to quarrel.
Understand that this is anti-God. You are
doing God’s work.
You have to move towards more
understanding, more coordination;
because this is such a tremendous work
and of such a sublime nature,
that we have to be sublime ourselves.
All right, now is there any other question?
[It] was a very nice suggestion
but don’t give Me such big suggestions
that I have to speak for half an hour.
Sahaja Yogini: Mother, when you say
collective consciousness,
does that exclude all the people who are
not Sahaja Yogis,
so does that mean that Sahaja Yogis are isolating
themselves
from the 90% of the people who are not
Sahaja Yogis?
Shri Mataji: What is she saying? I just
couldn’t hear. Can you come?
You come here and tell Me. Yes, it’s
all right.
Sahaja Yogini: When you are talking about
being collectively conscious,
that excludes the people who are not Sahaja
Yogis and therefore the Sahaja Yogis
are isolating themselves from the people,
from the majority of the other people.
Shri Mataji: Oh, that’s it. No, no, no.
She says that when collectively Sahaja
Yogis become one
then those who are not Sahaja Yogis
are isolated. It’s not so.
You see, Sahaja Yogis have to be strong
enough. Now take it like this,
that there are people, say, who are
in the water
and some people are in the boat, all right?
Now the people who are in the boat are
in the boat, so they are in a way
different from the people who are in the
water. That’s the situation is, all right?
Now the people in the boat have to save
the people who are in the water, all right?
So what I am saying that those who are
in the boat must first of all be united,
and then with full strength pull them out.
Why this collectivity?
Is just to pull out the rest of them.
This collectivity is just to achieve
their emancipation, their realization,
all right? It doesn’t mean that
they should exclude. Actually the whole
collectivity is to bring those people out.
But, you see, there are lots of anti-God
activities going on in this world,
you know that. For example, there’s a guru
who makes lots of money, all right?
And he has destroyed many people. Now
they come to Me and they are saved.
So he may send somebody here paid
for a job just to disturb us.
Then the duty of all the Sahaja Yogis is
to get together and see that,
to tell him that, “You see, now you are
doing wrong.
Your guru has done wrong to us and he
is going to do wrong to others.
Why do you join with that?” On that point
everybody should be one.
But if they are not strong and if they are
not one, they cannot pull out others.
You see, My point is like that. Not
to exclude - is all,
collectivity is to include everyone inside.
All right?
I mean to say, there is no specialization
in Sahaja Yoga, in simple words.
Everybody is a doctor of everything.
I mean to say that all the Sahaja Yogis
must form a strong group
by which they achieve enlargement
of Sahaja Yoga,
getting more people into Sahaja Yoga, more
people benefitted by Sahaja Yoga, all right?
All - anywhere I have seen, wherever there
is collectivity, like I would say,
Australia has the maximum collectivity,
or India of course it has, but Australia,
in all the European countries, or I should
say the western-styled communities,
Australia has the maximum collectivity and
they have achieved the maximum results.
Only in Sydney, today only, Warren told Me
that the halls like this get packed
for programmes.
Melbourne, there is no room for new people
who are coming,
and it’s such a big compound I’m amazed,
I mean, how many must be going there.
And it is because of collectivity.
And as soon as I went there
it started gathering up. But before that
the people were fighting among themselves
and many people ran away from Sahaja Yoga
because they thought,
“These people are fighting, what are they
going to give us?”
Maximum is in Australia, I think. Then is
Austria is having some problem there,
and as soon as the problem came in,
the whole thing became a very small group.
Again that problem is over now; positivity
has come;
the people have joined together; again
it has flourished.
It happens here also, we have seen.
Why Labor Party lost? If they had
not quarrelled
they would not have been so badly off.
Is absolutely a simple equation,
“United we stand,” isn’t it?
Is there any other question?
All right. So how many are new people
today here?
Can you raise your hands please?
One, two, three, five, six.
All right. Can I request you to come
to the front seats?
That will be better, will help Me
better too,
because you are so much here and there,
all right? Just come, please.
Be comfortable. Yes, come along,
all of you.
Just be seated. Yes. Be comfortable.
Now get some more chairs.
Can you get some more chairs here
for the front seats?
Douglas, can you put them in a line?
They cannot be lifted; they are fixed,
are they? All right.
Now for all the new people I have to say
one thing,
that, you see, you cannot argue it out.
It has to work within you. It has to work
within you. It’s a happening.
There is a force within you which we call
as Kundalini,
which is the pure desire of becoming one
with the Spirit.
All other desires are impure. That’s why
you are never satisfied.
Now this desire is not yet awakened
within us.
This power of desire, or energy of desire,
resides in the sacrum bone
and it has to be awakened, and when
it is awakened, it rises,
passes through six centers, subtle centers,
comes out of your medulla oblongata
into the brain
and then, out of this part which was a soft
bone in your childhood,
and you start feeling a cool breeze coming
out of your head,
and a cool breeze coming out of your hands
also afterwards.
Now this is a living process, as you cannot
force a seed to sprout.
It sprouts by itself spontaneously, but you
have to put it in the Mother Earth.
In the same way it sprouts. It sprouts
spontaneously
and when it happens then you have to see
for yourself.
One can help because if there is
an obstruction on any chakras,
especially if the Nabhi chakra is
caught up,
then what happens that on that center
the Kundalini tries to push
and you can easily see with your naked
eyes the pulsation
or the movement of your sacrum bone
just like a heart, just like a heart.
These things you cannot maneuver, you
cannot attain by effort.
Is a thing already settled there within you
and this has to be awakened.
Now what we can do is to try to remove
the hurdles that are there
during the ascent of the Kundalini.
That’s all we can do.
But if it doesn’t work out, we can work out
again and we can work out again.
But you have to have patience with yourself
and you have to have understanding
that you will get your realization.
It’s not so difficult.
All of these people who are sitting here
have got realization
and most of them are settled down
with their realization.
They know what the chakras are, what
are the obstructions,
how to remove the obstructions and how
to raise the Kundalini.
All this you will also know. All this
mastery you will also have,
but you have to, as I said, you have
to have that earnestness
and that kind of assiduity by which
you’ll achieve it.
So it is for us to raise your Kundalini and
it is for us to help you to achieve it.
Then once you have achieved it and you
have mastered it,
it is for you to teach others and to give
realization to others.
It is as simple as that. So I’m sure
it will work out tonight
and that all will work it out. We should
all cooperate with each other.
Now some people who are frightened,
I have to tell them
there’s nothing to be frightened
in Sahaja Yoga.
Thousands of people have got realization
without any difficulty.
Or those who are still discussing in their
minds, must stop it now,
because they have not found it; better
prepare yourself to have the realization.
It is not to be paid for. You cannot put in
any effort. Nothing can be done.
It has to work out, all right?
With this understanding let us see that
few things, whatever I tell you, you try
to cooperate with Me.
One of them is a simple thing, is to remove
your shoes. Please remove your shoes.
There’s nothing in the shoes, you see.
If you remove the shoes,
you’ll become relaxed, little bit more,
and also I feel that it helps
the Mother Earth to suck in problems
very well.
It’s a very simple method by which
it should work out.
So I would request you to put both your
hands towards Me, just like this,
and close your eyes. That’s all. Just
close your eyes.
You will also know why I asked you to put
your hands towards Me later on.
So don’t think about it. There are five
fingers and six centers –
and seven centers all on your hands, and
when you put your hands towards Me
the message goes to the Kundalini
and it rises.
It’s your own, everything is your own.
Only thing like one enlightened light
enlightens another light, I’m just
enlightening you
and then you can enlighten others exactly
the same way.
All right. I would request you also to take
out your spectacles
if you have any, because it helps your
eyesight also.
It helps your eyesight. Just take out
your spectacles.
Any other obstacle, anything that is little
bit uncomfortable,
you can reduce the pressure on your waist
if it is very tight;
or anywhere you feel the tightness you can
reduce.
Put both the feet on the ground, little
separate from each other
because both feet have different problems,
are to be attended to differently.
Now please keep your eyes shut and I would
request you not to open your eyes
till I tell you, because if your eyes are
open
the Kundalini refuses to rise up to Agnya.
So please keep your eyes shut.
Just with complete faith in yourself
you just wait and it will work out.
If it doesn’t work out, we’ll try to tell
you how you yourself can work it out
by awakening your own centers.
You have to sit quietly.
Please put your right hand – don’t open
your eyes –
please put your right hand on your heart.
Because the left hand is the hand
of your desire
so it should be kept where it is now
throughout.
Only you have to move the right hand because
the right hand is the hand of action.
Now at this stage you have to say – if you
are wearing a coat
put it from inside the coat, would be
better – hand on your heart
and left hand towards Me on the lap,
comfortably.
Now you please in your heart, with all
sincerity
you have to ask the question thrice,
“Mother, am I the Spirit?”.
Now why I say that you call Me Mother,
because you have to call Me
Shri Mataji, which is a tongue twister
and I think it will be difficult.
So to make it easier, I say “Call Me
Mother”.
Please ask the question, “Mother, am I
the Spirit?”.
Because the Spirit has to come in your
attention; you have to become the Spirit.
Many people think if you pray without being
realized, God will do what you want.
He won’t, because you are not yet
connected. You have to be connected to God.
That’s why Christ has said you are to be
born again.
That’s not an artificial thing, it’s
a reality.
Now as the Spirit is your guide, it is your
guru, you don’t need any guide anymore,
put this right hand down on the stomach
on the left hand side again,
and push it a little. On your stomach
on the left hand side put the right hand
and left hand towards Me, and push it
a little bit and say –
you must put your hand on your stomach,
stomach on the left hand side
and press it a little bit because there
lies – the right hand, the right hand,
take it to the left side and put it
on the center on the left side.
And now you ask the question, “Mother,
am I my own guide?
Am I my own master? Am I my own guru?”
Ask the question ten times because there
are ten sub-plexuses within us.
Later on your own guru, which is your
own Spirit, will guide you
because you’ll get vibratory awareness,
a new dimension in your awareness.
You’ll become collectively conscious.
You’ll become, again. It’s not just
a lecture but it is a happening.
Please ask ten times, “Mother, am I
my own guide? Am I my own guru?”.
Now again put the same right hand
on your heart
and now you can assert by saying, “Mother,
I am the Spirit”.
Just say that. On the heart, on the heart,
put it on the heart,
the right hand on the heart, where
the Spirit is,
where it resides, is reflected
in your heart.
So just say, “Mother, I am the Spirit”,
with full assertion.
You have to say that twelve times.
Now as the Spirit is guiltless, it never
commits sins, it is blemishless,
it is absolutely spotlessly clean,
sparkling diamond within you,
you have to raise this right hand at the
base of the neck on the left hand side.
We have to move on the left hand side,
throughout.
At the base of the neck on the left hand
side. This is a very important center,
very important center for the Western
people is through the neck,
at the neck on the left hand side.
You put it on your shoulders on the left
hand side.
Just take it from the front, will be
easier, yes; and press it hard.
And at this center you have to say that,
“Mother, I’m not guilty,”
sixteen times, because if you are
the Spirit, how can you be guilty?
But really you must say, “I’m not guilty.”
Get away from all ideas that you have done
this wrong or that,
you have committed this sin and that sin.
“Mother, I’m not guilty.” Say it sixteen
times, please.
You are not guilty; you are just thinking
like that.
By thinking you have made yourself
miserable.
There’s not to feel guilty about anything.
Now raise the same hand on your forehead.
Across. On your forehead across.
At this point you have to forgive others.
This is the center of Christ.
He forgave the people who crucified Him.
In the same way you forgive everyone.
Forgive everyone.
Please forgive everyone. People say it is
difficult to forgive,
but if you don’t forgive, actually what
you are doing
is you are harming yourself, and not
the people who have harmed you.
So just say, “Mother, I forgive everyone.”
From your heart. Whatever you are saying,
is working out.
So please say, “Mother, I forgive
everyone.”
If you don’t say it from your heart,
it will have no effect.
Now put the hand on top of your head,
where you had a soft bone, press it hard
with your palm.
And just move it a little bit, sideways
if you put it is easier,
in a clockwise manner – your head,
your scalp – you can say.
At this point it is the liberation point,
is that point where you get your moksha,
where you get your realization.
And I can’t cross your freedom. At this
point you have to say,
“Mother, I want my realization, please
give me my realization”,
at least seven times. Say it seven times.
[A] lot of a heat is coming out. That’s
a good thing. Let the heat come out.
Now raise the hand and see if there’s
a cool breeze
or a hot breeze is coming out. First
the heat will come out.
You can change over your hand and see
with the other hand.
With the right hand towards Me, with
the right hand towards Me
and [the] left hand on top and see if
there’s a cool breeze coming out.
You may change again your hand, whenever
you feel like
you can change your hand, and see if
there’s a cool breeze coming out.
He’s got it. He’s a born realized.
No problem with him. He is!
Let him feel yours.
Just feel him. On top, yes.
He’s got it?
Their certificates are correct. If they
give you the certificate.
You have got it, long time back.
Have you felt it? Not yet. Don’t open
your eyes. Keep your eyes shut.
It will work out.
You exchange your hands one by one
and see for yourself.
Put your attention there and see. You have
to work it out yourself.
Don’t get disappointed and don’t feel bad
about it.
Just go ahead with it. It will work out.
Now I’ll ask some of the Sahaj Yogis
to come and see and help you.
Please come along. At the back of these
people, you know, those who are sitting,
can you see for that – this little one can
find out about everyone.
Now here, keep your eyes shut. It will
work out.
Don’t you worry and don’t feel
disappointed.
It has to work out. It has to work out.
Did you feel the cool breeze?
Good. You have felt it already. Good.
What about you? No?
Why, why are you so dejected? It will
work out.
John? Just try this gentleman.
Now, don’t think about it, just you keep
in meditation.
He’s got it. The first one has got it.
[The] second gentleman.
Shri Mataji: Now, what’s your name?
Child: Anna. Shri Mataji: Anna.
Child: [Indistinct]
Shri Mataji: Let’s have him here,
let’s have him here.
She’s going to America now, she’s going
to America.
[Indistinct]
Hello, William, come along!
Come up, come up, come up. Take some
chana.
Be careful! Be careful.
Come along. William? Come here.
What about his teeth? Yogini: Yes, he’s
already got two big teeth coming, Mother.
Shri Mataji: But how can he eat this, he
will eat? Can he manage? All right.
Come from this side, all right? For you may
fall. Now come from this side, all right?
We’ll keep this one there. All right, now.
Now.
You take this. Do you want to have?
Do you like it? Good! Will you have
some more?
Will you have some more in your hand?
All right, you have it.
What about you? Will you have some more?
Child: More!
Shri Mataji: More? Where is it going?
In your stomach?
Now come along, come along. You have it.
You go then digest it there. Digest it.
Will you have this, first you eat that. Hm?
Oh. Take this, take this. Throw it away.
Now, just come here. Come, come, come.
Who is that? …
You all stand there… should not fall out.
Elizabeth? Will you have some more?