but today I am going to tell you
something more which we have to it's
very important to know because as was
described by people that again the
practice sahaja yoga as they go to
church but is not from their heart and
heart the abode of the spirit is the
Shiva within us so we have to know more
about heart and that is very important
you know about these three noddies we
have me rapping de suzuna but in the
heart there are for nerds
and the one nerdy goes to mooladhara and
if you cross the limits of mooladhara it
goes to hell that's why they say that
Shiva is a destroyer actually you asked
for your destruction and when you asked
for your destruction you have it even if
it destroys everything as I was telling
it's like when a fruit has to come the
petals look as if they're destroyed as I
have destroyed I would say many of your
things you can call it like your
conditionings your ego your rationalism
your fanaticism all this has been
destroyed it is a job
this has to be destroyed for the beauty
to come out so when your maryadas cross
beyond certain point you go to your
destruction in four directions
there are destructions made as there are
four NARAS so now what is to be done how
are we to stop this destruction of the
through the first daddy going to hell
one of the qualities of Shiva is that
his innocence this extremely innocent is
innocent like a child his innocence
personified
so we have to put our carnal desires
dissolve them dissolve them into the
innocence the ocean of innocence you
have to dissolve it in the ocean of
innocence innocence is something to be
appreciated to be understood to be
enjoyed like you see animals they're
innocent you see children they're
innocent flowers they are innocent
divert your attention to all these
things
you see unlocking on the street what is
there to see West is all like three feet
height you see at three feet height all
the flowers all the beautiful grass all
the children who are about three feet
are the best
we need not see people who are above
that just see on three feet level you
can see the legs of somebody that's
alright but you don't see the eyes of a
person who are not innocent
so dissolve this desire a little antenna
cells and this mullet Aramis is innocent
is not dead finished but is innocent
it is righteous
it is recognizes qualities
it's pure so even if you are in this
world even if you are living like a
human being even if you have children
still you are ignorant the second noreen
the second child that can take you to
destruction is desire
that's why Buddha said that
desirelessness is the only way that
people do not get old not sick not
worried
[Music]
now this desire that we have I want this
the West is much more than anywhere else
because the enterpreneurs are every day
producing new things desires can be of
any kind not only material the desires
could be also quite mental
I must possess this woman I must possess
this child all kinds of positions that
work into you as desires I wouldn't say
it is because of attachment it's not
attachment but it is just to have more
go on adding up things getting things
still one doesn't feel happy and
satisfied what is the reason for this
kind of desire is that it's not pure
desire it's an impure desire
it's an impure desire and when such a
desire starts working you can go any far
like Saddam Hussein like Hitler like
anything is nothing but absolutely
desired beyond any limitations you want
to dominate others is also another
desire
all these desires lead you ultimately to
a destruction because there's no joy
there's no happiness for example now I
want to have a sorry so I want to buy
aside all my attention will be how we
like in that sorry I must get that sorry
this thing that thing the attention
becomes polluted disturbed for a
nonsensical thing like a sorry the
attention which has to enjoy which has
to enjoy the spirit which has to nourish
the spirit becomes disturbed because of
desires in the first place
the attention is disturbed because we
are not innocent in the second place the
attention gets into turmoil because we
have desire
so what should we do as far as the
desire is culture a desire for beautiful
things we can shift our desire material
desire into aesthetics I have one thing
but which is really aesthetically rich
so whatever you desire if you start it
working it out desiring for something
aesthetically handmade nicely
[Music]
gradually you'll find will end up with
vibrations because all beautiful things
have vibrations and to have the
vibrations you have to go to pure desire
so this desire which is madness which
makes you mad which is so much darlin
boring becomes pure desire because you
have to dissolve all your desires into
vibration you to start desiring nothing
but vibrations after self so if you have
vibrations that doesn't mean that they
are something dry no it means the joy of
nothing Mukti is you cannot adoration
this that it's the ocean of love that is
God you just get dressed into it there's
no word stood and that is what when you
feel you must know that you have taken
the spirit as a real connection between
you and your mother or your father
there's no differentiation you are one
in that ocean grazed in the ocean
you are the drop you are the ocean you
are one in that nothing and that but
they cannot be mechanical because not
man-made so to enjoy sahaja yoga you
must know that it's not dry vibrations
only but misty bhakti
that is the joy of choise quality
quality of joy that he adds to our life
everything seems to be surrounded
resounding same thing the joy that I'm
loved so much by God that God God loves
me that I have a meaning in life then
the ego drops out first of all and also
the conditionings drop
[Music]
now the third Nadi
3rd Nadi is the Nadi by which we feel
attached attached to someone like this
is my child this is my husband this is
my family this is my wife this is my
father this is my mother in the
beginning of sahaja yoga of everyone
when they are just the beginners so they
talk about their whole family my father
is like this my mother is seeing my
mother sisters brothers these that's
real this thing is not right
as if you see we all have taken a
contract what should I do
so now this so-called limited love what
is the solution which takes you to
destruction is the unlimited because
Shiva is nothing but love is love
now is that corrects that nourishes that
wants your benevolence that's what you
eyes it wants your benevolence it looks
after your benevolence so when you are
looking after the benevolence of others
wait now then the whole life changes the
whole pattern changes and you really
enjoy it because you become one with so
many concern that so many families so
many things many problems of others sir
it just feels you are born with so many
all this is the most enjoyable
I mean why all this is for there after
all think about yourself why am I here
I'm here to enjoy everyone everyone they
are all realized Souls such beautiful
lotuses I am NOT going to stoop down to
the mud now I am aloneness that
is the way you open the heart the Lotus
of your heart and the fragrance of such
a person it's so beautiful it's so
beautiful so you are no more divisive
you do not want to separate from each
other anywhere is done you are agreeable
to that you don't think that it will be
done here or there or there but anywhere
but should be all of us together so
they're small attachments that are with
you have to be dissolved into this ocean
of love which is Shiva
fourth one is the most important for all
of us is to know that there's a nerdy
which passes through the official
different into the heart starts from the
heart goes up passes through our gap it
has four petals opens up this is the one
which gives you the state which is
called as thorium we live in three
states in the living in the awakened
state geography our attention goes to
these that and all that we spoiled our
attention but the second one is the one
what we call is that we sleep when we
sleep also all these things that have
happened come to us from our past and
things like that but then we go to the
deepest deep water specialty is a state
where we have deep sleep and you dream
of something that is reality also you
may dream about me
I kiss the ether a part of the
subconscious where some beautiful
informations are passed or supposing I
come say Italy Italians might know in
their social tea that I've come here or
maybe anybody might know depends all but
the fourth state is called Astoria there
are two more states you are in notorious
state is the fourth today means fourth
for state is where that you are in a
thoughtless awareness
when there is no thought just think of
it when there is no thought you have to
be innocent when there is no thought you
have to have vibrations when there is no
thought you cannot be attached to anyone
so into that hot a state you have come
now is through the artistic thing but in
this state when you are these four
petals which are within you have to open
out in your brain they come from your
heart to your brain and that is where
they absolutely understand what is God
absolutely no what is parties that is
the time when one receives the real
knowledge
but unless and until these four petals
open one may fall back that's where some
other sahaja Yogi's who are still
meddling with things if they should not
do wha and they don't understand what is
God is but it's not the understanding
you know you understand this one little
point that it comes from your heart
impure brain not from brain your heart
it comes as if the amarosa
of your body covers your brain
absolutely I will sure to achieve that
state my god