have you done yoga have you done a lot
of yoga now put these dots I'll tell
everybody all right what are do these
days it's true about everyone we shall
Hindus everybody get the massage you
asked about who these dancing where is
Buddha place within us do they know who
died is placed within us at a pond and
what does he control within us we have
to know this knowledge of the roots
unless and until you know the knowledge
of the roots how will you know about the
treat you cannot treat the treatment on
its leaves or branches you have to do
the roots first you find out the roots
in Buddhism is so superficial now that
have myself amazed and Radames living
for God from where death he says buddham
sharanam gachami what is it this is an
enlightened
the dumbest work with analyzer some
gumption cachaca means to the collective
in tandem is facilitating the monster
the mummy is the balancing how many
booties know about they don't know even
where Buddha is sitting on their head
and what I find most of the booties but
their center of Buddha is finished so
thighs disappeared from their husband
and he set me down here on the head on
the left hand we can prove it on
Kundalini
supposing somebody is following Goethe
immediately people will know that you
are because it's a catchy and then some
methods are there to awaken him
if you all right so you must know the
knowledge of routine we should not just
depend on to these lambs or any ism
yeah see we have to have complete
integrated knowledge no no there is no
system about it there's no system no
practice no person actually it is for
take I am talking about few revolutions
your evolution comes through a living
force of the Living God you cannot have
a course in that can you not how do you
sprout the season you have to just put
it in the mother earth it sprouts myself
is building in the same way within you
it is building and it stops maybe you
may not get you today use it some seed
sprouts faster
is going out
nunim which is you're sadly mistaken
about Buddhism the trouble is with the
Western people they are so fed up with
Christianity that they think the visa
meals are going to solve the problem
that just like any other all these Lama
should be hanged by the neck here these
people they're horrible either vibration
you miss Dalai Lama Monday sitting next
to me I was invited to the primary
suspect I just can't bear you and the
Prime Minister love of shah Crimson for
the realized role any cookie if you
leave any hot entities leave me in these
in the extremely hot fellow you get on
the other side you've made the part you
won't understand that's how you don't
understand even a given child who the
realized soul will understand but you
won't because you are not difference
means you are mentally understand I have
a granddaughter she was hardly five
years of age when my daughter and the
son-in-law went to LA it's an
interesting story and there was a llama
sitting you see like that and
everybody's touching his feet this
little child who is a realized soul who
made it anymore when the father went and
touched his food she just stood back and
she said what do you mean by shaving
your head and wearing this big stuff you
think you are a realized soul why are
you making everybody touch your feet
just is tada and my coming off and quite
embarrassed and he told that he not even
add a last so why do you touch it you
won't understand even a little child
will understand you won't understand
realized soul is a person
this is what could I say does not read
east on things yes said first of all see
yourself would that did he talk about
God why because he thought if you talk
about God again another religion in
stock
he just said first of all as I said
first of all teach yourself get yourself
knowledge nothing else but get your
realization or exactly so whether having
it better have it you seem to have good
reason there's nothing like that these
people are meant to have it means to get
realization what tradition are the
college carrying that ring like names
like that Matthew please that was
pathetic he thought his realization fit
into all these nonsensical things with
llamas and they even beat people and who
all kinds of seemed horrible twelve
people have got their out of that NASA
you should see the pivotal now they are
sitting on our head like parasites in
England and we had a parliament question
on them you see they look very
attractive because you have fed up with
your this charity that's what don't
believe in all this please whether they
induce Christians who scream all are
doing nothing you become the realized
version
you have beat it all right that's what
I'm saying
as a mother
and then if they started another one
Shambhala business this is another new
thing taking everybody to go be there
and to get somebody walking that Kobe
does not even one mile you will get a
Samadhi permanently lots of water there
to bring my child but what things
happening to you who don't know mall
dancing in Spain some Spanish people
have started they are recruiting people
to go to Gobi Desert I mean what is
going to happen to them think of the
Gobi Desert is one of the worst deserts
of the world can you imagine going to a
desert how will you reach God you have
to seek in the English
is there any other question of put
attention to that that is important
but one thing more when you follow them
you never ask questions I had one lady
from a llama
she came down from Norway she was
absolutely horrid the vibrations man
what was that mean coming Mia yeah
yeah she came to my house has a bob oh I
am just thinking her in a percent you
know arguing arguing with me throw out
an order I said oh how did you happen a
Michele me into this llama I said
whatever I said no he wrote to us that I
can't live in an ordinary house you have
to make a motion so first you'll starve
ourselves within one year we collected
money made a Marvel show for the fellows
we came and was sitting on the seventh
step and we were first one year we had
to just point out one thousand and one
time then he might in every day and I
have done that course but I said in
charge why any one of course I like that
you are because that shows you a free
world I am NOT mesmerised but must see
the sense
Oh how do we accept the good huh let's
see
have you seen Buddha
I will met him have you met anybody who
is a Buddhist who says he can give
realization but then why are we the
preachers of Buddha whom they have never
seen on the way we don't know anything
about him
why because I am living he's not when he
was living there are people who were
asking about other people better be in
the present
get what