this is the world that feed the Swiss
bank octopus this is the world where too
much is not enough this is the world
where negativity is a plus this is the
world where the same say in out
[Music]
this is a world where 1.3 billion people
live on an income of less than one
dollar a day and where the planet does
not have enough natural resources to
sustain at a worldwide scale the
consumption pattern of Malaysia leave
alone America
please shri durga destroy the evil
forces that materialism
[Music]
10% of world trade they generated by
drugs and our contracts are 100 billion
US dollars represents the amount that le
poisons mankind while money-laundering
in Switzerland and elsewhere has become
a most prosperous activity reaching all
levels of society
please Shri raktha beeja of in a [ __ ]
destroy the evil forces that materialism
created
w
Jeannie
this is a world where Wall Street's suck
the wealth from the working middle class
bestow it upon the rich and we're Walt
Disney makes you forget all about it
please shriek at eonni destroy the evil
forces that materialism created
this is a world where an Egyptian eats
at McDonald's in Cairo and a Chinese at
Pizza Hut in Beijing because modern
consumerism expresses the lowest common
denominator of world culture and erases
the meaning of national values and
traditions please free Shaq embody
destroy the evil forces that materialism
ha
the new multinational entities are
experimenting with you
dictatorship
setting their production sites in the
developing world reducing the slavery as
a dude working class and exploding
children on the altar our productivity
gains please free Rock Shikari destroy
the evil forces that materialism created
[Music]
the globalization of production and
services allow a few global players to
be foolish and impose the rules of their
game to the mass of unsuspecting
consumers
please Shree be my baby destroy the evil
forces that materialism
[Music]
[Applause]
vast restructuration endeavors are
progressively leading to the eradication
of small and medium-sized enterprises
for the Bennett for the benefit of
gigantic corporations operating on a
worldwide scale please treat Chandigarh
destroy the evil forces that materialism
created
[Music]
the gradual concentration of liquid
wealth in the hands of the super-rich
its marginalizing national serenity and
its elected officials that is opposing
our Titanic dimension to the rulership
of money please Shri RockShox Agni
destroy the evil forces that materialism
created Swami
Daksha
greed raised to the power 108 means the
polarization of the world's middle class
and outrageous wealth the remaining 10%
please treat IT Andromedan II destroy
the evil forces that materialism created
[Music]
the systematic elimination of
alternative economic solutions unequal
trade and financial financial
manipulations are challenging the
equitable distribution of wealth among
the population of the world please free
bad rainy destroy the evil forces that
materialism created
what you need
the regulations are the financial
markets has opened wide the gates of
Jurassic Park
for the large financial predators to
roam about and thousands of billions of
dollars are created from nothing by
speculated feet there are limited thirst
for money and power please Shree Agra
and Ajmer
destroy the evil forces that materialism
created
[Music]
the Swiss financial center works as a
haven for rich tax dodgers from
developing countries and diverts needed
capital from national investment
programs industrial infrastructure and
social expenditure to inflate the stock
exchange of the developed countries
please
Shri Agra Prabha destroy the evil forces
that material
[Music]
the trend of today's mega-mergers is to
marginalize the state bypass national
legislation manipulate the market
control the economy and for all
practical purposes finish off the social
foundations our real democracy
please sri maha kali destroy the evil
forces that materialism
the lure and merge of such a radical
concentration of wealth and power
threatens to neutralize all the leaking
of the spirit and a deafening roar of
the triumph of historic materialism
destroys the hope of millions of secrets
please free Mahamaya destroy the evil
forces that materialism
[Music]
the Alliance of mafia secretive bankers
and horrible managers has infiltrated
the world economy and is threatening the
ethics of collectivity which provide the
foundation for the value system of our
entire civilization
please Ramirez anger now destroy the
evil forces that materialism creator
[Music]
the enormous increase of financial
assets has zip and cash money out of the
real economy and channeled it into the
financial markets building up a
planetary gambling casino where
arbitrary currency speculation can mount
huge attacks against any country which
tries to follow socially minded policies
[Music]
my socks are
like the Bellini
[Music]
the ethics sophistication of financial
act electronic circuits has created a
virtual world where the immature ability
of money has become the sole reality
please Shri Vishnu Maya destroy the evil
forces that materialism create
[Music]
the aggressive domination of technology
is sucking the blood of the farmer the
artist and the Potter turning the man
who works with his hands into a
permanently handicapped person
please Sridevi Kalia samudaya destroy
the evil forces that materialism created
[Music]
the information highway leads to the
Maya web of a virtual world where human
attention is scattered desire is
confused truth is atomized and the soul
is thereby reduced to slavery
please Shri Radha destroy the evil
forces that materialism created
[Music]
modern communication can become a
domestic tool in the hands of a few
medium models and opinion making tycoons
with which are spreading their
Hellenistic world views of powers money
and sex
please Tricia cat Mika destroy the evil
forces that materialism created
[Music]
the ledgers of Saturn have infiltrated
the Internet's global village to pour
pornographic dirts and filled with in
the nest of the family and to spread
hell shadows the minds of helpless
people please she need my life Kumari
destroy the evil forces that man
[Music]
Heil salutations to the great Davey on
our men may there be auspiciousness joy
and peace may thy divine grace and a
trade the waters flowing from our
mountains to the four corners of Europe
and spread the pure vibrations of the
Aquarian age
salutations to these shri mataji nirmala
devi g the resplendent one o formidable
avatar we bow to thee most pleasing yet
most frightful who has been approached
by the Trimurti z' for the sake of
protecting the universe today in this
festival of Navratri we chant the litany
of thy children in switzerland for the
defeat of the foes of the spirit and we
offer to thy glittering teeth the new
suruc forms of materialism please fear
acted Antica destroy the evil forces
that materialism created
[Music]
me
suction
you
city
[Music]
need in my life
you