I
bow to all the seekers of truth.
Today they have decided that I should give
you a general idea about Sahaja Yoga and after
that on Monday and Tuesday I’ll speak to
you about all the details of the mechanism.
I have come to America to give you a great
message of the salvation of human beings.
Everybody is trying to frighten us that there
is going to be a doomsday and we are all going
to be doomed.
But the one who has created this universe
has some worry about His creation also and
that He is not going to allow this creation
to be destroyed.
Not only that but He is extremely anxious
that this creation should be saved, that human
beings must be saved and they should enter
into the kingdom of God to enjoy the realm,
the glory and the blessings of their Father,
the God.
It is hard to believe in those days of turmoil
that any such thing can happen to us.
But perhaps we are not aware that we are fantastically
made great instruments of God’s powers.
The only thing needed is that we should be
put to the mains.
Unless and until we have connected to Him
we do not understand the value of this instrument
which has been created with great care, love
and tenderness.
We just believe that this body has come to
us, we take it for granted and we actually
do not even think why we have become a human
being from a small insignificant thing like
an amoeba.
There must be some reason for becoming a human
being.
And what is the purpose of a life, why are
you on this Earth, what are we doing, what
are we [UNCLEAR]?
We do not ask these questions to ourselves.
On the contrary we have turned our back to
all such questions and we think make the hay
while the sun shines.
But actually we are not.
What we are doing in our pursuits also sometimes,
we just go after things which are destructive,
which are negative, which are anti-God because
the discretion, even to understand what is
right and wrong is being lost by our over-thinking
and ego orientation.
When for us I use my ego, what I might think
is correct then we do not think that this
ego can destroy others as well as ourselves.
So it is very important to know, first of
all, that we are not our ego, we are not our
conditionings and our blind faiths, but we
are our Spirit which is absolute and which
knows the reality.
So we have to become that reality.
Unless and until we become that reality, whatever
we do is just a mental projection.
There are many people in this world who just
abide by their mental projections and that
explains many things.
Like if you see Mr.
Khomeini.
You may not like him, but if you ask the Iranians
they think he is a god and they think he is
absolutely right.
If you meet somebody else like that, like
Hitler.
Hitler thought that he was the best man and
there are many even now, they believe that
it was just a mistake otherwise they would
have to live long to really create a new race
of Arians.
All these ideas can be explained because people
lived with their rationality and rationality
has no logic in it, it has no binding force,
it has no discretion, it has no understanding
to what limit one can go.
For example somebody murders someone.
So someone can say, “What’s wrong?
I murdered because this happened, that happened
so I murdered.
But under law all these things are punishable
so we are frightened to do it and we don’t
do it.
But God’s laws are not perceived in normal
life.
They start becoming evident when we start
denying the naturalness of life.
When we become extremely sophisticated, so-called,
and artificial.
Or we go too much into some sort of a fanaticism
or some sort of a conditioning by reading
some books or forming some sort of a club
or forming some sort of an organization.
One has to know that you cannot organize God.
God cannot be organized.
God can organize you, but you cannot organize
God.
Second simple thing people don’t understand,
especially in America, is that you cannot
pay for God.
This is something so simple what people don’t
understand because for them money is everything,
perhaps I don’t know what, but recently
one of our persons tried to send an article
about Sahaja Yoga to one of the magazines,
and the people of that magazine asked how
many Rolls Royces she had and when they said
she doesn’t take any money, they said we
are not interested in her.
We are not interested in good people.
If there is something sensational, then we’d
like to publish about it.
That is what we have come to.
That anything good or a message of salvation
is not going to go to many people because
for them it is not very much pay or I don’t
know whatever it is.
So one has to understand at the very gross
level that you cannot purchase God.
But this simple thing also people don’t
understand and when you are so naîve about
your spiritual ascent, all kinds of mistakes
can be done.
Now when we do mistakes the result of it we
get into problems.
I was addressing the Jungian society in New
York and I asked him, “Why do you accept
people that take you to the subconscious?
Why should you accept people who take you
to this kind of mesmerism and hypnotism?
What is the idea behind it?”
They said, “Actually, because it is unconscious
you have to pass through it.
It’s a hodgepodge or a mixed bag, as you
call it.
That whatever is unconscious within us is
not God.
Supposing a bird can hear much more than you
can hear, a fish can understand magnetism
of the Mother Earth, but you cannot, and there
are so many things which are unconscious to
you, that doesn’t mean that all that is
unconscious is God.
Also whatever is written is not scripture.
Now what is unconscious within us and what
is not you must understand very clearly.
According to them it was that the unconscious
was placed at the bottom, then on top of that
some can be made conscious, then on top of
that, they had subconscious, then they had
conscious mind, then on top of that was the
ego.
It’s absolutely like a bag into which everything
is pushed into.
God is the greatest organizer that you could
think of and He’s so systematic and He knows
that a day has to come when you have to ascend.
He must keep that road free, like you have
kept this road free for people to pass through.
They don’t have to pass through everybody,
to every bench, to every table to come on
their seat.
So this is a very wrong conception people
have about unconscious.
Now in our body you should how see clearly
unconscious is placed.
Whatever I am telling you, you should not
also take me for granted.
It’s not a correct attitude.
But also you should not deny it because, like
a scientist, you should keep your mind open
to see what I am saying.
People who deny are the same as who accept
it blindfolded.
You should not accept it blindfolded, but
keep yourself open and keep this as a hypothesis
which is to be proved, and if it is proved
you have to accept it as a fundamental law
of God’s government.
Now within us is placed – here you can see,
is a very clear-cut thing – is the lowest
part, is the center that guards this part
of the unconscious called as the Kundalini.
It is called as Asa in the Koran and also
in the Bible it is said that I will appear
before you like tongues of flames.
Now this is the reflection of the Holy Ghost
about which in the Bible nothing has been
written and whatever has been written is very
ambiguous or a mystique.
This is the reflection of the Holy Ghost within
you is this Kundalini, which is the mother,
which has to ultimately nourish you and to
give you your second birth.
This was known to the Greeks definitely because
they called this triangular bone as sacrum
bone.
Sacrum in Greek language means sacred, so
they were quite aware of the sanctity or sacredness
of this power which is within us, so they
called it the sacrum bone.
This power resides inside this triangular
bone waiting for a chance where it can ascend
and nourish you.
You must know that normally in the body nothing
ascends by itself.
There is some sort of a force that has to
ascend it or to bring it out like blood has
to circulate to the pumping of the heart.
In the same way this Kundalini, when She is
awakened, just like the pulsation of the heart,
rises above and you can see clearly with your
eyes the pulsation of the Kundalini and the
rising of the Kundalini and also the breaking
through of the Kundalini.
If you have a second [UNCLEAR] you can feel
the pulsation of the Kundalini, rising of
the Kundalini.
You can hear the same lub-dub of the heartbeat
and on top of the head where you get your
so-called baptism, you feel the throbbing
there and ultimately this break and you start
feeling the cool breeze of the Holy Ghost.
This is the real second birth and not an artificial
birth where we just decide that we have got
a baptism.
That’s artificial.
That’s just an immature, symbolic thing.
But really what should happen is that the
living process of your evolution must be exhibited
through its happening and not just a mental
projection of accepting that you have become
a person who is twice born.
It’s just a certification, again a mental
projection.
So one has to accept that something living
has to take place, something that you can
see clearly within you happening and you have
to get something that you cannot do.
For example you have seen people who say,
“We have got the blessings of the Holy Ghost.
So you ask them, “How?”
They say, “We are jumping."
If you are jumping, anybody can jump; what
is so great about it?
Jumping is not a big thing.
If you are jumping that doesn’t mean that
you have achieved anything great.
Anybody can jump.
But you can not get the cool breeze of the
Holy Ghost coming out of your own head.
One lady said, “There is always an air conditioner
and you must be feeling the air conditioner."
I said, “All right, but from your head it
is coming out."
She said, “Yes, it’s coming out of my
head."
So I said, “ So that means your head has
become the air conditioner."
And she said, “That’s true.
The air conditioner has started working here."
And that’s what one has to know that whatever
will happen to you that is Divine, we cannot
[UNCLEAR].
We cannot transform a flower into a fruit.
There’s a thousand and one things we cannot
do which are done by the living power of God’s
love and that living power of God’s love
is reflected within us as Kundalini.
So that’s one part of the unconscious.
This is the one which can become partly conscious.
Below that is the consciousness which we call
the collective hell.
One can go to hell.
It’s very simple to go to hell.
If you want, the simplest thing to do is to
go to hell.
On the left-hand side is another consciousness
– of which we are not aware so it is unconscious
– where we talk of the subconscious.
Whatever has happened to us in this life or
many lives or to all the world, all the creations
since we were created, all that resides beyond
that point.
So we have subconscious as well as collective
subconscious.
We have another unconscious area which is
not conscious to us.
You must have seen some people, like recently
I saw a very good film about a gentleman who
was never an artist.
Suddenly he became quite funny and he said,
“I’m Gaugin and I can paint like him."
He started painting on a canvas, you could
see, just like Gaugin style with very bold
lines and all these colors as you have seen
– exactly the same way.
People couldn’t understand.
This man was never an artist, nothing.
He has done suddenly.
What has happened to him?
That means he got possessed by someone, must
have been possessed by Gaugin himself because
he was mad when he died, and that he was expressing
himself through this man and he was a medium
now.
There are many things like this which act
as mediums and anybody can get possessed by
this and in my experience I have seen most
of the diseases are called as incurable are
done when people go to the left side.
Any kind of fanaticism can give you.
Then if you try to bow yourself before people
who are fake, you get problems on the left-hand
side.
If you bow to wrong ideas or to wrong conditionings,
also you go to the left side.
Or if you just start thinking about your past
and crying and weeping, you can get into it.
So the people who are more on the left side,
when they are of an extreme nature, we call
them masochists.
On the right-hand side you have another kind
of unconscious which we call as supraconscious
unconscious.
Supraconscious is where you think more of
the future.
Such people are more troublesome to others
than to themselves.
They are ego oriented and they talk so much,
they are so aggressive, very argumentative
– very right-sided people.
They trouble others, they torture others.
They don’t torture themselves.
When you have the left-sided problem you suffer
body, but these aggressive people try to trouble
others and they’re least bothered because
that’s not their problem.
What they do is to trouble others and they
enjoy that kind of troubling and that ego
orientation.
Beyond that lies another unconscious which
is called as a collective unconscious.
This collective unconscious is made up of
people who have died with their ambitions
still intact.
Hitler has used those dead bodies to entice
the whole German nation to do all the things
that they have done.
No normal human being can be that cruel.
This kind of a thing works out in all the
countries where it is very ego oriented.
For example, an ego oriented society can have
very cruel parents, can have very cruel people
and can be very aggressive people.
As a result of their activity on the right-hand
side they develop an institution called as
ego and this ego, when it covers them, they
cannot think that anybody is right.
They think they are always right.
They always try to establish their point,
whatever it comes to and they aggress others
and try to dominate others.
The other type are the superego people.
So the people who are extremely egoistical,
they call them as sadists.
So we have two types of beings within us,
two types of unconscious within us – one
on the right-hand side and one on the left-hand
side and the third is the hell where people
are thrown when they go too much to the extreme,
to the right or the left.
But now here we are dealing with another unconscious
which is the super unconscious which is on
top of your head and that is what we have
to achieve through our evolutionary process
– achieve a living process.
The Kundalini is the feminine, the mother
within you.
That doesn’t mean the feminist society or
the feminist movement, because the feminist
movement is absolutely against it, because
what I am saying that in your evolutionary
process you have to be crowned by the compassionate,
the kind, the soothing, the nourishing quality
of a mother.
But otherwise what happens is that women think
we should become like men and men start thinking
we should become like women.
It’s a very funny sort of thing going on.
Actually it’s a pendulous movement, it is
not any evolutionary.
In an evolutionary movement you move spirally
and come above a point, much above than where
you were and start seeing things at a much
better level and a subtler level.
But this kind of pendulum movement is very
common with people who want to solve their
problems by mental projections.
They think if you have this kind of government
is good, that kind of government is good,
they try all sorts of things.
Nothing is going to work out because that’s
not reality.
Reality is only possible when you are transformed
and you become the Spirit.
That time you move spirally and come up and
you become a person who is really an enlightened
person.
As an enlightened person you get the power
to be collectively conscious.
It’s an actualization.
It is not just a lecture that we are all brothers
and sisters.
It is not just a mental understanding that,
“Oh, I’m a twice-born person."
It happens to you by which you become collectively
conscious, means you actualize the experience
of self realization.
As it is said in the Koran also that at the
time of resurrection your hands will speak.
You’ll be surprised that in the Koran, much
more is written about the resurrection time.
That means He talked about the future.
He said that when the resurrection time will
come your hands will speak.
Now people just want to talk about doomsday.
They don’t want to talk about the resurrection
time.
Like the newspaper, we said that if you have
to give some bad news you’d better give
us, we don’t want to have good news, that
there is a saving point, we have a right.
Because perhaps they are afraid that their
existence will be lost if you say that there
is no need to worry, you will all get transformed.
So whatever it is, we have to get transformed
and without transformation there is no solution.
In Sanskrit language this is called as atma
sakshatkar, means the facing or actualizing
the Spirit.
Also a twice-born is called as dwijaha.
Even a bird is called as twice born because
first it’s an egg and when the egg becomes
the bird he becomes a dwijaha.
So there is a difference in the personality
of an egg and the personality of a bird and
that’s how this transformation has to take
place.
Like somebody asked me, “Mother, I believe
in this thing."
I said, “But ask yourself why did you believe?”
He said, “I felt like giving him."
I said, “This is an explanation."
Then everybody will say, “I believe in it,
I’m believing in that and if everybody believed
in something, they fight.
Why do they fight?
By believing into something you have just
used your ego, that you have fixed your ego
with certain ideas and you are accepting it,
or on your superego that you have conditioned
yourself, or this is the thing I have to do,
that thing I have to do.
But it is not because maybe it is wrong, maybe
it is right because you are still on a relative
terminology.
To believe into something is all mental projection
again, but you have to keep your mind open
and see for yourself.
First of all you must see those who believe
into it, what effect it has.
Like somebody told me that some people fast
on such and such day in India, or they fast
in Ramadan on a certain date.
I said, “All right.
One should do that in case you find by doing
such and such thing these people are exceptional,
that they are something great, that they have
achieved something in life, that they can
say that they have become the Spirit, that
they can say that they are collectively conscious,
that they can feel you and feel themselves
on their fingertips.
Not only that but they have to be peaceful
people, they have to be compassionate people
and their presence must nourish you.
If it is done then all right, it is a proper
thing.
But because there is a fashion to club something
like this or another fashion to club like
that, if you try to club under any banner
like that, then we are sadly mistaken that
we have not done full justice to our mind.
Anything that you cannot reflect back and
where you lose the capacity to reflect is
a wrong thing.
When you become the Spirit the more you reflect
the more you understand.
We had one gentleman who came to Sahaja Yoga.
He got his realization and he said, “Mother,
you said that you become collectively conscious.
I want to know about my father, what’s wrong
with my father."
He wanted to question and he wanted to see
if it is true or not.
I said, “All right, put your hands towards
your father and just say, ‘I want to know
about my father,’ because you are connected
and your computer is working."
What happened was that he got a burning on
his finger, on this part, He asked, “Mother,
what is the decoding of this?
That you are getting this burning means what?”
So I told him that this means that your father
must be down with very bad bronchitis because
this center is here [Shri Mataji points to
throat].
And he telephoned to his father and found
out that his mother said – exactly the same
sentence – that your father is down with
very bad bronchitis.
Now the telecommunication of God has started
working.
You can even cure your father sitting down
here.
Then he tried to do it and he asked after
3 or 4 hours and they said he is all right,
he’s out of his bed.
So first what happens, you start reflecting
about your achievements.
Start feeling openly does it work, how it
works, do you see anything like that?
and when you are convinced about it then you
start proceeding further with it.
But anything that makes you so incapable that
you cannot reflect then I see a kind of enslavement
of whatever type it is.
Like I have seen people just do it because
they are told to do it.
We are people who are freedom loving, especially
in this country has talked a lot about freedom
and the freedom doesn’t mean abandonment.
It doesn’t mean that you just get lost in
your freedom.
But it means that wisdom to balance your freedom,
how to understand the value of your freedom.
If you do not have that sense, all freedom
can be lost.
This freedom can only be understood and could
be valued when you become the Spirit.
If you are not the Spirit, even if you give
a hundred dollars to somebody, he might immediately
go to a place which will destroy him.
People do not have wisdom to understand even
the value of their money, their position,
their chastity.
They have no sense at all of their self also.
So how you develop this is through the awakening
of your Spirit within you.
There’s a category of people who are seekers.
They are a category.
Everybody is not a seeker.
They need not be showing that they are seekers,
they may not be apparently seekers but in
their heart of hearts, they are seekers and
they are the epitome of our evolution.
They are the ones who are going to be blessed.
Not every person.
He may be a king, He may be a big man, he
may be a minister, anything.
It makes no difference.
He has to be a seeker and a seeker is going
to be blessed to begin with.
It is a seeker who knows that she’s seeking
something beyond.
But those who are still seeking money, all
right, go ahead with your money.
When you are fed up with it then you will
come to God.
Those who are seeking power, all right, go
ahead with your power.
Those who are mediocres are not good for Sahaja
Yoga to begin with.
First only the seekers get the blessings.
They can be under any [UNCLEAR], they can
be anything.
Only their Kundalini judges them and tells
that they are the seekers.
I’ve seen people who have just met me once
and got their realization and settled down.
One of them came to America who started giving
realization to so many, another one came to
Boston, another part of America.
He just started giving realization, another
went to Vancouver, they just started giving
realization to people.
It’s not that the realization is a guarantee
for anyone.
It depends what is their physical, mental,
emotional and spiritual condition.
If any way there is an imbalance within you,
it has to be balanced and you have to get
your realization.
Nobody can fight for it, nobody can be aggressive,
you cannot argue it out.
On the contrary those who argue too much seldom
get realization.
You have to be humble about it.
If you are humble about it, you do get your
realization.
There is nothing to be given up except for
your ego and superego.
That’s what you have to get of and you can
see that very clearly.
When the Kundalini rises, when She touches
this point, then an awakening takes place
here.
By that awakening these two institutions are
sucked in and you get a very soft bone on
your head like a child.
As Christ has said you have to be like a child
to enter into the kingdom of God and then
you enter into the limbic area and through
this part you enter into the subtle energy
of that all-pervading power which is called
in Sanskrit as gamba shakti.
There is no difference in what these people
have been talking, They are all absolutely
one with each other, complete [UNCLEAR uni-religion].
There is no difference at all.
Christ himself has said those who are not
against Me are with Me.
But we never try to find out which are the
ones who are not against Him.
And He also said you will be calling Me Christ,
Christ, and I won’t recognize you.
Why?
He said, “By calling Christ, Christ, you
do not become Christians."
You become Christians only by real baptism,
by the awakening of the Kundalini, by breaking
of this area and entering into that subtle
area where you become one with the all-pervading
Diving power.
And this has to happen, this is your right
to have it.
Sahaja Yoga – Saha means with, Ja means
born.
It’s spontaneous, the spontaneous yoga of
the Spirit.
It’s a living force and you don’t have
to do anything about it.
It just works out.
Only in places where people are complicated,
I a little bit regulate the force and then
it works out.
I have to little bit nourish the different
centers which are suffering and it works out.
But in a place like India where, in the villages,
the people are extremely simple.
Thousands of them come in and get realization.
So many of them are getting realization and
having a better life.
They are no more slaves of any habits, any
diseases.
Diseases get cured because of nourishment,
your mental being improves, you get rid of
all your mental sicknesses, you get rid of
all your false guru problems and you get rid
of the oppression of the modern times that
is working on you.
You become a free bird and you start seeing
the whole thing as a drama.
This has to happen to many people – not
to one but to many.
When it happens you’ll be amazed this is
the time of our last judgment.
This is the time where you are going to be
judged by your Kundalini.
Nobody is going to put you on a scale to find
out how far you are good.
It’s only the Kundalini which is going to
tell.
When She rises She indicates that this person
has this problem, that problem and not only
that but through Sahaja Yoga problems can
be solved and you can be established into
Sahaja Yoga.
May God bless you all.
This is just an introduction to Sahaja Yoga
I’ve given you and again on Monday and Tuesday
I will tell you about the different chakras
and nadis within us, how they work out, how
we get diseases, how to get them cured, how
you can do it yourself, but how you become
the Spirit, what is the nature of Spirit,
how the Spirit expresses itself within ourselves
and what are its powers.
May God bless you.
As today is the first day I would like you
to ask me some questions but not like mad
people.
Ask good questions, sensible questions which
have some relevance.
There’s no need to be aggressive with me.
Supposing you believe in something.
All right you go ahead with it.
I have not to argue with you.
I’m here to give you the reality to find
out within yourself what is it.
No use saying this has happened, that has
happened.
If you belong to any group you go ahead with
it.
When you get fed up then you can come to me.
Still I’m willing to help you all.
May God bless you.
[Someone in the audience starts delivering
a long rant.
He doesn’t seem to
want to leave so Shri Mataji stands up to
talk to him]
Shri Mataji: No, no, let me handle him.
Gentleman, please listen.
Sir?
Hello?
Hey, mister, if you are talking about Christ
you have to change your tone.
This is not the way you should talk as a Christian.
Behave yourself.
This is not a Christian way of talking.
If you are talking about Christ, you are talking
like a satanic person.
That’s not the way to talk.
Ah, now you want to crucify me?
Is He in your pocket?
Was Christ born in America?
Just look at this madness.
What
to do?
Nothing you can do with these people.
Seeker: I have been meditating and had a vision
of you.
He then saw the picture of you.
He heard you were talking about collective
consciousness tonight and I presume he’s
trying to see through this maze.
Shri Mataji: You are a seeker.
That’s how the unconscious helps.
Many people dream.
Look at the unconscious, how helpful it is.
But for a person who is gross, what can one
do?
There are so many ways by which people are
suggested and told because God is anxious
that people should be saved.
Absolutely, it is true and it’s a good thing
that you have said it.
But one should understand the most important
thing is that you must become your own Spirit.
This is just a suggestion to you to come here
to become the Spirit.
It’s not important, whatever I am.
Supposing I am something, so what?
What have I done for you?
What you are going to get out of me is important.
So you get something out of me because you
have had a suggestion, you saw, is good.
So many people dream of me.
In India is very common because people are
simple and they go into their deeper sleep
very easily while here, people are not that
simple.
They are so pressurized in life that they
don’t feel that.
But I’m happy that you dreamt about it.
May God bless you.
Seeker: Will you be performing any healings
tonight?
Shri Mataji: Yes, maybe.
It might work out.
It just works automatically.
Actually I do not heal individually anyone.
We’ll give you little guidelines by which
it will work out.
In a general way it works out because then
the Kundalini rises She nourishes you and
you get healed.
I do not do anything particularly on one person.
You get healed because you have that power
within you to heal yourself.
Only what I do is like a candle which is enlightened
enlightens another light.
Yogi: Actually she is going to give you the
experience of self realization when the questions
are over.
So if you want to stay, please do and feel
it for yourself and then you will start to
become your own healer.
Shri Mataji: You have to become your own master,
your own guru.
You don’t need any guru.
Once you have your second birth that’s all.
It’s so simple, it’s so fantastic.
Why not have it?
Why was he fighting with me I just don’t
understand.
He must be paid by someone.
I don’t know what is the matter.
Is he drunk?
I’m saying that you have got something,
your own power, your own diamond within you.
Just have it.
Am I saying anything wrong?
Seeker: Is
meditation part of your program and do you
teach a technique of meditation?
Shri Mataji: Actually there is nothing like
doing meditation.
What happens is that you become one with your
present.
Means you are in meditation.
It is not that you have to do meditation but
you just become in meditation.
So the meditation has no technique as far
as the spontaneity is concerned.
First you are awakened spontaneously, just
like a seed is sprouted.
Then you have to look after yourself because
[UNCLEAR at the first shot] the Kundalini
rises, just like a jet it comes up.
But then it goes back and settles back into
other places where there is a problem.
Then you have to learn how to keep it going
and establish yourself like a little seedling
where you put in a proper place, look after
it properly and then it starts growing well.
So it is in stages.
First is the awakening of the Kundalini, secondly
is the breaking of the Sahasrara, and third
is the establishment of yourself as a realized
soul.
Then comes the stage where you are called
a Sahaja Yogi where you master the whole art
of giving realization to others, of understanding
yourself and there is a stage where there
aren’t any doubts.
Seeker: How long does it take generally for
one to get the kind of consciousness where
the Kundalini awakens?
Shri Mataji: It’s a very good question,
Sir.
It is the question of a seeker, It takes just
a split of a second.
But not with everyone.
If you say, “How much time does it take
for an aeroplane to take off?
We say if everything is normal it takes ten
minutes.
But everything has to be all right which is,
normally, you don’t find.
That’s an abnormal situation these days,
to find somebody normal.
So when they are abnormally like that, it
takes a little time, you have to work it out.
Otherwise it is spontaneous.
In a simple person like a child, it just shoots
off.
Don’t worry.
It will work out.
Seeker: One more question?
Shri Mataji: Yes, please.
Seeker: Somebody wants to get a job.
They need experience.
So you get experience you are good at job.
It’s like a big cycle.
So the profession you are talking about is
it possible that somebody here on the world
could never be able to awaken the Kundalini
because of his condition.
Is it assumed that everybody can do it maybe
in ten years, fifteen years?
Shri Mataji: I wish so, but do you know in
this place how many people have come out of
this great Los Angeles?
Just see.
This is the condition.
But let one fake guru come here.
He can fill the whole hall and people would
be hanging from there.
That’s the problem.
I wish that what you say comes true.
If they come they’ll get it.
But if they don’t want to come, you cannot
force it.
That’s their freedom.
You cannot hypnotize, you cannot do anything.
They have to come, really.
They have to knock at the door.
Seeker: If you are meditating at the moment
should you continue with your present meditation
or does it really matter?
Shri Mataji: No, you will give up on all that
yourself because you’ll find out that the
state of meditation is something that is inbuilt.
Once it starts, like, say, you are inside
this room.
You don’t need a car, isn’t it?
Once you are inside there then you don’t
need anything.
Then you have to know how to be there all
the time.
Seeker: When the Kundalini rises, then you
said it goes down.
Does it go down to a place where it has to
help and if that does happen can somebody
else help to fix it up?
Shri Mataji: Yes, many can, and thank God
now in your Los Angeles we have at least ten
people who can do that and you’ll be the
eleventh one to help them later on.
Don’t you worry on that point.
You have to work it out.
It’s not difficult.
It has become very easy now.
Seeker: When exactly does the Holy Spirit
reveal things to you?
Shri Mataji: The Holy Spirit which is reflected
within you as this Kundalini, when She rises,
She enlightens your centers.
By that, what happens is that you start feeling
your centers on your finger tips, on your
central nervous system, on your complete consciousness.
[Someone in the audience starts interrupting
which becomes more and more shouting and chaos.]
Shri Mataji: I don’t understand these people.
It has never happened whatsoever in any country.
Yogi: He’s probably a born-again Christian.
Shri Mataji: It must be fine for…
After all, what have you done?
He’s talking so big…
Now I think we’ll do the questioning tomorrow,
all right?
Let’s have the realization now my child,
if you don’t mind madame.
You can write it down, darling.
You give me all things written down and I
will answer all your questions because this
thing starts.
This is a funny thing, I tell you.
Yogi: They’re just saying this is Hollywood
Los Angeles.
Yogi: The questions we are going to leave
it for next time.
Mother wants to give you the experience.
If you want it, please stay.
If you do not want to receive it, that’s
fine.
Shri Mataji: Go away.
Give me my freedom.
Why are you doing like this?
[Woman in audience wants to continue the conversation.]
Yogi: Please, can we all just turn this way
and Mother is going to give you the experience.
Let’s get on with it.
Shri Mataji: Madame.
Hello, madame, can you give them the experience?
Can you do it?
No you cannot.
What you feel is different.
You are an individual.
But can you give the experience?
If you cannot, let me do it.
If you feel then go ahead with it.
I’m not saying you don’t feel it.
You can go out.
Why are you here disturbing others?
You can go away if you don’t want to stay
here.
Let the others feel also.
You cannot give them the experience, can you?
So you go away.
Yogi: Maybe, I think, she was saying that
these other people have evil spirits and not
you.
Shri Mataji: You see, I don’t know what
you were saying.
Whatever it is now you must understand.
Woman in audience: Can I say a word?
Maybe it is time to tell you that she loves
you…
Shri Mataji: I tell you I can’t hear, I’m
sorry for that.
Yes, now I understand.
What I’m trying to tell you: Be simple about
it.
I know that they are evil spirits or whatever
you say.
I don’t want to call them by any bad names,
I understand that but let it be.
Forget about that.
Don’t pay attention to anyone.
It’s all right.
I understand.
Just think, now, I couldn’t hear anything
at all what you were saying.
So forget it, madame, it’s all right.
They are not crucifying me at least, isn’t
it?
That’s not so bad.
It could be much worse.
It makes no difference to me.
Now can you much forgive?
Because they don’t know what they are doing.
They are out of gear.
Man in audience: No, I wouldn’t say they
are out of gear.
I would say they are in gear.
Shri Mataji: Ah?
Man: You used the words of Jesus Christ, right?
Shri Mataji: I have no right?
Listen now.
I think some people think that Jesus Christ
was born in America…
What right do you have on Jesus Christ?…
Why can’t I talk about Christ?
Yogi: It looks like an organized group that
came in numbers.
They’ve all got Bibles and they’re probably
all born-again Christians.
Shri Mataji: What’s he saying?
Yogi: He’s advising us not to say anything
just for the moment.
Shri Mataji: They get angry because I say
you can’t take money.
These groups always take money.
Yogi: Can I suggest that – a good way to
experience this is to slip your shoes off
to make the contact with the Earth, put your
hands out toward Shri Mataji – socks if
you wish, it’s up to you.
Just simply put your hands out and, in your
heart, all you have to do is ask for it, nothing
else.
Shri Mataji: Now, please, don’t disturb
anyone.
I request you, please.
It’s really sinful to disturb people who
are seeking God, who are seeking reality.
Yogi: Put your hands comfortably in your lap.
Shri Mataji: Just put your hands straight
and both your feet touching the Mother Earth.
Please sit straight, neither bending too much
nor pushing back your neck.
In a straight way please be seated.
Now close your eyes.
You have to keep your eyes closed.
Now as I’ve told you, when we have problems
with our centers we have to nourish them.
So keep your left hand towards me throughout
because the left hand is the desire power
within you.
And the right hand you have to use it to nourish
your centers which require nourishment.
First of all you have to know that we are
all Spirit.
And so, please put your right hand on your
Heart
and say – you can ask a question if you
want – to me.
You can address me as Mother or Shri Mataji
if you can say that.
Ask a question, “Mother, am I the Spirit?”
Ask three times.
Without feeling guilty.
Don’t feel guilty about anything because
we are in the present now here so you are
not to feel guilty at all.
Just ask the question, “Am I the Spirit?”
It’s like watering the plant.
You are nourishing your Heart.
Open your Heart.
With confidence, “Mother, am I the Spirit?”
Now if you are the Spirit, then you are your
own guide, you are your own master, you are
your own guru.
So you have to put your right hand…
Please don’t feel guilty.
All of you have this problem.
I think you should not feel guilty at all.
At this time you should say, “I don’t
feel guilty at all."
It’s very important.
Not to feel guilty.
Forget about the past.
Now put the right hand on the stomach on the
left-hand side.
Put your left hand towards me as it was and
put your right hand on the left-hand side
of the stomach and press it a little.
This is the center
of Primordial Master.
You have to say here in your Heart ten times
with full confidence, “Mother, am I my own
master?”
“Am I my own guide?”
“Am I my own guru?”
Or you can say with full assertion, “Mother,
I am my own master."
“Mother I am my own guru."
“Mother, I am my own guide."
Because “I” stands for the Spirit and
not for ego.
Again raise your hand to your Heart.
Now without feeling guilty again you have
to assert, no questioning.
You have to assert, “Mother, I am the Spirit."
Say it twelve times.
On the Heart, press it hard without feeling
guilty.
Now raise your right hand up to your forehead
and put it across.
At this center, you have to forgive everyone,
just forgive everyone.
Some people say it is very difficult to forgive,
but actually, logically if you see if you
don’t forgive you are playing into the hands
of others.
You must say I forgive everyone.
Now put this right hand at the back of the
head.
There’s another center there.
If you have forgiven everyone without feeling
guilty – again I say, without feeling guilty
– you have to say, “If I have done any
mistakes, let God forgive me."
But without feeling guilty.
It will just work out.
Now raise your hand on the head.
Put it on your head, your palm.
Press it and move it clockwise.
At this point as I have said, I cannot cross
your freedom.
You have to say that you want your realization.
Please say, “I want my realization."
“Please give me my realization."
I cannot force it on you.
Now put your right hand towards me and the
left hand on your head and see if you feel
the cool breeze.
Raise the hand about six inches above.
[Shri Mataji blows into the microphone several
times] Now change your hand and see again.
[Shri Mataji blows again] Change your hand
again and see.
Some of you might feel heat.
The first state you arrive at is called as
thoughtless awareness.
Now you watch me without thinking.
Put your hands like this.
Let’s see if you can do it.
Some of you might be feeling the left hand
or the right hand.
On whatever hand you are feeling, you put
it up like that and the other hand towards
me, if you are not feeling in the right.
If you are not feeling in the left hand, you
put your left hand towards me.
In any case you try it this way.
The ventilation helps you.
First you put the left hand towards me and
the right hand up.
Now put your right hand towards me (and left
hand up).
It’s better to keep it that way because
more are right.
Also tonight I will teach you to raise your
own Kundalini which you should do at home.
You should go home and sleep – not discussing
it, talking about it but I’ll tell you how
to do it and how to feel the cool breeze in
the hand by that.
You put your left hand which is hand of your
desire in front of your Kundalini, while you
are sitting down.
Just put it like this and you have to move
your right hand in this way such that it goes
upward, forward, downward, backward – like
in a clockwise manner.
So let us move it, one hand like this.
Now move this hand like this.
At this point you take it up, push back your
head and give it a twist.
And now you put it into a knot.
[Shri Mataji demonstrates raising Kundalini
again finishing with a single knot.]
Once more.
This is the last time you have to do it but
three knots we have to give.
Now let’s do it.
You are doing it yourself [Shri Mataji raises
Kundalini a third time giving three knots].
Now see for yourself.
It’s very subtle, a subtle thing, a new
awareness.
You can put up your hands like this and ask
a question in your Heart, “Is this the cool
breeze of the Holy Ghost?”
Put your hands like this and ask the question…
Now see it for yourself.
Are you feeling the cool breeze?
Put down your hands and see for yourself.
Are you feeling the cool breeze in the hands?
Seeker: I feel it in my feet as well.
Shri Mataji: It’s all over.
You’ll feel it on your feet, it’s all
around you.
It’s a game sometimes.
It’s all there.
First experience is very strong.
But you have to keep it on.
Don’t forget the first experience if you
have had and you have to be serious about
it.
You must understand, it’s a deep thing that
has happened.
This has been what you have been asking for
ages now and you are blessed.
If you feel extremely peaceful and happy without
any thoughts, go home, don’t talk too much
and sleep off.
This is you are in meditation.
Some people haven’t felt, doesn’t matter.
There is a way by which we can do it and can
establish it.
So please you go home, be silent about it
and understand that you’ve got it now.
Be one with yourself, respect yourself, you
are to be respected and I
bow to all of you.
Yogi: At the end of this program as you go
out, the people here in Los Angeles have asked
if you would just give them your name and
address so that they can let you know, the
reason being that they are going to have a
follow up seminar in about a week or ten days
time afterwards and they want to be able to
let you know the dates incase you cannot come
on a Monday or Tuesday night, they could advise
you so that you could follow this up and get
the experience deeper and deeper.
So please give them the address, there is
literature at the back, they’ll be giving
that out to you.
Shri Mataji: But don’t read and get confused.
That I must tell you because to put on the
light is very easy, but to understand the
mechanism and the history and all that is
very complicated.
Of course the first book is very simple, but
you people don’t read it and get worried
about it.
Just if you want to read it, you can read,
you will, if you don’t read, it’s all
right.
We don’t give all the books.
Actually, in Sahaja Yoga, we have many books,
but we just give the first book to begin with.
I have a very short time with you.
I think you can read it, you can understand
it and come back again and gradually progress
with it with respect to yourself.
May God bless you all.
Yogi: As you heard her say, the programs are
on Monday and Tuesday night here at the same
time.
The experience is something you have to deepen
into, so come back on Monday and Tuesday nights.
Thank you very much.