Today I am going to talk to you about attention.
What is attention, what is the movement of
attention
and what are the ways and methods of raising
our attention.
Keep it in broad ways.
Alright?
But when I am saying all these things
you must know that I am talking to you individually
– it’s not about others.
Always the first thing human beings do is,
when I am speaking to you,
you try to find out about who Mataji is speaking!
This is the best way of putting your attention
onto something else.
If you put your attention to yourself that,
“This is for me and me and me alone,”
then it will have an effect, because these
[words of mine] are mantras.
And that’s why it is wasted
because whatever is given to you is thrown
onto another person.
So the attention, that you have, is the only
way to know the reality.
Your own attention is important, not the attention
of others
or your attention on others!
This must be clearly understood.
If you understand this point that the whole
thing
is to be consumed by you,
through your attention to raise yourself to
a higher situation,
it will work out.
Otherwise, it is like giving food to you
and going to another person who is getting
nourished,
while you are getting nothing.
And that person also may not be able get nourished,
because he doesn’t know that you are throwing
it to that person.
So today, as I am going to speak to you about
attention,
you should know that your attention should
absorb all that I am saying.
It is not meant for anybody else.
You better sit in thoughtless awareness, that’s
the best way,
so that it goes into you.
Otherwise it’s like a lecture, you know.
That you listen to me has no effect.
Every lecture will transform you because,
after all, I am speaking.
But because you always think of others
and you think of your problems all the time
– something nonsensical is going on, about
which you are worried –
and the attention is so overloaded
that whatever is said to you doesn’t go
into you.
So, just now, utilise it by being attentive
and knowing
that all these nonsensical things have no
value.
It’s your attention that has to come up
and has to grow.
So, attention is the whole of the canvas of
your being
– is a complete canvas, is the attention.
Complete canvas of your being is the attention.
How much you have gone into it, how much you
have discovered it,
how far you have raised it is a different
point.
Attention is Chitta and God is attention.
How far your attention has been enlightened
is a different point.
But your attention is God
– if you become enlightened to that extent.
It is like a canvas.
You can say it is like a canvas which is spread
out for a film,
and whatever aptitudes or, you can say, the
drags or movements, your attention has,
shows on that canvas.
I don’t know what is the word for ‘vritti’
in English language.
It’s not aptitude, but a person gets prone
to, or his attention is dragged to
– I don’t know [if] there is a word like
that in English language – vritti.
Can you suggest any word?
So our attention is just a pure, completely
pure canvas
and is acted upon by the three gunas we have,
to begin with.
And the three gunas come to you, as you know,
one from your past, one from your future sense
and one from the present.
Now, whatever have been your experiences about
a particular thing or a particular occasion,
so far, is completely recorded in your memory.
For example, if you see the black colour:
all that goes with the black colour is recorded
in your memory.
As soon as you see this black colour, quite
a lot of it comes up.
That means, as soon as you see this with your
attention,
the attention gets muddled up, or you can
say the attention gets coloured
with all the memories about this black colour.
And then your action takes place according
to the way your attention is affected.
For example, just now something was burned
by these flames.
Now, all of you became aware of it.
Next time whenever you will see a flame,
first thing [that] will happen will be that
you will be cautious about it.
It is not going to happen again,
but the whole memory will come to you
and you will try to be cautious or warn others,
because your attention will become aware of
that
as soon as you will see that, because that
canvas of your attention
itself will start throwing out these pictures,
out of itself,
through your past experiences, on to the canvas.
This is a living canvas.
Or may be that
if you have got some ideas which you have
premeditated,
or thought of, of the future.
For example, you must have thought of somebody
that,
“If I meet that man I will tell him like
this.”
As soon as you will meet that man,
your attention will start bubbling out with
those ideas
that are coming about this man, and you will
start addressing to him accordingly.
It’s all stored up within you,
whether it is about the future or about the
past.
It’s given out of the attention through
that bubbling process
which depends on your dragging nature, where
are you dragged.
That’s called as vritti,
but I don’t know what you call it in English
language.
I do not know what is the, what you are prone
to (tendency).
Vritti is a very neutral word.
It doesn’t mean anything bad.
It means where you are drawn to.
Vritti means a temperament by which you are
drawn to.
And whatever is your temperament, it acts
like that.
For example, if you see a man walking, say,
blindly
– he cannot see things –
one person may get angry with that person,
another may have pity for that person,
third may come forward to help him out.
It’s the vritti, it’s the temperament,
that you have developed through your three
gunas.
That’s why this attention becomes identified
with you.
And when you are identified with this, your
vritti, your temperaments,
then you are still in a misidentified area.
Let us take a case of somebody who has been
possessed before.
Now, coming to Sahaja Yoga his possession
goes away.
But the memory remains in the brain that he
was possessed.
And [if] the memory is stronger in a person,
left side is stronger,
then that memory lingers on, and as soon as
that person comes in contact with anyone
which has got something to do with the past
possession, it clicks.
And the whole thing starts coming into you
bubbling out
and you think you are again possessed.
It is the memory which gives you [this reaction].
It’s a myth.
It’s the memory that tells you, “Oh, you
are again possessed!”
Because your left side is weak, means you
always live in your memory.
Your memory is stronger than yourself.
If you could make yourself stronger than your
memory, nothing can possess you.
But after you get your Realisation,
you are not still identified with that state
of mind
in which you see your ego and superego as
myths.
Still you get caught up into your ego and
superego,
and that’s why your attention is still in
a mess.
In a pure simple way of attention in an innocent
child,
he sees everything in pratyaksha,
means in actual experiencing of something
– for a child –
because he has no memory.
So he’ll have to burn his hand to feel that
this burns.
He has to touch something cold to know that
it is cold.
His memory is not yet built up.
So into the actual experiencing of it he lives.
But that actual experiencing becomes memory.
And once the memory is built up stronger,
the whole personality is affected by memory.
All the conditioning of all kinds come through
that;
your reading, even the whole atmosphere can
come to you.
You see, sometimes you smell a particular
soap,
or say a rose, you smell it –
then all the memories of smelling such a rose,
sometimes,
comes to you and you may feel really elated
maybe sometimes, maybe, or sometimes very
unhappy,
whatever may be the situation.
So you may feel happy or unhappy.
Because, whatever experiences you have had,
has given you a memory.
This memory might have given you a superego,
or might have given you a ego.
This scanning might have taken place.
If it has been a ego and a superego,
then may be that, if it was ego you must have
felt happy.
If it is satisfying to your ego you feel very
happy.
If it is not, if it is superego, if you are
suppressed by this,
then you feel very unhappy.
So both things like happiness or unhappiness
are the states where you are still in the
myth,
still the myth exists.
You have to still go beyond.
So if you feel happy about some situation,
you should know you
are only happy before Realisation,
because it is giving some support to your
ego to bloat.
And if you are unhappy, then you should know
that
there is some sort of a suppression on your
ego
and there’s a superego developing.
So both the situations have been of no help
to you,
of no help to you for your growth,
except that both these institutions develop
so much
that you are away from the real experiencing.
The real experiencing stops
because your attention is so much muddled
up.
So on one side if you move – on the left
hand side –
your attention is muddled up with fear, with
pain,
with unhappiness, with hopelessness, dejection.
The other side, if you indulge too much on
to the right hand side
– little bit also –
you start getting elated, excited, over-dominating.
The colour of the left side is blue.
And the blue colour starts changing to the
black.
While on the right hand side it is, to begin
with, yellow,
light yellow or you can say golden,
then yellow, then orange and then red.
So you go to aggression on the right hand
side.
On the left hand side you go into a complete
state of
entropy, you can call it,
or a state where you are separated from yourself
into a complete frozen state.
So [on] one side you become completely frozen,
on the other side you become completely heated
up.
Both these things are, again, movement on
the wrong direction.
Even in the centre when the attention is kept
– that you keep your attention more in the
centre –
there also, because it’s a very sensitive
point,
it doesn’t stay there.
For example,
when we, say, use fire, we can use it for
burning the house.
In the same way we can use it for creating
smoke.
But we can also use this fire in its proper
way, if we use it,
in its proper proportion, for cooking the
food [or] for giving us light.
If it is too much, it can burn like a big
fire.
If it is too little, it can burn like smoke.
But in the center when you know how to balance
it,
then you can use it for your own purpose
– for cooking or for giving light, and then
for a puja too.
So in the same way when we really balance
our gunas properly,
then we become gradually the master of the
whole situation.
The attention doesn’t get dragged
into things that we have been doing
or that we have understood through our memories
or through our experiences or whatever it
is,
and is not also dragged towards, too much,
on the right hand side
that we try to overpower, or try to dominate
someone.
Because if you move too much that side you
have seen [that]
it becomes blood.
It is difficult for people to understand how,
when people become very religious-minded,
like now Iran,
the movement is on the right
– all the austerities, all that, everything
– now bloodshed.
Christians also did the same.
Brahmins did the same in India.
Buddhists did the same, even [though] they
talked of nonviolence
they got to bloodshed, because movement started
[on the] right hand side.
Left hand side movement will take you to very
sly and dark methods.
So right-handed sided people – like big
nations
who are supposed to be developed nations –
they justify war.
“We must have weapons to face each other.”
But you all, each other, are the same people
from God’s point of view!
Why are you fighting?
When God asks you, “Why are you fighting,
what is the need?
Why don’t you sit down properly and listen
to each other?
What are you fighting about?
You are fighting about land.
Is it your father’s land?
It belongs to God!
God has created this land.
Why are you fighting?”
But your attention is such that immediately
you think,
“Oh, this is my land, this is my motherland,
this is my fatherland, this is my brotherland.”
But what about your land which is within you?
It’s not your own!
So if you go on telling these people that
we should have no war they will not listen.
Realisation is the only way.
By Realisation your attention gets higher
and gets separated from that strata from where
these things bubble in.
Do you understand my point now?
The strata goes higher,
the attention goes higher, at a higher state.
By right side movement you get vikshepa, confusion.
First you get confusion.
Every intellectual, whatever brilliant he
may be, he is confused.
And the more confused he is, the more he asserts
himself
because he is confused, he’s not sure of
himself, so he asserts,
“This is the thing; this is the thing.”
I mean, if it is so, why should you assert
it?
But he goes on asserting, “This is the thing!”
Then understand that now he is going towards
lunatic asylum – absolutely!
And the way he asserts, and goes on talking
about it,
all the time, that means he is not sure.
He becomes like a possessed personality.
When he explains everything through his brains
that
“This is the thing.
This is correct.
We must all do, this is what…”
and he convinces many others who are confused
like him.
They depend on him.
He becomes a leader because, you see,
they are much more confused
and they find somebody who is not so much
confused outwardly
[so] they stick on to him, and all of them
get to war
or some sort of a bloodshed or some sort of
– they want to see blood.
They become heartless, passionless, compassionless,
you can say – compassionless, loveless people.
The other movement is the blue side, is like
the blue moonlight.
So, for the romanticism starts.
Sitting in the moonlight, you see!
The ideas start coming from Lord Byron (laughter).
And they come into your attention
– then it becomes very strong passion with
you.
You think, “Oh, I am still, I have to find
out my loves!”
And you go on in search of your loves and
this and that.
These things are not really giving joy.
That’s why so many poems have been written
that,
“Love is the most painful thing, it’s
worse than death,”
and all sorts of poems are written like that
so why did you get into it?
I mean, it’s already written down, books
after books,
still why do you get into it? (laughing)
You are already warned about it that,
“Don’t go after love, love is deception,
love is this, that,
it is very temporary, it is for the little
while you get that.”
By chance, if somebody could stop at a point
by marrying somebody who is sweet enough and
realise
that love and marriage and all these things
are in the centre,
are like the fire in the kitchen,
are like the fire in the temple:
looks after it and doesn’t overdo something
about it.
Then maybe that this may be utilized.
In the same way the right side movement of
the Sun line.
If people think that, yes, the sun is important,
we have to have sun in the house,
but you are not to become naked and insult
the Sun and get your skin cancer!
Sun is not for your skin cancer!
But if you overdo it, also it is dangerous.
A person who exposes himself too much to planning
and doing that, and doing this, and doing
all this,
can land up into very great difficulties.
So you have to balance that side also
and this side and you have to be in the centre,
in the equilibrium.
Now this word ‘equilibrium’ doesn’t
exist in our day-to-day life.
It exists only in the fiction
or may be in the so-called scientific research.
But as far as human beings are concerned,
they do not know what is equilibrium is.
Because of this, the attention, though after
Realisation
comes up, still on the sides they just go
down,
this side or that side according to your vrittis.
And when these identifications still act in
them,
they are prone to go down again in their attention
and again start bubbling out the same thing
as they had.
Now one has to become lighter in one’s own
mind
and should think that,
“We have dropped all that now why are we
there?”
One should become lighter with all that load
flowing out,
because you are here to raise your attention
higher and higher
so that you come up to a point
where you become one with the attention of
God.
Already your attention is sparkled because
through your attention
you can see what’s wrong with you,
you can see what’s wrong with others
and you can see how far you are going with
yourself.
But the progress is retarded because you do
not know that this attention
is pure form and all that you get into this
attention
is a mythical stuff, is a myth.
If you drop this myth gradually, treat everything
as a myth
and not depend on becoming unhappy or happy
– just seeing the thing –
[then] your attention will take a flight
and it will be at a much higher level residing
there.
Instead of that, every moment you go this
way or that way
– it goes on like that –
and the movement upwards is much less.
Even in Sattvoguna, when you rise,
you can go much worse in that condition also.
For example, if you say that, “I am trying
to be Sattwoguni.”
In Sattwoguni it is that you start seeing
everything,
discriminating through your understanding
– not through vibrations – through understanding:
“Oh!
Should we not somehow or the other take out
our attention from here?”
“Should we not give up this?”
“Should we be charitable?”
“Should we go and serve the people?”
There are people who think,
“Oh, we are going to do something great!”
– like your Salvation Army.
Let them be salvaged by themselves!
I don’t know what salvation they are going
to do.
So these ideas – ideas, I am saying – of
Sattvoguna,
can also immobilise you and can really freeze
you down once for all,
and that also can work in you in such a sly
manner,
we can say, in such a secretive manner,
that you won’t feel it.
All these ideas of helping others, being charitable,
“Let’s have a charity association!”
– finished!
Once you work in a charity association,
your attention is finished there.
But if your attention goes higher
– say [as] my attention is.
I am only nothing but charity!
I mean what am I?
It just flows.
You just become the charity.
So the difference between
a person who is a realised and a not realised
is this
that the attention which was giving myth as
reality to you
is gone now, is gone higher.
It can see that it is myth.
Attention can clearly see that it is myth,
and you can see that yourself
and you can remove yourself from them.
That, of course, I have to give you a push,
no doubt,
and I am working hard on that to give you
a push.
But you should also know that mythical things
must be dropped out,
otherwise you will not grow.
All mythical things must be dropped out.
And the best way to do it is to be in thoughtless
awareness
because as soon as you transcend these three
gunas
you become thoughtlessly aware.
You have to cross Agya.
Once you cross Agya, these three gunas,
absolutely you go into a state where you are
gunateet,
you are beyond gunas.
So you do not deliberately do anything,
but it just works out.
But analysis is one of the diseases of the
West.
What are you analysing?
You ask yourself.
I feel like laughing at the whole analysis
that goes on.
See, they’ll sit down, take out a hair,
splitting the hair into hundred!
And great analysers are sitting down there!
They cannot even say how the chromosomes
have that spindle action
and, I mean at that minute level the things
are worked out.
They cannot say how a cell divides.
What are they analysing sitting down here?
Now, they have analysed for a purpose – also
done for God.
Through their analysis now my things are recorded.
Through their analysis I can go to the TV,
if they allow me any time, because of analysis
[it] doesn’t fit into me,
they won’t allow, they may not, it might
be expedited.
But say, for example, if you had not discovered
these things –
for example take it like that –
and the science was not discovered,
your attention would have been at least better
off.
Because of science, your attention is also
very much in confusion.
So I don’t know which one to praise, whether
the science or the primitiveness.
When you raised yourself to science also,
you got to another extreme as usual.
Till you burnt out your complete attention,
you were not satisfied.
I mean if you had kept your balance in science
also
it would have helped, but the balance was
lost there.
Give anything to human beings and they know
how to make the worst out of it.
They will go to the extreme.
You give them a horse,
they cannot go ordinary trotting or galloping,
they must have a double gallop, till they
fall and die!
Everything you see, they just are on the run
all the time.
So first thing is needed is to steady down
yourself
and tell yourself that, “Now all these mythical
things
I am not going to allow to come to my attention.”
All these things are nothing but myths.
But you are giving too much importance to
myths.
You are taking them bit so seriously.
They are just mythical.
Now, I mean, when you are realised now you
laugh at people
who just go mad over say, a moonlit night.
Alright?
But ask the fellow who is doing that,
he’ll say, “You are heartless, you have
no feelings!” (laughter)
He’ll give you a big poetry out of it.
You go and see anyone of these people who
are riding a high horse,
who are at the helm of affairs,
and you will feel like laughing at them.
But they will think that, “You are useless,
you are doing no work,
you are good for nothing, you are just wasters.”
So now for you, because you are enlightened
now, is to understand
that our attention has to move higher and
higher, at a higher space.
Now actually what has happened in Realisation?
Your Kundalini has risen and has come up,
just like, you can say, a small, thin hair,
one hair,
and that has broken your Sahastrara
and now the grace is flowing into you.
But it’s a very small movement that has
taken place, of course
which is a very difficult movement no doubt,
but it has taken place.
Now you have not expanded like this.
Your chakras are only pierced in the centre,
but the rest of the attention is still intact.
Actually it is so intact, that you don’t
even feel that it is pierced.
Now you have to expand that, open it out,
so that more strands of Kundalini can rise
and your attention,
which is in these centers, expands.
By expansion it drives out all that is mythical
on the sides.
On every centre we have our attention,
which is being enlightened in the centre
through this Light passing through.
But the Light is too small for the darkness
that you have collected.
Specially for the people of the West, I would
say,
your confusions, you must get rid of them.
But still you identify.
Because if I ask you anything [like], “How
are you?”
Means what?
Means you are still confused.
Alright?
Confusion should go.
One confusion was there that,
“This is Realisation or not?”
I hope that’s over now with you people.
At least now you believe it is Self-realisation.
I had to tell people, “No, you are self-realised
now, you are!”
Still they would jump up like [a] jack-in-the-box,
you see.
They’ll say, “No, we’re not Mother!
How do you say this is Realisation?”
“We expect this out of Realisation and that
out of Realisation
– that we’ll be flying out of the door
if we are Realised,”
or something nonsensical like that.
Thank God, these ideas have gone away.
But when we are Realised, there is Light that
has come in us,
we have to grow it only by separating our
attention
from the myths.
It’s all mythical.
I also play with you,
because unless and until you are sure,
I am not going to give you a wrong idea about
yourself.
I want to see how far still your attention
is moving,
and I know [that] still you are not sure,
still you are not sure of yourself,
that’s why the confidence is not there.
First of all you have to learn how to drive,
then you are tested.
There will be five stones put together,
the distance will be only that hardly a car
can pass through
and the fellow will say, “You bring it zigzag!”
And you cannot do it.
Why?
That’s how he makes you a master.
The mastery of your attention
will come when you will start seeing that
it is all a myth that upsets you.
It’s all a myth that upsets you.
Just throw it away.
Just throw it away and understand that you
are
the eternal attention, that you are the eternal
life,
that [the] only thing that keeps you away
from it is ignorance,
and the ignorance is too simple to understand:
that you have accepted myth as Truth.
Just drop it!
It’s all myth!
You’ll be amazed how your attention will
rise
and you’ll see all these nonsensical things
which used to frighten you or to elate you,
will drop out, and you will just smile at
it.
And then only you are going to enjoy yourself
fully
because your attention will be completely
drenched
into the bliss of Self.
I am saying you will, I say you are
already drenched into that bliss.
Keep it up.
Now, how to do it?
Actually, in every day-to-day life, how to
kill the memory of the past?
To kill the memory of the past is to have
new memories.
You must remember when you got your first
Realisation
– always think of it.
Whenever any such memory comes to you,
you [should] try to think how you got your
Realisation.
Any memory that is troublesome or even so-called
elating,
you just try to remember how Realisation has
come to you.
When you feel aggressive about something or
angry [about] something,
just try to remember how you felt the joy
of surrendering.
Just think of that joy of surrendering, of
dissolving yourself.
So the new memories must be built up.
If you start building up new memories,
then you will start collecting moments
to establish other moments which have such
memories.
Like a memory when you tried to help somebody,
you raised the Kundalini of someone.
Now the problem would be
when you will be raising the Kundalini of
others,
you will be in thoughtless awareness – there
won’t be any thought –
and thought is the only thing which impresses.
But [at] that time you can record the joy
of raising the Kundalini.
If you could record the joy of raising the
Kundalini
of others, you will feel [that] a new wealth
of these beautiful moments will be accumulated.
And all those moments which were giving you
confusion
or fear or so-called unhappiness and happiness
will drop out
and pure joy will remain.
Because now most of the experiences you have
had
are more of joy.
Joy has no thoughts.
It’s just an experience, a pratyaksha.
That’s why I said you keep your eyes open.
I hope
you will understand what
I mean
by that.
May
God bless you all.