Title: Talk on evening before Sahastrara Puja
Location: Thredbo, Australia
Date: 2.5.1987
So very nice to see you all here, all my children.
Your love out beats me. I really find no words
to express my feelings. The way you have taken
to Sahaja Yoga and the way you have established
yourself in Sahaj Yog. I know it is very difficult
to spread Sahaja Yoga. Everywhere it is difficult
because you know these are the times of kaliyuga.
I am not tired of the journey so much as the
fighting the evil forces around us. When I
came to Canberra, I felt the left swadhistana
very strong, so strong that I could not walk
few steps and I asked them what’s the matter?
They told me that TM, there is some Chinmoy
fellow, they are very strong here. Apart from
that there are other spiritualist forces which
they are announcing in the newspapers.
It’s shocking that human beings take to
these horrible things so easily and try to
work it out. When you study the reason why
they take to these horrible things then you
realize one thing that these things promise
quick results. Like supposing somebody’s
son has been lost. So, they will say, “All
right. You come to our group, we’ll find
it out for you.”
Or else, somebody says, “I am under a great
strain.”
“All right. You come to our group, we will
remove your strains.”
It’s very easy to remove the strains by
putting a entity, what we call the bhoots,
into someone so that the bhoot takes over
for the time being. But, here the seeker is
not a deep person. Those who were deep people
came back from all these horrible people.
With the TM, I can tell you, we have been
able to salvage some people, not all of them.
When first it was brought to my notice, I
had a meeting in England and we had from TM
at least hundred people. Out of which we can
say about ten to twelve people we have been
able to salvage. But the growth, spiritual
growth in them was very slow and they were
just frightened of Me. They would not look
at Me. They had awe about Me. Whenever they
saw me they would shake. There is one fellow,
Chinese, who came from TM, and I think Rustom
was there, and he just took My name and he
jumped under a table and landed himself outside
in the lounge and they started looking at
him where has he disappeared. With this Chinese
fellow, we tried with him, but he used to
shake and horrible [UNCLEAR], poor thing.
Then he left Sahaja Yoga in a way and somebody
met him in a restaurant or in a book shop
and somebody met him there, and they asked
him, “How do you feel? How do you feel about
Mother?” He said, “Oh! Ho! Ho! Ho! She
is a tremendous power.”
So, you see, they are so weak, they are so
gone down. It’s very difficult to bring
them to normal conditions. Within two, three
years they become recluses. They are even
afraid of, what you call garlic. If you show
them the garlic they start shaking. If you
show them the lemon they start shaking. They
become recluses. We get few people from there,
TM, but their bhoots are so strong that they
will not stick on to us much. Even they come
down for a short time, again they go back.
So, this is the situation with these TM people.
And with this Chinmoy fellow I had an encounter
in America and there the people they came
and told me that “Why this Chinmoy is here
and why doesn’t your husband tell to Secretary
General about it?” And you know who was
the Secretary General that time, [Wol Dahm?]
and all the rest of it. And they were all
crazy people. How Wol Dahm is now being cheated
by people and now he is not allowed to go
to America and all that. Actually his luck
was not so bad but this bhoots, you see, they
made him so funny that he just could not come
back to his normal self. Now this gentleman
was not so much into this Chinmoy but there
was one south Indian gentleman who was in
the UN and he said that “This Chinmoy is
very good.” This Chinmoy used to play tennis,
used to swim, used to drink, have women, he
was a real yanky and despite that people said,
“Oh! He is great because he knows how to
speak well.” So, all those speech loving
people he got. That’s another style of people
who are not seekers but who just want somebody
to talk, talk, and talk. He could talk on
Gita, he could talk on this, he could talk
on every kind of thing. Now, the big difference
is, in Sahaja Yoga you have to accept Me.
There you don’t have to accept anyone. As
long as you accept Gita, as long as you accept
Bible, as long as you accept something – is
not there, which is dead, which is finished.
So, these people are interested only in your
money.
So, they don’t worry about these old, we
should say, prophets who are dead now or we
can say the incarnations who are dead. They
have nothing to do. Just they describe them,
take the money. That’s they want. They only
want to have money, money, money and money.
They are not interested in your welfare or
anything. They have no idea of Kundalini,
they cannot raise your Kundalini, they cannot
give you realization, they cannot look after
you – nothing of the kind. Only thing what
they want, whatever money you have they should
have it. And the way they do it is a very
camouflage sort of a drama they play, that
they can deliver the goods. What are the goods
they are going to deliver to you? Except Self-Realization.
Even the people who talked of Self-Realization
never gave Self-Realization to anyone. I have
seen this Yogananda’s disciples. The early
ones, they had to cut their tongues because
according to him, in his own kriyayoga, you
had to put back your tongue here for a khechri
and that’s why they had to cut their tongue.
They cannot speak, they cannot do anything.
They are just like dogs, you see, wagging
their tails. Very good people, they are doctors,
architects, very good people. All these things
have happened to all these great seekers,
I should say, but they were stupid to accept
anyone like that. First of all, you must see
what are other, are doing others, say other
disciples are doing. How are they, majority
of them? In Sahaja Yoga also we might get
somebody a very useless person and might get
somebody a very low grade or a very low caliber
personality. We do get on the periphery, we
do get. But they should see other people who
are seriously involved in Sahaja Yoga. How
they are behaving? What is their way of doing
it? And how their life is? What have they
achieved? What powers have they achieved?
And what kind of a life they lead? That is
how you should judge the person to whom they
have to do.
I am sorry that this Canberra is so full of
Left Swadistana and if you allow these things
to continue I don’t know what will happen
to your government. It will all go to dogs
if this stupid thing is allowed to work out
because all those booths will jump on all
these civil servants and serious things can
happen. I am quite surprised how it is allowed
in Australia where is the land of Shri Ganesha.
As it is I am here now, I am sure something
will happen and they will give up that. But
as far as coming to Sahaja Yoga, I would say,
it’s a headache. You better give yourselves
a bandhan before touching them anywhere near
because they will give you lot of trouble.
I have had lots of trouble with them. So much
so, we had to leave one of our ashrams. You
see, we had three persons in that ashram from
TM and they used to scream so much and this
jumping about was so much that the neighbors
told us that, ”You better get out from here”
and because of them we had to get out. All
kinds of funny things they do.
First time I saw these TM people, were in
a hall, and they took the first chairs. First
row they were sitting there. As soon as I
started speaking they all started jumping
like jack in the box. I was wondering, “What‘s
the matter? Is perfectly alright? Who are
these people?” I had never seen such a thing
before. I was quite surprised that who are
these people jumping like this one by one.
Then I asked them, they said, “We do TM
and we are doing siddha course.”
“Siddha course? Stupid people you are, that’s
what you are.” And out of these 6 or 7 people
who were jumping we could save about, I should
say, two or three.
So, those people who have gone to that you
shouldn’t worry so much about them. But,
of course, if it is gone to the government
it is better to beat the government with shoes
and give bandhan to the government so that
they don’t get entangled with it. But is
serious thing and I have to work it out myself
on those lines because I was quite shocked
that in Canberra they have such bad vibrations.
I came to Canberra much before with my husband
and I told him that “The vibrations here
are very, very bad.”
So he said, ”All the capital cities are
like that.”
I said, “But it seems rather funny that
both the centers are catching so badly.”
And I couldn’t walk that time also and today
also the same thing happened to Me.
Now, we have many other people who are seeking
God. They live in the villages. These people
have not gone to the villages because they
wanted only rich people, monied people. So,
there are many people in the villages who
haven’t yet received their Self-Realization
and they can receive their Self-Realization
without any difficulties. You can go there
and talk to them and get them realized because
they are not people for whom these rakshashas
are waiting. We have to give them realization.
Once you give realization to people in the
villages, things will change. The atmosphere
will change and you find lots of people coming
to Sahaja Yoga. So, I would say, I am very
happy that in Sydney itself we have so many
centers and in other cities you have so many
centers. But now we have to reach the villages
and see them. They are innocent, simple people
living in the villages in a very simple manner
and is better to give them proper attention
because they are the ones who will get realization.
Then the children, children should be attended
to. They can be very nicely brought to Sahaj
and because there may be many of them who
are already born realized. So the children
can be brought into Sahaja Yoga but not without
the permission of their parents because the
laws and regulations are such that we may
land up in the prison without asking the permission
of the father or mother. So, one has to be
very careful.
The another are the adolescent boys and girls
who are studying in the colleges and who are
not yet exposed so much to all these bad things.
They might be drug addicts little bit or may
be other addiction they might be having but
they are not yet touched by these horrible
evil forces. So, you can just attend to them.
You can also advertise that you can look after
people who are addicted to all these drugs
and all that. You can relieve them. If you
are allowed to do that you can advertise,
get those people and if you give them realization
they might be able to get over their addiction
completely. There is a doctor, Dr. Wells,
in London who has now become a very big doctor
in charge of a hospital of addiction. So,
I said, “What do you do to them? How do
you manage this addiction business?”
He said, “In their absence I beat them with
shoes, that’s all and they are all getting
rid of their addiction.”
So, you can attend to those boys who are now
grown up boys and are taking to drugs and
things like that. They are seekers. That’s
why they are going to these things. I think
this kind of an attitude if you have that
you are not going to attend to people who
are already with some gurus and with something
and encounter them. But attend to people who
by their innocence have fallen into some problems
or to the innocent people in the villages
or children who are innocent. I am sure you
can prosper faster.
So, Sahaja Yoga is growing very much faster
here and in a way in a city it is growing.
We can grow much faster, I think, the way
there are people, so many people, are in the
villages and in the countryside; in a very
simple way they live. As for Myself, to come
to Australia is such an excitement and such
a joy because last year I could not come and
this year when they said it was a Sahastrar
Puja and had to perform here and be there,
I was very happy. Tomorrow we have to have
that Puja. I was also a person in a way you
can say, a seeker, because I was trying to
find out a method, the way, by which I could
really give en-masse realization. I could
give realization to many people at the same
time and for that I was really working very,
very hard, understanding lots of people, human
beings, and out of them I found bureaucrats
are the worse. As you have lots of bureaucrats
in this Canberra, may be, that they are not
so good because they have to compromise all
the time. They have to say, “Yes sir, yes
sir,” and despite their resistance, despite
their not liking, to say that, they are poor
things, pushed into a job where they have
to work it out because after all job is important.
When all these things become important, the
person’s personality suffers a lot. That’s
what I found that the bureaucrats who are
seeking all the time power, go after the man
who can give them some more power, in the
sense the power not of the divine but over
the people that they can dominate more people
and they can manage more people. And that’s
why these people fall into these groups because
in the beginning they feel relaxed in a way
and they dominate many people as there are
booths sitting with them who give them ideas.
But then they get tired of them and then they
fall sick. So, many people commit suicide
also, suicide. I was told that suicide is
maximum, suicide cases are maximum in Canberra.
The reason is this only that you don’t know
what to do with yourself. You suffer from
some sort of a miserable disease. You don’t
know how to get out of it and then you commit
suicide. So, all these things are connected
with the attack of the evil forces and these
evil forces attack you in a very subtle manner.
So, one should be careful as to mature. One
has to mature in Sahaja Yoga so that nothing
can affect them, nothing can trouble them,
nothing can bother them. One has to mature.
The maturity should be such as like Mine.
If I catch it, I mean, I deliberately catch
it and then I try to solve the problem. But
if you cannot do that then you should not
catch also because you will suffer little
bit by catching them.
Now, for tomorrow’s puja I hope you will
all be ready and you will all enjoy tomorrow’s
puja. Had a very nice puja in Pune which I
had to perform on the thirteenth because it
is the date called Akshaya Thrithya, means
undestructible third day of the moon. That’s
actually nobody knew, but it is the puja of
the Kundalini. That day everybody felt very,
very clear. Very clear. Puja was hardly for
about half an hour, the real puja of the Kundalini.
But everybody felt extremely clear and beautiful.
So, that sort of puja we should do tomorrow
also, if possible, so that we’ll have the
feelings of Sahastrara completely opened out
because even if Sahastrara is opened, the
rest of the chakras, if they are caught up
then you have problems. It’s better to clear
out all the chakras and then the Sahastrara.
So, tomorrow we’ll do the puja in that fashion
and I hope it will work out very well for
all of you.
I hope I have been rather late for all of
you and I am not taking too much of your time
here. Tomorrow I think it should be, you see,
actually you’ll be surprised that this is
the time I opened the Sahastrara in India.
This is exactly the time because just now
is 6.30 there, 6.35 and about 6.30, I opened
Sahastrara. So, you can imagine this is the
time I opened the Sahastrara there and
this is the time we are sitting on
the other side of the world and celebrating
that day, that great day
of Sahastrara being opened out. It’s a very
great day in the history of spirituality,
very great day for the whole world. They will
realize one day what
it was. Such a big time that Sahastrara could
be opened for masses. Not only that but you
are empowered to do that great work.
May God bless you.