I bow to all the Sahaja Yogis.
In this beautiful surround, surroundings,
many of you are wondering why God has created
these beautiful things. Because you people
had to come on this Earth and enjoy the beauty
that is one of the reasons. And now God feels
very much fulfilled with the joy and satisfaction
and a kind of a completion of His desire.
Why God has created this beautiful universe
has been a question asked for thousands of
years.
The reason is very simple to understand: this
beauty that is created cannot see itself.
In the same way, God who is the source of
beauty, cannot see its own beauty, like a
pearl cannot enter into itself to see its
beauty, like the sky cannot understand its
own beauty, the stars cannot see their own
beauty, the Sun cannot behold its own brilliance,
in the same way God Almighty cannot behold
His own being. He needs a mirror and that
is how He has created this beautiful universe
as His mirror. In this mirror He has created
now beautiful things like the Sun, then the
Sun has to see his own reflection also. So
He has created these beautiful trees to see
that when he shines, they come up so well
and look so green.
Then He has created those birds to rise early
in the morning to greet the Sun, so the Sun
knows that: “Yes, I am there, I am existing”;
or else He has created these beautiful lakes
for these trees to see their reflection and
the lakes to feel their existence when the
ripples start moving within themselves.
So then He created human beings. The human
beings cannot also see their own beauty, their
own glory. That is why they are in the darkness,
they are ignorant. They cannot see what lies
within themselves. So they are running after
something which is absolutely against themselves,
which is ugliness, which is self destructive.
And the struggle to get to reality is such
a lot, that as a result, they destroy themselves.
Like as people have taken to these drugs,
taken to all bad habits – of in this place,
they say a lot of smuggling going on – and
all such endeavors that people take up because
they do not know what beautiful things they
are.
So now a mirror has to be created for them,
to see for themselves how beautiful they are.
Their mirror is their Spirit. That Spirit
is to be brought in their consciousness, in
their attention. If it comes in their attention
then they can see their image. Now this attention
that comes in, as an enlightened attention
is called in Sanskrit language as chidabhas
is the expression of the attention which is
enlightened. But it is also said that it is
got a nature, which is very transitory, or,
we can say, which is disappearing every moment
to moment. When this is happening what is
to be done? For that you have to steady yourself
with meditation, with hearing the enlightened
talks, by seeing the good things of life without
thinking about them, by seeing also the goodness
of others and then you start seeing goodness
in yourself also.
That is why I always say that one should not
feel guilty, because you are feeling guilty
of something, which is just, just an illusion.
You are guilty that you have got a shadow.
It is something like that. So if you know
that you are beautiful beings and that you
have got a shadow is nothing to do with you
and your beauty. If you can see you own beauty
then you will be amazed that within us lies
all those joy giving, all those beautiful
things, which we are seeing outside. But just
now, the mirror is not all right, that’s
why you have to see in the nature the beauty.
But, when you are one with your Self, then
you see all these nature within yourself,
all the joy giving qualities of this nature
within yourself.
So I wanted you to come to this place just
to learn how God has created this beautiful
area for you people to enjoy and to be here.
May God bless you.