Today you have arranged this worship of your
Guru, that is your Mother.
Perhaps you are very unique people that have
a Guru who is a Mother.
Why this Puja is arranged?
One has to know that it is very important
for every disciple to worship the Guru, but
the Guru has to be a real Guru, not a one
who is just exploiting the disciples and who
is not authorized by God.
The Puja is arranged because you have been
initiated into the Statutes of the Lord.
You have been told what are the dharmas of
a human being.
For that actually you need not have a guru.
You can read any book and you will know what
are the Statutes of the Lord.
But guru has to see that you practice them.
These Statutes are to be practiced, to be
brought into your own life, which is a difficult
thing.
And without a guru, a correcting force, it
is very difficult to follow these Statutes
of Lord, because there is a gap between human
awareness and Divine awareness, a very big
gap, and that gap can be only fulfilled by
a guru who himself is complete.
Today is a purnima day, “purnima” means
the complete moon.
The guru has to be a complete personality
to talk about these Statutes and to elevate
his disciples to this level of understanding,
by which they imbibe those Statutes.
He is there to fulfill this gap, and for that
it is essential that every guru has to be
a realized soul of a very high quality and
greatly evolved.
He need not be a person who is an ascetic,
or he need not be a person who is living in
the forest.
He could be a common householder, he could
be a king.
All these outward manifestations of one’s
life do not matter.
Whatever may be your position, I would say
the so-called position in this world makes
no difference to your being a guru, as long
as you have imbibed the Statutes of the Lord.
Again, I say you have to imbibe the Statutes.
Let’s see what are the Statutes.
First is, you do not harm anyone.
First principle is that we are not to harm
anyone.
Animals do harm without knowing that they
are doing harm.
If you go near a snake, he’ll bite.
If a scorpion is there he can put his poison
into your being.
Animals [should be:”Human beings”] are
not to harm anyone; they can correct but not
harm.
So the principle of not harming was taken
to a very, very.
.
to a point where reality disappeared.
For example, when it was said “Do not harm
anyone”, so people started saying: “All
right, we’ll not harm mosquitoes, we’ll
not harm bugs.
We’ll not kill them.
” And there are some people who are following
religions in which they preserve mosquitoes
and bugs.
This is absurdity!
Taking anything to absurdity cannot be reality.
First of all, we should not harm anyone who
is walking in the path of God, the one who
is a realized soul.
He may be wrong, there may be some mistakes
in him, still he needs correction; nobody’s
perfect as yet.
So do not harm, always try to help.
Secondly, anybody who is a real seeker, he
may be wrong, he might have gone to wrong
gurus, he might have done wrong things; but
have feelings, because you have been going
on the wrong path yourself sometimes; you
have been misled before, so have more sympathies.
That’s why, if you have done mistakes, in
a way is good because you have more sympathies
for such people.
Then you are not to harm human beings in any
way.
You are not to cause them any bodily harm,
any emotional upsetting just for harm’s
sake; for correction it’s all right.
The second Statute is that you have to stand
on your own legs and know that you are here,
one with the truth, the testimony, the testimony
of the truth: that you have seen the truth,
you know what truth is, and you cannot compromise
with falsehood, you cannot.
For that you need not harm anyone, you have
to just profess it.
You have to stand up and say that you have
seen the truth and this is the truth, and
you have to be one with it, so that people
see that light of truth in you and they accept
you.
It’s not for telling others that: “You
have to be truthful, and this is the truth
we have seen, that this is what God’s laws
are, how they work out.
Through vibratory awareness we have been able
to see this is the truth.
” But be completely confident about it.
But for that, first of all you must test yourself
completely, otherwise you might be playing
into the hands of ego.
It happens with many people who start doing
Sahaja Yoga, to begin with.
So be cautious, be sure that you are telling
the truth and nothing else, and that you have
felt the truth in full ways.
Those who have not felt any vibrations, shouldn’t
talk of Sahaja Yoga at all; they have no authority.
They have to receive vibrations, they have
to fully imbibe within them, and then they
can say: “Yes, we felt.
” This is a very important task Sahaja Yogis
have to do in these modern times, is to tell
aloud that they have found the truth.
That part is very weak.
In whatever way you like: you can write books,
you can announce it, you can talk to your
friends, to your relations and everywhere.
Tell them that this is the truth now, that
you have entered into the kingdom of God;
that you are blessed by the Grace of God,
that you are realized souls, that you have
felt the Divine power which is pervading everywhere,
and that you can give Realizations to others.
This you have to tell others, and know that
by your accepting truth you are not adding
anything to the truth, but you are adorning
yourself.
One requires courage to enjoy the truth.
Sometimes people will laugh at you, will mock
at you, may persecute also; but that should
not be any worry to you, because your relationship
is with the Statutes and with the Grace of
God.
When that is your connection, you should not
worry about other people, what they have to
say about it.
You have to stand up, adorn yourself with
that truth and talk to people, that people
will know that you have found it.
With that authenticity with which you speak,
people will know that you have found it.
The difference between a realized soul and
a non-realized soul is basically this: he
doesn’t talk of his woes and his separation
with God, but he says: “l have found it
now, this is it.
” Like Christ said: “I am the Light, I
am the Path”.
Or anybody else can say that, but you can
make out that it is not true.
With the confidence, with that complete understanding
coming out of your heart, people can make
out this is absolute truth.
And then all kinds of falsehood must be denounced.
Doesn’t matter if somebody feels bad, because
by telling that you are saving them, and not
harming them; but must be told in a correct
way, not in a frivolous way.
In a very persuasive way, you must tell them
that: “No, this is wrong.
” You must wait for the time when you can
tell people, more in confidence.
Talk to them: “This is wrong, this is wrong,
you don’t know.
We’ve done the same thing.
” This is how you are going to express your
principle of mastery, or you can say “Guru
tattwa”.
You have to be truthful: first, foremost thing
is that you should know the truth, you should
stand this testimony, and that you should
announce it.
The third thing for a guru in Sahaja Yoga
has to do, is to develop detachment.
Gradually you do develop it, because you find
that unless and until you develop that detachment,
you are not receiving vibrations in full way.
All kinds of detachments have to be developed,
means your priorities change.
Once your attention gets fixed up with your
Spirit, the catch or the hold on things which
are of no importance starts reducing by itself.
For example, you have a father, you have a
mother, you have a sister, this is a bigger
problem in India.
Here you are over-detached, but in India people
are very much involved in their own children,
in their own: “This is my son,” and others
are all orphans.
Only your sons are the real children: your
daughter, your sons.
“My daughter”, “I must do this for my
son, for my father, mother” – here also.
Two types of attachments are there, one through
mohah, through involvement into them; that
you want to do this for them and that for
them, and give all the property to them, insurance
for them, every sort of thing.
And another could be, the way we have here,
that you hate your mother, you hate your father,
you hate everyone.
Both things are just the same.
So a detachment must be developed.
The detachment is that you are your father,
you are your mother, you are everything, your
Spirit is everything to you.
You have to enjoy only your Spirit, as everything.
Then the detachment comes from there, and
then you really do good to them by detaching,
because you see the complete vision about
them and about what is to be done.
For example, people have also attachments
to certain crazes.
Human beings always become crazy after something,
I mean it can be anything.
One has to understand there should be only
one craze: is to be settled absolutely into
your Spirit.
All other crazes will disappear, because that’s
the greatest joy-giving thing, that’s the
most nourishing thing, that’s the most beautiful
thing.
So the, all the other things fall off, you
enjoy only that which is the source of all
enjoyments.
So you get yourself attached to your Spirit:
detachment starts working.
Sometimes detachment is taken as a license
for becoming dry to others, which is absurd.
This is only human quality also: make everything
ugly, whatever is beautiful.
Actually, a person who is detached is the
most beautiful person, is the extremely loving
person, he’s love.
Look at the flowers, they are detached.
They are dying, tomorrow they are not going
to live, but every minute they live, they
are emitting fragrance to you.
The trees are not attached to anything, they
will die tomorrow, doesn’t matter; but anybody
who comes to them, they give shadow, they
give fruits.
Attachment means death of love, complete death
of love is attachment.
For example, in a tree, say, the sap rises,
goes to all the leaves, goes to all the necessary
parts, all the flowers, all the fruits, and
goes back to the Mother Earth.
He is not attached to anyone.
Supposing the sap goes and gets attached into
one fruit.
What will happen?
The tree will die, and the fruit will die.
Detachment gives you the movement of your
love, circulation of it.
For things now, things have no value unless
and until there are emotions behind it.
Now for example, a sari, this one I am wearing
today, was bought for Guru day, Guru Purnima,
but they had no sari.
The other day they wanted to have a sari for
Puja, so I said: “All right, use this.
” But I wore it again today, just to say
that this was bought with that emotion that
on a Guru day, Mother would like to wear something
of a lighter shade: white, the pure color
of silk, it’s complete detachment.
But in white all the colors are mixed, then
only it becomes white.
In such a balance and unity it is, should
be, that you become white, and whiter than
snow.
Detachment is purity, is innocence.
Innocence is such a light, I tell you, light
that really blinds you to all that is filthy.
You wouldn’t even know that a person has
come with bad intentions.
You look at the person, you see, say somebody
comes to you, you’ll say: “Oh, come along,
what do you want?”
You’ll offer him tea and all that, and he’ll
say: “I have come to rob you.
” “All right, rob me if you want to, it’s
all right.
” He may not at all rob you!
That is what is innocence, which one can develop
only through detachment.
Detachment is of the attention.
Do not allow your attention to get involved
into something too much, even rituals of anything.
Say, now, we have not washed Mataji’s Feet
– all right, doesn’t matter.
You love Me, all right?
If some mistakes are committed, what does
it matter?
If you see on the abstract plane, it’s love.
This is just a step forward.
Like somebody ran very fast and fell down
before reaching Me, and he said: “Mother,
sorry I fell down before reaching You, I should
have not done that.
But see how I prostrated before You!
” It’s complete poetry, detachment.
So one has to develop that detachment to be
a guru, and that detachment doesn’t mean
sanyas or anything like that.
Yes, sometimes one has to wear those dresses
to announce, because if you have to do lot
of work in a short time, then you have to
take such intensive behavior, like Christ,
we can say, Adi Shankaracharya.
All these people had a very, very short life,
and in that short life they had to achieve
such a tremendous task that they had to actually
take a military uniform, just to avoid problems,
not to impress others.
Now-a-days people wear that dress just to
impress others that they are detached, and
do just the thing opposite of it.
So we understand that first, one is not to
harm anyone, ahinsa, not to kill anyone.
That doesn’t mean that you shouldn’t eat
meat and fish and all that – that’s all
nonsense.
Of course I mean, you should not hanker after
food, no doubt about it.
“You don’t kill anyone” means you do
not kill a human being: “Thou shall not
kill”.
So
first thing is not to harm anyone.
Second is to know that you have found the
truth and give the testimony of the truth.
Third is the detachment, the way I have told
you about detachment: not to get attached
to any one person because he’s a relation
or a something, but develop a universal feeling.
And also not to hate anyone: that is even
worse, that’s a kind of a worse type of
attachment.
This word should go away from the mouth of
all the Sahaja Yogis: “I hate”.
It is called as a dandak, is the Statute.
You cannot hate anyone.
Even rakshasas, you better not hate them,
give them a chance.
Now the fourth thing, the fourth Statute of
the Lord is to lead a moral life.
These Statutes were given by all the Gurus,
take them from Socrates onward, Moses, Abraham,
Dattatreya, Janaka, up to, say, Nanak, Mohammed
Sahib, and take up to the point where it was
only about a hundred years back you can say,
at the most, was Sai Nath.
All of them have said that you have to lead
a moral life.
None of them have said that you do not get
married, that you do not talk to your wife,
that you have no relationship with your wife;
all this is nonsensical.
Lead a moral life.
When you are young, not married, keep your
eyes on the ground; Mother Earth gives you
that innocence by which you develop that principle
within you, is very important principle.
It’s such a pure principle, it really helps
the society to develop its dignity.
Now think, in a society where you do not know
who is your sister, who is your brother, who
is your mother, what complications it can
create; what confusion, what unhappiness.
It is one of the most essential things for
human beings, to be moral.
For animals it is not necessary.
Most of the confusions and problems, specially
in the Western life, have come because they
have thrown morality in the sea, and to accept
morality as the very basis of society, it’s
very difficult for them, it’s a complete
reversion.
But you have to do it, you have to turn the
whole wheel back.
So, many things were done in the beginning
of the society to establish this pure relationship.
There are laws which act, as if there are
laws of, chemical laws are there, there are
physical laws are there, in physics and chemistry.
Indeed, there are human laws which one should
understand.
The relationships between each other, the
sublimity of their relationship, the purity
of their relationship must be understood,
and then only you can have a very, very happy
married life, which is the basis.
“Thou shall not commit adultery.
” But Christ has said – perhaps He knew
the modern people as they would be using their
brains for this – He said: “Thou shalt
not have adulterous eyes.
” What a vision, in those days to think;
I mean, even I could not understand it when
I was in India.
After only coming here I could see that, what
did it mean.
It’s a possession on the eyes, possession.
It’s a joyless, useless behavior, it’s
tiring.
Attention is frittered away completely; there’s
no dignity.
Eyes should be steady.
When you look at somebody steadily you should
know that you have got Sahaja Yoga in you;
with love, with respect, with dignity.
Not staring at people and just playing into
the hands of these possessions.
The whole society is possessed.
All the satanic forces have been let loose,
I think, and the way people are possessed,
they cannot see through these things.
And they are supposed to be Christians!
Attention is to be looked after.
That’s the most important thing, because
attention is the one which is going to be
enlightened.
So we have to know what morality is.
Let people laugh at us, let them say that:
“These are goodie-goodies,” or this sort
of thing.
We are!
We are proud of it.
We are not ashamed of being righteous people.
This is a very important part of righteousness.
Those who do not follow this will lose their
vibrations very fast.
Then, for a guru, he should not accumulate
things, he should not have possessions, much
possessions with him.
If he has possessions, they should be just
for giving away.
A guru must give away his possessions.
He should not have stamp-collection, and all
kinds of collections that people go on.
Whatever things are useful, beautiful, which
give happiness and joy to others, to their
eyes: such things must be collected, such
things which give the symbol to his life.
Very symbolic things he should have, which
suggest that he is a dharmic person.
He should not have things which are symbolic
of adharmikta, of irreligious life.
Everything that he has or he wears, or he
shows, should be representative of his dharmikta.
I don’t know but, I don’t know what was
the situation here, but in India, when we
were young, we were not allowed to listen
to all kinds of music, not allowed, just not
allowed.
Not to see all kinds of filthy things and
filthy documentaries and things, not allowed.
Anything that is impure, giving bad vibrations
should not be possessed, and even a, whatever
you have, you should think whom you can give
this.
So it means you should have possessions to
express your generosity.
Sahaja Yogi has to be generous like the sea.
A miserly Sahaja Yogi, I cannot think of that,
it is like mixing of darkness with light.
Miserliness is not allowed in Sahaja Yoga.
Anybody whose mind goes: “How much I can
save money, or save my labor”; how?
There are many labor-saving devices also,
and money-saving devices.
Or cheating others, or making money out of
certain few things here and there: all such
things are against Sahaja Yoga, they will
pull you down.
Enjoy your generosity!
How many times I must have told you about
generosity.
I remember once I wanted to give a sari that
I had from abroad, you see, because in India
people like that kind of a sari very much;
though I mean, I don’t understand why they
like it, nylon sort of thing.
And a lady said that: “I haven’t got any
sari from outside and I would like to have
one imported sari.
” And I had only one left with Me, because
I am quite good at giving away.
So I told one of my niece-in-laws, I said:
“I want to give away this sari to her.
On a holy day we can give it to elders, so
I’ll give it.
”
She said: “You have only one left now, why
do You want to give away?
You have given away all You had.
” I said: “Now, I feel like giving.
I’ll give away.
” And we were discussing this in the kitchen,
you see, and I said: “Why do you tell Me?
I am not going to take your advice on this
point.
” And at that time the bell rang and a gentleman
came.
He had brought three saris for Me from Africa,
and one of them was exactly the same as the
one I had.
Because I had given some silk saris to this
lady when she was going to Africa, she thought
she should send Me some saris, so she sent.
You are just standing in the center, from
one door it comes and at the other door it
goes.
It’s nice to see all that movement, it’s
very interesting.
Apart from that, the way you give it, you
see, the emotional side of it is so beautiful,
you can’t imagine.
I met a lady after, say, twenty years of her
married life, in London suddenly, and she
said: “Oh, what a coincidence!
” I said: “Why?”
“You see, I’m wearing the same pearl necklace
You had given me on my wedding day, today,
and I should meet you!
” I mean, the whole thing, the whole drama
changed, you know, that meeting.
I mean it was something, nothing so great.
It is how you give even a small thing, it’s
the greatest art of giving, one has to learn
in Sahaja Yoga.
Give up the mundane type of things, you see,
like if you go to somebody’s birthday, you
send a card: “Thank you very much.
” Make it a more deeper, significant thing.
Let us see how you develop your symbols of
love.
And when you’ll have these things of vibrations
and then you’ll give it to a Sahaja Yogi,
he will know what it is.
Never lack in generosity, specially amongst
Sahaja Yogis.
Gradually you’ll be amazed how through small
things you win over, as if the vibrations
flow through those things and work out on
those people.
Then for a Sahaja Yogi it is important to
use things which are more natural in their
character; to give up artificialities, to
be more natural.
I don’t say that you go and take out the
roots and eat them, or you can eat the fish
raw, I don’t mean that.
When going too far with things, always you
must avoid.
But try to lead a life which is more natural;
natural, in the sense that people know that
there is no vanity about you.
Or some people can be the other way round,
you see, they will dress up like a tramp just
to attract more attention.
I mean they can be both ways, you see.
When I find some of
the people, you see, coloring their hair and
all that.
So you have to be natural person, very natural
in your behavior.
It can mean anything absurd also to some people
who do not use their wisdom.
Wisdom is very important in Sahaja Yoga, that
one has to keep intact all the time.
“Natural” means you must wear natural
dresses which are suitable to you.
For example, in this climate there is no need
for you to wear dress like Rama used to wear.
He would not wear anything on top, you see.
There is no need.
You have to wear the dress to whatever country
you belong, whatever suits you for the occasion.
Whatever you think is dignified and good,
which speaks for your more elegance and your
personality.
Whatever suits you, you should wear, not like
all the people wearing that Moss Brothers
dress, in the grey suit, horrible-looking,
and absolutely making clowns out of them.
No clownish things are necessary, no dandy
stuff is necessary: simple, beautiful dresses
should be worn, which give you dignity.
Actually in the East, people believe that
God has given you a beautiful body, and it
is to be adorned with the beauty of what human
beings have created, just to respect it, just
to worship your body.
For example now in India people wear, women
wear their saris.
The saris are expressive of their moods of
these women and of expression of their worship
of their body, because you must respect your
body.
Dresses should be such that should be for
utility as well as dignity.
There is no need to have uniform clothes for
Sahaja Yoga at all, you see, I do not like
it.
There should be variety, as the nature is.
Everyone should look a different person.
For a puja and all that you may wear something
similar, doesn’t matter, where your attention
need not be on the variety, but outside, you
should be a normal person.
You are all householders, nobody has to announce
something.
Even you people, I do not tell you that you
put on your red mark while walking on the
street, because you should be like normal
people, not to be pointed out.
You need not be absurdly dressed or funnily
dressed; in a normal way as others wear.
To be normal is very important in Sahaja Yoga.
Then we have to know that Sahaja Yogis have
to get over all kinds of discrimination and
identifications according to races, color
or different religions into you are born.
Because you are born as a Christian, you do
not belong to a church.
You were not born in a church, thank God,
otherwise all the spirits there would capture
you immediately.
But these identifications will linger on.
To accept anything new, you are to be reborn,
and you are reborn now.
Now you are dharmatita – means you need
not follow any particular type of religion.
You are open to all the religions, and all
the essence of religions you have to take.
You are not to denounce any religion any time,
to insult any religion any time, or to insult
any religious Incarnation at any time: it’s
sin, it is a great sin in Sahaja Yoga; any
one of them, and you know who they are.
There should be no racial understanding of
oneself.
You could have been a Chinese or you could
have been a Negro, you could have been anything.
As long as we are all human beings, we should
know that we laugh the same way, we smile
the same way, we hold the same way.
This is all conditioned in our mind of this
society that you, some are untouchables, some
are touchables: this is in our Indian community
– horrible people.
Brahminism of India has ruined India completely,
and you learn from them.
For example, who was Vyasa, the one who wrote
Gita?
Who was he?
He was illegitimate son of a fisherwoman.
That’s why deliberately he was born like
that.
All these Brahmins who read Gita, tell them
who was Vyasa?
“Brahmins” are those who are realized
souls, and for realized souls there’s nothing
like all these nonsensical things, like where
are you born, in what caste and community
you are born.
With all education and everything in the West,
you find this nonsense of racialism; I just
can’t understand.
If somebody is fair or dark, after all God
has to make variety, in color, in every way.
Who told you that you are the most handsome
people going round?
Maybe for some of the markets here, or maybe
in the Hollywood it may fit in; but in the
kingdom of God all these so-called handsome
people will be denied entry; marrying seven
husbands and all sorts of things.
They will be all put in hell.
The beauty is of the heart, not of the face,
and that shows and shines.
I mean, people are a little bit aware of it,
that’s why they go and tan their faces.
I don’t know.
They are quite aware that it is too much showing
off we are doing.
But to have vanity, to have such absurd ideas!
Some people like red hair, some like black
hair, some like this; I mean, there have to
be different types of hair.
And why do you like a particular type of hair?
This I can’t understand.
There’s nothing like “like” and “dislike”,
whatever God has created is all beautiful.
Who are you to judge whether “I like this”
and “I like that”?
“I”, who is this “I”?
Who likes is Mr.
Ego, which is being pampered by this society,
which teaches you how to smoke cigars and
how to have your lager, morning till evening.
All this training and all this conditioning
has to be thrown away, just like filth, and
see that God has created all of you as His
own children.
It’s such a beautiful thing!
Why do you want to make it ugly with these
ugly ideas?
All this ugliness of “I like” and “I
dislike” are nonsensical.
Only there should be one word: “I love”.
Forget everything.
There’s no need to remember what British
did to Indians and what Germans did to Jews:
forget it.
Those people who did anything are dead and
finished; we are different people, we are
different people.
We are saints.
This is for your Statutes, I have told you,
which you have to imbibe.
But today I authorize you to be the gurus,
so that through your own character and through
your own personalities, the way you practice
Sahaja Yoga in your own life and manifest
the light, others will follow you.
And that you will establish the Statutes of
the Lord in their hearts and emancipate them,
give them their salvation, because you have
got your salvation.
You are the channels.
Without the channels, this all-pervading Power
cannot work out, that’s the system.
If you see the sun, its light spreads through
its rays.
From your heart the blood flows through arteries;
they become smaller and smaller.
You are the arteries which is going to flow
this blood of My Love to all the people.
If the arteries are broken, it will not reach
the people.
That is why you are so important; very, very
important.
The bigger you become, the bigger artery you
become, then you encompass more people.
By that also you are more responsible.
Guru must have the dignity, as I have told
you last time.
“Guru” means the weight, is the gravity.
“Gurutwa” means gravity.
You must have the gravity, by your weight.
“Weight” means the weight of your character,
weight of your dignity, the weight of your
behavior, the weight of your faiths, and your
light.
You become the guru not through frivolousness
and vanity, cheapness, vulgar language, cheap
jokes, anger, temper: all must be avoided
completely.
With the weight of your sweetness, of your
tongue, the dignity will attract people, just
like the flowers when loaded with nectar attract
the bees from all over; in the same way you’ll
be attracting people.
But be proud of that; be very, very proud
of that, and have sympathies for others and
care for others.
Now in short I have to tell you how you have
to do it yourself, this, of the Guru’s working.
You have to work out your Void clearly.
First of all, you have to know that the Void
catches when you have a wrong type of a guru
– you have had.
You must know about your Guru entirely.
Try to find out the character of your Guru.
Rather difficult, because your Guru is very
elusive, She’s Mahamaya, not easy to find
out.
She behaves in a very normal way, and sometimes
you are outwitted.
But you see how in small things also, how
She behaves, how Her character is expressed,
how Her love is expressed, try to remember
all that; Her forgiveness.
And then you should know that you have the
Guru which many people must have desired to
have, which is the Source of all the Gurus.
It is the ardent desire of even Brahma, Vishnu,
Mahesha to have a Guru like that, and They
must be all jealous of you.
But this Guru is very elusive.
So to improve your Void, say that: “Mother,
You are our Guru”.
Because of this elusiveness, that fear or
that awe which is necessary, that respect
which is necessary for the Guru is not established.
Unless and until you develop that awe, complete
awe within you, your Guru principle won’t
develop.
No liberty is to be taken.
I am telling you Myself, but I am extremely
elusive.
Next moment I’ll make you laugh and forget
about it, because I’m testing your freedom
to do it, complete freedom.
I’ll play with you in such a manner that
you’ll be forgetting every moment that I’m
your Guru, every moment.
So first of all you must find out about your
own Guru.
Establish Her in your heart.
I mean you have a wonderful Guru otherwise,
I must say, I wish I had one like that!
And She is desireless and sinless, absolutely
sinless.
Whatever I do, it’s not a sin for Me.
I can kill anyone, do whatever intrigue or
do anything.
I really tell you, that’s a fact.
Do anything, I am above sin, but I see to
it that I do not do anything like that in
your presence, so that you do not get one
of these things, because that is My quality.
You have a very supreme Guru, no doubt, but
still you must know that those powers of supremacy
you don’t have.
I am above all these things.
I don’t know what are temptations are, nothing!
I mean, I’ll do whatever I like, it’s
all My whim.
But despite that, I have made Myself very
normal, and because I must appear before you
in such a manner that you understand what
is the Statutes.
For Me there are no Statutes.
I make all the Statutes, isn’t it?
Because of you I do all these things and teach
you every small, small thing, because you
are still children.
In the same way, you must remember that when
you are talking to other people about Sahaja
Yoga, remember that they will see you all
the time, and try to understand how far you
are in it.
As I understand you, you try to understand
them.
As I love you, you try to love them.
I definitely love you, no doubt, but I am
Nirmama, I am beyond love: it’s a different
state altogether.
Under these circumstances you are better off,
much better off, because no guru ever goes
to that extent.
Apart from that I am the Source of all the
shaktis, of all the powers.
So you can have all the powers from Me, whatever
you like.
I am desireless, but whatever desire you have
will be fulfilled.
Even about Me you have to desire, look at
that: how much I am bound by you.
Unless and until you desire My good health,
I’ll have bad health; it is to that extent.
But to Me, what is bad health and good health?
And under these beautiful conditions you should
really prosper so well.
There should be no problem for you to be gurus.
Now, the Void is to be established.
First of all you must know your Guru, and
She is on every Chakra working – imagine!
What a tremendous Guru you have!
With that you’ll feel the confidence.
And because it is such a tremendous Guru,
everybody is getting Realization so easily.
If you go to a rich man, for him he’s not
going to give you two “p’s”.
Because She’s so powerful, you are getting
your powers just like that.
So you have to feel very happy about it, extremely
happy and beautiful that you have got all
these powers.
At least, those who have been in Sahaja Yoga
will know this, for some time; those who have
come for the first time may be little bit
puzzled with My lecture.
All of you know, all of you know for definite
what it is.
So to understand your own Guru power, you
must know Who is your Guru: Sakshat Adi Shakti!
Oh God, it’s too much!
Then establish your Void.
A guru does not bend his head before anybody
else, and specially My disciples.
Except for mothers and sisters and, you see,
in some relationship if it is so, so you bow
to that.
But they do not bow to anybody else.
And secondly, you must know that your Guru
has been the Mother of very great people.
The thought of them itself should establish
your Guru tattwa.
What tremendous Sons I have had, what great
Personalities.
No words can describe them, and so many of
them, one after another.
And you are in the same tradition, My disciples.
Keep them as your ideals.
Try to follow them.
Read about them, understand them, what they
have said, how they have achieved such heights.
Recognize them, respect them.
You will establish your Guru tattwa.
Imbibe all the Statutes within you, and be
proud about it.
Don’t be misguided by what people are talking,
multitudes are talking.
We are going to pull the whole multitude towards
ourselves.
First of all let us establish our weight,
the gravity.
As Mother Earth keeps everybody pulling towards
Earth, we’ll be pulling all of them to ourselves.
Today all of you must, within yourself to
your Spirit, promise that you will be a guru,
worthy of your Mother.
May God bless you.
(Now for people who have come for the first
time, they should know that Puja is a thing
not meant for everyone.
Actually we do not get people here really….)