[Music]
in the same way - vibrations vibrations
are coming they are radiated what you
have to do is to expose yourself to the
best is not putting any effort don't
worry
at what point you say many people
dealing with the dish enhancing if they
catch away they go on looking out you
just don't have to worry you just let it
go so you don't have to put in any
effort this is what meditation means
meditation means exposing on yourself
what's this now the grace itself knows
how to cure you it knows how to mend you
how to settle down itself into being if
your spirit take it it knows everything
so you don't have to worry as to what
you have to do or what name they what
massage you have to do in meditation you
have to be absolutely effortless tsunami
exposures are fully and you have to be
absolutely
[Music]
suppose you know possibility you know at
that time you have to just watch your
thoughts but don't get involved into
them we'll find gradually as the Sun
rises the darkness goes away and the
sun's rays move into every image and
every part that makes the whole place
light it the same way you but if you put
in an effort that time or try to stop
something within you or try to give it a
burn and it will effortlessness is the
only way to meditation but if we do not
be like classic about yogurt and watch
the other side maybe people just doze
off no you have together if you don't
have nothing in one you have to be alert
and open absolutely aware completely
effortless absolutely effortless if you
have absolutely effortless meditation
will work the voice don't think of your
problems at all
whatever chakras you have anything just
expose yourself see when the Sun shines
all the nature exposes it to the south
and it seems the blessings of the Sun
effortlessly it isn't put in any effort
it just receives when it receive them
some states in the sun's ray start
acting and activity
[Music]
the same way the all-pervading power
starts with
you are not a man over it you are not to
do anything about it just be effortless
absolutely effortless don't take any
names do not bother if you guys can see
this is catching that is catchy it is
working out it will go on working as
long as it can and it will
moody there are that it has to do you
don't have to worry about it it know
this job but when you put in an effort
actually create a barrier for so known
effortlessly be absolutely effortless
and say that it won't let go that so far
no one has to be chanted in case you
find it's impossible thing you get it
but there is no need you when you put
your hand towards me that's done so much
this gesture itself with the money you
see there is no need to say the thought
the divine motion should be that we have
not spread on the hands to that which
were whence this when this emotion is
absolutely complete there is no need to
say a you
so one has to be absolutely effortless
absolutely effortless that is what it is
meditation is for your own ascent it's
for your own capital gains that you have
to have but once you get into it you
also achieve you bombs like you become a
governor believe in the power circle at
this time you don't have to think about
anybody else they are not to put your
attention to anybody else but just to
see me just received do not think of any
other problem but that that you have to
be effortless absolutely it would work
best when the people who are just
assuming you have problems that's why
you're here but you cannot solve them
they have to be solved by divine power
this must be understood fully that we
cannot solve our problems it is be
honest to solve our problems so leave it
in the hands of the divine power and
expose yourself effortlessly absolutely
effortless sit in comfort and properly
sleep good
we hold the hands relaxed like this the
comforter should not be uncomfortable at
all it's very long time because you
loose it for quite some time and you try
to put your attention to me within
yourself if you have to make you believe
me if you can you can come into my
Kundalini
just like this the hand should be like
this state so effortlessness is the
keyword absolutely effortless
whether you are meditating before me or
before my photo
you