Shri Mataji: It’s quite.
Sahaja Yogi: Still quite, some more people
are coming.
Few people are still coming.
So, with Mataji’s permission, I will just
say a few more words while people are still
coming into the hall so that when She speaks
that can be full attention.
Because this is a subject where we have to
really give our attention fully and not be
distracted by what’s going on in the next
seat or behind us.
What has to happen is that our attention should
go inside.
It’s not an easy thing for people who are
used to thinking, to stop thinking, and just
watch what’s going on.
Because we are so identified with our thoughts,
we don’t realize that they’re not reality
and they’re actually preventing us from
experiencing reality which is absolutely the
present time.
So, please realize that if you have come here
to get something, it’s something personal
to you by which your relationship to others
is very much purified and improved but which
is for you and it’s for them also, but you
don’t worry about them.
Now one thing which will help this experience
to take place, this happening to work out,
is if you don’t mind to take out take off
your shoes and just rest your stocking feet
on the floor.
It’s a very simple reason for doing this
it’s like an earthing system.
It’s just giving a contact with the Mother
Earth.
It’s not a meaningless thing that the Muslims
insist that we do this when we go to their
mosques because Mohammed was a genuine teacher
who was connected to this All-pervading source
and who tried to teach people the actions
that would help them to be balanced and to
reach this higher state.
But people follow it without understanding
why they’re doing it.
So it’s simply to provide an earthing an
outlet if you like for negativity to pass
out because we have to become the Spirit.
We are the Spirit but we have to have that
knowledge.
And by letting all our thoughts all up but
Karma’s all our emotional hang-ups farce
out through the different elements like the
earth, the flame of the candle, into the sky,
then we find the Spirit is what remains.
It’s absolutely silent, it’s absolutely
untarnished it cannot be killed as Christ
proved.
It cannot be harmed by anything; it’s born
again and again.
And we have to know the joy of the Spirit
which is just to be the Silent Witness of
all the activity that goes on in our lives.
So now I’d like to introduce the Divine
Mother Shri Mataji Nirmala Devi.
Sahaja Yogi: [Inaudible]
Shri Mataji: No, I’ll stand.
Shri Mataji: I bow to all the seekers of truth.
At the very outset I must thank our very respected
mayor of North Hank Hampton to grant us permission
to use this beautiful Hall for this work of
God.
Yesterday, at Bedford, I explained to you
about this energy which is placed in the sacrum
bone which in Sanskrit language is called
as Kundalini.
This energy is placed in the “sacrum”
bone which is the Greek word; that means Greek
people also knew that there is something sacred
in this bone.
Now this energy is the energy of desire within
us, the primordial desire, the ultimate desire
that is not yet manifested.
That is the reason it is called as residual.
This desire is to become one with the Divine.
We are born today in these modern times in
a very great time I should say because this
is the Blossom time of human beings.
Never before in the history of spirituality,
so many seekers were born, so many honest
sincere seekers of Spirit were born.
There are a special category of people they
don’t know why they are not satisfied with
what they have, perhaps they don’t know
even what they have to seek but definitely
they know that they have to seek something
new.
We have our scriptures all over the world
and to understand as I said the personality
of any incarnation like Christ, we have to
consult every scripture to see where it is
indicated about the life of these incarnations.
This knowledge of the beyond, knowledge about
the roots of the Tree of Life was a secret
knowledge before, was very limited, was given
to very few people.
It’s described that at the time of Rama,
his father-in-law Nanaka, who was the incarnation
of the Primordial master, had
only one disciple who came to ask for Self-realization.
And he said: “You can ask for my kingdom”
because he was a king, “but don’t ask
for this”.
Because that was the beginning of life.
But as in the story of a tree, there are only
one or two flowers in the beginning a time
comes when there’s a Blossom time and many
flowers blossom and the wind comes which sends
the
message and they become the fruits.
That’s what is the time today is the time
of Resurrection as described in Quran, as
time of judgment as described in the Bible.
This is described by a great astrologer in
India, who was born thousands of years back
whose books were revised about 300 years back.
He has described this time again.
When we think of the Resurrection time or
the time of judgment, we must understand that
this judgment has to come to us spontaneously
from a living force.
Because God is a living being and his force
is living.
All the living things you see that exist – for
example, a flower becomes a fruit.
All such tremendous things, we see we take
it for granted, are the blessings of this
living force which is all-pervading but it
is subtle which we cannot feel.
That’s what Christ has said that, “you
are to be born again” that’s a very important
thing.
Actually, he came on this earth with this
message.
He didn’t come to establish any balance
within us because that was done by Moses and
Abraham and all these people.
But he actually came on this earth for us
to ascend.
This is the greatest message and Resurrection
is his message and not crucifixion.
Crucifixion has a very great
meaning no doubt and about which I’ll tell
you later as I’ll go from chakras to chakras.
When he said about the Holy Ghost he could
not explain either.
The reason being there was no time.
There were only four years for him to speak
about all these things and that’s how he
could not explain what was the Holy Ghost.
So, for every practical purpose, it’s a
mystery.
But after Realization, you will be amazed,
it’s not a mystery.
You know everything about the domain of God,
his laws and methods.
Once you get your Realization, it’s a surprising
thing.
But it is surprising because we do not know
what we are.
We do not know the Tree of Life is within
us and that this divine power appears as the
centres as described in the Bible: tongues
of flames, I will appear before you like tongues
of flames.
And you really see them as tongues of flames.
These centres are silent tongues of flames
burning with different colours.
Of course, especially at the top, they have
many colours and all these colours are beautifully
displayed and really peace giving.
But all this, what I am saying to you, is
not to be taken for granted either and not
to have faith in Me blindly.
That’s not the way to approach Sahaja Yoga.
Because I’m talking of reality and not of
some brainwashing.
It’s the reality that you must get and you
have to be honest about it that you have to
get the reality.
Now, when I say that all these things are
within us, I am saying it like a hypothesis
in a scientific research.
And once it is proved to be true then you
have to believe in it.
So, as a research
student or as a person who is trying to know
the new knowledge about the roots, you have
to keep yourself open and a little tolerant
about it.
As Mr.
Brown has told you that we have many angsts
and that’s why the problem is that’s why
we are confused.
But this Kundalini is such a force that it
shoots off taking you away from all those
angsts and makes the Spirit shine in your
attention in your central nervous system.
Now the Spirit is a reflection of God Almighty
within you.
That’s the collective being because God
is a collective being it is a collective being.
It is not that I say you are all brothers
or sisters that’s not the way so brainwashing,
but it exists within us as an actuality.
And when you actualize the Spirit you become
collectively conscious.
You become, that means on your fingers as
you see, you start feeling other people.
Then there is nobody the other you can feel
yourself your centres and you can find out
what’s wrong with you what’s wrong with
others.
Today, when I met the radio gentlemen, they
suggested that people would be very anxious
to
know how people get cured by Sahaja Yoga.
So, first I would like to explain to you what
happens.
This force the residual force within you is
the Kundalini as I told you and is the power
that, when rises, she pierces through all
these centres.
And all these centres represent our physical
being our emotional being our mental being
and our spiritual being.
For example, the very first one that you see
here, the red one, is our innocence.
Innocence as human beings.
As animals we had innocence.
Then God created human beings and he gave
them freedom.
He said: “All right, you’ll be on your
own keep your innocence.
Don’t run towards the so-called knowledge,
the knowledge: “What is this matter?
What is that?
Who is God?
All those things.
Keep innocent”.
If he had maintained that innocence with our
freedom intact there would have no problem
at all.
But in the curiosity of human beings when
they had the freedom, they consulted a satanic
force.
And the so-called book of knowledge started
opening out.
So, whatever we have got the knowledge is
a “avidya ” is not knowledge, it is non-knowledge.
Because by knowing this you do not know the
way about it.
For example, if you know that is gravity in
the matter or you can say there is gravity
in the mother earth, you just know there is
gravity.
It’s just a statement of fact which you
see with your eyes but you can’t say why,
why there is gravity.
Whatever you learnt through science is just
the knowledge that you see but you cannot
explain why it is there.
So, it is not a complete knowledge it is just
a gross knowledge of the thing that you have
which you can use for your purpose.
Also, science can help.
Now, I find science is very helpful because
if there was not a microphone, I could not
have talked to you people.
If there was no television people could not
have received
vibrations those who received on the television
today.
It should not have impossible.
So, even the science has helped you.
But that knowledge was not required and it
was all right.
But when we chose the other way, God also
helped us by sending on this earth many incarnations
to first tell us that: “You’d better establish
your balance”.
And this balancing was done at this point
[the Void] where you see the green circle
which is here in the stomach.
So, this balance has to be established.
When we got the Ten Commandments, you see,
we thought it’s a challenge to our ego:
who are they to say: “Thou shalt not do
this “.
What’s wrong?
Everybody says “what’s wrong?” when
they preach people don’t like it because
those please do not follow it, you see?
Naturally people say: “What’s this?”
But when the Kundalini awakens, she enlightens
these Ten Commandments so we can say the religion
within you.
That’s called as the principle of the Master
The master – say, in the car the one who
is the master is watching the driver who’s
driving.
First, learning how to drive, then suddenly
he finds a driver has become an expert.
And then he becomes a master.
In the same way, when you start moving towards
the right-side of action and the left-side
of desire you act.
Balance it: you make errors, mistakes you
correct them, again you balance it.
You discover the mistakes you have made, again
you balance it.
But these Ten Commandments, when they are
enlightened within you, you just don’t do
those things, you don’t like it, you just
don’t like, you just give up because there’s
enlightenment.
For example, in this hall there is no light
then you may fumble down when they fall down
you may learn by following ten times that
there are so many steps.
But if there is light you can see everything.
You can see the absolute relationship between
everything.
So, when you discover your absolute, the relative
position of everything is understood and automatically
you become righteous.
Nobody has to tell you: “Become righteous
“.
You just become you can’t help it.
So, this is what it is we the diseases are
caused mostly by imbalances.
As Mr Brown has told you that the Mother Earth
sucks the problems because all these centres
are made out of the elements, different elements
at different levels.
And we have imbalances of these elements in
our body and that’s how we get sick.
So, now the Mother Earth gives us, if she’s
here, if she knows Me, she’ll suck your
problems which are come by the imbalance of
the mother earth.
For example, arthritis and things like that,
all these come as problems of Mother Earth.
Especially in the cold countries people have
this trouble they can be cured by taking help
of the Mother Earth.
It’s very surprising.
The other day I had an Indian lady at my house.
She has terrible arthritis, and her hands
were like this and she couldn’t walk.
But when she understood how to ask the Mother
Earth to take away her problems and the methods
of divine laws, within half an hour she got
rid of her arthritis.
Even yesterday there was one gentleman who
got better, much better which his arthritis.
In the same way, we have problems with the
imbalances within us.
Now, let us see what problems do we have with
imbalances.
I am sorry, today I am going to speak on more
about our physical side because specially
he said people will be interested and I think
if you are physically not all right, how can
you be all right spiritually?
Now the imbalances we have within us, because
we are extremists.
If you are a person who is emotional you go
to the end of your emotions till you become
mad and lunatic.
You weep out yourself so much that you have
to land up in some lunatic asylum.
But nature has its own way of controlling
that.
For example, a person who is a lunatic never,
never has the failure of the brain.
It should be but the failure- on the contrary
the failure of the brain it has, but not the
failure of the heart, though an emotional
person works with the heart.
On the contrary the one who works too much
with the brain, thinks of the future, plans
too much, his brain should fail but his heart
fails.
All heart failures come to people who think
of the future, plan too much, think all the
time, all the time worried about the future,
work very hard physically because the right
side is the physical and the mental side.
They have all heart problems.
And those who are very emotional, I mean,
you say heart too much, always crying, weeping,
they get failure of the brain.
Just imagine, what a balance is build!
And a doctor told Me, from a mental hospital,
that they have a cardiograph machine, but
it was never used because a lunatic’s heart
never fails.
So, once you have such an imbalance nature
takes the respite but it can be very fatal
and dangerous.
There are many diseases which are caused,
really, most of the diseases are caused by
imbalances.
Now let us take out a person who is a very
speedy person, it’s very common these days.
I mean people are so speedy that you don’t
know how to talk to them.
They are telescopically speedy their words
go telescopically and you don’t know how
to scan it out, how to talk to them.
Now such people who are speedy, who are running
all the time, who are not there in the present
at all, all the time of the future are the
people who move too much on the right hand-side.
And there is the second centre which is looking
after the right-side, the creativity, the
thinking.
Because when you think the cells of the brain
are replaced every minute by the fat that
is in your stomach, by this centre which we
call as Swadisthana which in the gross expresses
itself as aortic plexus.
Of course, the medical science won’t accept
it but when we have proved it by curing people
I hope they will accept it.
Now this imbalance comes in because you are
all the time thinking.
Now this poor centre has to look after other
organs within us like the liver, spleen, pancreas,
kidneys, intestines and uterus.
Now such a person who is thinking all the
time neglects all these organs and any one
of these diseases he can have.
For example, he can have liver [problems]
he can have diabetes, he can have leukaemia.
Leukaemia cost more to these speedy people
not so much to the people who are futuristic,
but more to the people who are speedy.
Because the spleen acts for our emergencies.
Supposing a person is extremely speedy; he
just rushes to the bathroom, takes his bath
goes and gets his breakfast and drives on
the way eating his breakfast all the time.
Poor spleen does know how to cope with this
crazy personality.
Because here it is, he’s going in a mad
rush.
In the modern times, you see the traffic is
so bad, they just, they are shouting at the
traffic.
Then there’s a breakfast going on.
All these things are going simultaneously
and poor, this spleen, doesn’t know how
to react and how to cope all the time to these
emergencies, one after another, simultaneously
so many coming up.
So, it gets crazy it loses its control completely
and it starts producing additional blood cells
and blood cells and blood cells.
And when they become too much then they start
flowing on their own, because there is no
relationship left now because of the speediness.
And that’s how Leukaemia has established.
Now leukaemia can be easily cured, very easily
cured.
Because when you put your hand when you are
a Realized soul the energy is flowing.
You just you put your hand on the spleen of
the person, you’ll be surprised that the
spleen settles down because it gets new vitality.
It gets the wisdom from these vibrations,
we can say, from this energy because this
energy is the one that thinks, that cooperates
and organizes.
That’s the one which sorts out also all
kinds of plants and everything.
It is this living energy which when given
to the spleen it becomes wiser: it rests,
it becomes silent.
And also, if you give the person the balance
with your hand, you can make the person much
more relaxed, much more silent within himself.
And that is how you can cure.
And we have, not only that, I have cured of
course nowadays, I don’t cure people much.
There’s a disciple in America and one gentleman
met Me in a village.
He came in his car and he told me that: “My
grandson has gone to America for his treatment
of leukaemia and now they said he’s a gone
case and in 15 days he is going to die.
That’s the certificate”.
So, I told him that: “I’m so busy in the
villages now, you can go back and bring up
this lady she’s there in New York and she’s
an American Sahaja Yogini “.
And he rang her.
She said: “All right, I’ll try to work
it out “.
And she cured him.
The boy came to see Me in London he’s now
back in the school, he’s perfectly all right.
Now people think it’s magical.
It is not!
It’s nothing so great.
Because we take so many things for granted,
every day, if you see the living work of God,
it’s tremendous!
Look at this honey, look at the way the flowers
become fruits.
I mean millions and billions of things we
take it for granted even our evolution from
amoeba to the stage we have come.
We don’t know how we have come, how God
has done it.
It’s done so delicately with such care with
such understanding.
At least we should know that there must be
some meaning when he has brought us to this
level as a human being.
What is the meaning?
Why?
What was the reason?
Why he made us like this?
And just when you discover this meaning spontaneously
automatically this thing gets cured, because
that vitality starts coming to you from the
top.
Now we grow over tensions why?
Because you see, there, with the activity
of these two sides left and right side, we
develop two big balloons in our head.
With the left-side one which is for conditioning
us, which frightens us, gives us fear and
all that, which is our past, we develop an
institution call “superego”.
Such people are all the time under fear, under
danger, or crying, weeping sort of people.
The other side are the people who act.
When they act, they have another by-product
in the head called “ego” which you must
have heard quite a lot.
And this Mr ego is on one side and superego
on another side and once they close down will
become like an eggshell.
You are closed.
You have an “I-ness”.
You are Mr So, you are Mrs So.
Now when this is accumulated there [Agnya]
we feel the tension because either we are
in action or we are in whipping conditions
where we are in inaction.
This tension mounts up in the head and you
feel the tension.
And with this tension you get all sort of
complications.
With the left-side you might get low blood
pressure and all that.
With the right-side you might get high blood
pressure.
Now how do you reduce the tension?
People ask Me how do you reduce the tension?
It’s a very simple thing.
You see, life’s work is extremely simple.
Like your own breathing is so simple!
Have you ever thought about the breathing
that you do?
You don’t read any books you don’t go
anywhere you don’t consult anyone it just
happens to you.
In the same way, it’s such a simple thing
that your tension on the head is because either
you are worried or you are planning something.
You are aggressive or you are taking the aggression;
one of the two.
So, what happens?
Here I say that Christ plays a very big role
in our life because he is placed in that crossing
point if you see.
This is the cross.
When he said on the cross: “It has been
accomplished”.
When he says that the placing of Christ in
that little space of ego and superego is accomplished.
When Christ is awakened through the kindling
of the Kundalini then these two things are
sucked in.
That’s why we say he died for our sins because
the left-side are the sins and the right-side
are the Karmas the action, the ego.
So, he sucks it.
By that suction you are amazed that suddenly
you find there’s a depression here like
a child has.
And you feel the throbbing here.
And after the throbbing you feel the cool
breeze coming out of your head.
From your own head the cool breeze is coming
out.
This Holy Ghost is manifesting herself.
And she’s all around.
Also, you can start feeling in your hands
if your- this centre is all right.
This is what he meant “to be born again”.
Not just to call some people: “All right
now we have a baptism”.
So, the poor child is screaming and you put
your hand on his head and say: “All right,
you’re baptized now”.
That’s artificial, it’s just a drama.
And this kind of drama they do in every religion.
It’s not only in Christianity.
You’ll find even Hindus do the same joke
and everybody has the same joke.
But it’s not true because if there is baptism
there has to be transformation.
And there is no transformation whether you
baptize a child or not.
On the contrary, I have seen some children
they become funny.
Because this is a very precious place, it
is a very holy place [Sahasrara] and anybody
who is not a holy person who is not a sanctified
person places the hand on top of the head
of such any child, he can become even mad.
We had three examples of that kind that people
who got baptism, children who are perfectly
normal but after baptism their eyes started
squinting around and they lost their awareness.
Because the people who put their hands on
this very precious holy place where not themselves
holy.
They didn’t have a clean heart.
And that’s why- this is the centre of the
heart which is there in the Spirit.
And this one [Sahasrara] when it is touched
by someone who has a heart of a stone can
pass bad vibrations satanic vibrations.
People can spoil them.
You have a very great poet in this country-
you had him- was William Blake.
And he said: “A priest cursed on my head”.
And people asked Me: “What it is?”
I said: “The priest must be somebody who
is not such a good man perhaps and he touched
his forehead”.
Because he was a Realized soul.
And he’s written so much about Sahaja Yoga
that nowhere in the world I have seen so much
written about Sahaja Yoga as your great poet
William Blake.
Now when this happens so many other things
can also happen to us.
For example, a person who is very emotional,
for example, the one who is always whipping
crying going to the left-side.
Oh, they are – most of the people feel guilty
that’s the worst disease of the West.
By feeling guilty you get spondylitis, thyroid
all kinds of troubles.
So, no use.
What’s the use to feeling guilty after all?
Or people who believe that “we must suffer”.
Now this I can’t understand at all!
Because Christ has suffered for us.
What more are we going to suffer?
Now he suffered already for us.
Has he left something for us to suffer?
Those people who believe like Jews did believe
in such a thing, they suffered.
We don’t have to suffer at all!
That’s a promise.
He suffered for us.
Only thing, we have to awaken him, that’s
all.
Nor do we have to feel we are very guilty
because if you feel guilty then this left-side
gets caught up [Left Vishudhi].
And it creates a problem for your Realization
first of all and secondly, it might give you
a physical problem.
I’ve seen this is very common with the West
people I don’t know why they should feel
guilty.
One must know that God Almighty is the ocean
of compassion, ocean of love, ocean of forgiveness.
We cannot understand his forgiveness, we cannot
be like him.
And what guilt can we have?
Even the judges on this earth who are just
human beings cannot punish you.
How can that God is going to punish you for
what?
So, we live with myths: “Oh, I should not
have done it, I should not have done it”.
This has come also with our modern life.
For example, if you put your fork and spoon
in this way then you are all right, sophisticated.
If you just put it a little this way: then
you are: “Oh, I should not have done it”.
If you spill the coffee then you are as if
you’d murdered three persons the way you
feel about it.
It is not so.
It’s not so.
In the realm of God what does it matter?
It’s nothing important.
For him, the most important thing is that
you are a human being.
And you must know that you are at the epitome
of the whole creation and that should have
no self-pity about it, no self-pity at all.
But you must have self-confidence that God
has created you with a purpose, that you become
collectively conscious and you see the play
of God’s beauty and his glory.
That’s why he has created you.
Not to feel guilty not to have self-pity and
to cry and weep and always say: “I’m horrible.
I have problems”.
Such people get troubles to themselves while
those are aggressive trouble others.
Both are just the same in the eyes of God
whether you trouble yourself or others, it’s
just the same.
Now this kind of an imbalance that comes within
us can be corrected with the awakening of
Christ within us.
The chanting at this place when he is awakened,
when he is awakened because you are to be
connected with him.
Then is our Lord’s prayer that’s the mantra.
We have to say that he is kept awakened and
that is the chanting we have.
You’ll be amazed after coming to Sahaja
Yoga the Christians who hated the Jews have
understood the importance of Moses because
he resides in this void part, this green circle
and all ten of them who incarnated again and
again reside there.
Now those who are fanatics say, those who
believe that only more Muhammad is the one
or those who believe that only the Moses is
the one or any such funny ideas, they also
suffer physically.
I had a doctor from Iran, about ten years
back I should say, he came to England to see
me and he had a cancer of the stomach.
And I asked him, I said: “Do you believe
that Muhammad is the only one you had?”
“Yes.
I believe in that."
I said: “How can it be?
He himself has said there have been many prophets.
And how can you say that he’s the only one?”
So, he said: “No, no, no.
He was the last.
He was the most modern so I believe in him
and I don’t believe in anybody else”.
I said: “You have to believe in Moses.
“Oh!
That I cannot believe.
These Jews, I can’t believe in them.
I hate the Jews I can’t believe Moses."
I said: “All right, go ahead, if you can’t
believe in him.
Same is Nanaka.
Same is Janaka.
They are the same people again born again.
And the same quality of the Primordial master
is born again.
I said: “All right, go ahead, I cannot cure
you if you are a fanatic you suffer."
So, he went home and he had a bad time.
Doctor said: “You are going to die now”.
So, after eight days his wife brought him
again.
I said: “Now do you believe in it?” he
said: “Yes Mother, I do.
Please, cure me”.
And he got cured.
He’s still alive all right.
Fanaticism has its own respite to.
Fanaticism is real madness I should say to
be fanatical about something.
It’s a mental projection to believe that
somebody belongs to you.
Actually, you have to belong to them and nobody
belongs to you.
This fight of religion imagine when you see
that in this world there are fights going
on in the name of God, in the name of religion,
you’re shocked!
The things that were created for peace, for
bliss and for heavenly abode of human beings
are being used for something that is absolutely
opposite of that.
It’s most surprising how people are believing
into a team to such an extent that they are
just getting monopolized and filthen [unsure]
and they are torturing others.
It could become even very sophisticated like
people who have formed lots of mental projections
you see, they have dogmas, this, that and
they cultivate you every time they have a
lecture and then you believe in it: “Oh,
oui, [yes?] this is this”.
And from your childhood you are told, “you
are like this you are like that”.
Ultimately, what do you find at the end of
life?
Nothing but the same and same and same going
on.
But the principle of religion is to give you
a balance and that doesn’t happen unless
and until this religion is awakened within
you.
Once it is awakened, I don’t have to tell
you that: “You give up your drugs”.
You just give up.
I don’t have to tell you: “Take your alcoholism
out.
” You just do it.
I just don’t tell you.
I don’t say that if you have alcoholism
or anything as a disease it just drops up
automatically.
Even if you want you cannot drink.
You won’t enjoy it at all!
It’s just as a by-product as you get rid
of your troubles.
In the same way, these habits also drop out.
You become independent you become free not
slave of anything because you are the Spirit
which is the freedom within you.
Complete supreme freedom is your Spirit.
Last of all, I will tell you about a horrible
disease, which is the modern disease nowadays,
is the disease of cancer, which is a horrible
thing as people say.
Cancer is caused mostly, which I have seen,
in the people who are left-sided.
Not so much in the right-sided people, those
who are aggressive.
But those who are emotionally ones disturbed
get this trouble.
So far, I have not seen one patient of cancer
who has not been emotionally very much inclined.
It might look, appear that a person is very
aggressive, but if you really go into the
history of a person you will find that he
had a problem, that his mother died, or his
father died early, or some sort of an emotional
problem he developed later on, or a shock
from his wife or a fiancée, from his children
or something like that.
It’s more a case of emotional disturbance.
Now when you find, that a person has a cancer,
on the hands you’ll find that all these
fingers are burning [Shri Mataji shows all
the fingers of Her left hand], sometimes even
these fingers start burning [Shri Mataji shows
fingers of Her right hand].
When it is on a galloping state you put your
hands towards a person who is suffering from
cancer- even doctors might not diagnose it,
they might find it later on – all your fingers
start burning.
You start burning here and here [Shri Mataji
points on the top of the palm near the fingers].
Also, you may start feeling a throbbing here
[Shri Mataji points to the solar plexus].
Of course, throbbing doesn’t mean that a
person has a cancer, but is one of the symptoms.
Now how cancer is caused?
It’s very simple.
And to understand it- it’s better that if
you understand- you will not those things
which are not to be done.
Anything we do into extremes, I mean any emergency
is taking over by this two sides, because
they manifest the sympathetic nervous system.
They act for our sympathetic nervous system
whenever there is an emergency.
For example, a person has a habit, a simple
habit, of say, rubbing his ears, very simple
habit.
He may develop a cancer there.
Because he has overdone it.
An extreme thing he has done is rubbing, rubbing,
rubbing.
So, what happens is that the cells which are
supported by a centre here, for example, it’s
coming from left and right [Shri Mataji forms
a triangle to mime the spinal cord] – and
that’s how a centre is formed.
If you can see all of you.
This is the one through which the medulla
oblongata passes, the spinal cord, this is
the spinal cord.
Now, when there is a pull on right-side or
left-side too much, on the sympathetic nervous
system, then this connection breaks out like
that [Shri Mataji splits the hands].
When it breaks out the connection of the centre
with the whole, because this centre [right
thumb] is supplying the energy, is broken.
When the connection with the whole is broken,
there is no coordination left, there is no
control left.
So, the cells become on their own what we
call malignant.
They start growing on their own.
For example, if their nose develops the cancer,
than nose becomes big.
The rest of the- is smaller and the cells
of the nose start pressing all other organs
in here [on the throat].
And sometimes they may pass into blood and
go to other areas also.
So, these are aggressive cells, malignant
cells are on their own, you cannot control
them.
By some chance, if you could bring them back
in connection with the whole, if you can do
that, cancer can be cured.
It’s as simple as that.
When the Kundalini rises, what she does is,
she awakens the centre.
And when the centre is awakened, it just comes
back to normal and a person becomes normal.
That’s how cancer can be cured.
It is very simple, it’s not so difficult.
Human life we have made it so difficult, actually
it’s not so difficult.
It’s a very simple thing if you understand
the laws of nature and laws of God’s divine
Power.
You can overcome most of your maladies, most
of your problems and you’ll reside in the
kingdom of God.
Now, there are so many other diseases which
I don’t want to refer now because I have
tell to you the physical side.
And the mental side is the left side as I
told you.
Also, on the left side is another disease,
is multiple sclerosis.
I saw a very good television show the other
day.
It was put up by some doctors.
And they said that in ourselves there is an
area which is built in from our creation,
means the collective subconscious.
That’s what we call it.
And there are proteins which they call protein
58, protein 52 or something like that.
They enter into our being and trigger the
cancer.
So that shows what we have said, that there
are dead within us.
On the left-hand side is the subconscious
and then the collective subconscious.
And when you enter into the collective subconscious,
anyone of this spirits can catch hold of you.
Once they catch hold of you, you are liable
to any of these diseases.
Specially I have seen if there is a possessed
person – of course they become mad, they
get epilepsy, all this are possessed people.
Epilepsy can be cured; we have someone here
who had epilepsy of the worse type.
She is cured completely.
And all such mental troubles, depression,
can be cured.
Not difficult at all.
But one must know, that if you are possessed
you must really work it out and see to it,
that it goes away from you and you become
yourself.
Because when you are the other, you don’t
know what’s happening to you.
Now this affliction when it comes to you,
there is another horrible disease called multiple
sclerosis which comes up.
I have seen so far there three cases in England
of multiple sclerosis which have been cured
by Sahaja Yoga.
All of them had either the wife or the husband
possessed.
Can you imagine?
It’s something surprising.
We do not know these things are so important.
These are very important things and that’s
why all these people come on this earth said,
that you lead a clean life.
And a sensible married life.’
It is not permitted to have an adulteress
life in any religion whatsoever, because adulteress
life brings forth all kinds of problems of
the sex spoiling the last chakra.
People can become impotent or overexcited,
could become suffering from all the troubles
of this centre, which you know are diseases
which are kept as secrets.
So, one has to lead a very clean wonderful
married life, because marriage is supported
and sanctioned by the collective.
It is sanctioned by God almighty.
So, that kind of a life, that kind of a sexual
life, is a sensible one.
One should not get a shock out of it.
When I say this in the west, people really
don’t like it.
But I’m your mother.
I have to tell you the truth.
Even whatever you have done is done – finished,
doesn’t matter.
But now come to your sanity.
Because there are all these horrible satanic
diseases waiting just to gulp you down.
Apart from diseases such a person creates
a problem for children.
He creates a problem for the whole society.
The whole society topples down.
If they do not respect the marriage, if the
woman becomes aggressive and try to sort of
replace men – they cannot do it, they are
woman.
Men are man, woman are woman.
But that doesn’t mean that somebody is going
to suppress.
They are equal, no doubt, but not similar.
This is a simple point we don’t understand.
They woman is to be respected, but she has
to be respectable.
And she has to be respected, because she is
one who is the power behind the man.
If we understand all these simple things of
life, the life becomes very beautiful.
How we have to respect our elders.
How we have to respect everyone.
The respect itself is gone from the modern
times.
People have accepted themselves as something
you see ‘what’s wrong’ business.
There is no respect for anything whatsoever.
I mean the way they bark at each other; one
doesn’t understand how human beings have
become now dogs or what have they become the
way they start barking at each other.
The whole system goes out of gear when we
become too much materialistic also, because
the matter makes us absolutely a dead matter
also.
But I’m not saying that you have to give
up anything.
What do you give up?
You don’t give up anything because if you
have not taken anything into you, if you do
not cling anything to anything, what do you
give up?
Like this people Hare Rama came to Me and
they saw Me in My house and of course I mean,
we live very well.
Perhaps they thought it was too much for a
saint like Me to life in all these luxuries.
And they started saying: ‘Mother, You are
living in this fashion and how people call
You a saint.
I said: All right.
Now, you talk of Lord Krishna, isn’t it?
Now in this house or one My body anywhere
you find anything equal to the dust of the
feed of Lord Krishna, you take it away.
Anything, but must equal!
‘ That’s one thing.
They looked around and they could find anything.
I said: ‘What have you given up?
Stones?
Ashes?
What is there to give up?‘
When you just see the whole thing as a drama,
when you are not clinging on anything, what
is there to give up?
In Sahaja Yoga we don’t believe in false
asceticism at all.
Be believe in the real asceticism which comes
from within.
Where a person gives.
Where a person enjoys matter in giving others.
We don’t believe in this kind of a falsehood
that you wear a certain type of cloth or you
have a nunnery or this judo-sannyasis going
around.
None of these things.
You have to lead a very normal life in the
centre.
All the great saints of India were married
and had children.
Except for some people like Buddha who died
very early.
He had to take a sannyasa because of His work.
Then we had people like also we can say Kabira,
Nanaka – all of them were married people.
And nobody talked of this extreme nature that
you have to give up everyone.
Such people can be very, very dangerous.
They can be very hot tempered.
They can be so hot tempered that you cannot
just face them.
Because marriage makes you very normal to
come in the centre.
In this life, in this married life you are
going to receive the blessings of God.
There is no abnormity needed.
Actually, we become extremely normal when
you get your realization.
Of course, some of these ideas may not appeal
to you.
But you can see for yourself, whatever I say
is true or not?
After Realization, you become a different
person.
Your priorities change, you become such a
beautiful person because you start giving.
The whole thing starts flowing from you.
Because you become the light and the light
starts flowing from you.
And then you understand and assume your powers,
powers of your Spirit and you enjoy this compassionate
flow.
And all the things look very different, the
whole life changes.
This has to happen to the whole world if you
bring peace and sanity, if you have to save
this creation, we have to do this.
Actually, the divine is more anxious than
anybody else to do it because the creation
will be lost if human beings are lost.
So, those who are people who are seeking should
understand their responsibility that they
have to become the spirit.
And after becoming the spirit they have to
manifest the powers of their spirit.
These are their own powers which they manifest.
Only they have to know how to work it out.
It’s very simple as I said.
And to have it is the best way to understand
it.
May God bless you all.
I would like to have some questions from new
people because today is the first lecture
here, but for a short time.
Please ask constructive questions.
Don’t ask offensive questions unnecessarily.
I’m here to do good to you, not to do any
harm to you whatsoever, take it from Me.
So, be kind to Me and ask Me questions which
are good for you and for everybody else, because
they are all just waiting for their Realization
which should not also spoil their chances
and delay the matter.
So, I would request you to ask Me questions
which are sensible related to the subject
and I’ll be very happy to answer them because
certainly when you get your Realization you
will find your mind will peep out: ‘Oh,
you didn’t ask this question to mother.’
I’m sorry I have been speaking now every
day and last month I was too [?].
Everyday there was a speech on, so little
bit there is a strain on My throat, doesn’t
matter.
Can I request you to ask Me questions please?
Thank you.
Shri Mataji: Yes, please?
Woman: Can you get rid of epilepsy?
Shri Mataji: What is it?
Sahaja Yogi: Can you get rid of epilepsy?
Shri Mataji: You just come here to tell Me.
Sahaja Yogi: The lady is asking can you get
rid of epilepsy?
Shri Mataji: Yes.
All right.
Yes.
Woman: [Inaudible]
Sahaja Yogi: What is it?
I didn’t follow, can you raise your hand,
please, where are you?
Sahaja Yogi: The lady’s question was whether
one can you get rid of epilepsy.
Shri Mataji: Yes, we do, we can.
If you really cooperate with us it will work
out.
It will work out definitely.
But you have to cooperate.
You see, I’m not a doctor which is one who
takes money from you, so you are not bound
to Me.
It’s your freedom.
It’s your freedom!
Whether you want to cooperate or not, but
sometimes people don’t cooperate, then I
can’t help it.
It’s noting great is to be done but few
things that have to be followed if you cooperate
with Me, of course it can be done without
of course any charges, anything, it just works
out.
Yes.
Woman: [wording incomprehensible]
Shri Mataji: What’s she saying?
Woman: Will You help me please?
Shri Mataji: Definitely, why not?
I’m here for that, all right.
Make yourself comfortable, yes.
Actually, I’m not helping anyone, I’m
helping myself.
Supposing this finger is paining and if I
rub it, do I help anyone?
Because you are within Me.
When you start everyone – you’re feeling
another person within yourself we really don’t
help anyone.
There is no question of charity.
It’s question of my saving myself.
All right?
Woman: I’d like your help too, please.
Shri Mataji: What is it?
Woman: I’d like your help too.
Shri Mataji: What did she say, Gavin?
Gavin: She say’s also that she would like
to have your help.
Shri Mataji: All of you.
All of you are going to be helped in a way
if you say call it ‘help’, but I don’t
like the word ‘help’ much.
It’s your own.
Just like if you go to a banker for example.
Then you say: ‘Can I have my check cashed?’
All right?
At the most you’ll say ‘can you help me?’,
because you are very generous, I should say
and sophisticated.
But actually, it’s your bank there and it’s
your money.
You better have it.
Woman: Mother, can you [inaudible]
Shri Mataji: Can you raise your hand I can’t
see which one is speaking?
Yes, my child.
Woman: Mother, … [wording incomprehensible]
Shri Mataji: What she is saying?
Sahaja Yogi: What do You hope to achieve through
Your lectures?
Shri Mataji: What do you do Myself?
Sahaja Yogi: What do You hope to achieve?
Shri Mataji: Achieve?
I mean, don’t you understand.
[laughing] What am I achieving is that you
all have to become collectively conscious.
That’s what I’m achieving, nothing else.
As I am.
I will tell you in political terminology,
all right?
I have all the powers within Myself, so I’m
a capitalist.
But I can’t enjoy it because I have to give
you, so I’m a communist.
And I want you to enjoy your own powers, that’s
all.
Nothing more than that.
Shri Mataji: Yes please?
Man: Is it possible to receive help after
a surgery or before.
Shri Mataji: After?
Sahaja Yogi: After surgery.
Shri Mataji: Yes, yes, of course, of course.
There is no problem even after surgery.
But if you put something artificial there
– sort of a – say a rod or say, steel
or something, then we can’t move it.
It has to be something living.
We can repair it, regenerate it and we can
give vitality, but to the rod, say, it’s
of steel, then what can we do?
But other surgeries we can work out.
Shri Mataji: Yes, please?
Yes?
Please ask the question?
Man: [Inaudible]
Shri Mataji: What?
Sahaja Yogi: He also wants the help of Mother.
Shri Mataji: All right, for all of you, I’m
there.
You don’t worry, you all are there.
I’m going to come down and see all of you,
all right?
All of you I’m going to see like yesterday,
as we did.
Man: Mother.
When You were speaking about Holy Ghost
Shri Mataji: Yes.
Man: You use the word ‘She’ which regard
to that.
Shri Mataji: Shri?
Man: She
Shri Mataji: Yes
Man: You said She.
Shri Mataji: ‘She’, yes.
‘She’ is the power and She is called as
Shakti.
‘Shakti’ – She is the power.
So ‘He’ is the God Almighty and His power
is the ‘She’ – the Holy Ghost.
Man: The creator’s power?
Shri Mataji: That’s the power of the divine
power of God, His love.
Which has got one: is a creative power.
Another is the power of His desire.
First you must have desire.
Then he creates, so He has a power of desire
and He has a power of creativity and also,
He has a third power, which is the power which
gives us sustenance.
We become say – we have our qualities, like
carbon has four valences and all that.
And then it also gives us evolution.
So, this third power is more important, because
that gives us this ascent also.
This is the manifestation of the Holy Ghost
which is the power of God Almighty, which
is the power of His divine love.
Woman: Mother, if some diseases are caused
by our parents, why innocent children get
leukaemia for example?
Shri Mataji: Oh, they get it because the mother
is like that.
Mother must be a speedy lady.
You see, if the mother – today only I had
a lady, I must tell you: I saw a lady, she’s
told Me that: ” My child is overactive,
she is so active that I don’t know how to
control.
It’s not a mental case, but it is a funny
situation, that she is overactive “.
So, I said: “What were you doing?
” when she was pregnant.
She was such, she told Me, in the night she
used to work in the factory, the whole day
she used to work in the house.
Imagine?
I mean, you pay no respect to your pregnancy.
So, what will happen?
If the mother is so, sort of a speedy person,
the child gets it.
You see, mother has such an influence on the
child, isn’t it?
The blood of the mother goes into the child.
And that blood carries the message.
That’s how the children get it.
And that’s very difficult to cure also.
One has to know also, when you are pregnant,
how to treat your children, how to be looking
after your foetus.
That’s one has to know all these things.
These are very important basic things which
we do not know.
Shri Mataji: Yes?
Man: Your power of healing, is it something
that you sought yourself or were you born
with it?
Shri Mataji: What is it?
Come and tell Me as I just can’t hear.
Sahaja Yogi: He is asking, is your power of
healing something You sought yourself or which
was born with You?
Shri Mataji [smiling]: It’s all with Me,
all right?
As you know you are a human being, I knew,
I was this.
But about Me I’d better not tell.
It’s better you discover it.
It’s better not to tell about oneself.
You better discover it.
Gradually, you will discover about Me.
Shri Mataji: Yes?
Now, say loudly.
Woman: Is it possible to go to classes in
Northampton and ….
how much is it?
[Unsure]
Sahaja Yogi: She wants to know if there are
classes in Sahaja Yoga in Northampton.
Shri Mataji: You cannot have a course in it,
you see.
It is not courses, but we have centres.
You have to just go and know about it.
There is no classes, nothing like that, but
you can come to the centre, where they will
tell you how to use this power, what does
this mean, all the decoding of it, how to
establish your Realization.
We have a centre here in Northampton and I
don’t know when you have it.
I’ll tell- I don’t know.
But we have a centre here, just right here.
Can somebody tell when is the program, at
what time?
Sahaja Yogi: The program in Northampton [Inaudible
conversation]
Shri Mataji: You can become masters, real
gurus.
Yes, you can.
But I think people must take it more seriously
about the whole thing and should understand
it and learn it, because the main thing is
we do not take any money, you see.
So, people think, that you see, you are not
bound.
You are absolutely free to come and to go.
But this freedom sometimes makes a person
a little superficial or sometimes a little
frivolous about it.
But this is so precious, so invaluable, that
you cannot charge any money for this knowledge.
All right?
Now, should we have it?
No questions?
Man: [Inaudible]
Shri Mataji: Gavin, what did he say, I just
can’t?
Did you hear?
Gavin: No…
Shri Mataji: You didn’t hear him: Just stand
up, I think.
You better stand up here.
Gavin, you just stand up.
Just say it loudly, please, if you don’t
mind.
Yes!
Man: [Inaudible]
Gavin: When you have a pain within yourself
[…] through the mother earth?
[some words incomprehensible].
Shri Mataji: Yes, some things are sucked by
mother earth, as I told you – some.
Some are sucked by the flame of the… – can
be the flame, can be the fire.
The sun also sucks in.
Then the sky also sucks in, anything can.
It depends on, on what centre you have a problem.
All these centres are separately made by different
elements.
It depends on, what problem you have.
All right?
But on the whole mother earth is the most
precious thing.
She helps the maximum on thing.
Man: You spoke about living energies and vibrations
and the scientist with us […] not the scientist
he enjoys trying to get the rays within, he
mentions the gravity […].
Because there were people who thoroughly enjoy
… into the rays of gravity.
I’ve been very … in things like dowsing.
[some words incomprehensible].
Shri Mataji: Ah, dowsing.
Dowsing is…
Man: A force now … bring … together [unclear]
Shri Mataji: I talked about this yesterday.
Yesterday I talked, but again if you want,
I’ll tell you in short.
You see, we have some other dimension which
we are not know, they are unknown to us.
But they are not divine, like we have the
left side dimensions as I told you, you go
into the collective subconscious.
Now if you go into collective subconscious
some of this busy bodies can enter into your
being.
And they are the once who give you this power
of dowsing.
You see, that’s how you start knowing there
is water, because there are some spirits in
you which can [?
] to it.
You see, there are ESP’s and all this thing
come from the same sources.
There could be some on the right-hand side,
supra-conscious once, which are very aggressive.
Hitler used them.
He is the one who used this supra-conscious
people, very aggressive people and enticed
all German people and made them so aggressive.
So, these two areas are within us.
In Sanskrit the one on the left is called
‘adi bhautic’ and the right as ‘adi
daivic’ [?].
Both of these are to be avoided.
For example, somebody sees auras around Me,
for example now.
I would say he should not.
It’s not proper.
Because then you are on the right side.
But if you see some gods and goddesses around
Me, that also is not good, because you’re
seeing the left side – the past, and the
future.
What you have to be is in the centre, in the
present.
So, all these things come to you from some
busy bodies as I said, that they enter into
your being.
I have seen another television show where
they showed Gogin entering into somebody.
And he was painting just like him.
The lines were just like him, bold the same
wave very different styles that he has.
And he was doing it and he said: ‘I’m
Gogin.’
And this is very common even with curatives.
When people cured, they use spiritualists.
That’s very dangerous.
All these are taking you to the realm, which
is not your own.
It is somebody else who acts in you.
Even a thing like, say acupuncture can be
very dangerous, because acupuncture uses the
whatever energy in you of the sympathetic.
This is energy I’m talking which is all
the time flowing.
When you get connected with the mains all
the time it is flowing within you.
That’s the energy we should have.
And the scientists are correct when they say
vibrations.
But they can’t say, why there are vibrations.
This is the point.
Not that I’m against science because today
the science is helping us so much.
Man ask about his son, which have skin problems.
[analogous]
Shri Mataji: Ah, skin problem.
All right, there’s nothing, that’s liver.
Woman: How can I help myself…
Sahaja Yogi: How can she learn to cure herself.
Shri Mataji: Yes, that’s what I’m saying
that today if you get Realization well and
good.
Otherwise there is a centre, you can come,
by which whatever you have cured yourself,
but you can cure others also.
[1:06:59]
Man: The Self-realization, Sahaja Yoga.
Is that the answer about our problems?
[… some words unclear]
Shri Mataji: Hundred percent, to all problems.
You see, because we live in a relative world.
We are living relatively and we are confused,
isn’t it?
But when you find the absolute, all the questions
are solved.
That’s true, because spirit is to be awakened,
that’s the main thing.
Spirit is the solution.
Firstly, it is the collective being.
Again, it is the source of all vitality.
It is the source of all the creativity.
It is the source of all the joy and bliss.
Once you achieve that being within you, when
that being shines in your attention, you become
the master of that.
[1:08:03] Woman: Question incomprehensible.
Shri Mataji: Can you say it loudly?
Man: She says Mother, has the mother nature
provided the answer in terms of herbs to cure
people?
Shri Mataji: We don’t use any herbs or anything.
We at the most can sanctify some water or
salt or sugar, these basic things, that’s
all.
We don’t use any herbs or anything, that’s
not needed now anymore.
Woman: Excuse me, do we have to be religious
to… [some words incomprehensible]
Shri Mataji: You don’t have to be religious
at all.
But religious is different from religion!
Religion is within you, you can’t get rid
of it.
You see, religion is your quality as a human
being.
That’s within you, you can’t get rid of
it.
If you go against it, whatever is within you,
then there is a problem.
Yes, everyone has that, everyone has that!
That’s true and that’s why you get problems.
But religious is a very absurd thing.
Sometimes religious so called people can be
horridly hot tempered, you know.
Could be very bad and could be – I mean,
it has no relationship whit reality sometimes.
So religious is a different thing, but religion
is important.
Religion is universal, which is within you.
Now, let’s start now.
Woman: Question about diet.
[exact wording unclear]
Man: She says Mother, does the diet which
we … solve her problems?
Shri Mataji: Yes, not the diet want solve
it completely, but when you take to Sahaja
Yoga, supposing you are a liver-patient, all
right.
So, we give you some sanctified or vibrated
sugar to eat, white sugar.
Now doctors will say: “Don’t eat white
sugar”, but we have cured so many of liver
troubles.
All have migraines and this and that and so
many troubles of the allergies are to be cured.
Now for that of course we say, for about a
month, you just don’t eat some fats.
You see, that’s all right.
But that by eating, you see, you paying so
much attention ‘eat this, eat that!
That food, that food!’
That’s not needed.
It’s too much attention diverted to food.
But you should know basics.
But if this is the problem with you then what
you should eat.
That’s all, it’s not such a emphasis on
diet that you eat this.
Only by dieting you maybe, all right, at the
most physically, but you are not only a physical
being.
You are also an emotional being.
If you pay too much attention to your physical
side, you can become a dry personality.
Absolutely.
There could be divorces in the families and
such a person who just is nothing but a physical,
imagine.
It can be very dangerous and can be a very,
very angry person who has just physical thing.
And such a person gets heart – heart trouble,
because the spirit resides in your heart and
if you are too much physical, then the heart
goes out, because you must pay attention to
your spirit.
So, you are not only a physical being, you
are a mental being, you
are an emotional being
and you
are
a spiritual being.
All
this
must
be integrated and there should be
a complete balance.