You see, actually in subtle form it’s this.
That thing which is Kailash, part of His domain.
Kailash is a very big space, you see. Peak of …. Kailash.
You must see the pictures of Kailash.
It looks like a human face, absolutely – so wonderful.
And three little heads, can you see?
Absolutely clearly you can see this.
And the vibrations are tremendous.
And what about the day we had Shiva Puja?
That day it was frozen completely.
Heroine.
Nayika is the commander, that’s correct. Shri Chakra:
it’s the chakra with which the whole world is created,
everything; creative chakra is Shri.
Chintamani is the jewels which is,
which emits the fulfilment of your desires.
Whatever you desire, your worries, your desires are fulfilled
by that jewel, called Chintamani.
She is the one who fulfils all your desires. You must desire.
Brahmas, five Brahmas. Five elements.
Loudly.
Vaibhava.
Vaibhava, is the glory.
… combines.
Manatma.
What is translated, read it.
You see, this is because of samasas;
Vigraha is not correct, that’s why.
Now you read the …
Atmanas.
Manatmanas:
the ones whose minds have become atmas.
Manatmanas.
See, they are Her dignity – that’s the point.
That’s Her vaibhav. Vaibhav means, we can say,
the majestic pulsation She emitted.
Something – vaibhava can be, bangles can be My vaibhav,
means they’re ornaments which add to Her majesty.
Vaibhav, you see.
Rishis are My vaibhavas, see;
now what I’ve told you is true. You’re My vaibhavas.
This Bandhasur, this what’s-his-name is –
was yesterday that lady was entangled by him …
Muktananda – is Bandhasur.
Yogi: The asura who ties you up.
Very difficult to get rid of these people.
Muktananda, see is the one who makes you absolutely
bound to him – and he says, “Have muktananda.”
This lady is down with tuberculosis,
but she can’t give him up, you see.
She has both the hearts catching very badly,
she’s going down, and she can’t give up
because he’s tied him – he’s Bandhasura.
But Bandhasura has this quality:
you have to tie up people, you see,
and even if they are dying they cannot leave.
Sampatkari.
Sampati means “property” and is represented by elephant.
This is the main point.
See, ashwakoti – crores of ashwas.
Ashwa means horses; so, white horses – crores of them.
Do you know that?
Ashwarudha.
The ones who are on the horses, white horses,
are representative of the Shakti, of the Power,
and they are the ones who are part of the Kalaki.
Crores of them, crores. “Crores” means ten million – one.
She’s the action; action chakra is Shri Chakra,
through which one acts.
It’s the right side, Shri Chakra.
Geya chakra. “Geya” means “by which you know.”
Geya is the, by which you know.
She is the one who is in possession of that center
by which you know.
Knowledge is that chakra only.
Those who are served are the mantrinis.
You have – your mantras are enlightened mantras.
Whatever you say is mantra.
Kiri? Kri, kri. Yes, that becomes “Sa”.
Kri is Karochita, is Shri Chakra only.
So Sahaja yogis must be careful, you see, also.
A little bit frightening.
Madhyaga.
Blazing garland – Jwalamalini.
Jwalamalini is...
Horrible Bandhasur.
What is the valor of Nitya?
Is crucifixion of Christ.
It’s the valor of Nitya, because He’s eternal Being,
so you can see Him crucified; otherwise
for a Mother to see Her Child crucified is horrific.
But because He’s the valor of Nitya,
that’s the valor of Nitya – the valor of eternity.
You see the valor of eternity,
how He is killed actually, and He resurrected.
But when you see that valor, it is so beautiful.
Yogi: We must know that the same thing is in us.
Yes, of course.
Bala is Kartikeya. It’s Kartikeya.
And He kills, because at this point the Kartikeya
works out, you see – at this point.
And this is one, this horrible fellow Bandhasur, creates your
Was terrible lady, that night!
Is there not going to be … now.
Now it’s done or not? It’s done now.
I gave it to Pamela.
Pamela, where are those ornaments I gave you?
Where is that? … Yes, where is it?
Both things are there.
Karanguli.
From Her …
...fingernails. Karanguli.
Anguli is “fingers.”
Pashupati’s Shiva, and She’s Mahapashupati.
Burning the cities, is just like Rajneesh’s city was burnt.
Madhyakuta. Middle part.
Kula is, you can say, it’s a dynasty, dynasty; house, house.
Yogi: Mataji’s kula is all the Sahaja yogis.
Of course …
See, it’s very delicate.
See, what are the symbols of, say -
now, Gavin has given Me a little crown
as a symbol of England, you see,
which I really look after very much, you see –
kept it very carefully.
Also Kulangana is a word used for a lady
who cares for the kula, means for the house,
for the dignity of the house, dignity of the family,
of all the dignity.
She cares for the dignity of all the members of her family.
To her, the dignity of her family
is the most important thing.
She enjoys that.
There’s another word is kaul.
Kaul is this thing where they ask whether it is correct
or not for the kula, that is;
and if the flower falls on this side or that side,
they say, “Yes, kaul, yes, yes.
The Goddess has said yes to me.”
So Kaulini: She’s the one who is the,
of course the mistress of the kula;
but She’s the one who gives you yes and no,
the indications which way to go.
Akula. Akula means “the one who is beyond any disturbance.”
Kula also mean “banks of the river” – kula,
so also can mean “the one who has no banks.”
Samaya means “time.”
She’s the one who knows the time when to start puja,
when to do what, She knows, She knows the timing,
because She is inside the time.
This is very important.
What is it?
Samayachaara, samayachaar means whatever is to be done
in a particular time.
For example now in modern times, see, that particular,
that whatever is to be done,
auspicious thing for modern times, one should do.
For example, learning English is important for us.
But apart from that, samayachaar means mannerism
of a particular time, you see, certain mannerism
of a particular time which is good,
auspicious, must be done:
like putting the belt, see, while sitting in the car
you must put the belt – samayachaar, whatever it is.
You see, for Devi it is not necessary.
For example, if you give Me some money,
I need not put it in the bank.
I can lose all that up and say that I’ve finished –
there’s no sin for Me.
I can take away all your properties,
everything, there’s no sin.
But I must do according to the time,
to prove what is good for you,
how you should behave towards money,
towards collectivity; and accordingly I behave.
And there is no need for Me,
because I am beyond it, isn’t it?
But samaya, whatever is necessary for
according to the time, I have to do.
And that’s what you should understand.
Not to be abnormal people, you see,
behaving in an abnormal way.
Even I tell you that you need not put on this red thing,
because it may not be samaya kul at this time,
you see – people won’t understand,
so you need not put.
It is wisdom to behave in a way that you lead normal,
you behave in a normal way, do something that is normal.
But God need not.
For God it is not necessary because He’s beyond,
but when you have disciples who have to come up,
who have to deal with other people,
they must know how to behave.
Like to say thank you is not necessary for Me to you, at all.
If you give Me a glass of water
it’s a privilege to you, all right?
But I say thank you ten times,
because you must also say thank you.
Samaya kul, samaya kul.
Yogi: Salutations to Her as the only one
who lives in the Mooladhara.
Nobody can enter in.
Brahma granthi.
See, you can’t enter inside the center unless
and until your Kundalini rises,
and the Kundalini is the representation of Holy Ghost.
And She’s the only one which can enter into it.
And also She resides, the Devi resides there
as Mahalakshmi or as Lakshmi, in Manipura.
Now see, without coming to Sahaja Yoga
you would not understand all these things, isn’t it?
Because it’s not known to you that
there are granthis within us,
there are centers within us, that these centers
are to be broken, then there’s granthis are formed
between the centers – all this knowledge is impossible.
If you are not realized what’s the use of talking
about it to you, because you cannot see that.
But in a person you can see it,
that at a certain point you find it is between
two centers this Kundalini stops, you see.
There is the center, say, of Manipura and Swadhisthana,
in between the two the Kundalini stops.
Now what is that?
That is the granthi of Vishnu,
so that’s the Vishnugranthi vibhedini.
If you say the mantra of “Vishnugranthi vibhedini”,
then only the Kundalini will rise.
But before Realization,
before the movement of the Kundalini, it is what?
It is just talk, it has no sense at all.
Here, at the Agnya Chakra.
Antaral. Antaral means the innermost core.
Antaral – in the innermost core of Agnya Chakra
She resides. Rudra.
“Sahasraram bhuja” means in the lotus of the Sahasrara,
aarudh – She is bestowed upon that.
Ascend – aarudh. All right.
Actually when you go onto a throne or
onto a horse is what you call mounted:
She is mounted upon, She is mounted upon – aarudh.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who is slender as a lotus stalk.
That mean you should not be harsh with Me.
Bhavani. “Bhava” means “to manifest.”
Whatever is manifested. Known.
You must have feeling.
If you don’t have feelings for Me, you won’t know Me.
Rationally you will not know.
Those people who tried to know Me rationally
can never know Me.
You have to have feelings.
Forest of …?
You see, if you have to become,
there’s a big mesh on, and She’s the one
who cuts that and makes you the spirit.
See, whatever is manifested is created,
is nothing but a forest, isn’t it,
and She takes you beyond that.
“Bhadra” means actually “gentlemanly”, see?
She likes people who are gentlemanly.
She doesn’t like arrogant people,
people who have no sense how to behave,
ill-mannered sort of people She doesn’t like, you see –
except for Shiva, who is His own style, you see.
He’s very kind, but He’s so innocent, He’s so sweet.
Imagine, He comes on a bull – He’s not very bhadra!
Not very gentlemanly to come on a bull, isn’t it!
I mean, She’s a lady. She’s ladylike, you can say.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who gives
all good things to Her bhaktas.
All good things, not bad things –
supposing you ask for a whisky, I will not!
Yogi: Salutations to Her who loves Her devotees.
Definitely. You must know this in your hearts,
that I love all of you very much, all right?
So you won’t be diffident at all.
I love you, every one of you,
much more than you love Me.
So that you love yourself and each other.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who can be approached
only through devotion.
Through devotion.
You can only control Me through bhakti.
Sharada is Saraswati.
Shatodari doesn’t mean that.
Shatodari. Shat means hundred.
She has hundred, hundred – udara means stomachs,
see, udara means the wombs.
She has hundreds of wombs.
Otherwise how will I do the work?
… is going to make Me red!
Should be also unruffled type.
There’s nothing to be ruffled,
it’s all a joke going on.
That means completely integrated personality.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who is beyond desire.
That’s why I say you must desire.
She’s purposeless, you see, purposeless.
This Prapancha means “purposeless”, you see.
All the elements are the ones which create the purpose.
If the elements are not there, there’s no purpose.
I mean, if you become abode of everyone,
how can you have abode?
If you become the support of everyone,
how can you have any support?
Imagine the situation!
Nirupadhi.… upadhi means there’s no upadhi.
Means, see, additions, an addition, you see.
A upadhi is, you see, like they say
“Sir this and this”, “Lady this and this” – you see,
these are all upadhis.
This is additions; which, if you are complete,
you don’t need this thing – attributes.
I mean, if you have passions, how can you destroy passions?
But it’s so natural, you know.
There’s nothing special.
Nothing special about a person
who didn’t take to these passions.
Naturally.
These are called as dual names, you see:
that the first they give the quality,
and then what does that quality do.
Say, if they say “Nirmama” it’s a person
who doesn’t say “this is mine,” who doesn’t feel
“this is mine, this is mine.”
Such is the person only –that’s the quality.
Nirmama quality itself destroys this attachment in you
when you say “this is mine, this is mine, this is mine.”
You see, like a soap has the quality to cleanse,
all right?
The soap has to cleanse, now nobody cleanses the soap.
That’s how it is.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who has no doubt.
About anything.
See, this is what it is.
If I had doubt then you would be doubtful also.
But you know Mother has no doubts about things,
so when you come near Me your doubts also vanish,
automatically.
That’s it … Very good …
“Bhava” means whatever is manifested.
You see, whatever is manifested is bhava;
and whatever is manifested is this flesh,
this body, this everything, see.
So you just get above it, that you deny it –
the denial of the flesh, as Christ has said.
So Bhavanashini means the one who takes you away
from this world of illusions, the world of manifestation,
in which you think “Now this house is mine, that is mine.”
All these ideas go away,
and you become one with the Reality.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who has no plans,
no mental acitivities.
Not at all. But what to do?
The mental activity I don’t understand.
I sometimes say “I think” because of samayacha,
you see; but to be very frank, I never think.
I don’t know how to think.
It’s impossible.
It’s a funny machine, you know.
That’s why for you I have more respect and concern,
because whatever I have I have,
it’s nothing so special, you see?
But you are achieving it,
so it’s something special about you.
If you have everything, what is so great?
If somebody is achieving it, it’s a greater thing,
much, much greater.
That’s all right.
But for that I cannot take any credit,
because it’s automatic people take it.
I don’t know how to take the credit, you see.
That capacity is also not there, you see,
to take the credit. I’ve tried, but I can’t!
I never feel, you see,
that a very credible about it that
I should take a credit,
and come and “this is My doing.”
I just don’t feel it that way,
I don’t know how to feel – I mean,
there’s something’s missing in the personality.
The ignorance is missing. All right?
Now this is the integration,
and non-integrated, you see.
When you are integrated there’s no problem, about it:
you are integrated.
So whatever your body is – it will eat what is good,
everything is integrated; no problem,
there’s no quarrel about it.
Within yourself you are at peace.
Let others do what they like,
whatever they think about themselves doesn’t matter.
But as far as you are concerned,
you have no problem because you are so integrated
and supported: there’s no left Vishuddhi
feeling-guilty business.
I don’t feel guilty for anything at all, you see.
If I scold somebody – all right,
I had to scold, I’ve scolded, finished.
I don’t sit down and start feeling my left Vishuddhi.
I am completely integrated.
Whether I am in peace or in turmoil,
or in anger turmoil I’m never –
but I deliberately take anger upon Myself.
Because it is deliberate, what is there
to feel bad about it?
Because you get, you see, blown into it:
that’s why you feel bad, “Oh, why I did it?”
But this I do it deliberately.
Then what is there to feel bad?
Yes, yes, of course. I do.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who destroys death.
The other day I used the mantra of Mrutunjaya.
Did you hear that?
That is should be used for people who are possessed
by sort of a cemetery business, see.
So imagine a complete cemetery possesses a man;
then what to say?
It’s Mrutunjaya:
that “You are victorious over the death.”
That’s what I said.
I don’t do anything, I am lazy person.
Yogi: Salutations to Her who takes nothing.
Yes, who takes nothing.
Really, to be very frank I cannot take, you see –
that doesn’t work out.
You see, whatever comes to Me goes with a double speed.
You know who is Durga?
Durga is the one who is that fellow who did anand marg.
All right, now give some rice on top.
This is what it is.
Now if I take this, it will blossom into thousands.
Take where?
And you see, what is this ritual?
What does that mean – (that’s all) – what does that mean?
Now this is the expression when you do like that,
is that now we have, making this auspicious,
with this rice
and what you’re calling, turmeric.
Now the turmeric is a very special thing
which is very auspicious, created by Mother Earth.
Is a very auspicious thing.
You cannot say why – it is.
So mix it up with rice – rice is also a favorite
of Mother – and make it auspicious with your hands.
You have put it there, by which you say that
“Mother, this we give it to You.”
But actually, to put this akshatas – akshata;
akshata means “this cannot be destroyed.”
So while doing this what you are suggesting,
that “Let us detach ourselves from these fruits,
which we are giving to our Mother.”
All right? The detachment.
By that detachment, you develop a detachment
within yourself.
It’s a simple thing. That is, to give something
to Mother is something not needed;
but when you give it,
by that you develop a detachment.
That’s why you have to give:
you develop a detachment from that.
Of course you get it back, hundred times more back,
but that detachment is developed within your heart;
and even if you get thousandfold more,
you are not attached to it. See?
Then you become generous, you start giving to others.
And when you are blessed by the same type of fruits,
you don’t enjoy it alone, you only enjoyed it with others.
You see, human beings have a capacity to enjoy everything
all alone.
They can sit down in a room,
close the door and peel out a fruit and eat, themselves.
I mean, they can do it, quite capable.
Even the crows cannot do it, the animals can’t do it,
but human beings have a capacity: they can do it.
I don’t know how – it’s an impossible situation for Me,
impossible.
Even to eat food sitting alone is an impossible situation.
But to sit down and enjoy yourself alone is possible.
But by doing this, what you are saying:
that we make it auspicious, give it to Mother.
By that, you develop a detachment that
whenever you will eat these fruits,
always shared with others,
and they’ll be bountiful, bountiful:
meaning when you have more, give it to others.
All right? So I’ll just touch it, all right?
That means I have accepted.
May God bless you.
And when you eat these fruits now,
you will develop that detachment in your Nabhi Chakra,
that you will not hanker after fruits of the season,
but you’ll be satisfied.
That is auspiciousness, that you feel satisfied.
And what satisfies you more is giving:
that’s the sign of a realized soul, you see.
When you understand the joy of giving,
then you are a realized soul – otherwise you are not.
May God bless you.
Whichever you think I should eat it, I’ll touch them …
Strawberries? Strawberries I like. It’s the easiest to eat.
You must eat strawberries always
with a little bit of salt for the throat.
Thank you.
Now what else? This puja is done now…
See your scholarship! Absolutely is true.
Now as you have done the job of the unmarried girls,
let the unmarried girls do this. Come along.
Unmarried girls from Brighton.
Brighton is a nice place, very few unmarried girls!
Unmarried men, all right.
Let unmarried men and unmarried girls! Come along.
Unmarried men of Brighton. Only two? Three?
Mike, you are supposed to be Brighton fellow.
All right, come along. You become one.
You can include Anand if you want.
He’s from Shicarpur.
And Sonu. Sonu, you can join us, all right? Open the sari.
Gavin, that’s too much.
Who has done – this is too much!
See, these are very expensive in England,
you should not buy them. Bought in India?
Open it out. It’s beautiful, isn’t it?
It has got fans, I think, and what else?
Real Bengali sari.
That’s the blouse-piece.
It’s complete with the blouse-piece.
Now, the bachelors must know which side is right side.
Is correct, you’re right.
This side is right side.
Now bring the sari round.
It’s a training!
Ah, how nice!
So can you take the photograph of all
the bachelors and the spinsters?
All girls.
In India they are called as kanya, kanya.
Are you not a bachelor? A bachelor ….
Done now?
This is from London. All right.
It’s very beautiful.
This one is from Brighton.
Let Jeremy put it, the Brighton, all right? Jeremy.
The sari.
Get this out, it’s too much.
Let’s put the sari on both the sides.
Is that for the arms? Now come along, come along now.
Bachelors have a special – they’re blessed today.
They are called as kumaras, kumar.
And the, I suppose what they call spinsters are called as –
but what do you say in English?
This is the word, but you use for old women!
Then it is the marriage is announced?
I see.
So, they are called as kumaris,
and the boys are called as kumars.
I think Sanskrit has more decent names, isn’t it?
That’s because they respect the unmarried men
and unmarried women very much – they’re very much respected.
This for arm? Arm, here. And here,
it’s too small – too loose, too loose.
Better make it tight. Tie it up.
Must tie it tight, otherwise it doesn’t stay, you see.
This is for Shri Chakra,
or you can say the right Nabhi and Shri.
Why his hands are shaking – with vibrations!
Ah, great – it’s a great task you have done.
Yes, it is.
Just pull it, pull it out.
First tie it that way.
Give him a hand.
Come along, tie it up properly.
Come along, come along. Tie up …right.
No, when you have done it with these daisies,
you have done it.
All right now.
It’s all right, done; it’s a great job, no?
It’s not easy.
It’s only because you are Sahaja yogis you can do it.
No, no, it’s not easy. Ask anyone.
These flowers in front.
These are all Vishnu’s powers.
Such fragrant!
Look at this one, has such a Sahasrara open.
See these daisies,
see what a beautiful Sahasrara they have!
See these, look at this one. Just see it, all of you.
Only the daisy flower have this kind of … in them,
have you noticed?
And now you will know why My name is Daisy.
See, one better than the other – see?
Yes, really!
Yes, that’s it!
And the fragrance,
you should see the fragrance of the daisies.
All right, I think the boys put the sari in such a way.
May God bless you.
I would suggest that all these
should be given to the sea here.
These flowers can be thrown into the sea.
Yogi: Mother, may I read a prayer?
This is a prayer for collectivity.
All right. Read it loud. Stand up.
Very good.
Vishuddhi is a very big fight, I must say,
to work it out as Shri Krishna.
This left Vishuddhi is a big problem, very sly.
Right Vishuddhi is another problem.
We have to fight it out.
May God bless you all.
So havan we’ll do, after lunch –
would you do with Ganesha’s names?
Unfolding is easier than to fold it.
Give it to the bachelors to do!