I think some of the Sahaja Yogis were rather
amazed that I accepted Rita’s invitation
to come to this place! Rita has been very
kind to call me here.
Every place has its own attractions, as far
as the Divine is concerned.
And I knew there must be some very deep seekers
in this place who could be really benefited
if I could visit this place. And I was overjoyed
to arrive here.
Now the question about Sahaja Yoga is very
simple to understand. All that is vital is
extremely simple. For example the way we breathe
is so simple. We don’t read any book, we
don’t do any exercise for that. We don’t
have to go and learn from anyone, we just
do it. In the same way, if our seeking has
some meaning and if we have to find out something
it must be the most vital thing offered. It’s
not just an alternative life. Many people
have a feeling that the seekers are nothing
but they are finding alternative theories,
and to alternate, with the present norms and
conditions – it’s not so.
The time, that is today, the modern times,
are special times described in the ancient
scriptures in India and also in The Bible
and Koran. In all the scriptures they are
described. In the Koran they are described
as the resurrection time. Christ has many
a time talked about it that: you have to know
My Father forever. That your hands will speak.
Lots of descriptions he has given of this
state which you will achieve at a time. As
in life you have seen [that] a tree has to
grow. First it may have just one or two flowers
but when time comes when the same tree which
has only one or two flowers – about, say,
two years back [or] three years back – suddenly
gets into a blossom time and has lots of flowers.
Like that, today is the time of blossom time
of all the seekers.
So many seekers have taken birth today on
this Earth. Especially England it’s described
by William Blake that these times are going
to come when England is going to become Jerusalem.
‘Jerusalem’ means ‘where it will be
pilgrimage.’ For people will think this
is the Holy Land of God. That people will
come to this Holy Land, to visit this place.
So the people have to be holy, they have to.
It’s not the trees that are going to become
holy, it is not the land that is going to
be holy but it’s the people. Their hearts
are going to be holy.
Then how do they become holy? What happen
to a person when he really becomes holy? We
talk of saints. We talk of prophets. What
is the difference between these revered people
and ordinary people? There’s only one difference.
The difference is this: that in their attention,
in their central nervous system, there is
the light of their Spirit. While for the other
people, they live in ignorance without this
light of the Spirit.
The Spirit exists in every one of us. It is
always there, present, all the time. It’s
Omnipresent. It’s all the time present within
us. But the problem is that we are not aware
of it, that it is not shining in our attention,
in our awareness.
When Gavin told you about the new awareness
it means that the awareness that we have,
the human awareness, becomes enlightened – a
new awareness – and in that awareness what
happens is that our Spirit manifests.
Now one may say, Mother it must be a difficult
thing. People have to do so many tapasya,
they have to do so much penance and they have
to go to Himalayas and do all kinds of things,
stand on their heads for days together, and
how is it that it is working so easily now?
Actually that kind of thing is not needed
today because the time has come.
When the time has come it just work out fast,
it works out en masse. Now I am with you here
but in India, those people who have visited
with me know that there are thousands of people
for every programme I go [to] there. And all
of them get realisation. All of them get realisation.
Means they started feeling the All-pervading
Power for the first time on their hands. “Your
hands will speak.” First time the All-pervading
Power about which Christ has described, every
scripture has described, you start to feel
it as cool breeze of the Holy Ghost.
Now this feeling, somebody can say, “Could
be due to this, could be due to that,” because
we are doubting Thomases sometimes and we
start doubting it. But the thing is, you can
see, in so many people, the rising of the
power from the triangular bone which is called
as ‘Sacrum’. Surprisingly ‘sacrum’
means ‘sacred’. That means that Greeks
knew that it is a sacred bone, it’s a sacred
bone. Nowadays this word has no meaning but
it will come back when people realise what
is sacred.
In this bone, the triangular bone, we have
this power called Kundalini settled down.
This residual power which creates us, which
creates the whole being, is still not manifested,
it is still sleeping. Because it is the power
of our desire which is the ultimate desire
to become one with the Spirit, to feel the
All-pervading Power, to be the instrument
of the God.
Until this power, or we can say this power
of desire has manifested itself, we are not
going to be happy people. We can try anything
we like [but we will not].
Now, in the beginning you may say, that so
many prophets came in: Christ came in, all
of them came just to make us ready for this
day when we can be born again. Christ has
clearly said you have to be born again. Now
who is bothered about it? There are people
I have met who have certified themselves “born
again,” but you can’t certify yourself
as “born again”. “Born again” means
a person who has felt this All-pervading Power.
Who can make this All-pervading Power flow
through his being and can manoeuvre it and
understand it.
Now this All-pervading Power is the power
that has all the powers that you see: all
this electricity, everything is a part of
that power. That’s the vitality of the whole
Universe, that has created this Universe.
This All-pervading Power that flows when you
get your realisation, gives you tremendous
powers. But the biggest power it gives you
is to love. God is love, and His power is
the power of love. He really loves us. He
loves us so much that He is the one who wants
to save us. It is He who is anxious to save
His creation. He doesn’t want that His creation
which He has created with such love with such
attention, with such delicate help, out of
which you are the epitome of His creation.
The human beings are the highest, and [for
them] to be destroyed – that He cannot bear.
And it is His desire that is flowering today
as Sahaja Yoga and that the people are getting
Self-realisation in such a mass quantities.
But the main problem today is that there are
so many in the market that people don’t
know what to do. To begin with, we have churches,
we have mosques, we have temples, we have
all kinds of people selling God, or maybe
talking about God, or saying that, “This
is God.”
Now these religions came on this Earth, all
the Prophets came on this Earth, to establish
a balance within us, as I told you, to prepare
us for the ultimate. But I have noticed that
without enlightenment whatever is the belief,
whether it is Christianity, Hinduism, Sikhism,
all any isms or Communism or Capitalism or
any sort of thing, it is fanatic belief.
The reason is without the light, you can not
see.
For example, I come upon this table, I feel
this table [when] there is no light [in the
room]. To me this table is the main thing,
the rest doesn’t exist. To another person
comes here and sees a chair, to him this chair,
nothing [else] exists. Now this myth that
he believes into, he has to establish it.
It’s a myth because he’s not yet enlightened
and he cannot enlighten other people so it’s
a myth. And he has to adhere to that myth
with such glue-like tenacity that created
a great barrier between him and the Truth.
Because he has not known the Reality yet.
Reality is very different from what we feel
today as human beings.
For example, I will tell you that this Gavin
(Brown) who has today spoke to, met me about
six, seven years back or we should say more
than that.
And first he got his realisation I told him,
“This is All-pervading Power. ” He started
feeling the Cool Breeze. He said, “Mother
how are we to know that it has got telecommunication,
it has every way of informing us?” I said,
“Alright, what do you want to find out?”
He said, “I want to find out about my father.”
I said, “Alright, you put your hands and
just ask ‘how is my father?’.” And he
asked this question: immediately he started
getting the burning on his hand, on here.
Now, these are the centres of your father.
These are the centres of your mother. When
he started getting the burning here, he said,
“Mother what is this?” I said it means
you father is down with very bad bronchitis.
His father was in Scotland. I said, “Why
don’t you telephone to him and find out?
It’s very easy to find out.” And when
he telephoned, he found out, his mother told,
that, “Your father is down with very bad
bronchitis.” So that is how the information
comes to us from this All-pervading Power.
Now before that, whatever we do, say we talk
of capitalism, we talk of communism. I would
say I am the greatest capitalist because I
have all my powers within my control. I have
all my powers within my control And I am the
greatest communist because I cannot live without
sharing. I have to share them because otherwise
I cannot enjoy all those powers that I have.
I really cannot enjoy my own life unless and
until I share it with all of you.
I have lots of joy within myself but unless
and until I share my joy with you all, I am
not going to enjoy it. So I am a regular communist.
So all these things you have done, like communism,
capitalism, communism, democracy are nothing
but the myths of the Reality. Like, sometimes
you say, “I am my nose, I am my ears, I
am my eyes.” They are all one!
You do not see the integration. Why? Because
you haven’t yet awakened yourself.
Once you are awakened you find “Oh! I am
the whole body.” All this whole body has
all these different parts which we consider,
“This is good, that is good,” but none
of them have proved to be really perfect.
They are good, but they are not that good.
So there must be some way where all these
things integrate, and they integrate at a
point where you become the Spirit because
Spirit is the thing within you which is the
Collective Being.
Now my husband, as you know, is at the UN
system and you have an agency here called
the ‘Maritime Organisation’. And he also
feels that, whatever they are doing on a global
level, on an international level lacks something,
lacks something, in human beings. Because
rationally they understand that the whole
world is the same, that you are my brother
and I am your sister this sort of things but
in their hearts there is still something lurking
because the heart and the head are not integrated.
We believe into so many things but the heart
and the brain, they are not integrated.
How do you find, that the person who is believing
into something but is not doing that? Because
they are not integrated. When the heart and
brain both are absolutely integrated then
you do what you believe into, and [if] you
believe into something, then you do that.
Both things go hand in hand, and that’s
how these things that we feel look so funny
with people. They talk so big! They say they,
“We’ll do this for you,” and, “This
is what we feel,” They make all kinds of
drama. And ultimately you find they have no
feels about it. But I do not blame them because
they haven’t found their Spirit, which integrates
you completely. And this is the time when
you will get your complete integration in
life.
Now coming to absolute mundane level of things:
the other day, a gentleman of the radio came
to interview me and he said, “Alright. You
tell tell me that physical, emotional and
also mental problems can be solved through
Sahaja Yoga.” It’s true. We have cured
cancer. There is one girl today, who came
today from America. She has cured a blood
cancer [case]. Of course it’s true. It can
be cured. With this happening, with the awakening
of Kundalini you can cure all these diseases.
Heart troubles, all these can be cured. Then
mentally also: many mad people have become
sane people. Many addicts and all sorts of
things have become alright. No doubt! It can
be done. But you have to first of all get
your realisation. Without that, without that
first step, nothing can be achieved.
First step is that you get your light in.
Now some people think that we should work
very hard and we should cleanse ourselves,
we should do this and we should do that and
then we should take realisation. But why?
Unless and until you get out of yourself you
cannot cleanse yourself, you cannot see yourself,
and you cannot understand because you are
so identified. For example, if you correct
somebody, “You have got ego.” He’ll
just punch you on your nose and say, “What
do you mean by such a thing? What do you mean,
‘You have an ego’? You are the one who
has the ego! What do you mean by saying such
a thing to me that ‘You have an ego’?”
But when you get your realisation, when the
Kundalini rises, here at this point, where
you see this red mark, behind it, on the optic
chiasma there’s a very subtle centre called
Agya chakra. On this centre resides our Lord
Jesus Christ. And He sucks in your ego and
superego. And when your attention is there,
you can see your ego bloating up like a balloon.
You see it and you say, “Oh God! This is
me? Alright.” Nobody minds then if you tell
them that, “Your Agya chakra is catching.”
Nobody minds it. Because they don’t like
it [to be catching]. They want to have these
vibrations flowing into you.
Then there can be a person with a superego.
A person who is always frightened, who has
fear and who always keeps quiet and goes into
some sort of alcoholism or something, shuns
the society. There could be person like that.
Such a person, also, when he sees light within
himself he becomes normal. Sahaja Yoga is
there to normalise you completely, to make
you a normal person.
But coming to the absolutely mundane thing
like this gentleman asked me a question that,
“What about our unemployment in England?
What do you say? What is the solution you
give for our unemployment if through Sahaja
Yoga?” I said, “That’s a very great
employment for you?” He said, “How?”
I said, “Let’s see how you got employed.
Let us be very practical about it.” You
are over developed people. You have got your
railways done, you have got your aeroplanes
done, all kinds of machineries you have finished
with. I mean, you have done everything and
to add to it now you have computers! Sitting
down here you can move everybody’s nose
and eyes and everything, you don’t have
to move out of here. You can even destroy
the whole world sitting down here. You don’t
have to do anything.
So you have reached that state where, now,
you must rest. You have had too much development.
So, as a holiday, now you are resting. And
that’s how you are unemployed. But, in the
subtle way, it is a Divine’s working. How?
Science and all these powers have been given
to us, exposed to us because we have to finish
our every day-to-day work and save time. We
have been wearing watches. I don’t think
my grandmother wore any watch all her life.
Nor could have been yours also. That time
nobody bothered about time. Time was passing,
nobody bothered about that. But now we are
all the time, “Save the time, save the time,
save the time.” But save for what? Save
for the pub, or save for the ballroom dancing,
or for the quarrelling, or for hitting others
or talking ill of others? Save for yourself.
Save for your meditation. Save for your ascent.
And this saving itself, the time that you
have saved, has brought in the birth of so
many seekers on this Earth.
Now this is the time [that] you have got such
a lot of spare time to you. Why this spare
time has been awarded to you? Is to ascend.
Now you have been employed for worldly things
and worldly materialistic things and all that
but now you are to be employed by God. You
have to seek His employment. Once you get
your realisation, now we have Sahaja Yogis,
first I first said all Sahaja Yogis must seek
some jobs. They should not be unemployed.
But just to make it look normal I told that.
But they are so employed now, they have no
time, they are so busy. They are giving realisation
to people, they are curing people, they are
going round telling them about the message.
They are so busy, they are doing God’s work.
Now you are no more employed with the government.
You are not employed by any private companies,
but you are employed by God. So, you are free,
you are getting your food alright, you are
getting your pensions alright. Now you work.
I have seen people who are even eighty years
old, ninety years old [that] are doing God’s
work. From India, recently when I went to
America, a gentleman who is about seventy-six
years of age came down to get me from India,
all the way. And he said, “Now I am doing
God’s work, so I am not at all tired, I
am not at all afraid.” He and his wife,
both of them, came to Los Angeles to help
me down there.
So now the new employment has to start and
that is the employment of God.
You can meet the Sahaja Yogis and ask them.
They are very busy people. They have no time.
Now my grandchildren who are here, they are
also born-realised people, they are very enlightened
people. And they are very busy. They have
no time for anything. You see, since we have
come here they have been busy going round
and trying to see wider people. Now, we went
to the airport one day, and this girl was
tying up like this, very fast, she was doing
like this, very fast, like a machine was on.
So her mother asked, “What are you doing?”
She said, “I’m trying to tie up the whole
of airport. You see, they are running helter-skelter
they are all getting mad!” And this action
works out because the hands are flowing [with]
that Divine Power. So this action has a meaning.
And she was working it out like that and she
was going on, and she said, “I have to tie
up all these people, they are so speedy, so
crazy, they are running fast for nothing at
all.” And she was just trying to do that.
They are all the time busy. [If] you talk
to them, “No I’m just I’m busy!” They
will do something here and there and they
try to correct it.
So the new employment one has to take. But
the first of all, the first criteria of this
new employment is that you should become the
Spirit. If you are not the Spirit, you cannot
do it. So you become the Spirit. Then you
must learn the methods of how to use this
Divine Power, how should it be done.
That’s all! It’s so simple. It’s all
made for you. It’s very easy. Nothing to
work out. But one should not go on thinking
about it. Because it is beyond thought. By
thinking you have built up all these things,
by planning you have done all this. But now
you have to enter into the Realm of God, to
be the citizen of God Empire where he gives
you powers by which you work out the world.
But the whole. And then you really feel your
generosity and your giving powers which are
so great, your forgiving powers, which are
so satisfying. All the great powers will start
feeling once you become that Spirit. And that
is very important, to become the Spirit.
Now of course, you can say, there are many
who talk like this. They have to! They have
to talk like this, but there are ways of understanding
how to make out a person who is real and who
is unreal.
First of all, it is a living happening. It’s
the happening in your evolutionary process.
As you have become human being you have to
become a higher being. You are still in transition.
You do not know why you are here. You don’t
know your meaning, that’s why you are frustrated,
that’s why you are unhappy. So this has
to happen to all of us.
Now for this, everybody can say, “Alright,
I’ll give you an experience.”
The other day one girl told me that a gentleman
came and told us, “I’ll give you an experience.”
And what experience did he give? She said,
“We became dumbfounded.” I said, “What
is there [so special] to be dumbfounded?”
Supposing you go to a pub and have a big drink
you can be dumbfounded! What’s so valuable
[in that]? What is an experience? Supposing
you are pricked you might get the experience
of pain or something. Experience is not the
thing, it’s the awareness. What happens
to your awareness is the point. Is your awareness
is enlightened? Has your awareness got the
new dimension by which you understand other
people, the collectively consciousness? Did
you become collective? Are you collectively
conscious? Ask this simple question to yourself.
But it’s very easy to scan out these people
because everything they do is for money or
for women, or something very, very low level
thing. I mean, everybody who is trying to
do something is nothing but money or buildings
or all these things which are not important.
In the realm of God, what is important is
the joy, is the peace, is the love. And when
we can achieve that Spirit then only we can
talk about it. Before that, if I tell you
a big story, what’s the use? It has to happen,
it has to work out. It’s your own right
to get it. You cannot sell it in the market
because it’s a living process. For example,
supposing there’s a seed which has to grow,
sprout, and it’s a living process, can we
pay money to the seed? “Now you please grow?”
Or a flower which has to become the fruit,
can you pay money to the flower? “Alright,
come along now, become a fruit!” Will it
become? It’s as simple as that.
All these living things are done by this All-pervading
Power. We have become human beings also through
the grace of this All-pervading Power. Even
you have to become higher beings it will be
through that.
‘Sahaja’ means ‘born with you’. Also
it means it’s ‘simple’, ‘spontaneous’.
Everything living is spontaneous and that’s
why you cannot pay for it, you cannot sell
it in the market. It has nothing to do with
money.
God doesn’t understand money. He never saw
money. He doesn’t know what it is you human
beings have created, this money, this poverty,
this richness. He has nothing to do with it.
He has created a beautiful world, a beautiful
place for all of you live and He has created
you to enjoy it. But if you have made complications
and hangs-up and you are so complicated it’s
better to get out of it and become a simple
personality. To become a simple personality
also you have to get to that level which is
the Spirit.
And that is what Sahaja yoga is today.
As Gavin has told you that you have to put
hands towards me.
Now I must say, I must confess that that’s
my job. I have to accept it. But it should
not in any way hurt your ego. Because the
other day somebody told me, “Why you Mother?”
I said, “Please come along! I’ll be very
happy.
If you can do it nothing like it! I’ll be
very happy. Now see, I have a good family,
a very good husband, my family, my children,
my grandchildren and they are happy people.
Actually yesterday he was not well also so
much and he didn’t want me to come here
but I said, “No I must go to this place.
It’s definite I must go.” And I managed
to come here. And he also realises how important
it is to transform people. But it’s my job
what can I do? You see, if it is my job are
you going to crucify me for that? I have been
really asked to do this job and I am doing
it in my own humble way just to give you something.
I have to just give you. I have nothing to
take from you. I am standing at an end where
I cannot take anything. I can just give you
my love and you should just accept it. Is
there any harm in accepting somebody’s love?
Which you cannot pay for.
But once you get realisation, once you are
enlightened, you can enlighten other people.
Like one light which is enlightened can enlighten
another person and when that person is enlightened,
can enlighten another person.
It’s simple as that. I was born as an enlightened
personality. And I was aware of it. And then
my father told me, very frankly that, “Now
you find out a method by which you can give
a en-masse realisation. Because otherwise
if you speak it will become another Bible,
and people will fight; it will be another
Judaism, and they will fight, another Islam,
and they will fight. It’s better that you
give them realisation. Because [if] somebody
is born on the tenth storey and he talks of
the tenth storey and people on the ground
do not rise. First they are jealous or they
are angry or they think the man is mad and
they will do all kinds of things like crucifixion,
giving poison, torturing the saints and all
that.” He said, “Nothing doing! First
of all you make them rise at least two storeys
or three storeys. Let them feel that there
is something beyond. Once they start feeling
there’s something beyond that they have
to achieve it in their awareness then only
they will understand that there is God and
there is Divinity.”
Blind faith is no use. In the same way, denying
God is also no use. You must see and witness
this happening and then, once you become the
Self, you will understand God. Before becoming
the Self you cannot understand God, that’s
why even Buddha didn’t talk about God. He
said, “You better not talk of God. Once
you talk of God, again hypocrisy starts.”
So he said, “Let’s talk of the Self-realisation
only. Once they get their Self-realisation,
then I’ll talk about God.” But you know,
he didn’t live that long to tell people.
Actually, in his life time, he couldn’t
give realisation to many people.
Luckily I am in England. It’s all arranged,
I think. I have to be here because this is
going to be the Jerusalem. And I have been
struggling with English people quite a lot!
And I had six people with me for four years
– you won’t believe – and I was struggling
with them, with the six people. But they were
managed and they are now the foundation of
Sahaja Yoga in England.
English people are wise people. They are scholarly
people. They don’t rush to conclusions.
They are sensible people. But a kind of an
inertia is settled because of the experiences
of the past. Experiences of the religious
people, experiences of the fake gurus, experiences
of the other experiments that people have
done and they are really now fed up and fagged
out that, “We are not going to go in for
anything more!”
But supposing you are seeking a diamond and
ultimately find it.
Won’t you ask for it? Because you have been
seeking that only. So why not get to it and
do it?
No use identifying yourself with something:
with some organisation, with some cult, with
some sort of a misguided religion, or religious
behaviours.
Best is to be your Self. And then, you will
be surprised, your hands will speak. You yourself
will know who is the real who is the unreal.
Now there is one drawback that people feel
that, if you start jumping, you have become,
you are, blessed by Holy Ghost! If you start
talking something non-sensical, you have been
blessed by Holy Ghost.
How can that be? We can always jump. It’s
not difficult. Is it difficult to jump? Anybody
can start jumping. Anybody can start saying
something like that. Now, this misunderstanding
has come, because
‘Saint’ Paul I think said something, which
he should not have said because he was not
realised soul. And he had no business to say
that the Holy Ghost made them jump. Actually
this is done by the [dead] spirits. People
can mesmerise you and can make you jump. They
can mesmerise you. You have seen so many cases
where mass hypnosis has taken place. People
are just hypnotised to become the slaves of
these people, to give them money,
to give them Rolls Royces, to give them all
kinds of useless things.
So we must understand that this happening
is a living happening. You cannot pull out
your Kundalini like that. You cannot pull
out the primule, the germinating seedling
from the seed. You cannot pull it out [and
say], “Now come along now! You grow.”
It has to grow by itself. In the same way,
the happening of the Kundalini, in so many
people you can see. If you come to my programme
later on, you will be able to see. That you
can see the pulsation of the Kundalini in
the Sacrum, you can see the pulsation rising.
You can feel it on the fontanel bone area.
And once this opens out, you can feel the
cool breeze coming out of your head. You can
feel it, the cool breeze, coming out. And
also then you start feeling the cool breeze
in your hand.
Now this you cannot do! No one can do it.
Something has happened to you. And then once
you get it, if you start practicing it, you
will be amazed what powers you have got. Because,
supposing, even if I have powers, or if I
have money and I don’t know how to spend
it, I don’t know what the money is, what
this paper means – what’s the use? In
the same way, when you get this, you have
to give it to others. You have to look after
others. You have to impart this beauty to
others. In doing that you do not get into
any trouble, you do not suffer from anything.
On the contrary you feel so elated. And the
fulfilment of your being comes into you that
there’s some meaning to our lives. Something
that we are doing which is so substantial,
so living. We are doing the work of God.
May God bless you all.
It’s such a big subject that, in this short
time, I cannot explain every aspect of it.
It’s a very, very wide thing. But now I
can only say that there are about six [to]
severn hundred lectures I have given only
in England and I don’t know how many in
India. Still they say, “Mother, always you
say something new. I just don’t understand.”
But whatever it is, knowledge by words is
of no use. Knowledge should be your own which
should come to you as light. For example,
in a library, if you get a way of knowing
every book, just by the subtle entering into
it, or penetration into it, you [will] become
the knowledge. So best thing is to become
the knowledge instead of just knowing through
me and understanding it through me, which
you can do it. You are quite capable of doing
it and it can happen to all of you.
I wish this evening especially it should happen.
They say it is a small village. And to me,
small or big doesn’t matter. It’s how
many are there [who are] genuine seekers,
who are genuinely seeking God, who are seeking
their Spirit? That’s the most important
thing for me. Even there is one person like
that I’ll go to that place. Whether it’s
one house, or one village, or a big city,
makes no difference to me.