shree our garage totem
Oh
and it is recited for the love of Shri
Jagadamba a mother of the universe as
part of the door goes up the sheti are
mean salutations to sri chandika free
markandeya spoke thus Oh goddess
jayanthi who wins everyone mangala who
gives salvation golly bhadrakali who is
benevolent devotees the polony Durga
chama who tolerates everyone Shiva
daughtry swaha and SWA da salutations to
you
victory BTW you Oh Davy chamunda victory
BTW you or a mover of miseries of all
living beings victory be to you Oh Davy
was present everywhere
salutations to you Oh cholera three the
last night salutations to you Oh Davy
the killer of the demon madhu and kotoba
and the restorer of Boone's on Sri
Brahma Deva please give us the spiritual
personality the victory the glory and
destroy our enemies salutations to you o
Devi the killer of mahishasura and giver
of happiness to your devotees please
give us the spiritual personality the
victory the glory and destroy our
enemies
Oh Davy the killer drugged abuja and
destroyer of demons chanda and Wanda
please give us the spiritual personality
the victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy the killer of demon
shumba nashumba and Dumber aksha please
give us the spiritual personality the
victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy was Lotus sweeter
worshiped by gods and gives good fortune
please give us the spiritual personality
the victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy was Foreman character
are beyond the mind will destroys all
the enemies please give us the spiritual
personality the victory the glory and
destroy our enemies
Oh Davy chandika but asteroid of
sufferings please give those who always
humble before you in devotion the
spiritual personality the victory or
glory and destroy our enemies Oh Davy
chandika the destroyer of all diseases
please give to the devotees who praise
you with devotion the spiritual
personality the victory the glory and
destroy their enemies Oh David Chandaka
please give those who always worship you
with devotion in this world the
spiritual personality the victory a
glory and destroy their enemies Oh Davy
please give us good fortune health
complete happiness spiritual personality
the victory or glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy please destroy those who
hate your devotees give us strength a
spiritual personality the victory the
glory and destroy our enemies Oh Davy
please confer upon us the benevolence
great wealth the spiritual personality
the victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy ambika your lotus feet
are out by the gems of the Crown's worn
by gods and demons please bestow upon us
a spiritual personality a victory a
glory and destroy our enemies Oh Davy
please make your devotees knowledgeable
glorified and wealthy and give us the
spiritual personality the victory the
glory and destroy our enemies Oh Davy
the destroyer of the ego ferocious
demons or chandika please give us the
spiritual personality the victory the
glory and destroy our enemies oh but
initially the supreme goddess having
four arms and who is praised by the
four-faced one true Brahma Deva
please give us the spiritual personality
the victory the glory and destroy our
enemies Oh Davy ambika who was ever
praised with all devotion by Shri
Krishna please give us the spiritual
personality the victory the glory and
destroy our enemies or parameshwari the
supreme goddess was praised by the
husband of the daughter of the Himalayas
Shri Shiva please give us the spiritual
personality the victory a glory and
destroy our enemies Oh parameshwari was
worshipped with true feelings by the
husband of Indrani Indra please give us
the spiritual personality the victory
the glory and destroy our enemies
Oh Davy the destroyer of pride of
Beeman's by your strong arms please give
us the spiritual personality a victory a
glory and destroy our enemies or Davy
ambika you enlighten the supreme joy
moksha of your devotees please give us
the spiritual personality the victory
for glory and destroy our enemies
sasha shri adi shakti my body shreeman
mile rd ba
number
you